const dictionary=[{term:"ALTA",definition:"American Land Title Association",id:"1223"},{term:"ALTA Owner's Policy",definition:"American Land Title Association policy of extended title insurance",id:"1224"},{term:"ALTA POLICY",definition:"American Land Title Association policy of extended title insurance policy can be purchased by lender or buyer.",id:"1225"},{term:"ABSTRACT OF TITLE",definition:"A full summary of all consecutive grants conveyances wills records and judicial proceedings affecting title to a specific parcel of real estate.",id:"1226"},{term:"Abstractor",definition:"A person who, historically, searches out anything affecting the title to real property and summarizes the information in the findings",id:"1227"},{term:"ACCELERATION CLAUSE",definition:"A clause in a loan document describing certain events that would cause the entire loan to be due. in the event the property described herein or any part hereof or any interest therein is sold conveyed alienato assigned or otherwise transferred by the maker or by the operation of law or otherwise all obligations secured by this instrument irrespective of the maturity dates expressed therein at the option of the payee thereof and without demand or notice shall immediately become due and payable. This phrase must be placed on note and trust deed and incorporated into instructions.",id:"1228"},{term:"Acceptance",definition:"An unqualified agreement to the terms of an offer",id:"1229"},{term:"ACCESS TO PROPERTY",definition:"Seller will provide reasonable access to the property to buyer inspectors representing buyer to representatives of lending institutions for appraisal purposes or for any other purpose relating to the sale.",id:"1230"},{term:"Accession",definition:"The acquisition of title to additional land or to improvements as a result of annexing fixtures or as a result of natural causes such as alluvial deposits along the banks of streams by accretion",id:"1231"},{term:"ACCOMMODATION RECORDING",definition:"I hand you herewith executed by-to which you are authorized to use in connection with the subject escrow. It is agreed that shall assume no responsibility in connection with recording of said- on my behalf as an accommodation to the undersigned. Affix $ documentary transfer tax (if a Deed) as total consideration is $-. Charge $-for transfer tax if applicable and for recordation of document.",id:"1232"},{term:"Accountant",definition:"A person who supervises the keeping of financial records pertaining to properties being managed. Generally more qualified than a bookkeeper.",id:"1233"},{term:"Accredited Management Organization (AMO)",definition:"A property management designation offered by the Institute of Real Estate Management (IREM) to property management companies that meet prescribed high standards.",id:"1234"},{term:"Accredited Residential Manager (ARM)",definition:"A property management designation offered by the Institute of Real Estate Management (IREM).",id:"1235"},{term:"Accretion",definition:"A buildup of soil by natural causes on property bordering a river, lake or ocean",id:"1236"},{term:"Accrued",definition:"Accumulated over a period of time",id:"1237"},{term:"Accrued Depreciation",definition:"The difference between the cost to replace the property and property's current appraised value",id:"1238"},{term:"ACKNOWLEDGMENT",definition:"A formal declaration to a public official.",id:"1239"},{term:"Action",definition:"A lawsuit brought to court",id:"1240"},{term:"Actual Age",definition:"The real age of a building",id:"1241"},{term:"Actual Depreciation",definition:"That depreciation occurring as a result of physical, functional or economic forces, causing loss in value to a building",id:"1242"},{term:"ACTUAL NOTICE",definition:"Notice given by possession of property.",id:"1243"},{term:"Ad Valorem",definition:"A Latin prefix meaning 'according to value.' Local governments levy real property tax based on the assessed value; property taxes are known as ad valorem taxes",id:"1244"},{term:"ADDITIONAL INTEREST DUE/PAYOFFS",definition:"The buyer and seller agree that disbursement of any payoffs for encumbrances being paid off at close of escrow must be received by the Lender by a specific date to avoid further accrual of interest. You are instructed to forward payoff funds to the lender and charge the appropriate account any fees at close of escrow. In the event the lender demands additional funds after the close of escrow buyer or seller agrees to deposit additional funds according to lender's instructions.",id:"1245"},{term:"ADJUSTABLE RATE MORTGAGE (ARM)",definition:"A note whose interest rate is tied to a flexible index.",id:"1246"},{term:"Adjusted Cost Basis",definition:"Original basis plus capital improvements and costs of the sale, less depreciation if income producing",id:"1247"},{term:"Administrative Assistant",definition:"A position that assists any of the execu-tive or middle management personnel in the achievement of their job objectives.",id:"1248"},{term:"Administrator / Administratrix",definition:"A person appointed by the court to handle the affairs of a deceased person when there is no one mentioned in a will to do so",id:"1249"},{term:"Adverse Possession",definition:"Acquiring title to property by continued possession and payment of taxes",id:"1250"},{term:"After Acquired Title",definition:"Any benefits that come to a property after a sale must follow the sale and accrue to the new owner",id:"1251"},{term:"Agency",definition:"A relationship in which one party (principal) authorizes another party (agent) to act as the principal's representative in dealing with third parties",id:"1252"},{term:"AGENCY RELATIONSHIP CONFIRMATION",definition:"The following agency relationship is hereby confirmed for this transaction: The selling agent is the agent of the buyer exclusively; or seller exclusively; or both the buyer and seller.",id:"1253"},{term:"Agent",definition:"A person who acts for and in the place of another, called a principal, for the purpose of affecting the principal's legal relationship with third persons",id:"1254"},{term:"AGREEMENT OF SALE",definition:"A contract for the sale of real property where the seller gives up possession but retains the title until the purchase price is paid in full.",id:"1255"},{term:"Agricultural Land",definition:"Land used for farming purposes including growing crops and raising livestock.",id:"1256"},{term:"AH&MA",definition:"The American Hotel and Motel Association the only trade association representing the lodging industry.",id:"1257"},{term:"AIDA Formula",definition:"In marketing a formula for writing an ad that is designed to get maximum results. A=Attention I=Interest D=Desire A=Action.",id:"1258"},{term:"Airport Hotel",definition:"A lodging accommodation to meet travelers' needs at the beginning or end of a journey. The modern ones include conference rooms fitness centers and restaurants.",id:"1259"},{term:"Alienate",definition:"Transfer ownership or sell",id:"1260"},{term:"ALIENATION CLAUSE",definition:"A clause in a loan document that would allow the lender to call the entire loan due upon the sale of the property.",id:"1261"},{term:"ALL-INCLUSIVE TRUST DEED",definition:"A purchase money deed of trust subordinate to-but still including-the original loan.",id:"1262"},{term:"All-Suite Hotel",definition:"A hotel offering full suites to its guests similar to a one- bedroom apartment.",id:"1263"},{term:"Alluvial Deposit",definition:"Sand or mud, carried by water and deposited on land",id:"1264"},{term:"Alluvium",definition:"Soil that builds up as a result of accretion",id:"1265"},{term:"AMENDING PREVIOUS INSTRUCTIONS",definition:"These instructions supersede and amend any previous instructions in your escrow no.- relative to the terms set forth These instructions shall be your authority to act as directed in your capacity as escrow agent.",id:"1266"},{term:"Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA)",definition:"A law passed by Congress in 1990 requiring any business or public facility to be accessible to everyone including those with disabilities.",id:"1267"},{term:"Americans with Disabilities Act Accessibility Guidelines (ADAAG)",definition:"A document which provides standards to be observed in the design construction and alteration of buildings that come under the jurisdiction of the ADA.",id:"1268"},{term:"Annual Net Income",definition:"Also called net operating income the amount of income left from an income -producing property after all expenses have been deducted.",id:"1269"},{term:"ANNUAL PERCENTAGE RATE (APR)",definition:"The relationship of the total finance charge to the total amount to be financed as required under the Truth-in-Lending Act.",id:"1270"},{term:"Appraisal",definition:"An estimate or opinion of value supported by factual information as of a certain date",id:"1271"},{term:"Appraisal Report",definition:"A written report stating an appraiser's estimate of a subject property's value",id:"1272"},{term:"Appreciation",definition:"An increase in value",id:"1273"},{term:"APPURTENANCE",definition:"Those rights privileges and improvements that belong to and pass with the transfer of real property but are not necessarily a part of the actual property.",id:"1274"},{term:"Arm's Length Transaction",definition:"A transaction, such as a sale of property, in which all parties involved are acting in their own self-interest and are under no undue influence or pressure from the other parties",id:"1275"},{term:"Asbestos Hazard Emergency Response Act (AHERA)",definition:"A law passed by Congress in 1986 which amends the Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA). It requires all public schools to be inspected for the presence of asbestos and to remedy the problem if it is likely to be hazardous to people's health.",id:"1276"},{term:"Assessment Roll or Tax Roll",definition:"A list of all taxable property showing the assessed value of each parcel; establishes the tax base",id:"1277"},{term:"Asset Manager",definition:"An executive who oversees the firm's real estate resources setting goals and strategies with ownership interests. Also called a portfolio manager.",id:"1278"},{term:"Assignee",definition:"The person to whom a claim, benefit or right in property is made",id:"1279"},{term:"Assignment",definition:"The transfer of a claim, benefit or right in property from one person to another",id:"1280"},{term:"ASSIGNMENT OF RENTS",definition:"An agreement between a property owner and the holder of a trust deed or mortgage by which the holder receives as security the right to collect rents from tenants of the property in the event of default by the borrower.",id:"1281"},{term:"Assignor",definition:"The person transferring a claim, benefit or right in property to another",id:"1282"},{term:"Assistant Manager (Hotel)",definition:"The manager who relieves the general manager of selected duties and interfaces with department heads.",id:"1283"},{term:"ASSUMPTION CLAUSE",definition:"A buyer takes over the existing loan and agrees to be liable for the repayment of the loan.",id:"1284"},{term:"ATTORNEY FEES",definition:"if the buyer seller or broker brings an action to enforce his or her rights under this agreement including an action to recover commissions the prevailing party shall be entitled to receive from the defaulting party a reasonable attorney fee to be determined by the court or arbitrator.",id:"1285"},{term:"Attorney in Fact",definition:"A competent and disinterested person who is authorized by another person to act in his or her place in legal matters",id:"1286"},{term:"Avulsion",definition:"The sudden washing or tearing away of land by the action of water",id:"1287"},{term:"Back- of-the -House",definition:"Operations of the hotel business that are preparatory in nature and take place behind the scenes out of the view of guests.",id:"1288"},{term:"Back-End Ratio",definition:"The ratio of all fixed debt including housing expenses to gross income.",id:"1289"},{term:"Balance Sheet",definition:"A report showing the assets of a business the liabilities and the net worth.",id:"1290"},{term:"BALLOON PAYMENT",definition:"Under an installment loan a final payment that is substantially larger than any other payment and repays the debt in full.",id:"1291"},{term:"BALLOON PAYMENT CLAUSE",definition:"This note provides that the holder of this note shall give written notice to Trustor (borrower) of prescribed information at least 90 and not more than 150 days before any balloon payment is due.",id:"1292"},{term:"BALLOON PAYMENT DISCLOSURE",definition:"All parties agree that they have not received or relied upon any statements or representations made to them by the broker regarding availability of funds or rate of interest at which funds might be available when buyer is obligated to refinance or pay off the remaining balance of any loan which is part of this agreement.",id:"1293"},{term:"Band of Investment",definition:"A method of determining the capitalization rate in which the return demanded by investment money in various positions is calculated and combined.",id:"1294"},{term:"Banquet Director",definition:"The person in charge of all physical aspects of a banquet.",id:"1295"},{term:"BASE LINE",definition:"A survey line running east and west used as a reference when mapping land.",id:"1296"},{term:"Bed & Breakfast Inn",definition:"A lodging accommodation generally con-verted from a large house or hotel with personal service to offer a pleasant get-away experience.",id:"1297"},{term:"Bell Captain",definition:"The second-ranking job in the service department in charge of the bellhops.",id:"1298"},{term:"Bellhop",definition:"A service assistant in a hotel to usher guests to their rooms carry baggage and offer other personal services.",id:"1299"},{term:"BENEFICIARY",definition:"The lender under a note and deed of trust.",id:"1300"},{term:"Beneficiary Statement",definition:"A statement of the unpaid balance of a loan and the condition of the debt, as it relates to a deed of trust",id:"1301"},{term:"Bequest",definition:"A gift of personal property by will; see legacy",id:"1302"},{term:"Bilateral Contract",definition:"A contract in which each party to the contract promises to perform some act or duty in exchange for the promise of the other party",id:"1303"},{term:"BILL OF SALE",definition:"A written agreement used to transfer ownership in personal property.",id:"1304"},{term:"BILL Of SALE*",definition:"Buyer and seller agree to make a joint itemized inventory of all personal items to be conveyed through this escrow and will deposit it with escrow holder. You are to prepare a bill of sale to be executed by the seller who states that all items being conveyed will be free and clear of encumbrances and/ or liens unless previously disclosed to buyer. You are instructed to include list of the bill of sale being created in escrow instructions.",id:"1305"},{term:"BLANKET LOAN",definition:"A loan secured by several properties.",id:"1306"},{term:"Block Busting",definition:"Causing panic selling by telling people that values in a neighborhood will decline because of a specific event, such as the purchase of homes by minorities",id:"1307"},{term:"BONDS OR ASSESSMENTS",definition:"if there is a bond or assessment on the subject property with an outstanding balance and is a lien upon this property it shall be paid by seller (assumed by b. if the bond or assessment is to be assumed the obligation shall (not) be credited to buyer at closing. This agreement is conditioned upon all parties verifying and approving in writing the amount of any bond or assessment within ten (10) days of receipt of the preliminary title report. The disapproving party may terminate this escrow in which case all unused deposits shall be returned to Buyer.",id:"1308"},{term:"Book Depreciation",definition:"An accounting concept which refers to an allowance taken to provide for recovery of invested capital",id:"1309"},{term:"Book Sale",definition:"A sale of real property to the state, in name only, when a taxpayer is delinquent in paying property tax",id:"1310"},{term:"Book Value",definition:"The initial cost of the property plus capital improvements minus the total accrued depreciation",id:"1311"},{term:"Bookkeeper",definition:"A person who keeps financial records on properties being managed.",id:"1312"},{term:"Boot",definition:"Money or any 'non-like' property put into a sale by an investor to balance the equities in a l03l tax deferred exchange; cash or mortgage relief in an exchange",id:"1313"},{term:"Breach of Contract",definition:"A failure to perform on part or all of the terms and conditions of a contract",id:"1314"},{term:"BROKER",definition:"Listing broker selling broker cooperating brokers and all sales persons.",id:"1315"},{term:"BROKER BUYING AS PRINCIPAL",definition:"Seller acknowledges that buyer is a licensed real estate broker (salesperson) acting as a principal for his or her own account.",id:"1316"},{term:"BROKER REPRESENTING BOTH PARTIES",definition:"By placing their initials here: b and seller agree that the broker in this transaction represents all parties with the consent and knowledge of all parties.",id:"1317"},{term:"Brokerage",definition:"The occupation of a broker; the business of selling real estate through a broker who negotiates the sale for a commission",id:"1318"},{term:"Building Engineer",definition:"A position that inspects the structured com-ponents and the permanent systems of a building to ensure safety and compliance with all government regulations.",id:"1319"},{term:"BULK TRANSFER LAW",definition:"The law concerning the transfer in bulk by a retail business (not a sale in the ordinary course of the seller's business).",id:"1320"},{term:"Bundle of Rights",definition:"An ownership concept describing all the legal rights that attach to the ownership of real property",id:"1321"},{term:"Business Cycle",definition:"The constant fluctuation of levels of income employment and the amount of goods and services produced in a given fiscal year.",id:"1322"},{term:"BUSINESS OPPORTUNITY",definition:"Any type of business that is for lease or sale.",id:"1323"},{term:"BUYER'S APPROVAL OF DISCLOSURE STATEMENT",definition:"If Transfer Disclosure Statement is delivered to buyer after the execution of this offer buyer is allowed to terminate this agreement by written notice delivered to seller or his agent within three (3) days from receipt of the Transfer Disclosure Statement. All deposits to be returned less expenses incurred to date of termination.",id:"1324"},{term:"Buyer's Market",definition:"A stage in the real estate market in which the ready willing and able buyer is in the minority and is in control of the market. A time of oversupply and decreased demand. Prices decline during this stage of the cycle.",id:"1325"},{term:"By-Laws",definition:"Rules and regulations that govern the activities of a homeowner's association.",id:"1326"},{term:"CLTA",definition:"California Land Title Association",id:"1327"},{term:"Calendar Year",definition:"Starts on January l and continues through December 3l of the same year",id:"1328"},{term:"California Land Title Association",definition:"A trade organization of the state's title companies",id:"1329"},{term:"CANCELLATION INSTRUCTIONS",definition:"The buyer had agreed to purchase the seller agreed to sell that certain property commonly known as . However buyer and seller mutually agree to cancel the subject escrow and escrow holder is hereby authorized to disburse the deposit you now hold in the sum of $-as follows:$-to- $ to and any charges for title or escrow services $-to It is also agreed that buyer and seller will hold the broker and escrow holder harmless and free of any liability in connection with the release of funds as directed by the buyer and seller and for the cancellation of the escrow as directed by the principals.",id:"1330"},{term:"Cap Rate",definition:"A term sometimes used when referring to capitalization rate",id:"1331"},{term:"Capacity",definition:"Legitimate legal status to enter into a contract (not mentally incompetent nor under-age) one of the legal essentials of a valid contract.",id:"1332"},{term:"Capital Improvements",definition:"Any permanent improvement made to real estate for the purpose of increasing the useful life of the property or increasing the property's value",id:"1333"},{term:"Capitalization",definition:"The process of calculating the present worth of a property on the basis of its capacity to continue to produce an income stream",id:"1334"},{term:"Capitalization Rate",definition:"The desired rate of return on an income producing property expressed as a decimal or percentage indi-cating the relationship between the value and the income.",id:"1335"},{term:"Cash Flow Statement",definition:"A report showing cash flow after distribu-tion for various categories of expense.",id:"1336"},{term:"CC&Rs",definition:"Covenants conditions and restrictions placed on certain types of real property which limit the activities of owners.",id:"1337"},{term:"CERCLA",definition:"The Comprehensive Environmental Response Compen-sation and Liability Act a law passed by Congress in 1980. Establishes two trust funds to help finance the cleanup of prop-erties that have been impacted by the release of hazardous wastes and substances. Commonly known as superfund.",id:"1338"},{term:"Certified Apartment Maintenance Technician (CAMT)",definition:"A desig-nation offered by the National Apartment Association (NAA).",id:"1339"},{term:"Certified Apartment Manager (CAM)",definition:"A designation offered by the National Apartment Association (NAA).",id:"1340"},{term:"Certified Apartment Property Supervisor (CAPS)",definition:"A designation offered by the National Apartment Association (NAA).",id:"1341"},{term:"Certified International Property Specialist (CIPS)",definition:"A property management designation offered by FLABCI-USA.",id:"1342"},{term:"Certified Leasing Specialist (CLS)",definition:"A designation offered by the International Council of Shopping Centers (ICSC).",id:"1343"},{term:"Certified Manager of Community Associations (CMCA)",definition:"A des-ignation offered by the Community Associations Institute (CAI).",id:"1344"},{term:"Certified Marketing Director (CMD)",definition:"A designation offered by the International Council of Shopping Centers (ICSC).",id:"1345"},{term:"Certified Property Manager (CPM)",definition:"The most advanced property management designation offered by the Institute of Real Estate Management IREM).",id:"1346"},{term:"Certified Shopping Center Manager (CSM)",definition:"A designation offered by the International Council of Shopping Centers (ICSC).",id:"1347"},{term:"CHAIN Of TITLE",definition:"The recorded history of matters such as conveyances liens and encumbrances affecting title to a parcel of real estate.",id:"1348"},{term:"CHATTEL",definition:"Personal property.",id:"1349"},{term:"CHATTEL REAL",definition:"An item of personal property which is connected to real estate for example a lease.",id:"1350"},{term:"Classified Ad",definition:"A small ad designed to give basic information.",id:"1351"},{term:"Clean Water Act",definition:"A law passed by Congress in 1972 to prohibit the discharge of pollutants into our natural waters.",id:"1352"},{term:"Clerk",definition:"A position in a hotel devoted to the detailed attention to one or more specific functions such as reservations or floor activities.",id:"1353"},{term:"Client",definition:"The person who employs an agent to perform a service for a fee",id:"1354"},{term:"CLOSING COSTS",definition:"On or before - or within- days of acceptance all parties shall deposit with Escrow Holder all funds and instruments necessary to complete the sale. Escrow fee to be paid by _ Documentary Transfer Tax if any to be paid by",id:"1355"},{term:"Codicil",definition:"A change in a will before the maker's death",id:"1356"},{term:"Collateral",definition:"Something of value given as security for a debt",id:"1357"},{term:"Commercial Property",definition:"A property where commerce is conducted such as an office building or retail shopping center.",id:"1358"},{term:"Commingling",definition:"To deposit client funds in the broker's personal account",id:"1359"},{term:"COMMISSION",definition:"A commission is to be paid to the broker at the close of escrow as directed by the terms of the commission agreement.",id:"1360"},{term:"COMMISSION SPLIT",definition:"The previously agreed upon division of money between a broker and sales associate when the brokerage has been paid commission from a sale made by the associate.",id:"1361"},{term:"Common Interest Developments (CIDs)",definition:"Real property develop-ments that include common interests and shared common areas.",id:"1362"},{term:"Community Apartment Project",definition:"One type of CID in which the owner has an undivided interest in the land with the exclusive right to occupy a particular unit.",id:"1363"},{term:"Community Center",definition:"A retail center anchored by a small depart-ment store and supported by up to 50 smaller stores. At least 5 000 households are usually needed to support a community center.",id:"1364"},{term:"Comparison",definition:"A method of determining the capitalization rate by looking to the operational capitalization rate of similar properties in the area.",id:"1365"},{term:"Compliance Clause",definition:"A clause in a lease designating which party is responsible for complying with various laws.",id:"1366"},{term:"Comps",definition:"A term used by real estate agents and appraisers to mean comparable properties",id:"1367"},{term:"Concierge",definition:"An employee in a large hotel who makes special arrangements for guests such as procuring theater tickets.",id:"1368"},{term:"CONCURRENT RECORDING",definition:"The closing of this escrow is contingent upon the concurrent closing of escrow no- . Neither escrow may close without the simultaneous closing of the other escrow.",id:"1369"},{term:"Condemnation",definition:"A common name for eminent domain, or the right of the government to take private property from an owner for the public good, paying fair market value",id:"1370"},{term:"Condition",definition:"A limiting restriction in the ownership of real property the violation of which could cause the owner to lose title or have his or her estate modified in some way",id:"1371"},{term:"CONDITION PRECEDENT",definition:"A condition which requires something to occur before a transaction becomes absolute and enforceable; for example a sale that is contingent on the buyer obtaining financing.",id:"1372"},{term:"CONDITION SUBSEQUENT",definition:"A condition which if it occurs at some point in the future can cause a property to revert to the grantor; for example a requirement in a grant deed that a buyer must never use the property for anything other than a private residence.",id:"1373"},{term:"Condominium",definition:"A structure for either residential industrial or commercial use whereby the owner owns the interior airspace of the unit plus an undivided interest in the common areas.",id:"1374"},{term:"Consideration",definition:"Something of value-such as money, a promise, property or personal services",id:"1375"},{term:"CONSTRUCTIVE NOTICE",definition:"Public notice given by recording a document with the county recorder.",id:"1376"},{term:"CONTINGENCY (WAIVED/SATISFIED)",definition:"Escrow holder is instructed that when the condition concerning has been (satisfied/waived) escrow holder is to proceed with the completion of this escrow. If the contingency is waived all parties should consent in writing.",id:"1377"},{term:"CONTRACT OF SALE",definition:"A contract for the sale of real property where the seller gives up possession but retains title until the total of the purchase price is paid in full.",id:"1378"},{term:"Contract Rent",definition:"The amount of rental income due from the tenant as agreed in the lease agreemen",id:"1379"},{term:"Contractual Intent",definition:"Intention to be bound by an agreement, thus preventing jokes and jests from becoming valid contracts",id:"1380"},{term:"Convention Hotel",definition:"A large hotel designed to accommodate thou-sands of guests for attendance at conferences.",id:"1381"},{term:"Conversion",definition:"The appropriation of property belonging to another",id:"1382"},{term:"Convey",definition:"To transfer ownership or title",id:"1383"},{term:"CONVEYANCE",definition:"The transfer of title to land from one person to another by use of a written instrument.",id:"1384"},{term:"COPIES",definition:"Copies of all documents must be given to buyer and seller at the time of signing.",id:"1385"},{term:"Corner Lot",definition:"A lot found at the intersection of two streets",id:"1386"},{term:"CORRECTIONS AND DELETIONS",definition:"Any corrections and deletions must be approved by all principals.",id:"1387"},{term:"Cost",definition:"Represents expenses in money, labor, material or sacrifices in acquiring or producing something",id:"1388"},{term:"Cost Basis",definition:"Usually the price paid for a property",id:"1389"},{term:"Counteroffer",definition:"The rejection of an original offer that becomes a new offer",id:"1390"},{term:"COURT CONFIRMATION",definition:"This escrow is subject to court confirmation. A certified copy of the court order confirming the transfer is to be recorded concurrently with or prior to the recording of other documents of the sale.",id:"1391"},{term:"Covenant",definition:"A promise or assurance set forth in a written agreement allowing or disallowing certain activities on the part of the owner.",id:"1392"},{term:"Cul-De-Sac Lot",definition:"A lot found on a dead-end street",id:"1393"},{term:"Customer",definition:"A prospective buyer of real estate",id:"1394"},{term:"Damage or Destruction Clause",definition:"A clause in a lease detailing how the partial or total destruction of the property would be handled between the parties to the lease.",id:"1395"},{term:"DATE OF ACCEPTANCE",definition:"Means the date the seller accepts the offer or the buyer accepts the counter offer.",id:"1396"},{term:"DATE OF CLOSING",definition:"Date title is transferred to buyer.",id:"1397"},{term:"Decimal Point",definition:"The period that sets apart a whole number from a fractional part of that number",id:"1398"},{term:"DECLARATION OF HOMESTEAD",definition:"The recorded document that protects a homeowner from foreclosure by certain judgment creditors.",id:"1399"},{term:"DEED OF TRUST - PRIORITY CLAUSE",definition:"This Deed of Trust is given to secure a portion of the purchase price of the subject property and is junior to a Deed of Trust in the amount of $_in favor of recording concurrently. OR This Deed of Trust is junior to that certain Deed of Trust for $_ in favor of _which recorded on as Instrument#_ Official Records of _County.",id:"1400"},{term:"DEED OF TRUST SECURING INSTALLMENT NOTE INTEREST INCLUDED",definition:"A Deed of Trust to record executed by buyer securing an installment note for $_in favor of payable at _with interest from at the rate of _percent per annum principal and interest payable $_ or more on the day of each month beginning and continuing until at which time all principal and interest has been paid in full. At close of escrow escrow holder is instructed to list the interest rate accrual date first payment date and maturity date on the reverse of the executed note according to the instructions of the parties.",id:"1401"},{term:"DEFAULT",definition:"Failure to pay a debt or on a contract.",id:"1402"},{term:"Default Clause",definition:"A clause in a lease setting forth the lessor's remedies in the event of a default by the lessee.",id:"1403"},{term:"Deferred Maintenance",definition:"Negligent care of a building",id:"1404"},{term:"DEFICIENCY JUDGMENT",definition:"A judgment against a borrower for the balance of a debt owed when the security for the loan is not sufficient enough to pay the debt.",id:"1405"},{term:"Definite and Certain",definition:"Precise acts to be performed are to be clearly stated",id:"1406"},{term:"Demise",definition:"A conveyance of an estate in real property to someone for a certain length of time, as in a lease; to let",id:"1407"},{term:"Demographics",definition:"The study of statistics relating to populations especially in the areas of demand for certain types of real estate.",id:"1408"},{term:"DEPOSIT INCREASE IN CASH",definition:"Initial deposit to be increased to $- within days from acceptance of this agreement.",id:"1409"},{term:"Deposit Receipt",definition:"Also known as a sales contract; the primary document used to present an offer on real property",id:"1410"},{term:"DEPOSITS",definition:"Escrow holder should note the form in which the deposit is received: Cash personal check certified check cashier's check.",id:"1411"},{term:"Depreciation",definition:"Loss in value from any cause",id:"1412"},{term:"Depression",definition:"A rare stage in the business cycle following a recession characterized by extremely high unemployment and very little purchasing power.",id:"1413"},{term:"Deregulation",definition:"A process where financial institutions that formerly had been restrained in their lending activities by the law are allowed to compete freely for profits in the marketplace",id:"1414"},{term:"Devise",definition:"A gift of real property by will",id:"1415"},{term:"Discrimination",definition:"Violating someone's right to fair housing oppor-tunity on the basis of who they are such as characteristics of race color sex religion familial status marital status disability or national origin.",id:"1416"},{term:"Disintermediation",definition:"The process of depositors removing funds from savings",id:"1417"},{term:"Display Ad",definition:"A large expansive ad that may use graphics and pictures to tell a more complete story.",id:"1418"},{term:"Dividend",definition:"A number to be divided by another number",id:"1419"},{term:"Divisor",definition:"A number by which another number is divided",id:"1420"},{term:"DOCTRINE OF CORRELATIVE USER",definition:"A riparian owner may use only a reasonable amount of the total water supply for his/her beneficial use.",id:"1421"},{term:"Dominant Tenement",definition:"The property that benefits from an easement",id:"1422"},{term:"Door Attendant",definition:"An employee in a large hotel who assists guests through entrances and exits and keeps foot traffic moving.",id:"1423"},{term:"Double Net Lease",definition:"An arrangement whereby the tenant pays the rent utilities property taxes special assessments and insurance premiums.",id:"1424"},{term:"Downtown Hotel",definition:"An older hotel with a downtown location.",id:"1425"},{term:"Dual Agent",definition:"An agent who represents both parties in a transaction",id:"1426"},{term:"DUE ON SALE DISCLOSURE",definition:"If there is a due on sale clause in any existing loan the lender may demand full payment of the entire loan as a result of this transfer. All parties agree that they are not relying on any representation by the other party or the broker about the enforceability of such a clause in existing notes or deeds of trust to be executed as a result of this sale. All parties have been advised by the broker to seek legal advise.",id:"1427"},{term:"Duress",definition:"The use of force to get agreement in accepting a contract",id:"1428"},{term:"EASEMENT",definition:"The right to use another's land for a specified purpose sometimes known as a right-of-way.",id:"1429"},{term:"EASEMENT IN GROSS",definition:"An easement that is not appurtenant to any one parcel; for example public utilities.",id:"1430"},{term:"Economic Life",definition:"The estimated period over which an improved property may be profitably used to yield a return",id:"1431"},{term:"Economic Rent",definition:"What a leased property would be expected to rent for under current market conditions if the property were vacant and available for rent",id:"1432"},{term:"Economic Rent Increase",definition:"An increase in rent prompted by a shrinking supply of comparable rental units in an area and the ability of tenants to afford the increase.",id:"1433"},{term:"Economics",definition:"Related to real estate a study of the factors that cause people to prosper and create a viable demand for real property.",id:"1434"},{term:"Effective Age",definition:"The years or age shown by the condition and utility of a structure, rather than its actual or chronological age",id:"1435"},{term:"Effective Gross Income",definition:"Also known as adjusted gross income the income actually collected after deducting for collection losses.",id:"1436"},{term:"Elevator Operator",definition:"Nearly obsolete an employee in a large period hotel who adds authenticity and keeps traffic moving.",id:"1437"},{term:"Emancipated Minor",definition:"Someone who is legally set free from parental control/ supervision",id:"1438"},{term:"EMBLEMENTS",definition:"Annual crops produced for sale.",id:"1439"},{term:"Eminent Domain",definition:"The right of the government to take private property from an owner, for the public good, paying fair market value",id:"1440"},{term:"ENCROACHMENT",definition:"The placement of permanent improvements on adjacent property owned by another.",id:"1441"},{term:"Environmental Impact Report (EIR)",definition:"A study of how a development will affect the ecology of its surroundings",id:"1442"},{term:"Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)",definition:"A federal agency estab-lished in 1970 to ensure the enforcement of the National Envi-ronmental. Policy Act (NEPA).",id:"1443"},{term:"EQUAL CREDIT OPPORTUNITY ACT",definition:"A Federal law that requires lenders to assure that credit is available with fairness impartiality and without discrimination.",id:"1444"},{term:"EQUITABLE TITLE",definition:"The interest held by the trustor or vendee.",id:"1445"},{term:"Equity",definition:"The value remaining in a property after payment of all liens",id:"1446"},{term:"EQUITY OF REDEMPTION",definition:"Also known as the right of redemption; the right of a debtor before a foreclosure sale to reclaim property that had been given up due to mortgage default.",id:"1447"},{term:"Erosion",definition:"The gradual wearing away of land by natural processes",id:"1448"},{term:"Escalation Clause",definition:"A clause in a lease that allows for rent increases based on the occurrence of a certain event.",id:"1449"},{term:"Escrow",definition:"The deposit of funds or documents with a neutral third party who is instructed to carry out the provisions of an agreement",id:"1450"},{term:"Escrow Holder",definition:"An independent third party legally bound to carry out the written provisions of an escrow agreement; a neutral, bonded third party who is a dual agent for the principals; sometimes called an escrow agent",id:"1451"},{term:"Escrow Instructions",definition:"Written directions, signed by a buyer and seller, detailing the procedures necessary to close a transaction and directing the escrow agent how to proceed",id:"1452"},{term:"ESTATE",definition:"A legal interest in land defines the nature degree extent and duration of a person's ownership in land.",id:"1453"},{term:"Estate at Sufferance",definition:"A tenancy created when one is in wrongful possession of real estate even though the original possession may have been legal",id:"1454"},{term:"Estate at Will",definition:"The tenancy may be ended by the unilateral decision of either party; no agreed upon termination date, however, and either party must give 30 days notice before ending the tenancy",id:"1455"},{term:"Estate for Years",definition:"A leasehold estate with a definite end date; must be renegotiated; commonly used for commercial leases",id:"1456"},{term:"Estate from Period to Period",definition:"A leasehold estate that is automatically renewed for the same term; a conveyance for an indefinite period of time; does not need to be renegotiated upon each renewal; commonly a month to month rental",id:"1457"},{term:"ESTATE IN FEE",definition:"The most complete form of ownership of real property also known as an estate of inheritance.",id:"1458"},{term:"ESTATE OF INHERITANCE",definition:"A freehold estate that can be passed by descent or by will after the owner's death.",id:"1459"},{term:"Estoppel",definition:"A legal doctrine which prevents a person from denying something to be true or a fact which is contrary to previous statements made by that same person",id:"1460"},{term:"ETHICS",definition:"A set of principles or values by which an individual guides his or her own behavior and judges that of others.",id:"1461"},{term:"Eviction",definition:"The legal process of removing a tenant from the premises for some breach of the lease",id:"1462"},{term:"EXCHANGE RESERVING RIGHT TO",definition:"The buyer and seller agree to complete a 'like kind' tax deferred exchange under Section 1031 of the Internal Revenue Code and acknowledge that escrow holder has made no representations as to the sufficiency or effect of this exchange as it relates to Federal and State or Tax law.",id:"1463"},{term:"EXCHANGE TAX CONSEQUENCES",definition:"Escrow holder has recommended that buyer and seller obtain legal counsel as to the tax consequences and other effects of this transaction. Escrow holder shall be held harmless from any loss which buyer and seller may sustain in the event this transaction is audited and disallowed by the Internal Revenue Service as a tax deferred exchange.",id:"1464"},{term:"EXCHANGE: AGREE TO COOPERATE",definition:"Buyer and seller agree to cooperate with each other in completing all documents required to effect their respective exchange. All parties agree that neither party is to be at any additional expense or liability in connection with the other party's tax deferred exchange.",id:"1465"},{term:"Execute",definition:"To perform or complete; to sign",id:"1466"},{term:"Executed Contract",definition:"A contract in which the obligations have been performed on both sides of the contract and nothing is left to be completed",id:"1467"},{term:"Execution",definition:"Completion of an act or process, such as an escrow",id:"1468"},{term:"Executive Manager",definition:"An executive who oversees the entire opera-tion of a property management firm.",id:"1469"},{term:"Executor / Executrix",definition:"A person named in a will to handle the affairs of a deceased person",id:"1470"},{term:"Executory Contract",definition:"A contract in which obligation to perform exists on one or both sides of the contract",id:"1471"},{term:"EXISTING LOANS",definition:"within three (3) days of acceptance of this offer seller shall provide buyer with all notes and Deeds of Trust to be assumed or taken subject to and within five (5) days after receiving them buyer shall give approval or disapproval of the terms of the documents in writing. Seller shall submit a Statement of Condition on the above loan within three (3) days after buyer's acceptance. All loans in the transaction will be current at close of escrow as per seller warranty.",id:"1472"},{term:"Expedientes",definition:"Land grants recorded by the Mexican government in California",id:"1473"},{term:"Express Contract",definition:"The parties declare the terms and put their intentions in words, either oral or written",id:"1474"},{term:"Express Warranty",definition:"An obligation to a tenant created by a promise made by the lessor or lessor's agent that caused the tenant to enter into the lease.",id:"1475"},{term:"EXTENDED POLICY",definition:"An extended title insurance policy.",id:"1476"},{term:"Facilities Management Administrator (FMA)",definition:"A property management designation offered by the Building Owners and Managers Institute (BOMI) with emphasis on the management of a commercial facility.",id:"1477"},{term:"Fair Housing Laws",definition:"Laws originating in the United States Constitution ensuring all persons the fair opportunity for hous-ing of their choice in the United States.",id:"1478"},{term:"Fair Labor Standards Act",definition:"A law enacted during the depression regulating certain aspects of labor that the lodging industry feels is in need of revision.",id:"1479"},{term:"Fair Market Value",definition:"The price the property would bring if freely offered on the open market with both a willing buyer and a willing seller",id:"1480"},{term:"FAX TRANSMISSION",definition:"A signed copy of any document sent to the other party or his or her agent by facsimile transmission followed by faxed acknowledgment of receipt is considered delivery of the signed document.",id:"1481"},{term:"FDIC",definition:"The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation a federal agency which insures depositors in banks and savings and loan asso-ciations to protect their deposits in case of bank failure.",id:"1482"},{term:"FEE",definition:"See fee simple or estate in fee.",id:"1483"},{term:"FEE SIMPLE",definition:"The largest most complete ownership recognized by law also known as a fee simple absolute or fee.",id:"1484"},{term:"FEE SIMPLE ABSOLUTE",definition:"Also known as fee simple or fee.",id:"1485"},{term:"FEE SIMPLE DEFEASIBLE",definition:"Also known as fee simple qualified.",id:"1486"},{term:"Fee Simple Estate",definition:"See estate in fee",id:"1487"},{term:"FEE SIMPLE QUALIFIED",definition:"An estate in which the holder has a fee simple title subject to return to the grantor if a specified condition occurs.",id:"1488"},{term:"FEES",definition:"Buyer and seller shall be charged equally for fees and expenses of this escrow one-half (1/2) each unless noted elsewhere in escrow instructions.",id:"1489"},{term:"FHA",definition:"The Federal Housing Administration established in 1934 to insure certain types of home loans protecting the lender and allowing a small down payment from the borrower.",id:"1490"},{term:"Fiduciary",definition:"A relationship that implies a position of trust or confidence",id:"1491"},{term:"Fief",definition:"Rights in the land that become heritable.",id:"1492"},{term:"Financial Analysis",definition:"A study of the property's income producing performance and potential.",id:"1493"},{term:"Financial Intermediary",definition:"An organization that obtains funds through deposits and then lends those funds to earn a return-such as savings banks, commercial banks, credit unions and mutual savings banks",id:"1494"},{term:"FINANCING STATEMENT",definition:"A written notice filed with the county recorder by a creditor who has extended credit for the purchase of personal property establishes the creditor's interests in the personal property which is the security for the debt.",id:"1495"},{term:"FIRST RIGHT OF REFUSAL",definition:"This escrow is contingent upon the sale and close of escrow on buyer's property at . meanwhile it is agreed that seller shall continue to show subject property to other prospective buyers. In the event that seller should receive a bonafide offer from another buyer the seller shall immediately notify the buyer in this escrow in writing. At the time buyer shall have hours to remove the contingency or withdraw from this transaction in favor of another buyer.",id:"1496"},{term:"Fiscal Year",definition:"Starts on July l and runs through June 30 of the following year; used for real property tax purposes",id:"1497"},{term:"FIXTURE",definition:"Personal property that has become affixed to real estate.",id:"1498"},{term:"FIXTURES AND EQUIPMENT",definition:"Seller guarantees that fixtures and equipment shall be in working condition at the time of buyer's possession.",id:"1499"},{term:"Flag Lot",definition:"Looks like a flag on a pole, which represents the access to the site; usually located to the rear of another lot fronting a main street",id:"1500"},{term:"FLOOD HAZARD ZONE",definition:"Subject property is located in an area which has special flood hazards and that flood insurance must be purchased by the buyer in order to obtain any loan secured by the property if a federally regulated financial institution is involved. Buyer is aware of this condition.",id:"1501"},{term:"Forbearance",definition:"Refraining from action by a creditor against the debt owed by a borrower after the debt has become due",id:"1502"},{term:"FORECLOSURE",definition:"A legal procedure by which mortgaged property in which there has been default on the part of the borrower is sold to satisfy the debt.",id:"1503"},{term:"FORECLOSURE SALE",definition:"A sale where property is sold to satisfy a debt.",id:"1504"},{term:"Fraud",definition:"An act meant to deceive in order to get someone to part with something of value",id:"1505"},{term:"FREEHOLD ESTATE",definition:"An estate in real property which continues for an indefinite period of time.",id:"1506"},{term:"Front Footage",definition:"The width of a property along a street",id:"1507"},{term:"FULLY AMORTIZED NOTE",definition:"A note that is fully repaid at maturity by periodic reduction of the principal.",id:"1508"},{term:"Gift Deed",definition:"Used to make a gift of property to a grantee, usually a close friend or relative",id:"1509"},{term:"Good Consideration",definition:"Gifts such as real property based solely on love and affection",id:"1510"},{term:"GOODWILL",definition:"An intangible saleable asset arising from the reputation of a business the expectation of continued public patronage.",id:"1511"},{term:"GRACE PERIOD",definition:"An agreed upon time period after the payment of a debt is past due during which a party can perform without being considered in default.",id:"1512"},{term:"Graduated Lease",definition:"A lease calling for periodic increases in the rental payments; sometimes called a stair-step lease",id:"1513"},{term:"Graduated Payment Adjustable Mortgage (GPAM)",definition:"A loan in which the monthly payment graduates by a certain percentage each year for a specific number of years, then levels off for the remaining term of the loan",id:"1514"},{term:"Grant Deed",definition:"A type of deed in which the grantor warrants that he or she has not previously conveyed the property being granted, has not encumbered the property except as disclosed, and will convey to the grantee any title to the property acquired later",id:"1515"},{term:"GRANT DEED FROM SPOUSES TO CREATE SEPARATE ESTATE",definition:"This deed is executed by the husband or wife of the grantee for the sole purpose of giving up any community property interest He or she may have in the subject property. it is his or her intention to vest the subject property in _ as his or her sole and separate property.",id:"1516"},{term:"Grantee",definition:"The person receiving the property, or the one to whom it is being conveyed",id:"1517"},{term:"Grantor",definition:"The person conveying, or transferring, the property",id:"1518"},{term:"Gross Lease",definition:"Landlord pays for most of the operating expenses, including property taxes, maintenance and repairs",id:"1519"},{term:"Gross Rent",definition:"Income (figured annually) received from rental units before any expenses are deducted",id:"1520"},{term:"Guarantee of Title",definition:"An assurance of clear title",id:"1521"},{term:"Hard Money Loan",definition:"The evidence of a debt that is given in exchange for cash",id:"1522"},{term:"HOLDER",definition:"The party to whom a promissory note is made payable.",id:"1523"},{term:"Holder in Due Course",definition:"A person who has obtained a negotiable instrument (promissory note, check) in the ordinary course of business before it is due, in good faith and for value, without knowledge that it has been previously dishonored",id:"1524"},{term:"Holographic Will",definition:"Written in the maker's own handwriting, dated and signed by the maker",id:"1525"},{term:"HOME EQUITY LOAN",definition:"A cash loan made against the equity in the borrower's home.",id:"1526"},{term:"Homeowner's Exemption",definition:"A $7,000 tax exemption available to all owner-occupied dwellings",id:"1527"},{term:"Housekeeper",definition:"An employee in a hotel who cleans and stocks the guest rooms.",id:"1528"},{term:"Implied Contract",definition:"Agreement is shown by acts and conduct rather than words",id:"1529"},{term:"IMPOUNDS",definition:"Escrow holder is instructed to charge buyer and credit seller with the amount shown on Beneficiary Statement as being impounded for future payment of taxes fire insurance premiums or any other items shown.",id:"1530"},{term:"Improvements",definition:"Any buildings or structures on a lot",id:"1531"},{term:"Industrial Property",definition:"A property where products are manufactured or assembled. The conducting of industry.",id:"1532"},{term:"INSPECTION",definition:"This escrow is contingent upon written notification to escrow holder of buyer's approval of property inspection. Any professional inspector shall be selected and paid for by Buyer.",id:"1533"},{term:"INSTRUMENT",definition:"A written legal document setting forth the rights and liabilities of the parties involved.",id:"1534"},{term:"INTEREST",definition:"The cost of borrowing money.",id:"1535"},{term:"Interior Lot",definition:"One that is surrounded by other lots, with a frontage on the street; the most common type lot, which may or may not be desirable-depending on other factors",id:"1536"},{term:"Intermediation",definition:"The process of transfer capital from those who invest funds to those who wish to borrow",id:"1537"},{term:"Intestate",definition:"Dying without leaving a will",id:"1538"},{term:"JUDGMENT",definition:"The final legal decision of a judge in a court of law regarding the legal rights of parties to disputes.",id:"1539"},{term:"JUDICIAL FORECLOSURE",definition:"Foreclosure by court action.",id:"1540"},{term:"JUNIOR TRUST DEED",definition:"Any trust deed that is recorded after a first trust deed whose priority is less than that first trust deed.",id:"1541"},{term:"Key Lot",definition:"So named because it resembles a key fitting into a lock; one that is surrounded by the backyards of other lots, therefore is the least desirable because of the lack of privacy",id:"1542"},{term:"LAND CONTRACT",definition:"A contract for the sale of real property where the seller gives up possession but retains the title until the purchase price is paid in full; also known as a contract of sale.",id:"1543"},{term:"Land Projects",definition:"Subdivisions located in sparsely populated areas of California, made up of 50 parcels or more",id:"1544"},{term:"Landlord",definition:"Lessor; property owner",id:"1545"},{term:"LATE CHARGE",definition:"Regarding the note created by this escrow; in the event that any installment payment is not received by the holder within days of its due date a late charge of _may be charged by the holder.",id:"1546"},{term:"Lawful Object",definition:"The purpose object and operation of the contract is legal one of the essentials of a valid contract.",id:"1547"},{term:"Lease",definition:"A written agreement by which possession of the property is transferred and the stream of income is secured.",id:"1548"},{term:"Leasehold or Lease",definition:"An agreement, written or unwritten, transferring the right to exclusive possession and use of real estate for a definite period of time",id:"1549"},{term:"Leasing Agent",definition:"An agent who secures qualified tenants for leases on residential commercial or industrial property.",id:"1550"},{term:"Legacy",definition:"A gift of personal property by will",id:"1551"},{term:"LEGAL TITLE",definition:"Title that is complete and perfect regarding right of ownership; may be held by a trustee under a deed of trust.",id:"1552"},{term:"Less Than Freehold Estates",definition:"Leasehold interests.",id:"1553"},{term:"Lessee",definition:"Tenant; renter",id:"1554"},{term:"Lessor",definition:"Landlord; property owner",id:"1555"},{term:"LESS-THAN-FREEHOLD ESTATE",definition:"A leasehold estate considered to exist for a definite period of time or successive periods of time until termination.",id:"1556"},{term:"Liability Indemnity Clause",definition:"A clause in a lease holding landlords harmless from the actions of their tenants.",id:"1557"},{term:"LICENSE",definition:"Permission to use a property which may be revoked at any time.",id:"1558"},{term:"Lien",definition:"A claim on the property of another for the payment of a debt",id:"1559"},{term:"LIFE ESTATE",definition:"An estate that is limited in duration to the life of its owner or the life of some other chosen person.",id:"1560"},{term:"LINEAR FOOT",definition:"A measurement meaning one foot or twelve inches in length as contrasted to a square foot or a cubic foot.",id:"1561"},{term:"Liquidated Damages",definition:"Sets in advance a specified amount of money as a penalty in the event of a breach of contract",id:"1562"},{term:"LIS PENDENS",definition:"A recorded notice that indicates pending litigation on a property; preventing a conveyance or any other transfer of ownership until the lawsuit is settled and the [is penclens removed.",id:"1563"},{term:"Listing",definition:"A contract by which a principal employs an agent to do certain things for the principal",id:"1564"},{term:"LITTORAL",definition:"Land bordering a lake ocean or sea-as opposed to land bordering a stream or river (running water).",id:"1565"},{term:"Lord",definition:"In earlier times a regional supervisor of a large piece of land.",id:"1566"},{term:"Love and Affection",definition:"Consideration used in a gift deed",id:"1567"},{term:"Maintenance Clause",definition:"A clause in a lease designating which party is responsible for maintenance of the property beyond normal wear-and-tear.",id:"1568"},{term:"Maintenance Supervisor",definition:"A position responsible for maintenance of buildings in his or her charge. This person hires workers and supervises all maintenance activities.",id:"1569"},{term:"MAKER",definition:"The borrower who executes a promissory note and becomes primarily liable for payment to the lender.",id:"1570"},{term:"Management Plan",definition:"A plan for future management based on finan-cial reports and projection accepted by ownership.",id:"1571"},{term:"MANUFACTURED HOUSING",definition:"A housing unit primarily constructed in a factory and moved to a permanent site another name for a mobile home.",id:"1572"},{term:"Market Analysis",definition:"A study which gives an understanding of the economic factors operating in the local marketplace related to the subject property.",id:"1573"},{term:"Market Rent",definition:"The rent a property should bring in the open market",id:"1574"},{term:"Market Survey",definition:"A report generated by software comparing the subject property in various categories of performance to compet-ing properties in the area.",id:"1575"},{term:"Marketable Title",definition:"Good or clear saleable title reasonably free from risk of litigation over possible defects",id:"1576"},{term:"Mega-Center",definition:"An oversized shopping center that attracts shoppers from hundreds of miles around. Also called a super-mall.",id:"1577"},{term:"Menace",definition:"Using threat of violence to get agreement in accepting a contract",id:"1578"},{term:"MERIDIAN",definition:"A survey line running north and south used as a reference when mapping land.",id:"1579"},{term:"METES AND BOUNDS",definition:"A method of land description in which the dimensions of the property are measured by distance and direction.",id:"1580"},{term:"Middle Managers",definition:"Property managers who are involved in hands-on activities that implement the decisions of owners and upper management.",id:"1581"},{term:"MIMO Form",definition:"The move in move out form detailing inventory and initial condition of rental space and inventory and condition upon move-out.",id:"1582"},{term:"Minor",definition:"Someone under l8 years of age",id:"1583"},{term:"Misrepresentation",definition:"An innocent or negligent misstatement of a material fact causing someone loss or harm",id:"1584"},{term:"Mistake",definition:"An error or misunderstanding",id:"1585"},{term:"MOBILE HOME",definition:"A manufactured unit constructed on a chassis and wheels and designed for permanent or semi-attachment to land.",id:"1586"},{term:"MONUMENT",definition:"A fixed landmark used in a metes and bounds land description.",id:"1587"},{term:"Moratorium",definition:"A temporary prohibition against building in certain areas to control the rate of development.",id:"1588"},{term:"Mortgage",definition:"A legal document used as security for a debt",id:"1589"},{term:"Mortgage Loan Disclosure State",definition:"A statement that informs the buyer of all charges and expenses related to a particular loan",id:"1590"},{term:"Mortgagee",definition:"The lender under a mortgage",id:"1591"},{term:"Mortgagor",definition:"The borrower under a mortgage",id:"1592"},{term:"Motel",definition:"A hybrid of motor-hotel a housing accommodation in outlying areas for middle-class America. Located along major highways it gives easy access to lodging to those traveling by automobile.",id:"1593"},{term:"Motor Camps",definition:"Chains of campgrounds designed to accommodate motorists and recreational vehicle drivers.",id:"1594"},{term:"Multi-Family Units",definition:"Residential structures intended to house more than one family unit such as duplexes or apartment buildings.",id:"1595"},{term:"Mutual Consent",definition:"Agreement to the provisions of a contract by the parties involved; a mutual willingness to enter into a contract",id:"1596"},{term:"Naked Legal Title",definition:"Title lacking the rights and privileges commonly associated with ownership",id:"1597"},{term:"National Apartment Leasing Professional (NALP)",definition:"A designation offered by the National Apartment Association (NAA).",id:"1598"},{term:"National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA)",definition:"A law passed by Congress in 1970 that requires an environmental impact state-ment to be prepared and released prior to any federal action that would affect the environment. This is also required by some state and local governments for private improvements.",id:"1599"},{term:"NEGOTIABLE INSTRUMENT",definition:"Any written instrument that may be transferred by endorsement or delivery.",id:"1600"},{term:"Neighborhood Center",definition:"A retail center supported by a thousand or so households usually anchored by a grocery store and sup-ported by a dozen or so other compatible stores.",id:"1601"},{term:"Net Income",definition:"Sometimes known as net operating income; the remaining income after operating expenses have been subtracted from the gross income of a property",id:"1602"},{term:"Net Lease",definition:"A lease where the tenant pays such costs as taxes, insurance and repairs, as well as a set amount for rent; a triple net lease is one where the tenant pays all expenses of operating the property as well as a set amount of rent",id:"1603"},{term:"Net Operating Income",definition:"Also called net annual income the amount of income left from an income -producing property after all expenses have been deducted.",id:"1604"},{term:"NEUTRAL DEPOSITORY",definition:"An escrow business conducted by someone who is a licensed escrow holder.",id:"1605"},{term:"NEW CONVENTIONAL FIXED RATE LOAN CASH DOWN PAYMENT",definition:"Purchase price payable in cash. Contingent upon buyer obtaining a fixed rate loan to be secured by the property in the amount of at % of purchase price with equal monthly payments amortized over a period of not less than - years with interest not to exceed _% per annum. Buyer shall have days from date of acceptance to obtain a loan commitment or waive this condition in writing. Loan fee not to exceed _%.",id:"1606"},{term:"NO BROKERS INVOLVED",definition:"Buyer and seller acknowledge that these escrow instructions are the only contract between them and that there are no real estate brokers involved in this transaction. No deposit receipt has been written and no commissions are to be paid.",id:"1607"},{term:"NO TAX ADVICE",definition:"Buyer and seller acknowledge that they have not received or relied upon any statements or representations by the agent regarding the effect of this transaction upon their tax liability.",id:"1608"},{term:"Notice of Default",definition:"A notice to a defaulting party that there has been a nonpayment of a debt",id:"1609"},{term:"Notice of Trustee's Sale",definition:"Notice given, and published, that a trustee's sale will be held to sell a property to satisfy a debt",id:"1610"},{term:"NOVATION",definition:"The substitution of a new obligation for an old one.",id:"1611"},{term:"Offer",definition:"A presentation or proposal for acceptance to form a contract",id:"1612"},{term:"Offeree",definition:"The party receiving an offer",id:"1613"},{term:"Offeror",definition:"The party making an offer",id:"1614"},{term:"On-Site Manager",definition:"A property manager who lives on-site handles day-to-day activities and interacts with tenants on a regular basis.",id:"1615"},{term:"OPEN END LOAN",definition:"A loan where the borrower is given a limit up to which may be borrowed with each advance secured by the same trust deed.",id:"1616"},{term:"Operating Budget",definition:"A basic tool of the property manager to help in planning.",id:"1617"},{term:"Operating Expenses",definition:"Expenditures necessary to the operation of an income -producing building that are subtracted from effective gross income to arrive at net operating income.",id:"1618"},{term:"Option",definition:"A right-given for consideration-to a party (optionee) by a property owner (optionor)",id:"1619"},{term:"'OR MORE' CLAUSE",definition:"A clause in a promissory note that allows a borrower to pay it off early with no penalty.",id:"1620"},{term:"PACKAGE LOAN",definition:"A loan on real property that can be secured by land structure fixtures and other personal property.",id:"1621"},{term:"Page",definition:"An employee in a hotel who delivers a message or summons a guest.",id:"1622"},{term:"Paired Sales Analysis",definition:"Matching up two properties that are identical in all respects except for one variable. Determines the value of that variable in the marketplace.",id:"1623"},{term:"Parole Evidence",definition:"Oral or written negotiations made prior to a dispute about an executed contract",id:"1624"},{term:"PARTIALLY AMORTIZED INSTALLMENT NOTE",definition:"A promissory note with a repayment schedule that is not sufficient to amortize the loan over its term.",id:"1625"},{term:"PARTITION ACTION",definition:"A court action to divide a property held by co-owners.",id:"1626"},{term:"PATENT DEED",definition:"Deeds used by the United States government when confirming or transferring ownership to private parties.",id:"1627"},{term:"Percentage Lease",definition:"A lease where the landlord receives a percentage of the gross sales as part or all of the rental payment",id:"1628"},{term:"Period Hotel or Inn",definition:"A hotel or inn that conveys the essence of a particular period of time in history.",id:"1629"},{term:"Periodic Tenancy",definition:"Tenancy from period to period such as a month-to-month tenancy",id:"1630"},{term:"Personal Property",definition:"Anything movable that is not real property",id:"1631"},{term:"PERSONAL PROPERTY INCLUDED IN PRICE",definition:"Upon the close of escrow the following personal property observed on the property when inspected by buyer shall be transferred to buyer by a bill of sale. No warranty is implied about the condition of the personal property.",id:"1632"},{term:"Planned Unit Development (PUD)",definition:"A development in which each owner owns his or her own housing unit and land and has an undivided interest in common areas with other owners.",id:"1633"},{term:"Plat Map",definition:"A map of a town or subdivision showing the location and boundaries of individual properties, used in the recorded tract system to describe land",id:"1634"},{term:"PLEDGE",definition:"The transfer of property to a lender to be held as security for repayment of a debt; lender takes possession of property.",id:"1635"},{term:"Plottage or Assemblage",definition:"Putting several smaller, less valuable parcels together under one ownership to increase value of total property",id:"1636"},{term:"Police Power",definition:"The power of the state to pass laws, within lawful limits, that promote the order, safety, health, morals and general welfare of its citizens",id:"1637"},{term:"Porter",definition:"A baggage handler.",id:"1638"},{term:"Portfolio Manager",definition:"An executive who oversees the firm's real estate resources setting goals and strategies with ownership interests. Also called an asset manager.",id:"1639"},{term:"Post-House",definition:"An inn accommodating travelers in the 1600s.",id:"1640"},{term:"Power of Attorney",definition:"A written instrument giving a person legal authority to act on behalf of another person",id:"1641"},{term:"POWER OF SALE",definition:"A clause in a trust deed or mortgage that gives the holder the right to sell the property in the event of default by the borrower.",id:"1642"},{term:"Preliminary Title Report",definition:"An examination of the public land records to determine the extent to which someone has legal interest in a parcel; a report on the quality of the title that searches for encumbrances and liens or any other items of record that might effect ownership; used as a basis for title insurance",id:"1643"},{term:"Prepayment Clause",definition:"A clause in a trust deed that allows a lender to collect a certain percentage of a loan as a penalty for an early payoff",id:"1644"},{term:"PREPAYMENT PENALTY (NONE)",definition:"Buyer has the right to pay this note in full or in part at any time prior to its maturity without penalty.",id:"1645"},{term:"Price",definition:"What is paid for something",id:"1646"},{term:"Principal",definition:"Someone who directs or authorizes another to act in his or her place regarding relations with third persons; buyer or seller; the amount of money borrowed; the original amount borrowed",id:"1647"},{term:"Private Grant",definition:"The granting of private property to other private persons",id:"1648"},{term:"PROBATE SALE",definition:"A court approved sale of the property of a deceased person.",id:"1649"},{term:"Professional Community Association Manager (PCAM)",definition:"An advanced designation offered by the Community Associations Institute (CAI).",id:"1650"},{term:"Project Operating Report",definition:"A report that breaks income and expenses down into specific categories and matches them to budget objectives.",id:"1651"},{term:"Projection",definition:"An anticipated operational income and expense state-ment projected into the future to aid in planning.",id:"1652"},{term:"PROMISSORY NOTE",definition:"A written promise or order to pay evidence of a debt.",id:"1653"},{term:"PROPERTY",definition:"Any real or personal property included in the sale.",id:"1654"},{term:"Property Analysis",definition:"An on-site inspection and study of the sub-ject property so that the entire physical plant is thoroughly understood.",id:"1655"},{term:"Property Management",definition:"The practice of real estate that manages and preserves the real property assets of another person.",id:"1656"},{term:"Property Supervisor",definition:"A property manager who is responsible for several properties and supervises the on-site managers of those properties.",id:"1657"},{term:"Proration",definition:"The division and distribution of expenses and/or income between the buyer and seller of property as of the date of closing or settlement",id:"1658"},{term:"PRORATIONS",definition:"Rents taxes interest payments on bonds and assessments assumed by buyer homeowners afees and other expenses of the property are to be prorated as of the close of escrow.",id:"1659"},{term:"Prosperity",definition:"A stage in the business cycle when unemployment is low and consumers have a lot of purchasing power.",id:"1660"},{term:"Public Accommodation Property",definition:"A privately owned property where the public has certain rights such as a hotel or office building.",id:"1661"},{term:"Public Dedication",definition:"When private property is intended for public use, it may be acquired in this manner",id:"1662"},{term:"Public Grant",definition:"The transfer of title by the government to a private individual",id:"1663"},{term:"Puffing",definition:"Exaggerated comments or opinions not made as representations of fact, thus not grounds for misrepresentation",id:"1664"},{term:"PURCHASE MONEY LOAN",definition:"A trust deed created as evidence of a debt at the time of the sale of real property.",id:"1665"},{term:"Quiet Enjoyment",definition:"The right of a tenant to be undisturbed.",id:"1666"},{term:"Quitclaim Deed",definition:"Transfers any interest the grantor may have at the time the deed is signed with no warranties of clear title",id:"1667"},{term:"RANGE",definition:"A land description used in the U.S. Government Survey system consisting of a strip of land located every six miles east and west of each principal meridian.",id:"1668"},{term:"Rate",definition:"The percentage of interest charged on the principal",id:"1669"},{term:"Ratification",definition:"The approval of a previously authorized act, performed on behalf of a person, which makes the act valid and legally binding",id:"1670"},{term:"Ratified",definition:"Approved",id:"1671"},{term:"Real Estate",definition:"Originally the king's land. Today a term that refers to real property.",id:"1672"},{term:"REAL ESTATE AGENT",definition:"Someone licensed by the Department of Real Estate holding either a broker or salesperson license who negotiates sales for other people.",id:"1673"},{term:"REAL ESTATE BROKER",definition:"Someone permitted by law to employ persons holding a salesperson license and who may also negotiate sales.",id:"1674"},{term:"Real Estate Cycle",definition:"A fluctuation of supply and demand in real estate affected by the state of the business cycle and resulting in various levels of activity for building lending purchasing and leasing real estate. The cycle swings between the extremes of a buyer's market and a seller's market.",id:"1675"},{term:"Real Estate Investment Trust (REIT)",definition:"A way investors with a small amount of capital can pool their resources to buy real estate",id:"1676"},{term:"REAL ESTATE LAW",definition:"The law that affects the licensing and conduct of real estate agents.",id:"1677"},{term:"REAL ESTATE SALES ASSOCIATE",definition:"The same as a real estate salesperson holding a real license employed by a broker.",id:"1678"},{term:"REAL ESTATE SALESPERSON",definition:"Someone holding a real estate license and employed by a real estate broker for pay to perform any of the activities of a real estate broker.",id:"1679"},{term:"REAL PROPERTY",definition:"Land anything affixed to the land anything appurtenant to the land anything immovable by law.",id:"1680"},{term:"Real Property Administrator (RPA)",definition:"A property management designation offered by the Building Owners and Managers Institute (BOMI).",id:"1681"},{term:"Real Property Manager (RPM)",definition:"A property management designa-tion offered by the Building Owners and Managers Association (BOMA).",id:"1682"},{term:"Recession",definition:"A stage in the business cycle when production has surpassed demand resulting in unemployment and declining prices.",id:"1683"},{term:"Reconciliation",definition:"Sometimes called correlation, this is the adjustment process of weighing results of all three appraisal methods to arrive at a final estimate of the subject property's market value",id:"1684"},{term:"RECONVEYANCE DEED",definition:"A deed used to transfer title to a property back to the trustor after a trust deed has been paid off.",id:"1685"},{term:"Recovery",definition:"A stage in the business cycle when consumers once again buy goods at reduced prices increasing demand in relation to supply.",id:"1686"},{term:"Red Flag",definition:"Something that would warn a reasonably observant person of a potential problem, thus requiring further investigation",id:"1687"},{term:"Redlining",definition:"The use of a property's location to deny financing",id:"1688"},{term:"Regional Center",definition:"A large retail shopping center (sometimes called a mall) with half a dozen major department stores along with 100 to 200 general merchandise and specialty shops. Customers are drawn from as far as 50 miles and comprise 50 000 to 150 000 households.",id:"1689"},{term:"Regional Manager",definition:"A property manager who works for a large property management company and oversees the work of prop-erty supervisors or on-site managers.",id:"1690"},{term:"Registered Property Manager (RPM)",definition:"A property management designation offered by the International Real Estate Institute (IREI).",id:"1691"},{term:"REINSTATE",definition:"Bring current and restore.",id:"1692"},{term:"RELEASE CLAUSE",definition:"A provision found in many blanket loans enabling the borrower to obtain partial release from the loan of specific parcels.",id:"1693"},{term:"Reliction",definition:"Occurs when land that has been covered by water is exposed by receding water",id:"1694"},{term:"Rent",definition:"Consideration paid for the use of a property",id:"1695"},{term:"RENT BACK BY SELLER",definition:"Buyer and seller agree that seller shall hold possession of subject property for days after close of escrow.",id:"1696"},{term:"Rent Control",definition:"A local ordinance prohibiting rent increases on certain types of property.",id:"1697"},{term:"Replacement Cost",definition:"The cost of replacing improvements with modern materials and techniques",id:"1698"},{term:"Reproduction Cost",definition:"The current cost of building a replica of the subject structure, using similar quality materials",id:"1699"},{term:"REQUEST FOR NOTICE",definition:"A notice that is sent upon request to any parties interested in a trust deed informing them of a default.",id:"1700"},{term:"Rescission",definition:"Legal action taken to repeal a contract either by mutual consent of the parties or by one party when the other party has breached a contract",id:"1701"},{term:"Residential Property",definition:"A property where people reside including single family residences condominiums and apartment buildings.",id:"1702"},{term:"Residential Rental Property",definition:"Property from which 80 percent or more of the gross rental income is from dwelling units",id:"1703"},{term:"Restriction",definition:"A limitation on the use of a property by the owner. May be private (as in a deed or declaration of restrictions) or public (as in zoning).",id:"1704"},{term:"Retaliatory Eviction",definition:"An act whereby a landlord evicts a tenant in response to some complaint made by the tenant",id:"1705"},{term:"REVERSE ANNUITY MORTGAGE",definition:"A loan that enables elderly homeowners to borrow against the equity in their homes by receiving monthly payments from a lender that are needed to help meet living costs.",id:"1706"},{term:"Reversionary Right",definition:"The lessor (landlord) grants the right of possession to the lessee (tenant), but retains the right to retake possession after the lease's term has expired",id:"1707"},{term:"Revocation",definition:"The cancelling of an offer to contract by the person making the original offer",id:"1708"},{term:"REVOKE",definition:"Recall and make void.",id:"1709"},{term:"RevPAR",definition:"Revenue per available room a statistic followed in the lodging industry.",id:"1710"},{term:"RIPARIAN RIGHTS",definition:"The rights of a landowner whose land is next to a natural watercourse to reasonable use of whatever water flows past the property.",id:"1711"},{term:"Risk Manager",definition:"A property manager who evaluates complex issue s-sometimes global issues-to protect the value of real estate assets.",id:"1712"},{term:"ROLLOVER MORTGAGE",definition:"A loan that allows the rewriting of a new loan at the termination of a prior loan.",id:"1713"},{term:"RTC",definition:"The Resolution Trust Corporation established by the Federal Government in 1989 to help failed savings and loans liquidate real property assets.",id:"1714"},{term:"SALES TAX",definition:"Collected as a percentage of the retail sales of a product by a retailer and forwarded to the State Board of Equalization.",id:"1715"},{term:"Sandwich Lease",definition:"A lease agreement created when a tenant sublets the property to another person, thus creating a sublessor-sublessee relationship. The person in the 'sandwich' is a lessee to the owner and a lessor to the sub-lessee",id:"1716"},{term:"Scheduled Gross Income",definition:"All of the income a property is sched-uled to produce.",id:"1717"},{term:"Second Trust Deed",definition:"The evidence of a debt that is recorded after a first trust deed; a junior trust deed",id:"1718"},{term:"SECTION",definition:"An area of land as used in the government survey method of land description; a land area of one square mile or 640 acres. It is 1/36 of a township.",id:"1719"},{term:"Security",definition:"Evidence of obligations to pay money",id:"1720"},{term:"Security Agreement",definition:"The device commonly used to secure a loan on personal property",id:"1721"},{term:"Seller's Market",definition:"A stage in the real estate market in which demand is greater than supply-more buyers than sellers-and prices rise.",id:"1722"},{term:"SELLER'S PERMIT",definition:"Allows a retailer to buy his or her product at wholesale prices without paying sales tax. The retailer must then collect the proper sales tax from customers and pay it to the State Board of Equalization.",id:"1723"},{term:"Serfdom",definition:"In medieval times a status that was insufficient to allow a person to own land.",id:"1724"},{term:"Servient Tenement",definition:"The property that is burdened by an easement",id:"1725"},{term:"SEVERALTY",definition:"Ownership of real property by one person or entity.",id:"1726"},{term:"SFR",definition:"A single family residence. A house that is intended to be occupied by one family.",id:"1727"},{term:"Shared Appreciation Mortgage (SAM)",definition:"Lender and borrower agree to share a certain percentage of the appreciation in market value of the property",id:"1728"},{term:"Sheriff's Deed",definition:"A deed given to a buyer when property is sold through court action in order to satisfy a judgment for money or foreclosure of a mortgage",id:"1729"},{term:"Single Net Lease",definition:"An arrangement whereby the tenant pays the rent plus utilities property taxes and any special assessments on the property.",id:"1730"},{term:"Site",definition:"The position, situation or location of a piece of land in a neighborhood",id:"1731"},{term:"Skyscraper",definition:"Tall steel-framed structures that originally housed mostly office buildings.",id:"1732"},{term:"Soldier's and Sailor's Relief Act",definition:"A federal law designed to protect persons in the military service from loss of property when their ability to make the payment has been affected by their entering military service",id:"1733"},{term:"Special Purpose Properties",definition:"Properties that are designed to meet unique purposes within a community such as-but not limited to-mini-storage facilities and mobile home parks.",id:"1734"},{term:"SPECIAL STUDIES ZONE ACT",definition:"Buyer is aware that the subject property is located in a Special Studies Zone designated under the Priolo Special Studies Act and that construction or improvement of any structure may require the submission of a geological report by the buyer prepared by a registered geologist. Seller or broker have not made any representation about the cost of report or the geological characteristics of the property.",id:"1735"},{term:"Specific Performance",definition:"An action brought in a court to compel a party to carry out the terms of a contract",id:"1736"},{term:"Standard Operating Procedures (SOP)",definition:"Standard procedures that are followed for efficiency whenever specified regularly occurring events take place.",id:"1737"},{term:"STANDARD POLICY",definition:"A policy of title insurance covering only matters of record.",id:"1738"},{term:"Statute of Frauds",definition:"A state law which requires that certain contracts must be in writing and contain certain essential elements in order to be enforceable",id:"1739"},{term:"Statute of Limitations",definition:"The period of time limited by statute within which certain court actions may be brought by one party against another",id:"1740"},{term:"STATUTORY",definition:"Regarding laws created by the enactment of legislation as opposed to law created by court decisions.",id:"1741"},{term:"Steering",definition:"Illegal practice of only showing clients property in certain areas",id:"1742"},{term:"Step-up Lease",definition:"Sometimes called a graduated lease usually a long-term lease with an escalation clause allowing for a rent increase based upon the occurrence of a certain event.",id:"1743"},{term:"Stock Cooperative",definition:"A development in which a corporation is formed for the purpose of holding title to improved real property.",id:"1744"},{term:"STRAIGHT NOTE",definition:"A promissory note in which payments of interest only are made periodically during the term of the note with the principal payment due in one lump sum upon maturity; may also be a note with no payments on either principal or interest until the entire sum is due.",id:"1745"},{term:"Strip Center",definition:"A small retail center located in the suburbs contain-ing half-a-dozen to a dozen stores of various kinds.",id:"1746"},{term:"Subagent",definition:"An agent of a person who is already acting as an agent for a principal",id:"1747"},{term:"Subdivided Lands Act",definition:"A state law protecting purchasers of property in new subdivisions from fraud, misrepresentation or deceit in the marketing of subdivided property; concerned with financial aspects of a development",id:"1748"},{term:"Subdivision",definition:"The division of land into five or more lots for the purpose of sale, lease or financing",id:"1749"},{term:"Subdivision Map Act",definition:"Outlines rules for filing subdivision maps to create subdivisions; concerned with physical aspects of a development",id:"1750"},{term:"'SUBJECT-TO' CLAUSE",definition:"A buyer takes over the existing loan payments but assumes no personal liability for the loan.",id:"1751"},{term:"Sublease",definition:"Transfers less than the entire leasehold, with the original lessee being primarily liable for the rental agreement",id:"1752"},{term:"Subletting",definition:"The process by which the original tenant gives up use or possession of all or part of the property but receives payment from the sub-lessee and remains fully responsible for the entire lease payment to the landlord.",id:"1753"},{term:"SUBORDINATION CLAUSE",definition:"A clause in which the holder of a trust deed permits a subsequent loan to take priority.",id:"1754"},{term:"Suburban Hotel",definition:"A lodging accommodation within driving dis-tance of the downtown area of a large city designed to attract business clientele.",id:"1755"},{term:"Suburbs",definition:"The area within driving distance of a city's downtown.",id:"1756"},{term:"Succession",definition:"The legal transfer of a person's interest in real and personal property under the laws of descent",id:"1757"},{term:"Summation",definition:"A method of determining the capitalization rate in which various risk factors are weighted and combined.",id:"1758"},{term:"Superfund",definition:"Officially known as the Comprehensive Environmental Response Compensation and Liability Act (CERCLA) passed by Congress in 1980. Establishes two trust funds to help finance the cleanup of properties that have been impacted by the release of hazardous wastes and substances.",id:"1759"},{term:"Superintendent of Service",definition:"The person in a hotel who supervises all front office service personnel.",id:"1760"},{term:"Super-Mall",definition:"An oversized shopping center that attracts shoppers from hundreds of miles around. Also called a mega-center.",id:"1761"},{term:"Supply and Demand",definition:"A basic economic principle in which the greater the supply of an item the lower its value. When an item is scarce in relation to demand the value is high. Applies to real estate and all commodities.",id:"1762"},{term:"Surrender",definition:"The giving up of a lease, voluntarily",id:"1763"},{term:"SUSPEND",definition:"Temporarily make ineffective.",id:"1764"},{term:"Swing Loan",definition:"A short-term loan used to enable the purchaser of a new property to buy that property on the strength of the equity from the property the purchaser is now selling",id:"1765"},{term:"Syndicate",definition:"A group of individuals formed for the accomplishment of some business purpose such as a corporation or limited partnership.",id:"1766"},{term:"Systems Maintenance Administrator (SMA)",definition:"A property manage-ment designation offered by the Building Owners and Managers Institute (BOMI) with emphasis on supervision of systems and personnel.",id:"1767"},{term:"Systems Maintenance Technician (SMT)",definition:"A property manage-ment designation offered by the Building Owners and Managers Institute (BOMI) with emphasis on the technical maintenance of various systems such as heating and air conditioning.",id:"1768"},{term:"Tax Deed",definition:"A deed given to a successful bidder at a tax auction",id:"1769"},{term:"Tenant",definition:"A renter",id:"1770"},{term:"Tender",definition:"An offer by one of the parties to a contract to carry out his or her part of the contract",id:"1771"},{term:"TERMINATING THE AGREEMENT",definition:"Buyer and seller are relieved of their obligations and all deposits shall be returned to buyer less expenses incurred by or on account of buyer to date of termination.",id:"1772"},{term:"Testator/Testatrix",definition:"A person who has made a will",id:"1773"},{term:"Third Party",definition:"A person who may be affected by the terms of an agreement but who is not a party to the agreement",id:"1774"},{term:"Three I's Formula",definition:"An application of sound human relations principles when handling the impending removal of a tenant from the property. (# 1) Interaction (#2) Incentives (#3) Intimidation.",id:"1775"},{term:"Three-Day Notice to Pay or Quit",definition:"The initial notice given to a tenant to begin the eviction process.",id:"1776"},{term:"Tight Money",definition:"An economic situation in which the supply of money is limited, and the demand for money is high, as evidenced by high interest rates",id:"1777"},{term:"Time",definition:"Duration of loan",id:"1778"},{term:"Timely Manner",definition:"An act must be performed within certain time limits described in a contract",id:"1779"},{term:"Timeshare",definition:"A specialized type of resort property whereby owners purchase the right to occupy the space for a certain period of time during the year.",id:"1780"},{term:"T-Intersection Lot",definition:"A lot that is fronted head-on by a street; noise and glare from headlights may be detractors from this type of lot",id:"1781"},{term:"TITLE",definition:"Evidence of ownership of land.",id:"1782"},{term:"TITLE INSURANCE",definition:"An insurance policy that protects the insured against loss or damage due to defects in the property's title.",id:"1783"},{term:"Title Plant",definition:"The storage facility of a title company in which it has accumulated complete title records of properties in its area",id:"1784"},{term:"Tort",definition:"A negligent or intentional wrongful act arising from breach of duty created by law and not contract",id:"1785"},{term:"Tourist House",definition:"A lodging accommodation offered in a private home enjoyed by guests on bus or auto tours seeking to economize.",id:"1786"},{term:"TOWNSHIP",definition:"A land description used in the U.S. Government Survey system consisting of a six-by-six mile area containing 360 sections each one mile square.",id:"1787"},{term:"Toxic Substances Control Act (TSCA)",definition:"A law passed by Congress in 1976 which allows the EPA to determine which substances are hazardous to the health of human beings or to the environment.",id:"1788"},{term:"TRADE ASSOCIATION",definition:"A voluntary nonprofit organization of independent and competing business units engaged in the same industry or trade and formed to aid in the industry problems promote its progress and enhance its service.",id:"1789"},{term:"TRADE FIXTURE",definition:"An article of personal property affixed to leased property by the tenant as a necessary part of business; may be removed by tenant as personal property upon termination of the lease.",id:"1790"},{term:"TRANSFER TAX NOT TO SHOW ON DEED AT RECORDATION",definition:"Title Insurance Company shall be instructed by escrow holder to file grant deed as a separate declaration and not make it a part of the public record.",id:"1791"},{term:"Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo",definition:"Ended the war with Mexico in l848, and California became a possession of the United States",id:"1792"},{term:"Triple Net Lease",definition:"An arrangement whereby the tenant pays the rent utilities property taxes special assessments and insurance premiums; and takes responsibility for repairs and maintenance.",id:"1793"},{term:"TRUST DEED",definition:"A document where title to property is transferred to a third party trustee as security for a debt owed by the trustor (borrower) to the beneficiary (lender).",id:"1794"},{term:"TRUST FUNDS",definition:"Money received by real estate brokers or salespersons on behalf of others.",id:"1795"},{term:"TRUSTEE",definition:"Holds bare legal title to property as a neutral third party where there is a deed of trust.",id:"1796"},{term:"TRUSTEE'S DEED",definition:"A deed given to a buyer of real property at a trustee's sale.",id:"1797"},{term:"TRUSTEE'S SALE",definition:"The forced sale of real property by a lender to satisfy a debt.",id:"1798"},{term:"TRUSTOR",definition:"The borrower under a deed of trust.",id:"1799"},{term:"Truth in Lending Act (Regulation Z)",definition:"A law that requires borrowers to be informed about the cost of borrowing money",id:"1800"},{term:"UNDIVIDED INTEREST",definition:"That interest a co-owner has in property which carries with it the right to possession and use of the whole property along with the co-owners.",id:"1801"},{term:"Undue Influence",definition:"Using unfair advantage to get agreement in accepting a contract",id:"1802"},{term:"Unenforceable",definition:"A contract that was valid when made but either cannot be proved or will not be enforced by a court",id:"1803"},{term:"Unilateral Contract",definition:"An agreement in which one party promises to pay consideration or to do something in return for the performance of an act by another party; the party making the promise is not legally obligated to act unless the other party performs (a promise for an act)",id:"1804"},{term:"Unilateral Rescission",definition:"Legal action taken to repeal a contract by one party when the other party has breached a contract",id:"1805"},{term:"Unlawful Detainer Action",definition:"A lawsuit filed with the court against a tenant who remains in unlawful possession of rental property after breaching the terms of a lawful lease",id:"1806"},{term:"Urbanization",definition:"The clustering of people around big city areas for work and living.",id:"1807"},{term:"Use Clause",definition:"A clause in a lease designating which parties are authorized to use the property and for what purpose.",id:"1808"},{term:"USURY",definition:"The act of charging a rate of interest in excess of that permitted by law.",id:"1809"},{term:"Utility Value",definition:"The usefulness of the property",id:"1810"},{term:"VA",definition:"The Veterans Administration providing benefits to qualified veterans including the VA loan guaranteed by the VA and offering low or no down to the borrower.",id:"1811"},{term:"Vacancy Factor",definition:"Loss of income because of a vacant unit",id:"1812"},{term:"Valet",definition:"An employee in a large hotel who receives parks and retrieves a guest's automobile.",id:"1813"},{term:"Valid",definition:"Legally binding",id:"1814"},{term:"Valuable Consideration",definition:"Each party to a contract must give up something to make the agreement binding",id:"1815"},{term:"Value",definition:"The power of goods or services to command other goods in exchange for the present worth of future benefits arising from property ownership",id:"1816"},{term:"Variable Rate Mortgage (VRM)",definition:"A mortgage where the interest rate varies according to an agreed-upon index, thus resulting in a change in the borrower's monthly payments",id:"1817"},{term:"Variance",definition:"An exception granted to existing zoning regulations for special reasons",id:"1818"},{term:"Variance Analysis",definition:"An analysis of reports provided by software programs offering explanation for variances from the budget.",id:"1819"},{term:"Vassal",definition:"A person who received a fief from a regional lord.",id:"1820"},{term:"VENDEE",definition:"The buyer under a contract of sale (land contract).",id:"1821"},{term:"VENDOR",definition:"The seller under a contract of sale (land contract).",id:"1822"},{term:"VESTED",definition:"Owned by.",id:"1824"},{term:"Void",definition:"An agreement which is totally absent of legal effect",id:"1825"},{term:"Voidable",definition:"An agreement which is valid and enforceable on its face, but may be rejected by one or more of the parties",id:"1826"},{term:"Warehousing",definition:"The process of assembling into one package a number of mortgage loans, prior to selling them to an investor",id:"1827"},{term:"Warranty Deed",definition:"No longer used in California; a deed used to transfer title to property, guaranteeing that the title is clear and the grantor has the right to transfer it",id:"1828"},{term:"Washroom Attendant",definition:"An employee in a large hotel who ensures the cleanliness and supplies of restroom facilities.",id:"1829"},{term:"Will",definition:"A written instrument whereby a person makes a disposition of his property to take effect after his death",id:"1830"},{term:"Witnessed Will",definition:"Will usually prepared by an attorney and signed by the maker and two witnesses",id:"1831"},{term:"WRAP-AROUND LOAN",definition:"A method of financing where a new loan is placed in a secondary position; the new loan includes both the unpaid principal balance of the first loan and whatever sums are loaned by the lender; sometimes called an All-Inclusive Trust Deed (AITD).",id:"1832"},{term:"Writ of Possession",definition:"A court order directing the sheriff to remove the tenant and his or her possessions within five days",id:"1833"}];
const questions=[{category:"Brokerage",id:1,list:[{questionText:"A kiosk is:",hint:"Definition: A kiosk is a free-standing small booth, such as for jewelry, information, or newspapers.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the highest beam on a house.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a unit of measurement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a free-standing information booth.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an Eskimo house.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker Jones secured an agency listing in writing from the Johnson Co. on a commercial building that had been vacant for some months. The listing broker entered into a verbal agreement to share his commission with a cooperating broker. The cooperating broker procured a buyer, but Broker Jones refused to split the commission. The cooperating broker:",hint:"The Statute of Frauds does not require an agreement between brokers to split a commission to be in writing to be enforceable. If the cooperating broker can prove his case, he can recover his share in court.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"may recover his share in court.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"may not recover his share in court because this was only a verbal agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"should ask the Commissioner to arbitrate the dispute.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"should go to the Labor Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A policy manual is a(n):",hint:"The policy manual outlines the rules and regulations for office employees.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"outline of the Code of Ethics.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"book describing insurance coverage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"floor schedule for salespeople.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"outline of the procedures under which an office operates.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A real estate salesperson is responsible to his broker as:",hint:"As far as the Real Estate Law is concerned, a salesperson is an employee or independent contractor of the broker.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an employee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an independent contractor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a special agent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"either (a) or (b)",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"California Real Estate Law prohibits anyone licensed as a broker or salesperson from:",hint:"Although the law does not prohibit any of these, it does impose certain obligations on a licensee when he indulges in these activities.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"participating in a transaction as a principal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"taking an option.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"taking a listing and an option on the same property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Broker White obtained a deposit from buyer Farley. The seller did not accept the offer, however, and broker would not return deposit. Farley contacted the Real Estate Commissioner. The Commissioner can:",hint:'The law states that, "The Commissioner...shall, upon the verified complaint in writing of any person, investigate the actions...."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"act only as mediator.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"investigate as required by real estate law.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"not act on this since it involves a real estate license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not act on this since it involves civil court action.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"California Real Estate Law imposes upon a real estate agent the highest obligation of undivided interest and loyalty to his principal. This relationship is comparable to that of:",hint:"A fiduciary relationship exists between the agent and his principal. The trustee is the agent and the beneficiary is the principal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a lessee to the lessor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a trustee to his beneficiary.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a vendor to the purchaser.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a salesperson to his broker.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a salesperson leaves a broker, the broker must notify the Commissioner in writing:",hint:"The former employing broker must immediately notify DRE Licensing in Sacramento in writing ( Section 10161.8 of the Code)",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"within 10 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"within 5 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"immediately.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"within 30 days.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The name adopted by the National Association of Real Estate Brokers is:",hint:"Realtist.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"NAREB.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Realtors.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"realtist.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"brokers.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"With the broker's authorization, which of the following may withdraw funds from the broker's trust account?",hint:"The salesperson and the unlicensed employee working under a fiduciary bond would be acting as the broker's agent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A salesperson who works for the broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A corporate officer of a corporation acting as a broker for the corporation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An unlicensed employee of the broker working under a fiduciary bond",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Salesperson Ames tells his broker that he is quitting and will be going to work for another broker. His present broker should:",hint:"A broker must notify the Commissioner if a salesperson or associate broker transfers his or her license to another broker. The broker must return the license certificate to the salesperson or broker associate and must immediately notify the Commissioner of the associate licensee's departure. The new employing broker must notify the Commissioner within five days of arrival.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"notify the Real Estate Commissioner immediately and request cancellation of Ames' license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"give Ames his license and immediately notify the Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"notify the Real Estate Commissioner immediately and hold on to Ames' license until he has obtained his new one.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"send Ames' license to the Real Estate Commissioner within 5 days.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Salesperson Green is employed by Broker Smith. Broker Brown can employ Salesperson Green:",hint:"A salesperson must perform all his license activity for his employing broker. Appraising is not a licensed activity. All the other choices require a license.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"to collect rents.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to list property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to appraise property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"to sell vacant lots.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Regarding broker's trust fund accounts, which is not a requirement?",hint:"Real estate brokers and salespersons, in their capacity as agents, must handle, control, and account for trust funds according to specific legal guidelines including being named as trustee, keeping trust bank account records (i.e. those held in escrow), and being able to withdraw funds from an account they are maintaining. A broker may keep up to $200 of personal funds in the trust fund account to pay for bank charges or service fees related to the trust account, but there is no minimum balance required of the actual trust fund account.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Must be able to withdraw trust funds on demand",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Must keep records of trust funds being held in escrow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Broker must be named as trustee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Must maintain a minimum balance",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"With respect to the Real Estate Commission:",hint:"There are 4 public members, 6 members which must have at least 5 years experience as real estate brokers for a total of 10 members plus the commissioner. All members are appointed by the commissioner. (c) is a statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"it consists of the Commissioner and 8 other members, all of whom must have been active as real estate brokers for 5 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the Commissioner is elected by state vote; however, the other members are appointed by county.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the Commissioner has the power to create regulations that have the force and effect of law.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"five members are selected from the general public and need not be licensed brokers.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, who would not be required to possess a valid real estate license?",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (d) must all possess a valid real estate license. A person dealing in his own property does not have to possess a valid real estate license. A corporation is a legal person.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An attorney acting as a broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A person soliciting door-to-door for listings of real property for a specific broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A corporation leasing 3 or more of its own properties",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A person soliciting borrowers or lenders for or negotiating loans secured by real property or a business opportunity",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following statements concerning a broker's trust account are correct except:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all correct statements. Trust monies do not need to be deposited into a trust account. Trust monies may also be paid to the seller or deposited into escrow or other neutral depository. The buyer and seller may also give other directions.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"no minimum balance is required.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a savings and loan association may not be used as a depository.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a columnar cash receipts and disbursements journal must be maintained; however, a separate ledger account for each client need not be maintained.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trust monies received by a broker must be deposited in a trust account.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Any real estate licensee is subject to discipline by the Commissioner. Which of the following would be grounds for discipline?",hint:"All the other answers are not grounds for discipline. An exclusive listing must have a definite termination date. Five days after close of escrow may never arrive.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:'A licensed broker belonging to NAR and working exclusively as a loan broker using the term "Realtor" on his advertising',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Providing for the termination date of an exclusive listing to be 5 days after the close of escrow",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Failure to provide for a definite termination date of an open listing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Presenting an offer to his principal from a real estate syndicate of which he is a limited partner with disclosure of his interest on the offer",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"According to the Department of Real Estate, which of the following terms best describes the relationship of a salesperson to the broker?",hint:"A real estate salesperson is someone who holds a salesperson license issued by the Department of Real Estate. He or she must be employed by a real estate broker in order to perform any of the activities that require a license.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Independent contractor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Employee",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Limited independent contractor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Outside salesperson",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are correct statements concerning NAR except:",hint:"An appraiser may be a member of NAR and an appraiser does not ever have to have a real estate license. The other answers are all statements of fact. MAI (Members of Appraisers Institute).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:'it has a registered trademark on the term "Realtor."',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"NAR accepts only licensed real estate brokers as members.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"NAR's code of ethics limits the display of signs on a property to one broker and that must be with the consent of the owner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'an "MAI" may also be a member of NAR.',isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When the broker balances his trust account with the bank statement, this is called:",hint:'The definition of reconciliation is "the balancing of the trust accounts to the bank account."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"balancing the books.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reconciliation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"account balancing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"beneficiary statement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How long does a broker have to keep a deposit receipt from the date on the contract?",hint:"Business and Professions Code Section 10148 - A broker must retain the following documents for three years from the date of the closing or, if the transaction is not closed, from the date of the listing: listings, deposit receipts, cancelled checks, trust records, disclosure documents and other related documents.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"6 months",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1 year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2 years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3 years",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"If a broker's trust account is an interest bearing account, any interest must be:",hint:"Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"reinvested.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"given to the client.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"recorded in the trust record.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"turned over the real estate recovery fund.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A commission split describes:",hint:"A commission split is a agreement decided between the employing broker and each employed sales associate. The split usually is a certain percentage of the commission that comes to the brokerage from the closing of a sale or transaction for which the sales associate is responsible.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the division of the total commission that comes to a brokerage between the broker and a salesperson.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the division of a commission between two salespersons.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a disagreement between the broker and a salesperson.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the amount given to an unlicensed person for performing real estate duties.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'When a licensee places an ad in the newspaper without the broker\'s name that reads in total: "3 bdrm, 2 bath, den and spa, giant lot, $160,000-800-555-1212". This is :',hint:'A "blind ad" is an ad that does not identify the broker.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a violation of the Truth in Lending Law.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"misleading advertising.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"false advertising.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a blind ad.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'The broker\'s "desk cost" is based upon:',hint:'The broker\'s "desk cost" is calculated by dividing the total operating expenses of the office by the number of salespersons.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cost of furniture for all of the salespersons.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"gross profit minus expenses.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"costs divided by number of salespersons.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"total operating expense of the office divided by the number of salespersons.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A company dollar can be defined as:",hint:'The "company dollar" is the money left over after all commissions are subtracted from gross income.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the money required to establish the office.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the money left over after expenses.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the money left over after all commissions are subtracted from gross income.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the money the company spends to support the office.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The required employment contract between a broker and salesperson must be retained upon termination for how many years?",hint:"Both broker and salesperson must retain a copy of the employment agreement for three years from the date the salesperson leaves the broker's employment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"4",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"California Real Estate Law prohibits anyone licensed as a broker or salesman from:",hint:"Although the law does not prohibit any of these, it does impose certain obligations on a licensee when he participates in these activities.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"participating in a transaction as a principal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"taking an option.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"taking a listing and an option on the same property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Broker White obtained a deposit from buyer Farley. The seller did not accept the offer, however, and the broker would not return the deposit. Farley contacted the Real Estate Commissioner. The Commissioner can:",hint:'The law states that, "The Commissioner...shall, upon the verified complaint in writing of any person, investigate the actions...."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"act only as mediator.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"investigate as required by real estate law.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"not act on this since it involves a real estate license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not act on this since it involves civil court action.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If he or she does not have a college degree, how much previous full time experience as a real estate salesperson must a broker candidate have?",hint:"A broker candidate must have two years of full-time licensed real estate experience within the past five years, (or one of the following acceptable equivalents - a four-year degree from an accredited college or one year of full-time real estate experience combined with a two-year degree from an accredited college).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"4 years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2 years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"l year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a broker must have a 4 year college degree",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a broker fires a salesperson for cause, the broker must notify the Real Estate Commissioner in writing:",hint:"Business and Professions Code Section 10178 specifies that “When any real estate salesperson is discharged by his or her employer for a violation of any of the provision of the Real Estate Law, a certified written statement of the facts with reference thereto shall be filled forthwith with the (Real Estate) Commissioner by the employer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"immediately.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"within 5 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"within 10 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"within 30 days.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A majority of the Real Estate Commission is:",hint:"Six of the 10 members constitutes a quorum (majority).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5 members",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4 members",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6 members",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The License Law of California is very specific and exact. Which of the following would be required to have a real estate license in California?",hint:"According to Article 5 of the Real Estate Law, anyone who sells more than 7 trust deeds, mortgages, or land contracts in the same year must be a licensed real estate broker.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A man who buys four trust deeds in a month",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A man who sells six parcels through a real estate broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A man who buys three houses a month for resale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A man who owns four trust deeds and four mortgages, collects payment on them for two years, and sells them all in one year",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Assume a broker's license is suspended by the Real Estate Commissioner. All of the following statements are correct, except:",hint:"Be careful of the double negative in this question. Commissions earned when licensee was in good standing are collectable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the broker and his salesmen may not continue to collect rents.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commissions earned before the start of the suspension cannot be collected.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all listings in force are voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pending executory contracts are voidable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A permit is needed from the Real Estate Commissioner in which of the following instances?",hint:"Subdivisions come under the jurisdiction of the local government. A permit is not needed to sell existing trust deeds unless one sells 3 or more in one calendar year.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Selling real property syndicate securities",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Selling a California subdivision",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Selling existing trust deeds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you have a job for an insurance company to procure first trust deed loans and you are compensated for your services. This requires:",hint:"Article 7 of the Real Estate Law, commonly known as the Loan Broker Law, requires an active Real Estate Broker's License.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a real estate salesman's license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an active real estate broker's license.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"no license at all.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a loan correspondent license.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Real Estate Commissioner would most likely deny a license to which of the following applicants?",hint:'The chief requirement to obtain a license is honesty, truthfulness and good reputation which means "of good moral character."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A person unable to prove his reputation of honesty, truthfulness, and integrity",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A person having been acquitted of a felony",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A person having been adjudged a bankrupt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An unlicensed secretary in a real estate office may legally:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) would require a real estate license, answer (d) would not.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"discuss the terms of sale on advertised property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"quote prices on listed property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"collect rents on property managed by the company.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"type deposit receipts for the broker.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"For violations of the real estate law, procedure for disciplinary action is set in the:",hint:"This is found in the Government Code.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Business and Professions Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Civil Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"California Code of Regulations.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'When running a real estate office, the phrase "company dollar" means:',hint:'The "company dollar" refers to the amount left over after all commissions are paid.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the money the company initially invested to open the office.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the net income of a broker after all expenses are subtracted.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the income of an office after all commissions are paid to the salespeople.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"None of the following employees need a real estate license, except:",hint:"The hostess at an open house who hands-out information sheets about the home must have a license.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a clerical worker who only types sales reports for the agents in a real estate office.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a hostess at an open house who never tells the clients the prices, because all the information is contained in the data sheet she hands each client.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a resident property manager.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of these people need a license",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How long must a real estate salesperson keep a copy of his employment contract with a broker, after quitting the office?",hint:"Both broker and salesperson must keep a copy of the employment contract for three years from the termination of employment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"One year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Two years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Three years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Four years",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Salesman Green is employed by broker Smith. Broker Brown can employ salesman Green:",hint:"A salesman must perform all his license activity for his employing broker. Appraising does not require a real estate license. All the other choices require a real estate license.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"to collect rents.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to list property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to appraise property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"to sell vacant lots.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A California Real Estate license is necessary for which of the following?",hint:"A mortgage loan broker must be a licensed real estate broker according to Article #7 of the Real Estate Law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A subdivider",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A mortgage loan broker",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An escrow officer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An appraiser",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"John, a building contractor, and Fred, a REALTOR, wish to purchase a business property. To do so:",hint:"The fact that both men have state licenses of a different type does not prevent them from purchasing property together. However, they would have to do so as principals.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"they may engage in real estate acts together only as principals.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"John needs a real estate license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"they will need a partnership real estate license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"they will need a partnership contractors' license.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker refuses to return buyer's deposit upon seller's refusal of buyer's offer. Buyer mails a verified complaint to the Real Estate Commissioner, who should:",hint:"The Commissioner must investigate any verified complaint made in writing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"investigate as the law requires.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"it is up to his discretion as to whether to investigate or not.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"act as mediator between broker and buyers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must not investigate as it is a matter for the civil court only.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"After the broker reconciles his trust account, the broker's client liabilities should match the trust account:",hint:"Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"overages.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"shortages.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"balance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"fidelity bond.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The dictate that a sign should not be placed on a property without the owners consent is found in:",hint:"Found in the Code of Ethics of NAR.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Business and Professions Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"NAR Professional Code of Ethics.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"California Real Estate Act.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Commissioner's Regulations.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Real Estate Commissioner must approve which of the following forms used by a real estate broker?",hint:"These two forms must be approved by the Real Estate Commissioner.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Broker's loan statement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Security dealer's statement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"To obtain a real estate salesperson's license, an applicant must be:",hint:"All applicants for license must be fingerprinted.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"21 years of age.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fingerprinted for the Department of Real Estate.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"U. S. citizens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is never a solution to a commission dispute?",hint:"One of the jobs not assigned to the Commissioner is settling commission disputes. That issue falls under the power of a court of law, and must be handled through an attorney if the parties involved cannot settle the matter amicably.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The Real Estate Commissioner",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The parties involved (buyer and seller)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A civil court of law",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Arbitration",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'A real estate broker included the following clause in her standard listing contract: "In consideration of execution of the foregoing, the undersigned broker agrees to use diligence in procuring purchaser." This is:',hint:"A bilateral contract requires a promise given in exchange for another promise. This clause is the broker's exchanged promise to the seller.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"superfluous and unnecessary in current contracts.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"important to the creation of a bilateral contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"important to the creation of a unilateral contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"important according to the Statute of Limitations.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Alice's license has been suspended. The Recovery Account has paid on claims by both the buyer and seller. When may Alice's license be reinstated?",hint:"A license is suspended until the Recovery Account has been paid back, plus interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"When she pays the person the amount owed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When she pays the Recovery Account for money paid minus the interest",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A suspended licensee may never have his license reinstated",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When she pays the Recovery Account for money paid plus all interest",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"How often must a trust fund account be reconciled?",hint:"Per Comissioner's Regulations.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Weekly",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Daily",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Monthly",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Quarterly",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'A property owner rented out a home to a tenant for a short period, after which the tenant asked if the owner would be interested in selling the property. He consented and they verbally agreed to a purchase price. Before the offer could be drawn up, the owner visited the property while the tenant was away and realized that the tenant had been making significant improvements to the property without his knowledge. He called the tenant the next day and said he could only agree with the sale if the offer included an additional $50,000. Can the tenant sue for "specific performance" on a verbal contract?',hint:"Statute of Frauds requires transfers of property to be in writing, so specific performance cannot be a remedy for this contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Yes, due to the parol evidence rule",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No, verbal agreements are not admissible in the courts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Yes, this is a quasi contract and is binding",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No. Statute of Frauds requires transfers of property to be in writing",isCorrect:!0}]}}]},{category:"Practice",id:2,list:[{questionText:"Who enforces anti-discrimination and assures housing accommodations regardless of race, creed, or color?",hint:"The California Fair Employment and Housing Act (formerly the Rumford Act) prohibits discrimination in the sale, rental, or financing of practically all types of housing. Violations are reported to the state Department of Fiar Employment and Housing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Department of Housing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Department of Labor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Department of Fair Employment and Housing",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In 1968, the United States Supreme Court handed down a decision in a case involving the matter of fair and open housing. The Supreme Court's decision upheld the Civil Rights Act passed by Congress in the year:",hint:"Jones vs. Mayer prohibits discrimination based on race by upholding the 1866 Civil Rights Act and the 13th Amendment to the U.S. Constitution prohibiting slavery.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1942.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1948.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1868.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1866.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Any complaint as to the violation of the United States Civil Rights Act of 1968 should be filed within how many days of its occurrence?",hint:"An aggrieved person may file a complaint directly to a U.S. District Court within one year of the alleged discriminatory practice, whether or not a verified complaint has been filed with the Secretary of HUD.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"180 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"365 days",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"30 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"90 days",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a person is in violation of the Rumford Act in refusing to sell property to a minority person, he could be made to:",hint:"The Dept. of Fair Employment and Housing will investigate and can order the owner to sell or rent the unit to the complainant; offer to the complainant the next available unit; or pay civil damages up to $10,000 ($25,000 if there has been a prior violation).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"pay $1,000 in damages.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sell the property to the individual if it is still available.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sell a similar type property if he has a similar property for sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When there is a case involving discriminatory practices taken against a principal and his agent, which U.S. Supreme Court decision is often cited as a precedent?",hint:"In 1968, the Civil Rights Act of 1866, was upheld by the United States Supreme Court in Jones v. Alfred H. Mayer Company, when the court ruled that the 1866 federal law “prohibits all racial discrimination, private and public, in the sale and rental of property.”",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Wilson vs. Shaeffer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Smith vs. Bonnheim",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Jones vs. Mayer",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Title VIII",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following agencies mentioned, which has the authority to hear complaints of discrimination in housing?",hint:"Violations of discrimination in the sale, rental or financing of practically all types of housing are reported to the state Department of Fair Employment and Housing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real Estate Board",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Fair Relations Commission Board",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Department of Fair Employment and Housing",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is true about the Real Estate Law?",hint:"The license law is only effective if it can be enforced. The Commissioner can only investigate non-licensed persons, but can discipline licensed persons.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It is enforced in a court of law",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is enforced by local real estate boards",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is enforced by the California Association of Realtors",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is enforced by the Real Estate Commissioner",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In regards to the sale of a subdivision by a licensee of the Department of Real Estate, which of the following is not correct?",hint:"The Real Estate Law states that no parcel can be committed to a binding agreement to purchase until the Commissioner's Final Public Report is in hand.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An exclusive right to sell listing on a subdivision lot must have a definite termination date regardless of how long it takes to sell the lot",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The licensee may take listings prior to issuance of the Commissioner's Public Report",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The licensee may not advertise the sale of lots prior to issuance of the Commissioner's Final Public Report",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The licensee may not sell lots prior to issuance of the Commissioner's Final Public Report",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A real estate licensee under federal law should not take restrictive listings or advertise dwellings which suggest discrimination because of the:",hint:"Definition: Title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 and the Fair Housing Amendments Act of 1988, taken together constitute the Fair Housing Act, which prohibits discrimination based on rate, national origin, color, religion, age, sex, and handicap status.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Code of Ethics.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Rumford Act.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Unruh Civil Rights Act.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A listing agreement may be recorded at the county recorder's office by the:",hint:"Listing cannot be recorded whether notarized or not.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"broker.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"escrow company.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is a true statement?",hint:"The Unruh Civil Rights Act covers discrimination in business. It is against the law for anyone to deny a person the right to business products and services. The Unruh Act applies to a real estate brokerage because it is a business and may not discriminate against clients or customers.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Since a broker is an agent, he may discriminate if his principal authorized it",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"As of this date, there is no law against discrimination by an agent",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Businesses are precluded from discrimination against customers by the Unruh Civil Rights Act, and since a real estate office is a business, the broker cannot discriminate",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Discrimination is most effectively prohibited by N.A.R.'s Code of Ethics",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who enforces anti-discrimination and assures housing accommodations regardless of race, creed, or color?",hint:"The California Fair Employment and Housing Act (formerly the Rumford Act) prohibits discrimination in the sale, rental, or financing of practically all types of housing. Violations are reported to the state Department of Fiar Employment and Housing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Department of Housing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Department of Labor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Department of Fair Employment and Housing",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In 1968, the United States Supreme Court handed down a decision in a case involving the matter of fair and open housing. The Supreme Court's decision upheld the Civil Rights Act passed by Congress in the year:",hint:"Jones vs. Mayer prohibits discrimination based on race by upholding the 1866 Civil Rights Act and the 13th Amendment to the U.S. Constitution prohibiting slavery.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1942.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1948.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1868.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1866.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Any complaint as to the violation of the United States Civil Rights Act of 1968 should be filed within how many days of its occurrence?",hint:"An aggrieved person may file a complaint directly to a U.S. District Court within one year of the alleged discriminatory practice, whether or not a verified complaint has been filed with the Secretary of HUD.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"180 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"365 days",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"30 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"90 days",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When there is a case involving discriminatory practices taken against a principal and his agent, which U. S. Supreme Court decision is often cited as a precedent?",hint:"In 1968, the Civil Rights Act of 1866, was upheld by the United States Supreme Court in Jones v. Alfred H. Mayer Company, when the court ruled that the 1866 federal law “prohibits all racial discrimination, private and public, in the sale and rental of property.”",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Wilson vs. Shaeffer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Smith vs. Bonnheim",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Jones vs. Mayer",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Title VIII",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following agencies mentioned, which has the authority to hear complaints of discrimination in housing?",hint:"Violations of discrimination in the sale, rental or financing of practically all types of housing are reported to the state Department of Fair Employment and Housing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real Estate Board",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Fair Relations Commission Board",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Department of Fair Employment and Housing",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Federal Open Housing Laws prohibit discrimination by parties in the sale of which of the following properties?",hint:"The Federal Fair Housing Law (also known as the Federal Open Housing Law) pertains to all these properties.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A 25-unit apartment building",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A single-family residence purchased with government assistance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A single-family residence sold by a real estate broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A Caucasian person would have recourse to fair housing provisions under the Civil Rights Act of 1968 if denied the right to:",hint:"The Civil Rights Act of 1866 prohibits discrimination based on race in all property transactions.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"have minority neighbors.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"attend the church of his or her choice.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"meet neighbors.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"choose neighbors.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker had signed an agreement with an investor who was interested in a certain property. The broker, determined that she could purchase this property for less than her principal was willing to pay, purchased the property and later sold it to the principal at a profit. This constitutes:",hint:"This is a good example of secret profit and is a violation of the Real Estate Law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"commingling.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fraud.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"conversion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"secret profit.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Blue had been showing homes to a young, newly married couple for quite some time and finally found one which they wanted to buy. But even with the best loan available, they did not have enough cash for the down payment. They felt that they could raise the additional money they needed by borrowing against their automobile and other sundry personal property. Under these circumstances, the broker should:",hint:"The broker has certain obligations to the buyers but she must be careful not to give legal advise of this importance. To say nothing might imply consent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"advise against it.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tell them it is their decision to make, but point out the pitfalls of this kind of financing.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"advise them to go ahead because real estate always appreciates in value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tell them nothing and let them make their own decision.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker who is employed by the seller is liable to the buyer if:",hint:"A broker's contract ordinarily makes him the agent of the seller. If he performs an act which his contract does not authorize him to do, he is the agent of the other party, the buyer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"he acts under a power of attorney for seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"he acts in excess of the terms of his contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the offer is accepted but the contract is not performed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the listing agreement has no termination date.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If you were called upon to list a property that was owned by an unincorporated church group, you would:",hint:"Check the by-laws and charter to establish who is authorized to employ the broker for and on behalf of the group.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"contact the person who was the president at the time the property was acquired.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have the group form a committee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"check the by-laws and charter.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker refuses to sell property to an individual because of his color. His action is:",hint:"Reference the NAR Code of Ethics and the Fair Housing Act.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"unethical.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"illegal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"against public policy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mabel owns an acre of ground with 5 rental houses on it. She decides to sell them to the tenants. She needs:",hint:"She does not need a real estate license to sell her own property, but she does need a public report because she would be subdividing the property into 5 or more parcels.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a real estate license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a public report.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"You must have a real estate license if you are:",hint:"The other three choices would not need a real estate license.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"selling your own property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subdividing your property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appraising property for a fee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a mortgage loan broker.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The stated policy of the Real Estate Commissioner is to create a color-blind industry. This means:",hint:"The California Real Estate Commissioner has made it very clear that a person's real estate license will be restricted, suspended, or revoked for any violation of the fair housing laws.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an attitude free from bias.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"dealing without regard to race, creed or color.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"do unto others as you would have them do unto you.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A real estate licensee under Federal law should not take restrictive listings or advertise dwellings which suggest discrimination because of the:",hint:"Definition: Title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 and the Fair Housing Amendments Act of 1988, taken together constitute the Fair Housing Act, which prohibits discrimination based on rate, national origin, color, religion, age, sex, and handicap status.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Code of Ethics.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Rumford Act.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Unruh Civil Rights Act.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A real estate broker negotiated the sale of a home. Title was deeded to the buyer. The broker must notify buyer and seller within 30 days, in writing, of the:",hint:"A broker must notify the buyer and the seller of the selling price within one month after completion of the sale. It is usually done by the escrow company.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"amount of commission he received.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"selling price of the property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"new loans against the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"disposition of deposits placed into his trust account.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A listing would most likely be:",hint:"Would most likely be listed at high market value as seller would most likely try to get maximum price for his property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"low market value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"high market value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"average market value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not related to market value.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Rebate Law:",hint:"The rebate law requires title insurance companies to charge for preliminary reports and to make sincere efforts to collect for the charges.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"prohibits a broker from giving some of his commission to a buyer to help close a transaction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"prohibits a lender from paying a finder's fee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"requires a title insurance company not only to charge for a report, but also to make a sincere effort to collect.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In which of the following instruments would you find a safety clause for the protection of the real estate broker?",hint:"This is part of the compensation clause.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Deposit receipt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lease",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Loan broker's statement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Listing",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A deposit receipt is dated February 5 and gives the seller 5 days to accept. The offer is good until midnight:",hint:"The day it is dated counts as the first day: 5 - 6 - 7 - 8 - 9th.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"February 8.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"February 9.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"February 10.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"February 11.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Commingling is most opposite to:",hint:"Commingling is mixing. The opposite would be to segregate (keep separate).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trust fund.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mingling.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neutral depository.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"segregate.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A broker, who has a listing together with an option on a property, wants to exercise the option and sell the property himself. Which of the following is true?",hint:"The Commissioner permits the broker to take an option along with the listing, provided he divulges his profit and advises the owner in writing prior to exercising the option.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"He is an optionor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"He is an agent",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"This is permissible providing he gives notice to the parties that he holds an option and states to the owner how much profit he is to receive",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"This is not permissible since it violates his fiduciary relationship",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under Article 7 of the Business and Professions Code, Division 4, Part 1, Chapter 3, how much commission can a loan broker charge to negotiate a junior loan for $4,500, to be repaid in a period of 5 years?",hint:"15% for a period of 3 years or more.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"15%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Does not apply",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a minority comes into your office, you will:",hint:"As one of a realtor's duties to the public, he or she shall not deny equal professional services to any person for reasons of race, color, religion, sex, handicap, familial status, or national origin. NAR Code of Ethics.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"send him elsewhere.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"use your best judgment insofar as respecting social pressures.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"how houses in integrated neighborhoods only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be color blind.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following covers Federal Fair Housing laws?",hint:"The Rumford Act is the State Fair Housing Law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Rumford Act",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"13th Amendment to the U. S. Constitution",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Unruh Civil Rights Act",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title VIII, Civil Rights Act of 1968",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Normally, the amount of commission to be paid is decided by:",hint:"The amount of commission is decided by the seller and the broker, and is included in the listing agreement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"escrow agent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buyer and seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the seller and broker.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Conversion is a violation of the Real Estate Law. If a broker is sued for conversion, he is alleged with:",hint:"If a broker uses the client's money, it is known as conversion, or appropriation of property (or funds) belonging to another (a client).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"misappropriating client's funds.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"making a secret profit.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"segregation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commingling.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A permit is needed from the Real Estate Commissioner in which of the following instances?",hint:"Subdivisions come under the jurisdiction of the local government. A permit is not needed to sell existing trust deeds unless one sells 3 or more in one calendar year.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Selling real property syndicate securities",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Selling a California subdivision",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Selling existing trust deeds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you have a job for an insurance company to procure first trust deed loans and you are compensated for your services. This requires:",hint:"Article 7 of the Real Estate Law commonly known as the Loan Broker Law, requires an active Real Estate Broker's License.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a real estate salesperson's license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an active real estate broker's license.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"no license at all.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a loan correspondent license.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When an agent receives two offers on his principal's property at the same time, and one is better for the agent, he should submit:",hint:"Submit all offers, a demand of agency.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"both offers and let the owner decide.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the best offer first.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the deal which he thinks is best for his principal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the deal which would pay the most commission.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In describing an agency contract, which is most nearly correct?",hint:"Multiple listing groups demand exclusive listings.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Most multiple listings are exclusive listings",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An open listing without a termination date is unenforceable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Often multiple listings are net listings",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An exclusive agency need not contain a termination date",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Broker Smith operates a small business in a small room in his home. The room has its own entrance with just a sign over the door reading "Smith Realtor". He has no salesperson working for him except a 17-year-old student he has in training for the business and to whom he pays $5.00 for each listing the student brings in. Broker Smith is not a member of a real estate board. Since he lives outside of town he holds all deposits received until he goes to town, about once a week. From the information given, broker Smith is in violation of the Real Estate Law in all of the following, except:',hint:"He is definitely in violation of the Real Estate Law in answers (a), (b), and (d).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"paying compensation to an unlicensed person.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'using the term "Realtor."',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"location of his office.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"commingling.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Real Estate Commissioner would most likely deny a license to which of the following applicants?",hint:'The chief requirement to obtain a license is honesty, truthfulness, and good reputation which means "of good moral character."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A person unable to prove his reputation of honesty, truthfulness, and integrity",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A person having been acquitted of a felony",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A person having been adjudged a bankrupt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker took a listing for 90 days. During the term of the listing, the owner was declared mentally incompetent. The listing contract is:",hint:"Incapacity on the part of either of the parties to an employment contract will make it void.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"binding.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"enforceable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A license differs from an easement in that a license can:",hint:"A license right cannot by transferred or terminated. A license right may be revoked with cause where an easement may not be revoked. The key words to a license right are, it is personal, unassignable, and revocable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"be revoked.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"be transferred.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be terminated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An unlicensed secretary in a real estate office may legally:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) would require a real estate license, answer (d) would not.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"discuss the terms of sale on advertised property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"quote prices on listed property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"collect rents on property managed by the company.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"type deposit receipts for the broker.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"For violations of the real estate law, procedure for disciplinary action is set in the:",hint:"This is found in the Government Code.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Business and Professions Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Civil Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"California Code of Regulations.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker Al listed Desi's house. Desi told the broker that the roof leaked and to tell any prospective buyers it was in need of repairs. Al, in a conversation to Mr. Simple, said the roof did not leak and was in good condition. Simple bought the property and during the rainy season the roof leaked badly. Simple could receive damages from:",hint:"The broker owes a duty to the buyer to disclose all pertinent information that the buyer would be interested in. The seller is responsible for his agent's acts done within the scope of his authority.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"broker and seller for using fraudulent statements.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"broker only for over-exercising his authority beyond what the seller had given him.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"seller, since he should have told Simple.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'none because "caveat emptor " applies.',isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Agency is referred to as the relationship between the agent and his principal. All of the following statements are correct about agency except:",hint:"Answers (a), (c), and (d) are correct statements applicable to an agency relationship. Answer (b) is false. An agency relationship does not require the payment of money.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"agency may be an expressed contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the principal must pay money to the agent to create an agency relationship.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"agency may be an implied contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an agreement that may be in writing or verbal.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker has an option to purchase in an agreement which also employs the broker to sell the parcel of real property and to obtain a commission from the sale. Before the broker can legally exercise the option, he must:",hint:"An option listing gives the broker the right to purchase the property that is listed. A broker with an option is acting as a principal as well as an agent. Prior to exercising the option, he seller must be informed for the full amount of the broker's profit and agree to it in writing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"make a public notice of his intention to exercise the option.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"put the necessary funds in escrow.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"obtain the written consent of the seller.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"give constructive notice to the seller.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A real estate broker sold a farm acting as agent for the seller. By agreement, he may accept his commission in the form of:",hint:"Commission is the compensation paid to a real estate broker for services rendered in connection with the sale or exchange of real property. The amount of commission is not set by law and is always negotiable between sellers and brokers.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cash from the seller's receipts of the sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an assigned note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the buyer's note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A husband and wife owned their home as joint tenants. The husband signed an exclusive authorization and right to sell listing agreement with a broker without disclosing the manner of title holding in the property and without his wife's signature on the listing. In the event of a commission dispute, the broker:",hint:"The husband binds the community as statutory manager when he fails to disclose the joint tenancy holding.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"may bring action to force the wife to sell her interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may sue the husband separately in civil court for his commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"has no right to a commission because he failed to obtain the wife's signature on the listing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may bring court action against the community estate.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is closest to the same relationship as between a broker and seller?",hint:"A broker is the agent and the seller is the principal he works for. A trustee is also an agent who works for a beneficiary (the principal). Broker-salesperson (employer-employee relationship); mortgagor-mortgagee (borrower-lender relationship); vendor-vendee (seller-buyer relationship).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trustee and beneficiary",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Broker and salesperson",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mortgagor and mortgagee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Vendor and vendee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Prior to holding a hearing to consider revoking or suspending a real estate license, the Real Estate Commission must first serve the license affected with a(n):",hint:"If a verified written complaint has been made against a licensee that indicates that a violation of law has occurred while the licensee was acting as an agent, an accusation or statement of issues is filed and served upon the affected licensee. This is followed by a formal hearing held in accordance with the Administrative Procedures Act.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"complaint.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"demurrer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accusation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"statement of issues.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A cooperative service conducted by a group of brokers who are members of a real estate association:",hint:"A multiple listing service (MLS) is a cooperative listing service conducted by a group of brokers, usually members of a real estate association.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"CAR.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"NAR.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Multiple Listing Service.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Legal Hotline Service.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following actions would be in violation of real estate law except:",hint:"Answer (a) is the only one that is not in violation of the real estate law. Only brokers share commission, not salespersons. Only the broker accepts commission from one or more principals, not the salesperson.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a California real estate broker sharing a commission with a licensed broker in Wyoming who assisted in completing a real estate transaction in Wyoming.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a licensed salesperson sharing a commission with another licensed salesperson.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a licensed salesperson accepting commission from both principals to a transaction with the knowledge and consent of both principals.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a broker sharing a commission with a licensed salesperson employed by another broker.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An agency relationship is said to create a fiduciary relationship between principal and agent. Of the following relationships, which illustrates a fiduciary responsibility?",hint:"A trustee is an agent to the beneficiary (the principal). A real estate broker is an agent to his client (the principal).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Any trustee to a beneficiary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real estate broker to his client",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following statements concerning agency relationships are correct except:",hint:"All the other answers are correct statements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"most broker-seller relationships are expressed agencies.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the seller of a home is responsible for the misrepresentations of his real estate broker as long as the broker is acting within the scope of his authorized duties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the real estate broker is not responsible for losses suffered by a buyer who acted upon misrepresentations of the seller passed on to him by the broker as long as the broker was unaware of the seller's misrepresentations.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"net listings are encouraged in California, because they avoid conflicts of interest in the agency relationship.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'Section 10131.1 of the Real Estate Law defines "in the business" as "the acquisition for resale to the public, and not as an investment, of more than seven real property sales contracts or promissory notes secured by liens on real property during a calendar year. " This means:',hint:"The key word is for resale, not investment purposes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a person who purchases 8 notes secured by trust deeds for investment purposes must have a license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a person who buys even one note in a year for resale to the public must have a license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the acquisition for resale of 8 land contracts or 8 notes secured by trust deeds in one calendar year requires a license.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above is correct",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker receives a deposit of $1,000 cash with an offer to purchase real property. When the seller accepts the offer the broker gives him the money with the agreement it will be deposited in escrow at a later date. Such a transaction is:",hint:"A broker must either give the deposit to the seller, deposit it into escrow or a neutral depository, or put it in his own trust account unless he has directions from the buyer or seller which state otherwise.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"commingling.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"conversion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"contravention.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A broker receives a listing on a residence the owner tells him he is selling because a freeway is planned through the neighborhood and his home is in the path of construction. He further states that even though the freeway is seven years in the future, he is anxious to sell now. When showing the property to a prospective purchaser, the broker:",hint:"The broker has a duty to disclose all pertinent facts to the buyer when he has knowledge of the facts. If he does not disclose these facts he could be liable for damages to the buyer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"should not disclose the planned freeway as he owes responsibility only to the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may disclose the planned freeway if required to close the deal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must disclose the planned freeway only if asked by the prospect.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must disclose the planned freeway whether the prospect asks or does not ask.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'"A" is a real estate broker. "B" is a "real property securities dealer." Which of the following is a correct statement?',hint:'"B" may sell raw land. "A" cannot do everything "B" can do, but "B" can do everything "A" can do.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:'"B" may not sell raw land acting as an agent for the owner of the land',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"A" may not sell trust deeds to the public, nor solicit loans secured by real property',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"A" can do everything "B" can do',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"B" can do everything "A" can do',isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A broker negotiated a hard money $4,000 note secured by a second deed of trust with a term of 4 years, for a client. Considering the above transaction, which of the following is a correct statement?",hint:"Commission allowed on a note for less than $20,000, secured by a second deed of trust for a term of 4 years, is 15%. 15% of $4,000 is $600.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"There would be no limit placed upon the commission the broker could charge",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"His maximum legal commission would be $600",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"His maximum legal commission would be $400",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"His maximum legal commission could be 5% of the note or $325, whichever was greater",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the preparation of an exclusive listing contract, a licensee may be disciplined if he fails to include:",hint:"All exclusive listings must have a definite termination date.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the asking terms of the financing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a clause making the agreement bilateral.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a clause indicating that time is of the essence in carrying out the terms of the contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a definite expiration date.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A real estate broker arranges a hard money loan secured by a second trust deed for $7,000 to be repaid in 5 years. Her maximum commission would be:",hint:"Article 7 applies to first trust deeds less than $30,000 and second trust deeds less than $20,000. Commission on a second trust deed for a term of 3 years or more is 15%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"15%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"5%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The real estate "listing" is classified as an employment contract under whose terms the owner of the property appoints and authorizes a real estate broker to act as his agent. Which of the following statements is correct?',hint:"In an exclusive agency listing the owner maintains the right to sell the property himself. The owner is not liable for a suit for specific performance until he has entered into the purchase contract with the buyer. Death terminates both an Exclusive Agency and Exclusive Right to Sell Listing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An owner is liable for a commission if he sells his property himself during the term of an exclusive agency listing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The owner is liable for a suit for specific performance if he refuses a buyer's offer that meets the exact terms of an exclusive right to sell listing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'A broker has an enforceable right to a commission in an open listing if he is the "procuring cause" even if the owner sells through another broker',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Death terminates an exclusive agency listing, but not an exclusive right to sell listing",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker refuses to return buyer's deposit upon seller's refusal of buyer's offer. Buyer mails a verified complaint to the Commissioner, who should:",hint:"The Commissioner must investigate any verified complaint made in writing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"investigate as the law requires.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"it is up to his discretion as to whether to investigate or not.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"act as mediator between broker and buyers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must not investigate as it is a matter for the civil court only.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker hired hostesses at the office of a subdivision which he is selling. The hostesses are not licensed and are paid a flat salary. They hand out a descriptive bulletin to prospective buyers who visit the office, and quote prices and terms. Licensed salespersons, however, write up contracts of all buyers. Which of the following is correct?",hint:"Must be licensed to show property or to quote prices and terms.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The hostesses can legally do this as long as they do not write up contracts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The hostesses can legally do this, as they are paid a flat salary and are not on a commission basis",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The hostesses must be licensed because they quote prices and terms",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Salaried personnel need not be licensed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who is entitled to a commission when a property is not listed at the time of the offer and has been shown to a buyer by more than one broker?",hint:"The agent who writes an accepted offer is known as the procuring cause.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The broker who is the procuring cause",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Whoever listed the property prior to the sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No one",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All brokers who showed the property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under Article 7, if the actual costs are $159 on a $4,000 loan, the maximum costs that can be charged is:",hint:"The broker charges the actual costs or the maximum costs, whichever is less. The maximum costs for this loan are $390, therefore the broker may only charge the actual costs of $159.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$159.00.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$200.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5% of the loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$325.00.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker negotiating a loan under Article 7 with a controlled institution is not required to fill out a broker's loan statement if he is charging a commission which is not more than:",hint:"The broker must provide a broker's loan statement for every loan negotiated by a broker.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The dictate that a sign should not be placed on a property without the owners consent is found in:",hint:"Found in the Code of Ethics of NAR.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Business and Professions Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"NAR Professional Code of Ethics.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"California Real Estate Act.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Commissioner's Regulations.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The relationship of loyalty and trust that exists between a principal and agent most nearly resembles the relationship between:",hint:"The trustee holds the title in trust for the benefit of the beneficiary.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"broker and salesperson.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee and beneficiary.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"lessor and lessee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"optionor and optionee.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following titles are correct except:",hint:"Federal Housing Administration (not Association).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Federal Housing Association (FHA).",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Member of Appraisers Institute (MAI).",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Certificate of Reasonable Value (CRV).",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"National Association of Realtors (NAR).",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Real Estate Commissioner must approve which of the following forms used by a real estate broker?",hint:"These two forms must be approved by the Real Estate Commissioner.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Broker's loan statement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Security dealer's statement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"After obtaining a listing from a corporation, all the officers were killed in an accident. The listing is:",hint:"Death of the officers does not affect the listing contract made with the corporation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"invalid.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"To obtain a real estate salesperson license, a person must be:",hint:"All applicants for license must be fingerprinted.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"21 years of age.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fingerprinted for the Department of Real Estate.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a U. S. citizen.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An owner gave an open listing to broker Rose and broker Daisy, who have both shown the property to Ms. Lily. Broker Rose gets an offer from Ms. Lily and a signed acceptance. Which of the following is correct?",hint:"Under an open listing, the broker who presents the first offer to be accepted by the owner is entitled to the commission.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The commission will be split between Rose and Daisy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The commission will be paid to Rose",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"No commission paid on an open listing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The commission will be paid to Daisy",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker obtained an offer with a deposit from a buyer on June 10, 1992, which states that the offer was irrevocable for five days from date. There had been no acceptance by the next day when the buyer called and revoked his offer. The broker should:",hint:"The buyer may revoke his offer anytime prior to acceptance. The irrevocable clause is not binding because it is without consideration.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"get an acceptance by June 15th.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"get an acceptance by June 16th.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"return the deposit to the buyer.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"place the deposit in escrow.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not correct regarding a Broker's Loan Statement?",hint:"Must be kept 4 years. The other three are correct.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It must be kept 3 years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It must be approved by a Real Estate Commissioner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It must state amount actually received by borrower",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It must state costs and commissions",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A licensee listed a property, promising the owner she would advertise the home. The owner relied on the promise of the real estate agent and listed the home because of it. If the agent failed to advertise the property, which of the following is true?",hint:"Untrue statements made by an agent who knows he or she is not telling the truth is a fraudulent act.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It would be a misrepresentation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It would be a mistake",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It would be actual fraud",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It would be negligence",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a broker is representing the buyer exclusively under a buyer agency contract, which of the following is true?",hint:"The buyer's broker owes a fiduciary duty to his principal, the buyer, only.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The buyer's broker has no liability for acts of the listing broker",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The buyer's broker is responsible for his own and the listing broker's acts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The buyer's broker has a fiduciary duty to the buyer and seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The buyer's broker must represent both parties",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Regarding a real estate commission:",hint:"A commission is a negotiable fee for services rendered usually based on a certain percentage of the sales price of a property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"it must be paid in cash.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"it must be paid directly to an agent by the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"it may be in the form of cash, check, assignment of a promissory note, or anything of value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"it is set by the real estate commissioner.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An agent may refuse to present an offer when the:",hint:"Common sense.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"property has already been sold and the escrow has closed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"offer is too low.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"agent wants to sell the buyer a different property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buyer is rude.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The words "procuring cause" are most often found in which of the following contracts?',hint:'The "procuring cause" for a sale in an open listing is the broker that first produces a customer ready, willing, and able to buy the property according to the terms of the open listing.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An exclusive right to sell listing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Deposit receipt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Open listing",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Exchange agreement",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you are employed by an owner of a 20-unit apartment house, in which you reside, to manage all 20 units. You would be known as:",hint:"A person that manages an apartment house and lives in one of the apartments is considered a resident property manager.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a property manager.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a resident property manager.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a real estate agent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an independent contractor.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property manager:",hint:"A property manager is an agent/broker who manages property for his principal. According to the law of agency, the agent may not gain any advantage over his principal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"may not collect rents.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may manage the property and receive kickbacks from suppliers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may use the rent money as he sees fit.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may not gain any advantage over the property owner.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"All of the following statements are considered violations of the Real Estate Law, except:",hint:'Informing your buyer that seller will accept less is "not" a violation of the law.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"request for a commission on an exclusive right to sell that did not contain a termination date.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"exclusive agent for the buyer informing buyer that the seller will accept less.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"making a very small secret profit.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'using the term "Realtor" when unauthorized.',isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An offer on a home listed under an exclusive agency listing was presented to a seller and immediately accepted and communicated to the buyer. Before the deal could be placed in escrow, the seller found another buyer with all cash and notified the broker that the original deal was off. Which of the following statements are true?",hint:"Since the offer was accepted and communicated to the buyer, we have a valid and binding contract. If the seller wishes to back out of the deal after this, broker has legal right to collect commission.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Broker is entitled to no compensation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Broker has an excellent legal basis to collect a commission",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The deposit must be reimbursed to the buyer and the buyer has no further claim of right against the seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Anyone is required to have a Real Estate license when he performs certain real estate acts. In which of the following sales does the Real Estate License Law apply?",hint:"In order to handle the sale of a real property security, a real estate broker's license is necessary.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real property securities",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Selling two trust deeds every year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"One promotional note sale, seasoned for more than three years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The License Law of California is very specific and exact. Which of the following would be required to have a Real Estate License in California?",hint:"According to Article 5 of the Real Estate Law, anyone who sells more than 7 trust deeds, mortgages or land contracts in the same year must be a licensed real estate broker.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A man who buys four trust deeds in a month",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a man who sells six parcels through a real estate broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a man who buys three houses a month for resale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a man who owns four trust deeds and four mortgages, collects payment on them for two years, and sells them all in one year",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Assume a broker's license is suspended by the Real Estate Commissioner. All of the following statements are correct, except:",hint:"Be careful of the double negative in this question. Commissions earned when licensee was in good standing are collectable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the broker and his salesmen may not continue to collect rents.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commissions earned before the start of the suspension cannot be collected.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all listings in force are voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pending executory contracts are voidable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A policy manual is:",hint:"Every broker establishes his own office procedure. This will be found in the policy manual.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an outline of procedures by which an office operates.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the manual used by policy and title insurance companies.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the law of agency manual.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The person who gives authority to an agent to represent his or her interests in dealing with a third party is the:",hint:"A principal is one of the main parties to a transaction (i.e. the buyer and the seller are principals in the purchase of real property). In a fiduciary relationship, the person who hires a real estate broker to represent him or her in the sale of property is a principal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"client.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"principal.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"escrow agent.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A buyer who does not have a real estate license:",hint:"A non-licensee may buy a property and turn around and sell it for any amount he wants without revealing the amount of profit to the original seller.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"may only buy five properties a year without obtaining a real estate license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must disclose any previously bought properties to a seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must disclose his profit if he resells the property within a year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may make a secret profit without violating the law.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What law would real estate licensees be violating if they set fixed commission rates?",hint:"There are no longer any established commission schedules; in fact, any attempt by a group of brokers to fix brokerage rates would be a violation of antitrust laws.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Fair business laws",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Anti-trust laws",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Real estate law",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Licensing law",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What must be included in an ad placed by a real estate salesperson?",hint:"A salesperson must list the name of his broker in all ads.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The salesperson's name",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The salesperson's title",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The broker's name",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The broker's license number",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A salesperson sold a home in California. His commission would be paid by the:",hint:"Under California Real Estate Law, a salesperson's commission can only be paid by his employing broker.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"broker.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"escrow company involved.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In regards to a listing contract, a fiduciary relationship exists between the broker and:",hint:"The two parties involved in a listing are the broker and owner (seller) and the broker is working in a position of trust (fiduciary) for the seller.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the seller.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"both buyer and seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A California Real Estate license is necessary for which of the following?",hint:"A mortgage loan broker must be a licensed real estate broker according to Article #7 of the Real Estate Law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A subdivider",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A mortgage loan broker",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An escrow officer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An appraiser",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'"A" has given "B" the impression that "X" is "A"\'s agent even though "X" was never given the authority to represent "A". From "B"\'s standpoint, the agency is:',hint:"A good example of this would be watching a friend's store for him while he goes to lunch. Making a sale to a customer that comes in believing you to be the owner, you are \"ostensibly\" the owner's agent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"power-of-attorney.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"constructive agency.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ostensible.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"rectified agency.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Real Estate Law being exact and specific includes legal aspects. In legal aspects:",hint:"The person who receives the title in real estate law is called the grantee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"deeds must be recorded to transfer title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the receiver of title is called the grantee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"open listings must contain termination dates.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An exclusive authorization and right to sell listing to sell a home, just entered into, can be described as:",hint:"The exclusive right to sell listing is a bilateral contract. An executory contract is one which has not been completely performed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a cash agreement to purchase properties that are bilateral.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a bilateral executory contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a land contract whereby licensee may obtain commissions from both the buyer and seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The minimum amount of time that a broker must keep signed copies of listings deposit receipts, and most other contracts, is:",hint:"Most documents are kept for a period of three years. The exceptions would be in the area of real property loans or real property securities. These documents must be kept four years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"one year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"three years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"four years.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The initials "I.R.E.M." stand for:',hint:"The official Institute of Real Estate Management (IREM) property management site contains a resource area open to the public and a members-only section.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The Internal Review of Estate Members.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The Institute of Real Estate Management.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Interest of Real Estate Membership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"In Real Estate Memorandum.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Two real estate brokers wish to purchase a commercial building together and intend to use part of the property for their respective offices and lease the remaining space to various tenants. In order to legally do this, they would be required to obtain which of the following licenses?",hint:"There is no such thing as a license to enter into a partnership. Two persons who wish to purchase property can do so without a real estate license. No license would be required for this transaction.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Partnership",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Corporation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Security Dealer's Endorsement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What kind of agency is a listing?",hint:"A special agency is called upon to perform a specific task such as listing (a contract between an owner of real property and an agent who is authorized to obtain a buyer).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A special agency",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A general agency",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An executive agency",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A dual agency",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under Article 7 of the Business and Professions Code, how much commission can a loan broker charge to negotiate a hard money junior loan for $4,500 to be repaid in a period of 5 years?",hint:"15% for a period of 3 years or more.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"15%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Does not apply",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Deposit money never belongs to:",hint:"Deposit money never belongs to the broker.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the broker.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you are in need of money and ask broker John Jones to negotiate a second trust deed loan for you. You expect which of the following to be the broker's responsibility?",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are not the broker's responsibility according to the Real Estate Law. However, answer (d) is the broker's responsibility.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Make sure that the trust deed has the proper amount of revenue stamps on it",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Have the broker's loan statement signed by all three parties",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Make sure that the property is appraised to justify the loan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"See to it that the trust deed is recorded and names the lender as the beneficiary",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When a broker receives an advance fee for advertising a listed property:",hint:"Monies received by an agent from a client must be deposited within three business days after receiving them either into a trust account or a neutral escrow account (to avoid the illegal practices of commingling and conversion).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"he must cash the check immediately.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"he must hold it until the property is sold.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"he must put the money in his client trust account.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"he must return it if the property is not sold.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A licensee may advertise secured trust deeds if he discloses which of the following?",hint:"A buyer must be able to evaluate the value of trust deeds before purchasing them; the loan to value ratio would be a good indication of security. The extent of the security would be indicated by how much of the value is encumbered with the trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The extent the trust deeds are secured",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The property addresses of the trust deeds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The trustor's names",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"His name",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker does not need prior DRE approval to charge an advance fee when:",hint:"Statement of fact",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the fees are under $50.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the fees are collected to pay appraisal and credit report fees and any excess funds are immediately refunded to the borrower.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the fees are put in a trust account immediately.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the fees are collected and identified as non-refundable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The maximum commission a loan broker may charge to negotiate an $8,000 hard money first trust deed, due in 2 years is:",hint:"The Loan Broker Law states the maximum commission a loan broker may charge to negotiate an $8,000 1st trust deed loan, due in 2 years, is 5%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$400.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$500.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$600.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$700.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Funds received on behalf of someone else, are known as:",hint:"All funds entrusted to a broker or agent by the principal or others are considered trust funds and are deposited into an account set up by a broker, attorney, or other agent at a bank or other recognized depository (also known as earnest money or escrow account).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commingled funds.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trust funds.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a deposit.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Regarding trust funds, who has a fiduciary duty?",hint:"The broker has a fiduciary duty to uphold the law regarding trust fund monies.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The real estate agent",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The buyer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The buyer and seller",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The amount of personal money a broker may keep in his trust account is:",hint:"A broker may keep up to $200 of personal funds in the trust fund account to pay for bank charges or service fees related to the trust account.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"up to $50.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"up to $60.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"up to $l70.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"up to $200.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Real estate agents can sell mobile homes which are located:",hint:"Real estate agents can only sell mobile homes which are considered real property and are located in established mobile home parks.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"in new mobile home sales lots.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in urban areas.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"anywhere in California.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in established mobile home parks.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Broker Jones secured an agency listing in writing from the Johnson Co. on a commercial building that had been vacant for some months. The listing broker entered into a verbal agreement to share his commission with a cooperating broker. The cooperating broker procured a buyer, but broker Jones refused to split the commission. The cooperating broker:",hint:"The Statute of Frauds does not require an agreement between brokers to split a commission to be in writing to be enforceable. If the cooperating broker can prove his case, he can recover his share in court.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"may recover his share in court.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"may not recover his share in court because this was only a verbal agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"should ask the Commissioner to arbitrate the dispute.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"should go to the Labor Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under Article 3, Section 10176, of the California Real Estate Law, a broker could not be disciplined for which of the following?",hint:"The Real Estate Code permits a broker to act for two parties, provided he has advised both and received their consent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Acting for more than one party in a transaction with the knowledge and consent of all parties thereto",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Making any substantial misrepresentation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Making any false promises of a character likely to influence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Any conduct whether of a same or different character than specified in this Section which constitutes fraud",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker Jones had signed an agreement to locate some property for her principal. Having found a property which suited the principal, Broker Jones determined that it could be purchased for less than her principal was willing to pay. She then bought the property and later sold it to her principal at the higher figure and kept the difference for herself. This would be called:",hint:"The details of the story do not indicate if fraud was involved in this transaction but certainly secret profit was.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"commingling.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"conversion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"divided agency.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"secret profit.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An agency relationship is created by all of the following except:",hint:"A real estate agency can be created by express agreement, ratification, and estoppel.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ratification.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"specific performance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"estoppel.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In a real estate contract, the promise to use "due diligence" is made by whom?',hint:"The seller signs a listing agreement promising payment for service by the listing broker and the broker promises to “use due diligence” in finding a buyer - a bilateral contract in which a promise is given in exchange for a promise.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The buyer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The escrow agent",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The listing broker",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"By accepting the actions of an agent, even though there is no contract, a seller may create an agency by:",hint:"Definition: Ratification means acceptance of an act already performed. Ratification of an agency relationship is created by approving acts after they are done.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"estoppel.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"express agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ratification.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"collaboration.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a broker accepts a deposit from a buyer making an offer to purchase real property, the authority for his action is contained in which of the following agreements?",hint:"The listing agreement establishes the agency relationship between owner and broker and contains the terms and authority of the agent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Deposit receipt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Earnest money agreement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Listing agreement",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Escrow agreement",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A real estate broker arranges a loan secured by a second trust deed for $7,000 to be repaid in 5 years. Her maximum commission would be:",hint:"Article 7 applies to first trust deeds less than $16,000 and second trust deeds less than $8,000. Commission on a second trust deed for a term of 3 years or more is 15%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"15%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"5%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following forms must be completed before an offer can be written?",hint:"The law requires that an agent supply a written document, called Disclosure Regarding Real Estate Agency Relationships, explaining the nature of agency. This disclosure must be made prior to taking a listing or writing an offer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Agency disclosure",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Deposit receipt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real estate transfer disclosure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Listing",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A hard money loan is:",hint:"Hard money loans are given to existing owners of real property for any purpose other than buying real property. Usually considered a personal loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a loan of money when money is hard to get.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a loan made to the trustor to help him purchase a piece of real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a loan of cash to an existing owner of real property to buy an automobile.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Acting for more than one party in a transaction:",hint:"Failure to disclose dual agency is a violation of real estate law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is illegal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is unethical.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is within the law.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"makes the transaction void.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker cannot accept a deposit from a buyer unless:",hint:"It is a listing violation for a broker to accept a deposit from a buyer unless he or she is specifically authorized to do so in the listing agreement. This violation may result in the suspension or revocation of his or her real estate license.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"directed to by the buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"authorized specifically in the listing.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"authorized in the deposit receipt.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"it is a promissory note.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"To which of the following does a real estate agent owe a fiduciary duty?",hint:"The agent owes the principal certain fiduciary duties.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Third party",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Principal",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Escrow agent",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Customer",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'A contract between the seller of real property and a licensee whereby the seller agrees to pay the licensee a commission if he produces a "ready, willing, and able" buyer and the licensee agrees to use due diligence in procuring a buyer, is called:',hint:"A bilateral contract is a contract between two parties with each promising to act (a promise for a promise). An executory contract is a contract yet to be performed. This type of contract is a bilateral executory contract. An executed contract is one that has been completed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"unilateral executory contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"bilateral executory contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"unilateral executed contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"bilateral executed contract.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An agent has only a duty of honesty and fairness in dealing with:",hint:"The agent has an obligation always to act fairly and honestly with third parties.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"third parties.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"principals.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"attorneys.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"city officials.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An untrue statement made by an agent who knows he or she is not telling the truth is:",hint:"Fraudulent misrepresentations are untrue statements made by an agent who knows he or she is not telling the truth.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"puffing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fraudulent misrepresentation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"steering.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"redlining.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A real estate agent has earned a commission when:",hint:"If the broker brings about a “meeting of the minds” of the buyer and seller on price and other terms for the transaction, the broker has earned the commission.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:'there is a "meeting of the minds" between buyer and seller on price and other terms of a transaction.',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the seller signs the listing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the offer is written.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the offer is presented.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Provisions are made in the Real Estate Law whereby a real estate broker may seek reimbursement directly from his principal for expenses incurred by the broker in conjunction with his employment under which of the following transactions?",hint:'When a broker is employed to negotiate a loan under a listing agreement and he incurs expenses for appraisals and other services, he collects these "out of pocket expenses" from the borrower. This is not the case when he holds a listing on a home or business.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The sale of a home",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The sale of a business opportunity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Negotiating a loan in which a Broker's Loan Statement is required",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The maximum commission a loan broker may charge to negotiate a $4,000 hard money 2nd trust deed, due in 3 years is:",hint:"Loan Broker Law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"15%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"20%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25%.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Michelle, a real estate agent, sold a condo that was listed by an agent from another company. What is her relationship to the listing agent?",hint:"Since a cooperating broker finds the buyer, an issue that can be confusing is the question of whether the cooperating broker represents the seller or the buyer. A subagent is defined as the agent of someone who is already the agent of the principal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Principal",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Third party",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Co-agent",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subagent",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'A real estate broker included the following clause in her standard listing contract: "In consideration of execution of the foregoing, the undersigned broker agrees to use diligence in procuring purchaser." This is:',hint:"A bilateral contract requires a promise given in exchange for another promise. This clause is the broker's exchanged promise to the seller.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"superfluous and unnecessary in current contracts.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"important to the creation of a bilateral contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"important to the creation of a unilateral contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"important according to the Statute of Limitations.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An agent who acts exclusively as the agent for the buyer may:",hint:"An agent who is the exclusive agent for the buyer may present offers to the seller and/or the seller's agent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"present offers to the seller only",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"present offers to the seller and seller's agent",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"present offers to the seller's agent only",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is acting illegally",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a buyer gives the agent a postdated check, it:",hint:"The agent may accept a postdated check from a buyer as deposit, but he must disclose this to the seller when presenting the offer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"may not be accepted by the agent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must be cashed immediately.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must be delivered to the seller within one day.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may be retained but must be disclosed to the seller.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A licensee who misrepresents property to the buyer while acting as an agent of the seller, is subject to:",hint:"Licensees who make misrepresentations are subject to discipline, civil lawsuits, and/or criminal penalties.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"discipline.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"civil lawsuits.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"criminal penalties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An agent who pays part of the commission to the buyer:",hint:"An agent may pay part of the commission to the buyer if he informs the seller.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"must inform the seller.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"is subject to criminal prosecution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is subject to discipline by the Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is subject to a civil lawsuit by the seller, even if he disclosed everything to the seller.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Whenever a licensee negotiates a loan she must deliver the mortgage loan disclosure statement:",hint:"The mortgage loan disclosure statement is given when signed by the borrower.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"within 3 days of receipt of the loan application.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"within 3 days of time borrower signs it.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"when the statement is signed by the borrower.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The fiduciary relationship between an agent and the principal is comparable to the relationship between:",hint:"The trustee is the agent for the beneficiary in a trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trustor and beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mortgagor and mortgagee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor and trustee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee and beneficiary.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'When a seller sells his home "as is," which of the following is true?',hint:'Even though a seller sells "as is," the seller must still give the buyer a real estate transfer disclosure statement.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The seller must still give the buyer a real estate transfer disclosure statement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The sales agreement should warn that the buyer should beware.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"As is" means that nothing is warranted by the seller.',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller is relieved from the legal obligation to give the buyer a real estate transfer disclosure statement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"California Real Estate Law imposes upon a real estate agent the highest obligation of undivided interest and loyalty to his principal. This relationship is comparable to that of a:",hint:"A fiduciary relationship exists between the agent and his principal. The trustee is the agent and the beneficiary is the principal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"lessee to the lessor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee to the beneficiary.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"vendor to the purchaser.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"salesman to his or her broker.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you are employed by an owner of a 20-unit apartment house, in which you reside, to manage all 20 units. You would be known as:",hint:"A person that manages an apartment house and lives in one of the apartments is considered a resident property manager.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a property manager.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a resident property manager.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a real estate agent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an independent contractor.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker Jones secured an exclusive agency listing in writing from the Johnson Co. on a commercial building that had been vacant for some months. The listing broker entered into a verbal agreement to share his commission with a cooperating broker. The cooperating broker procured a buyer, but broker Jones refused to split the commission. The cooperating broker:",hint:"The Statute of Frauds does not require an agreement between brokers to split a commission to be in writing to be enforceable. If the cooperating broker can prove his case, he can recover his share in court.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"may recover his share in court.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"may not recover his share in court because this was only a verbal agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"should ask the Real Estate Commissioner to arbitrate the dispute.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"should go to the Labor Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Seller had been showing homes to a young, newly married couple for quite some time and finally found one which they wanted to buy. But even with the best loan available, they did not have enough cash for the down payment. They felt that they could raise the additional money they needed by borrowing against their automobile and other sundry personal property. Under these circumstances, the broker should:",hint:"The broker has certain obligations to the buyers but she must be careful not to give legal advise of this importance. To say nothing might imply consent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"advise against it.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tell them it is their decision to make, but point out the pitfalls of this kind of financing.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"advise them to go ahead because real estate always appreciates in value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tell them nothing and let them make their own decision.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Adams made a deposit on the purchase of a property. During the escrow the seller learned of a highway rerouting which would greatly enhance the value of her property. She instructed the broker to return the deposit to the buyer. Ms. Adams refused to accept the deposit. Her most unlikely course of action would now be:",hint:"Choices (a) , (b), or (c) could give Ms. Adams some degree of remedy. To rescind unilaterally (grudgingly give in) would gain her nothing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"to institute a civil action for specific performance against the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to institute a civil action for dollar damages.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to accept a settlement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a unilateral rescission.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'If you are asked to figure the net worth of a business, you would treat an "account payable" as:',hint:'The key word in this question is "payable." Hence, something that is to be paid; therefore, since it is to be paid it is classified as a liability.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"none of the following",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an asset.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a liability.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a credit.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A false statement of fact is considered to be:",hint:"Misrepresentation is making a false statement or concealing a material fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"menace.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"misrepresentation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"false promise.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"duress.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not required of a licensee under the current agency disclosure law?",hint:"The three steps required under the agency disclosure law are: disclose, elect, and confirm.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Disclosure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Election",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Confirmation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Representation",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A broker acting as agent for a principal has as much authority as:",hint:"An agent has as much authority as his principal actually or ostensibly confers upon him.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"other parties believe the agent to possess.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the agent chooses to accept.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the principal actually or ostensibly confers upon him.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"he chooses to accept as limited by the Statute of Limitations.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The usual listing contract authorizes a broker to:",hint:"A listing is an employment contract which usually authorizes the broker to find a purchaser and accept a deposit as the seller's agent. Broker is not authorized to do the acts described in the other choices.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"find a purchaser and bind the seller to a contract to sell.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"find a purchaser and accept a deposit with an offer to purchase.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"guarantee prospective purchasers that the home is defect free.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"convey the real property upon the receipt of a perfect offer.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A buyer and seller initial the liquidated damages clause in a deposit receipt and then the buyer defaults. The deposit is:",hint:"The standard deposit receipt provides that if buyer defaults, seller and agent shall split whatever seller actually recovers from the buyer, but never to exceed the agreed upon commission. Since buyer initialed liquidated damages, seller should recover the deposit and split it with the agent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"given to the seller when escrow opens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"limited to 3% of the selling price.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"divided equally between the seller and the listing agent.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"used to pay any costs incurred and then returned to the buyer.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"JoAnn, a licensed real estate broker, decides to stop selling real estate and start brokering real estate loans. What kind of a license does she need?",hint:'A "mortgage broker" is a licensed real estate broker who brokers loans. No other license is required.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A mortgage broker's license",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A real property securities dealer's license",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A lender's license",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No license other than the real estate broker's license she already has",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Julia owns an acre of ground with five rental houses on it. She decides to sell them to the tenants. She needs:",hint:"She does not need a real estate license to sell her own property but she does need a public report because she would be subdividing into 5 or more parcels.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a real estate license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a public report.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"both (a) and (b).",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neither (a) nor (b).",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker Bob collected rents from an apartment house under agreement with the owner. He had been collecting rents on the 1st of each month for several months and as of July 1, he had collected all but one. On July 2 the owner died. On July 3 the broker went to collect the last rental but the tenant refused to give the rent to the broker on the grounds that the owner had died and, therefore, the agency between broker and the owner was terminated. Which of the following is correct?",hint:"Agency terminates upon death of either party.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The tenant is correct",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The broker has the right to collect rents until an executor has been appointed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The death of the owner did not terminate the agreement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Under the law of agency, the broker has the right to continue collecting rents but he must place all monies received in a neutral trust account until the court appoints someone else to collect the rents",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker Sam had an exclusive listing on a residence which he sold. After buyer took possession of the premises, he discovered a leak in the roof. Broker Sam had told the buyer at the time of writing up the deposit receipt that the roof was in excellent shape and did not mention the leak. The buyer filed an action against the seller and broker and at the trial it was learned that the seller had told Sam that the roof leaked. Who is liable to the buyer for the leafy roof?",hint:"Broker is liable because he owes a duty to the buyer to disclose all pertinent facts in regard to the property and not to make any false statements. The seller is also liable as the agent's principal is liable for his agent's acts done within the scope of his authority.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Broker only",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Seller only",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both broker and seller",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Neither the broker nor the seller because caveat emptor applies",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Fiduciary applies to the relationships between people in many different positions. It does not apply to which of the following?",hint:"Fiduciary is an agency relationship. Trustor to beneficiary is borrower to lender.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trustor to beneficiary",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Attorney-in-fact to principal",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Attorney to client",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Agent to seller",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A national organization of black and other minority real estate brokers is known as:",hint:"The oldest and largest of the minority trade associations serving the nation's housing industry is the National Association of Real Estate Brokers.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"National Association of Real Estate Boards.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"National Association of Real Estate Brokers.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"National Institute of Real Estate Brokers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When may a real estate broker, acting as agent for the seller, refuse to submit a buyer's offer?",hint:"A broker must present all offers unless they are frivolous or unless seller has expressly instructed broker to submit no further offers.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"When the owner has already accepted an offer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When the owner has already accepted a better offer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When the owner has given broker express instructions not to submit any further offers",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Never, all offers must be presented",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Broker Smith operates a small business in a small room in his home. The room has its own entrance with just a sign over the door reading "Smith Realtor." He has no salesman working for him except a 17-year-old student he has in training for the business and to whom he pays $5.00 for each listing the student brings in. Broker Smith is not a member of a real estate board. Since he lives outside of town he holds all deposits received until he goes to town, about once a week. From the information given, broker Smith is in violation of the Real Estate Law in all of the following, except:',hint:"He is definitely in violation of the Real Estate Law in answers (a), (b), and (d).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"paying compensation to an unlicensed person.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'using the term "Realtor."',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"location of his office.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"commingling.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Rick, a real estate salesperson, worked for Pier Realty. During the course of his business, a seller offered to pay him a discounted commission with the suggestion that he not tell his broker, and thus net the entire amount himself. Is this a violation of the Real Estate Law? Why or why not?",hint:"Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"No, because Rick is an independent contractor and can make his own decisions about commissions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No, because Rick has an agreement with his broker about accepting discounted commissions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Yes, because commissions may not be discounted",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Yes, because all commissions earned by Rick, discounted or not, must be paid to his broker, who then pays Rick according to their commission split agreement",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The penalty for failing to identify a definite termination date in a listing is:",hint:"If an agent does not comply with several obligations including specifying a definite termination date, the punishment may be suspension or revocation of the real estate license.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"suspension or revocation of the agent's real estate license.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"forfeiture of commission by the agent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"loss of the listing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"revocation of the brokerage license.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Margaret, a broker, earned a commission on the sale of one of her listings. At the closing, the seller refused to pay the commission. What remedy is available to Margaret?",hint:"One of the jobs not assigned to the Commissioner is settling commission disputes. That issue falls under the power of a court of law, and must be handled through an attorney if the parties involved cannot settle the matter agreeably.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"She can hold up the closing of escrow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"She can file a complaint with the Real Estate Commissioner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"She can file a lis pendens on the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"She can sue the seller in civil court",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When the broker balances his trust account with the bank statement, this is called:",hint:'The definition of reconciliation is "the balancing of the trust accounts to the bank account."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"balancing the books.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reconciliation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"account balancing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"beneficiary statement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not essential to the creation of an agency relationship?",hint:"Agency does not require consideration. A broker could act as an agent without getting paid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Consent of the principal",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Competency of the principal",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A fiduciary relationship",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Agreement to pay consideration",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When a real estate agent acts exclusively as a buyer's agent, he can do all of the following except:",hint:"When the licensee is the exclusive agent of the buyer, he may not be the exclusive agent for the seller.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"present offers directly to the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"present offers to the seller and seller's agent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"withhold confidential information about the buyer from the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"act as an exclusive agent of the seller.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What listing requires an owner to pay a commission, even though she sells the property herself?",hint:"The broker gets the commission no matter who sells the property, if it sells during the term of the exclusive right to sell listing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Exclusive right to sell listing",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Exclusive agency listing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Open listing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Net listing",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Daniels made a written offer to purchase a home through Broker Starr. However, Daniels died in a car accident before Broker Starr could notify him of an unqualified, signed acceptance by the seller. Which of the following statements is most correct?",hint:"Death of the offeror constitutes a revocation of the offer. Legally, if the acceptance had been communicated to buyer before the accident, the contract would have been binding on his estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The death of Daniels constituted a revocation of the offer",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The acceptance does not have to be communicated to the buyer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Notification of acceptance to the executor would bind the Daniels estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The contract would not be binding because the deed had not been delivered into escrow",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An individual has been appointed by a life insurance company to solicit loans on real property which will be secured by first trust deeds on the properties. He will receive a commission for each such loan consummated. Under these circumstances, it will be required that he:",hint:"A broker's activity is soliciting loans and requires only a broker's license.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"possess an active real estate broker's license.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"secure a real property securities dealer endorsement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"obtain a surety bond in the amount of $5,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker is preparing a deposit receipt. Which of the following can be disregarded for the moment and be decided during the escrow period?",hint:"Answers (a), (c), and (d) must be decided before escrow.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Manner of payment of assessment bonds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Manner of taking title",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Proof of title insurance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Financing arrangements",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If you were asked to prepare newspaper ads for a home in a nice quiet area, $500,000 price range, you would appeal to:",hint:"Opinion answer of the state exam. We agree with their answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"prestige.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"higher income families.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pride of ownership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A salesman sold a home in California. His commission would be paid by the:",hint:"Under California Real Estate Law, a salesman's commission can only be paid by his employing broker.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"real estate broker.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"escrow company involved.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A real estate broker keeps records of all money transactions handled by him in a book usually called:",hint:"Process of elimination - all of the answers except the “trust ledger” refer to lending, closing, or banking procedures. The monetary transactions of a real estate broker are usually trust funds and should be recorded in a “trust” ledger.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an off-set statement book.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a trust ledger.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"closing statement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"profit and loss statement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An agency relationship, such as in a listing, may be terminated by all of the following methods except:",hint:"When the agent has an interest in the subject matter of the agency; for example the broker is a co-owner of the property, the agency cannot be revoked by the principal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"resignation of the agency by the real estate broker.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mutual termination by agreement of both the agent and the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"destruction of the property with which the agency is concerned.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"revocation by the principal if the agent has an interest in the subject matter of the agency.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is closest to the same relationship as between a broker and seller:",hint:"A broker is the agent and the seller is the principal he works for. A trustee is also an agent who works for the beneficiary who is the principal. Broker--salesman is employer--employee relationship. Mortgagor and mortgagee is borrower--lender relationship. Vendor--vendee is seller--buyer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trustee and beneficiary.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"broker and salesman.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mortgagor and mortgagee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"vendor and vendee.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Section 10131.1 of the Real Estate Law defines "in the business" as "the acquisition for resale to the public, and not as an investment, of more than 7 real property sales contracts or promissory notes secured by liens on real property during a calendar year. " This means:',hint:"The key word is for resale, not investment purposes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a person who purchases 8 notes secured by trust deeds for investment purposes must have a license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a person who buys even one note in a year for resale to the public must have a license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the acquisition for resale of 8 land contracts or 8 notes secured by trust deeds in one calendar year requires a license.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above is correct",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'"A" is a real estate broker. "B" is a real property securities dealer. Which of the following is a correct statement?',hint:'"B" may sell raw land. "A" cannot do everything "B" can do, but "B" can do everything "A" can do.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:'"B" may not sell raw land acting as an agent for the owner of the land',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"A" may not sell trust deeds to the public, nor solicit loans secured by real property',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"A" can do everything "B"can do',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"B" can do everything "A" can do',isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The real estate listing is classified as an employment contract under whose terms the owner of the property appoints and authorizes a real estate broker to act as his agent. Which of the following statements is correct?",hint:"When the listing is an open listing, the agent who is the procuring cause, or the one who brings the buyer to make the offer, is the one who earns the commission. In an exclusive agency listing, the owner maintains the right to sell the property himself. The owner is not liable for a suit for specific performance until he has entered into the purchase contract with the buyer. Death terminates both an Exclusive Agency and Exclusive Right to Sell Listing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An owner is liable for a commission if he sells his property himself during the term of an Exclusive Agency Listing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The owner is liable for a suit for specific performance if he refuses a buyer's offer that meets the exact terms of an Exclusive Right to Sell Listing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'A broker has an enforceable right to a commission in an open listing if he is the "procuring cause" even if the owner sells through another broker',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Death terminates an Exclusive Agency Listing, but not an Exclusive Right to Sell Listing",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume an offer has been accepted and the acceptance has been communicated to the buyer. The buyer then changed his mind and decided not to purchase the property. Which of the following is true?",hint:"If the buyer backs out of this purchase contract, the seller is entitled to sue for liquidated damages when the parties agreed to this in the contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The broker could sue the buyer for the commission",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The broker could not sue the buyer for a commission but could bring suit to require performance of the contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller could sue for liquidated damages if the parties agreed to liquidated damages in the contract",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above are correct statements",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When an agent receives two offers on his principal's property at the same time, and one is better for the agent, he should submit:",hint:"Submit all offers, a demand of agency.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"both offers and let the owner decide.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the best offer first.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the deal which he thinks is best for his principal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the deal which would pay the most commission.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A fiduciary relationship may be terminated by:",hint:"Answers (b), (c), and (d) all terminate a fiduciary relationship.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"all of the following",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"revocation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"death.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"agreement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An Exclusive Authorization and Right to Sell Listing just entered into can be described as:",hint:"The exclusive right to sell listing is a bilateral contract. An executory contract is one which has not been completely performed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a cash agreement to purchase properties that are bilateral.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a bilateral executory contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a land contract whereby licensee may obtain commissions from both the buyer and seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who has primary responsibility for property inspections?",hint:"The seller is primarily responsible for inspecting the property because he is most familiar with anything needing to be disclosed; he is legally responsible to disclose to his listing broker and all others anything that would affect the value of the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The buyer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The escrow agent",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a real estate agent acts as a dual agent for both the buyer and seller in a 1031 exchange, and does not disclose his dual agency to both parties, he may:",hint:"Agents must obtain the knowledge and consent of both parties to act as dual agent. Failure to do so may result in any or all of the choices in (a), (b), and (c).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"provide grounds for either party to rescind the purchase agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be prevented from receiving any commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be disciplined by the Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"On April 2, a buyer gave a broker a personal check as a deposit to accompany an offer. The buyer told the broker to hold the check uncashed until after April 15. What should the broker do?",hint:"The broker must present the offer and disclose the hold on the check, because it is a material fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The broker cannot legally accept the check",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The broker should present the offer and hope the seller does not ask about the check",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The broker should present the offer to the seller, but must tell the seller about buyer's instruction to hold the check until after April 15",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The broker should immediately deposit the check in his trust account",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The most essential element to create an enforceable broker-principal relationship is a:",hint:"A written employment contract is the most essential element. The relationship may be unenforceable without it.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"written authorization for agent to accept a deposit.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"written offer to buy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"written employment contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"written agreement for commission.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker has an option on a property which is also listed with him. He finds a buyer who will pay more than the listed price, so broker buys the property himself and in turn sells it to the buyer for a profit. This is called:",hint:"Under a listing, he is an agent and cannot personally benefit. To do so is a secret profit and in violation of the real estate law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"collusion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"secret profit.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"divided agency.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commingling.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which one of the following clauses is always in a deposit receipt?",hint:"The other clauses may be in a deposit receipt, but there is always an executory clause--which is a promise to be performed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Alienation clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subordination clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subrogation clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Executory clause",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An owner gave an open listing to broker Smith and broker Brown, who have shown the property to Mr. White. Broker Smith gets an offer from Mr. White and signed acceptance. Which of the following is correct?",hint:"Under an open listing, the broker who presents the first offer which is accepted by the owner is entitled to the commission.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The commission will be split between Smith and Brown",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The commission will be paid to Smith",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"No commission paid on an open listing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The commission will be paid to Brown",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'A listing contract has the statement, "The undersigned broker agrees to use diligence in procuring a buyer." This is used for what following reason?',hint:"Mutual exchange of promises: Bilateral contract. Promise for an act: Unilateral.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Means nothing and is not required",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"To make it a bilateral contract",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"To make it a unilateral contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'A new contract between the seller of real property and a licensee whereby the seller agrees to pay the licensee a commission if he produces a "ready, willing, and able" buyer and the licensee agrees to use due diligence in procuring a buyer, is called:',hint:"A bilateral contract is a contract between two parties with each promising to act (a promise for a promise). An executory contract is a contract yet to be performed. This type of contract is a bilateral executory contract. An executed contract is one that has been completed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"unilateral executory contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"bilateral executory contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"unilateral executed contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"bilateral executed contract.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you are in need of money and ask broker John Jones to negotiate a second trust deed loan for you. Which of the following will be the broker's responsibility?",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are not the broker's responsibility according to the Real Estate Law. However, answer (d) is the broker's responsibility.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Make sure that the trust deed has the proper amount of revenue stamps on it",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Have the broker's loan statement signed by all three parties",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Make sure that the property is appraised to justify the loan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"See to it that the trust deed is recorded and names the lender as the beneficiary",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would not be essential in order to create an agency relationship?",hint:"Definition of what is Agency.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A fiduciary relationship",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The agreement of the party to the agency",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An agreement to pay commission",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A competent principal",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Causing panic selling by telling people that values in a neighborhood will decline because of a specific event is known as:",hint:"Blockbusting is persuading an owner to sell or rent housing by saying that people of a particular race, religion, etc., are moving into the neighborhood.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"steering.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"blockbusting.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"redlining.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"undervaluing.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'When a licensee places and ad in the newspaper without the broker\'s name that reads in total: "3 bdrm, 2 bath, den & spa, giant lot, $160,000 800-555-1212". This is :',hint:'A "blind ad" is an ad that does not identify the broker.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a violation of the Truth in Lending Law.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"misleading advertising.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"false advertising.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a blind ad.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In a timeshare seminar that was advertised to 100,000 people, the timeshare people did not reveal the minimum attendance required for the prize giveaways. Is this a violation of the real estate law?",hint:"Ads must disclose if attendance at a sales presentation is required.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"No, the real estate law does not regulate advertising for time-shares",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Yes, anyone giving away prizes must disclose in advance the minimum attendance required for the giveaways",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"No, the law specifically allows the seller of the timeshare to surprise the consumer by requiring attendance at a presentation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Yes, unless the prize is in excess of $10,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Why do many brokers open client trust fund accounts?",hint:"A broker must keep a client's money separate from the broker's money. A trust account helps accomplish this goal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"To commingle funds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"To avoid regulation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"To separate the client's money from broker's money",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"To get a free credit card",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Trust fund money can be withdrawn by whom?",hint:"Any employee of the broker may make withdrawals from the client trust account, if authorized to do so by the broker.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Any person employed by the broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An unlicensed person",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A corporate director",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Any authorized employee of the broker",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A salesperson is using strong efforts to obtain listings in a nonintegrated community. He finds success by insinuation that if minorities move in, the value of the property will decrease. His activities may be best described as:",hint:'This would be both "panic peddling" and "blockbusting."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"steering.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"panic peddling.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"blockbusting.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both b and c",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"You are a California real estate broker. A prospect is referred to you by an out-of-state broker and a sale is consummated by you. You want to split your commission with the cooperating broker. Under the California Real Estate Law:",hint:"Business and professions Code Sections 10137 and 10138 specify that a broker may not pay a commission to an unlicensed person, except to a broker of another state.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"you may pay a commission to a broker of another state.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"you cannot divide a commission with a broker of another state.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"you can pay a commission to a broker of another state only if he or she is also licensed in California.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"For a real estate broker to be entitled to a commission if the property sells after the expiration of the listing, the broker should place into the listing agreement a:",hint:"A “carryover” clause (often referred to as a safety clause) may be contained in a listing. It provides that a broker is still entitled to a commission for a set period of time after the listing has expired if the property is sold to a prospect of the broker introduced to the property during the period of the listing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"liquidated damages clause.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"due diligence clause.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"safety clause.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is correct regarding trust fund bank accounts?",hint:"A maximum, not a minimum of $200 of the broker's own money can remain in the account (to cover bank service fees, etc.).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The broker may have a minimum of $100 of his or her own money in the trust account",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The broker may have a maximum of $200 of his or her own money in the trust account",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The broker may have a maximum of $500 of his or her own money in the trust account",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"There is no limit on the amount of the broker's own money in the trust account",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When acting as an agent, a real estate licensee is liable to third parties for:",hint:"A tort is any wrongful act (not involving a breach of contract) for which a civil action is available to the person who is wronged.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"only written contracts made in the name of his or her principal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"actions of properly appointed subagents.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"his or her own torts.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"torts committed by his or her principal in the transaction.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Code of Ethics in the field of real estate was formulated and adopted by the:",hint:"Members of the National Association of REALTORS® (NAR) subscribe to a very strict code of ethics, or a written system of standards of ethical conduct(NAR has published a booklet called Interpretation of the Code of Ethics, applying the code to practical situations).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"National Association of Real Estate Brokers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"National Association of Realtors.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Real Estate Board.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The "Real Estate Law" of California is distinguished from real property law, contract law, or other legal aspects of real estate ownership. Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning California Real Estate Law?',hint:"The Real Estate Law, which is part of the Business and Professions Code, is enforced by the Real Estate Commissioner.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It is contained in the Code of Civil Procedure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'The "Real Estate Law" of California is created by the state only',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real estate law is created by the state and local government",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The Real Estate Commissioner has the power to create, amend, or repeal real estate laws when in the interest of the public welfare",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"If a homeowner is seeking to hire someone for home improvements, what is the maximum dollar amount that can be earned without having a contractor's license?",hint:"Contractor's State License Board states that amounts over $500 must have a contractor's license.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Less than $500",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Less than $600",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$400",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Sally, a real estate agent, is advertising her listings on the World Wide Web. What must be included in her web page?",hint:"The Broker's name must be included in all advertising per Article 9, Section 2770 of the Regulations of the Real Estate Commissioner.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Listing price of the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Years of service as a Real Estate Agent",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Broker's name",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"How long property has been for sale",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'What is considered "frequent flooding?"',hint:"Frequent is defined as more than once in 10 years in the flood hazard report that details the frequency of flooding in the area.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Once in 3 years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Twice in 3 years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Twice in 10 years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Once in 10 years",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Target Housing refers to:",hint:"Target housing refers to residential housing that was built before 1978. A special disclosure form is required advising of the possible presence of lead based paint. An exception to this rule is housing designated for the elderly or handicapped, unless children reside there also.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"blockbusting.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"single family home built in 1975.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"home for the elderly built in 1970.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"home for handicapped built in 1980.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Broker John has been trying to sell a certain property for months without success. He knows there is some structural damage and it is overpriced by 10%. He runs an ad that reads: "Charming two-bedroom. You won\'t believe the price! Move in right away!" Is there a violation of truth in advertising laws?',hint:'Defects must be disclosed as soon as practicable and definitely by the time an offer is received by a prospective buyer. "Move in right away!" is misleading to a prospective purchaser.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Yes, because he knowingly listed an overpriced property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Yes, because he failed to mention the defects",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both A & B",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Nothing, the ad is fine",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An ad states that non-English speaking loan applicants must pay an additional 1% fee. This is:",hint:"This would constitute an act of discrimination.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"legal, if the 1% is used for the cost of translation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a violation of Regulation Z.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is unethical.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a violation of the Holden Act.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Joe Broker runs an ad that states he will give you a VCR valued at $500, if you bring in this ad and buy a home from him. This is:",hint:"Does not violate any of the Business and Professions Code laws pertaining to real estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"illegal to offer gifts valued over $50.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"legal, as long as it applies to everyone.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Illegal, per Business and Professions Code Section 10233.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Legal per Article 5.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is true of a buyer's agent?",hint:"An executed sale would make the buyer's agent now the procuring cause and now will be referred to as the selling agent. Commission is distributed through listing agreement with seller.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"They are illegal in California",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"They are not entitled to a commission",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"They do not form an agency relationship",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Compensation may not necessarily come from the buyer",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A buyer asks an agent to hold a deposit check for 30 days. The agent should:",hint:"It is up to the agent to advise the seller on all matters, but it is up to the seller to make the decision if a 30 day hold is acceptable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"refuse.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"advise buyer check must be deposited by the next day.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accept the check and advise the seller that the buyer requests the hold.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"accept and allow the seller to decide what to do.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A prospective DRE licensee was found to be delinquent on child support payments, the DRE will most likely:",hint:"The licensee has 150 days to make the required payments. Upon compliance a 4-year license will be issued.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"do nothing and process license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"notify the district attorney and not process license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"issue a temporary license.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"contact the police.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A husband and wife have been searching for a new home. One day when the husband was at work, his wife learns that a new listing has appeared on the MLS. Her agent calls her and urges her to come see it ASAP. She goes to view the property, without her husband, loves the house but cannot reach her husband at work to sign an offer on the home. If the seller accepts the offer, the contract is:",hint:"A voidable contract is a valid contract unless or until voided. What this means is that a wronged party has the right or election to void the contract or let it stand as an enforceable agreement against the wrong-doer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"invalid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is NOT necessary for a valid contract?",hint:"Recordation is not a necessity to have a valid contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Acceptance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Consideration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Recordation",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Legal Purpose",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Aliquist Priolo Special Studies Zone Act is required by law to produce geological reports for project approval within:",hint:"Aliquist Priolo Special Studies Zone Act is a law requiring geological reports for project approval within 1/4 mile of earthquake faults.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1/4 mile of faults.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1 mile of faults.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/3 mile of faults.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2 miles of faults.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When did the Transfer Disclosure Statement law take effect?",hint:"The TDS law took effect in January, 1987.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"January 1978",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"January 1977",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"January 1987",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"January 1980",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Constructive eviction may allow for a tenant to vacate the premises before the expiration of a lease term. Which would be an example of constructive eviction?",hint:"All of the above are examples of constructive eviction.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Landlord has shown property to prospective tenant and is negotiating terms",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Property cannot be used for original purpose due to unnecessary and considerable changes made by landlord",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Landlord fails to make necessary repairs",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The Washington Real Estate Commission consists of how many members?",hint:"The WREC consists of six members, appointed for a term of six years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"8",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The members of the WREC are appointed for terms of _____ years.",hint:"The members of the WREC are appointed for terms of six years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Any person who performs an act of real estate brokerage for a fee or commission for another person is required to have a real estate license. An “act of real estate brokerage” includes which of the following?",hint:"An “act of real estate brokerage” includes buying and selling or offering to buy or sell real estate; and renting, leasing, or negotiating the lease of real estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Negotiating the lease of real estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Leasing real estate for less than one year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Selling or buying real estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Performing acts of real estate brokerage without a real estate license is considered a:",hint:"Performing an act of real estate brokerage without a real estate license is considered a Class 1 misdemeanor. A third or subsequent violation within one year is a Class 6 felony.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Class 1 felony.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Class 2 misdemeanor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Class 1 misdemeanor.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Class 6 felony.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In order to take the real estate exam, the applicant must do all the following except:",hint:"To take the real estate licensing exam, the applicant must apply with the proper form and pay the license exam fee; provide proof of honesty, truthfulness, and good reputation; as well as identity, which may include fingerprints. However, they do not need to provide a blood sample for DNA testing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"provide proof of identity, which may include fingerprints",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"provide proof of honesty, truthfulness, and good reputation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"provide a blood sample for DNA testing",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"apply on the prescribed form and pay the license exam fee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Trust account and transaction records must be maintained for how long?",hint:"Records must be maintained for at least three years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Two years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Three years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Five years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Indefinitely",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker Tim has established a single agent relationship with a seller, Mary. Tim finds a buyer for Mary's property. The buyer wishes to establish a single agent relationship with Broker Tim. Can Broker Tim meet the buyer's request?",hint:"A single agent is a broker who represents either the buyer or the seller, but not both, as a fiduciary in the same transaction.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"No, a broker may only have a single agent relationship with a buyer or a seller, but not both in a single residential real estate transaction",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Yes, if Broker Tim provides both buyer and seller with the proper disclosure forms and obtains both parties' signatures on the document",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Yes, a broker may have a single agent relationship with the buyer and/or the seller in a single residential real estate transaction",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No, a broker may only have a single agent relationship with a seller",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Commingling refers to which of the following?",hint:"Commingling is the mixing of personal funds with those belonging to other people",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The common interest two or more people have in a single piece of property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The mixing of personal funds with those belonging to other people",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The interaction between a buyer or seller and his or her agent",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The depositing of trust funds into an appropriate financial institution",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Disciplinary actions are warranted against a licensee if that licensee has participated in blind advertising. Blind advertising does not include which of the following?",hint:"Advertising that does not include the broker's name as licensed is considered blind advertising and warrants disciplinary action.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The broker's name as licensed",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The address of the advertised property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The property's listing price",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All known material facts concerning the property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A real estate salesperson may accept compensation from which of the following?",hint:"A salesperson may accept compensation only from his or her employing broker.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The salesperson's employing broker only",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Any licensed broker in Texas",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Any licensed broker in any state",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller affiliated with the salesperson only",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Before accepting a postdated check as an earnest money deposit, the broker should do which of the following?",hint:"A broker should obtain the seller's approval before accepting a postdated check as an earnest money deposit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Obtain the seller's approval",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Verify the funds are in the buyer's account",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Notify the seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A postdated check is not acceptable as an earnest money deposit",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Salesperson Jane wants to place an ad in the phone directory under Real Estate that states: “Jane Smith, Real Estate Salesperson specializing in commercial properties.” Jane must also include which of the following in her ad?",hint:"All advertising must include the name of the salesperson's employing broker",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The expiration date of her license",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Her street address",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The name of her employing broker",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Her real estate license number",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When advertising listed properties, real estate licensees:",hint:"It is a violation of license law to advertise listed properties without including the broker's name.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"must identify the owner of the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may simply give a telephone number to call for more information",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may state the licensee's box number or street address",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must indicate that the ads were placed in the name of a licensed real estate broker",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When advertising listed properties, real estate licensees:",hint:"It is a violation of license law to advertise listed properties without including the broker's name.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"must identify the owner of the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may simply give a telephone number to call for more information",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may state the licensee's box number or street address",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must indicate that the ads were placed in the name of a licensed real estate broker",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"If an agent fails to deposit money received from the buyer as earnest money into an escrow account in a reasonable amount of time, which of the following may occur?",hint:"Failing to deposit a buyer's funds into a separate escrow account within a reasonable amount of time is grounds for license suspension or revocation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Suspension or revocation of the agent's license",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Financial penalties",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Imprisonment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A single act of brokerage for compensation without a license is considered:",hint:"A single act of brokerage for compensation without a license is considered a misdemeanor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a misdemeanor.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a felony.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"punishable by imprisonment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both b and c.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"It is illegal for a real estate broker to refuse to hire any of the following?",hint:"It is illegal for an employer to refuse to hire someone based on their race, color, religion, sex, national origin, age, handicap, or marital status.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Minority sales associates",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Male brokers",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A secretary, based on her religion",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Multi-family housing constructed after ______ must be designed and constructed with wheelchair-accessible entrances and other modifications to accommodate disabled tenants.",hint:"Multi-family housing that was constructed after March 13, 1991 must be designed and constructed with wheelchair-accessible entrances and other modifications to accommodate disabled tenants.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1974",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1980",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1991",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1993",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are violations of license law and are illegal except:",hint:"A licensee may place a “For Sale” sign in front of a listed property as long as he or she has obtained permission from the seller.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"receiving a commission without the knowledge and consent of the licensee's client.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"failing to disclose known latent structural defects to a prospective buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"advising a seller to reject an offer based on the prospective buyer's race.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"placing a “For Sale” sign in front of a listed property with the seller's permission.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Broker Todd procures a ready, willing, and able buyer for his client, the seller. The seller accepts the buyer's offer in writing, but then decides not to sell his house after all and withdraws his acceptance before the buyer is told of his initial acceptance. Which of the following is true of Broker Todd?",hint:"A licensee's duty is to procure a ready, willing, and able buyer for a client. If the broker has fulfilled this duty, regardless of whether the transaction closes, he or she may be entitled to a commission.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"He may retain the earnest money deposit in lieu of the commission he would have earned.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"He may sue the buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"He has no right to his commission because the transaction was never closed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"He may be entitled to a commission.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A broker must retain a copy of the closing statement for how long?",hint:"A broker must retain a copy of the closing statement for at least three years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Two years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Three years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Five years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Ten years",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume a sales contract is signed on August 21, the closing takes place on September 16, the security deed is recorded on September 24, and the buyer's first payment is due on November 1. When is the earliest time the broker may receive his or her commission check?",hint:"Commission checks are usually received at the closing, therefore September 16 is the earliest the broker may receive his or her commission check.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"August 21",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"September 16",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"September 24",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"November 1",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is the minimum age requirement to apply for a salesperson license?",hint:"An applicant for a salesperson license must be at least 18 years old.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"18 years of age",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"20 years of age",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"21 years of age",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25 years of age",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A salesperson may receive compensation from:",hint:"A salesperson may receive compensation only from his or her employing broker or owner-developer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the lender.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"his or her employing broker or owner-developer.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the buyer.",isCorrect:!1}]}}]},{category:"Ownership",id:3,list:[{questionText:"Ward owned a lot and had an easement across Lane's property. Ward sold the property to Stevens, but the easement which was appurtenant to Ward's property was not mentioned in the deed. The easement:",hint:"Whether mentioned in the deed or not, the easement automatically passes to Stevens.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"was held by Ward.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"does not run with the land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"passed to Stevens.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"reverts to Lane.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In a leasehold estate, the possessory interest in the real property is held by the:",hint:"The lessee (tenant) has the right of possession.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"lessor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lessee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"grantee.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A less-than-freehold estate would be:",hint:"An estate for years is a lease (one type of less-than-freehold estate). The others are freehold estates.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an estate in remainder.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a life estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate for years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The receipt for a Subdivision Final Public Report must be kept on file by the subdivider or his agent for a minimum of:",hint:"A subdivider must keep a copy of the final public report for three years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"one year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"three years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"four years.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a zoning law permits the use of a piece of property that is restricted in use and construction by the deed, which of the following prevails?",hint:"Deed restrictions will take precedence over zoning laws if the deed restriction is more stringent than the zoning law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Deed restrictions",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The master zoning law",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The variance permit",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The owner's planned use",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a non-riparian owner is given permission by the state to take water from a lake or river, he takes it by:",hint:"Where excess water is available to non-riparian users, the state appropriates the water and permits these users to take the excess.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"percolation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"prescription.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appropriation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"accretion.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not a characteristic of an easement?",hint:"The others are all true concerning an easement. Once granted, an easement can not be revoked.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It is an interest which may be protected against interference by third parties",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is capable of being created by reconveyance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is considered as a non-possessory interest",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is an interest which may be terminated at will by the possessor of the land",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lease beginning March 1, 1993, and terminating June 30, 1993, is:",hint:"A leasehold having a definite termination date is an estate for years, no matter how short the term.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a periodic tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate at will.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate for years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A corporation may take title to real property:",hint:"Since a corporation never dies, it cannot take title where right of survivorship exists as in a joint tenancy.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"as a joint tenant.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in severalty.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"as community property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A condominium may be:",hint:"Condominium ownership may be in: (a) residential, (b) industrial, or (c) commercial buildings on such property, such as an apartment, office, or store.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"residential property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"industrial property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commercial property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The California Real Estate Law defines a planned development as which of the following?",hint:"A planned development containing 5 or more lots is defined as a subdivision. A condominium project containing 2 or more units, a stock cooperative having 2 or more shareholders, and a community apartment project containing 2 or more apartments are other forms of subdivisions.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A condominium projects",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A co-op apartment project",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A subdivision",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A community apartment project",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If Ackerman deeded a ranch to Morlin for the life of Conklin:",hint:"The law allows the duration of a life estate to be based on the life span of a third party (in this case, Conklin). When Conklin dies, the estate held by Morlin will revert to Ackerman.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Morlin holds a life estate and Ackerman an estate in remainder.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Morlin holds a life estate and Ackerman an estate in reversion.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Morlin holds a fee simple estate and Conklin a life estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Conklin holds a life estate and Morlin an estate in reversion.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In order to record a lease, the document must be acknowledged before a proper official by the:",hint:"As a requisite of recording, a document must be acknowledged by the party transferring some right in real property, in this case, the lessor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"public administrator.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"notary public.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lessee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lessor.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lease on real estate is a(n):",hint:"A lease for even one month is an estate for years. A leasehold is a less than freehold estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"estate at sufferance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estate for years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"co-tenancy.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Statute of Frauds requires that all of the following contracts must be a record in writing to be enforceable except a(n):",hint:"An oral agreement to split a commission is enforceable at law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"agreement allowing a broker to sell real estate for compensation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lease agreement of one year to commence one month after date of execution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"agreement to sell land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"agreement between two brokers to split a commission.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following terms is not generally associated with encumbrances?",hint:"A claim is an asserted right, but not an encumbrance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Easement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lien",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lease",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Claim",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following terms is most commonly used in California in reference to liens against real property?",hint:"Statutory liens for taxes and liens such as mortgages, trust deeds, and mechanic's liens are all specific.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Specific",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Gross",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Personal",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Appurtenant",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The maximum length of time for which a valid lease may be written is:",hint:"The maximum lease on urban property is 99 years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"99 years on urban property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"55 years on agricultural property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A sublease is:",hint:"One thing that distinguishes a sublease from an assignment is that the sublease gives up only part of the leasehold.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the same as an assignment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a full interest in a leasehold.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"less than the entire leasehold.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an estate at sufferance.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In a city, compliance to the State Housing Act is enforced by the city:",hint:"The building inspector makes sure that the building complies with local and state building codes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"engineer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"police department.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"planning commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"building inspector.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"All of the following statements concerning condominiums are true except:",hint:"The county tax assessors issue separate tax bills to each unit owner covering his interest. All the other choices are true.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"real property taxes must be billed to the entire project and prorated by the project manager.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the unit ownership can be deeded for indefinite duration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"condominium ownership may be in residential, industrial, or commercial property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'there is non-severability of the "in-common" and "separate interests."',isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The party who is responsible for the enforcement of sanitation and sewage requirements in a subdivision is the:",hint:"It is the health department's duty to approve the adequacy of the sanitation facilities of a new subdivision.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"local building inspector.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"health department.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"local planning commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real Estate Commission.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appurtenance:",hint:"The definition of real property is land, anything used to benefit the land, anything appurtenant to the land, or anything immovable by law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"runs with the land.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"is personal property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is a license to use land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is an encroachment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"On a percentage lease, which of the following would pay the highest percent?",hint:"The lower the gross income, the higher the percentage to be charged.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Garage and parking facility",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Dime store",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Chain store",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Auto agency",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who places the restrictions in a deed to a condominium unit in a new subdivision?",hint:'Deed restrictions are normally placed in the deed by the subdivider-the original grantor. "Project developer" is the term used for the subdivider of a condominium project.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Local planning commission",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Project developers",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Elected governing board",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Unit owners",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Recording a deed:",hint:"Recording does not make a deed valid, but establishes the legal presumption that the deed was delivered. Recording gives constructive notice.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"presumes delivery.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"gives actual notice.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"validates a deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A landowner is advised that a railroad company plans to cross his property with a railroad line. If the landowner refuses, the railroad company can proceed by the use of:",hint:"The law delegates the right to eminent domain to public utility companies.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"police action.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"eminent domain.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"accretion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"partition action.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following indicates the tearing away of land by the action of water?",hint:"Avulsion--tearing away.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Alluvium",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Avulsion",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Accretion",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Accession",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following defines a partition action?",hint:'The term "action" indicates a court proceeding. Partition is the division of an undivided interest in common among the individual owners.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Action of water eroding the soil",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A court proceeding to sever a joint ownership",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A request for building code variance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A court proceeding to dissolve a partnership",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How long must a Structural Termite Report be held on file by the Structural Pest Control Board in Sacramento?",hint:"A termite report is not demanded by law, but if one is issued it must be filed in Sacramento and kept on file for two years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"One year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Two years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Three years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Four years",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A lien may be created by recording:",hint:"A money encumbrance--a lien.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a notice of non-responsibility.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a trust deed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a restriction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ingress and egress are terms used in:",hint:'Access by which to "go in" and "go out" across the property of another.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"appraisal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easements.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"land measurements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"construction.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Consideration is to a contract as endorsement is to a:",hint:"Endorsement is the symbol of consideration for the negotiation of a promissory note.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"promissory note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"land contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"option.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is permitted to use the county recorder's office and records without the presence of a recorder's officer?",hint:"The records of the county recorder's office are open to the public and any party listed in choices (a), (b), or (c) is permitted to inspect the records.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Bank and savings and loan employees",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Members of tax assessor's office",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title company employees",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Any of these",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"As a part of his submittal of documents to the Real Estate Commissioner under the Subdivision Lands Law, the subdivider must complete a form by which he agrees that, in the event he cannot be located via reasonable and diligent efforts, service can be legally effected by filing with the:",hint:"The Subdivided Lands Law is directly administered by the Real Estate Commissioner, who creates a public report disclosing all important marketing and financing facts about the subdivision. A copy goes to the buyer for his/her approval and signature on a receipt indicating the report has been read; the seller (or developer) keeps a copy of this statement for three years; and the public report is valid for five years, with any material changes in the development reported to the Commissioner, who then can issue an amendment to the original report.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"superior court in the county in which the property is located.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"county recorder in the county in which the property is located.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Secretary of State.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An option is different from other contracts, such as conventional or conditional sales contracts. The difference is due to what characteristic of an option?",hint:"Mutuality of obligations would mean that both parties are obligated to perform, which is the case with most contracts. An option does not have mutuality of obligations in that only the optionor is obligated to perform, not the optionee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Irrevocability",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mutuality of obligations of the parties",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Non-mutuality of obligations of the parties",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both (b) and (c) are correct",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A certain easement lies outside of and adjoins the land which it benefits. The land benefited would be the:",hint:"The owner of the easement controls the use of the adjoining land and dominates its use. The property subject to the easement serves the easement holder.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"dominant tenement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"servient tenement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"encumbered fee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"property subject to the easement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is the least enforceable requirement of a subdivision improvement?",hint:"The other choices are common and enforceable. It would be very difficult to enforce a requirement stating one had to spend a certain amount of money in the improvements as one may be able to build just as beautiful and big a house as someone else and for less money.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A minimum dollar value",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A minimum lot size",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A minimum area requirement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A maximum height restriction",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following dimensions would contain the largest area?",hint:"Two miles square = 4 square miles. (a) = 3.6 square miles; (b) = 2 square miles: (d) = 1.9 square miles.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10% of a township",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Two sections",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2 miles square",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"5,280' x 10,000'",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A lease beginning March 1, 1994, and to terminate April 30, 1994, is:",hint:"Any leasehold for a specified term, no matter how short the duration, is an estate for years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a month-to-month tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a periodic tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate for years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Bake, the owner of a duplex, leased one of the units for a two-year term beginning June 6, 1993, and received the rent for the last two months of the lease in advance. This prepaid rent should be:",hint:"Must be reported in the year received.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"declared in her income tax return for 1993.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"declared in her income tax return for 1995.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pro-rated over the term of the lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following statements is true with respect to planning commissions?",hint:"Members of the planning commission should be knowledgeable in the field of real estate and city planning, but this is not a prerequisite for being a member. The members are appointed and it is their job to develop a master plan and advise the city council in this area.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"All members are elected",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Members must have had real estate or subdivision experience",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"They are authorized to give advice to the city council on subdivisions",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Members must be real estate brokers",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In checking trust deed documents in the county recorder's office, you will find that the recorded deed of trust refers to standard clauses contained in a previously recorded trust deed. This previously recorded trust deed is known as a:",hint:'Nearly all deeds of trust used by banks, escrow and title companies are the "short form." This merely recites the trustor\'s name, the trustee, describes the property, and has a place for signature. The terms of the trust deed are not printed in the short form but refer to an original deed of trust recorded in each county, and it is identified as a fictitious deed of trust. This lists all the terms and conditions in detail.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"prima facia deed of trust.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"short form deed of trust.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"master deed of trust.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fictitious deed of trust.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The opposite of erosion is:",hint:"Accretion is the gradual addition to land from natural causes. Erosion is the gradual wearing away.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"appurtenant.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"dereliction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accretion.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"alienation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Land owned two pieces of property and sold one parcel bordering on the road to Ms. Crow, reserving in the deed an easement for ingress and egress to and from the remaining real property for himself. After 5 years of non-use, Land attempted to use the easement, but was prohibited from doing so by Crow. A court would rule in this case that:",hint:"Only an easement acquired by prescription may be lost through non-use.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the easement was forfeited because it was not used for 5 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the easement was still valid because non-use never terminates any type of easement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Ms. Crow could institute a quiet title action on the easement and probably be successful.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the easement was still valid since it had been created by deed.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not a requirement of a valid homestead?",hint:"A single person may file a homestead; being married is not a requirement. The other 3 choices are required.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A statement that the claimant is married",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The name of claimant's spouse, if any",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A statement that the claimant is residing on the property at the time of filing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A description of the property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An owner of a single family residence located in a rural area may lease the home for:",hint:"Agricultural land can only be leased for 51 years. All other land can be leased for 99 years. Rural land would not necessarily be agricultural land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a maximum term of 51 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"99 years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an unlimited period of time.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Real Estate Commissioner's Subdivision Final Public Report expires:",hint:"Matter of law, unless there is a material change.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"one year from the date of the report.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"never, unless a material change occurs.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"five years from the date of the issuance of the report.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"three years from the date of the issuance of the report.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is real property?",hint:"A riparian owner usually owns to the center of the stream.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trade fixture",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"washer/dryer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"emblements",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"running stream",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A less-than-freehold estate is:",hint:"The others are freehold estates.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an interest in joint tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate for years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a life estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The California State Housing Act, which contains minimum code requirements, is found in the:",hint:"The State Housing Law outlines minimum construction and occupancy requirements. Local building inspectors enforce the construction regulations and local health officers enforce the occupancy and sanitation regulations (Health and Safety Code Section 17910, et seq.).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"State Contractor's Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Uniform Commercial Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Health and Safety Code.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Fair Housing Act.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"With permissive use, an easement by prescription can be created within:",hint:"Must be hostile use, not permissive use.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The word that means the opposite of avulsion is:",hint:"Accretion is the increase of real estate by the addition of portions of soil through the action of the sea or river. Avulsion is the tearing away of the soil.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"accretion.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"erosion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"alienation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"acceleration.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A master plan may also be described as a(n):",hint:"A comprehensive or master plan, known as a “General Plan” is adopted for long-term physical development in seven major categories: land use, circulation, housing, conservation, open space, noise, and safety.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"elevation plan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"environmental plan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"general plan.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"specific plan.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following "runs with the land?"',hint:"Upon the sale of a property, the appurtenances, usually an easement, go with the sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An appurtenance",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An encumbrance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A lien",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A lis pendens",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would not create an estate in property?",hint:"Trust Deed",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Grant deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trust deed",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Gift deed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A preliminary subdivision report terminates:",hint:"Preliminary public reports allow taking reservations for the subdivision, but not accepting any non-refundable money or entering into any binding contracts until receipt of the final report from the commissioner. Preliminary public reports have a one-year term and may be renewed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"upon receiving the final subdivision report.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at the end of one year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"upon a material change.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When seeking a variance, an owner would petition the:",hint:"The owner may ask the city or county (local planning commission) for a waiver or zoning variance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"local Board of Realtors.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"local building department.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"local planning commission.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"If a married woman buys a grocery store which includes an off-sale beer and wine license:",hint:"They must be both named on the application to the A.B.C. even if the license is going to be in the wife's name. If he is an ex-felon this will keep the license from being issued for fear he may participate in the management of the business.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"she must apply to the State Board of Equalization.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"she must apply to the A.B.C. (Alcohol Beverage Control)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"she and her husband must apply to the State Board of Equalization.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"she and her husband must apply to the A.B.C.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A telephone company places poles and strings wire across privately owned land. This would be an example of a(n):",hint:"This would be an example of an easement in gross, which is an encumbrance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"specific lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"encumbrance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"appurtenant easement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"general lien.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A wife can will:",hint:"Both husband and wife have the right to will 1/2 the community property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"all the community property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/2 the community property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"any community property the husband has not willed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the community property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Unless specified otherwise, a husband and wife take title to property:",hint:"Property acquired by a married couple during marriage, if not specified otherwise, is presumed community property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"as joint tenants.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"as tenants in common.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in community property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The NW 1/4 of the SE 1/4 of Section 16, T4N, R4W, SBBM, is an example of what kind of land description?",hint:"Called U. S. Rectangular Survey, U. S. Government Survey, or U. S. Section and Township System.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Metes and bounds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"U.S. Rectangular Survey",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Lot, tract, and recorded map",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Three of the four following real estate terms are closely associated. Which of the four terms does not belong with the group?",hint:"Individuals claim many things, but they are not necessarily liens. A trust deed and judgment would be liens.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lien",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Judgment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Claim",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A gift of real property by will is a:",hint:"Bequest is a gift of personal property by will.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"demise.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"devise.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"legacy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"bequest.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'A homestead may be filed on real property wherever there are "structural improvements." Which of the following properties would not be eligible for a homestead?',hint:"One of the requirements of a homestead is that you live on the property. A homestead may be filed on all of the other types of property listed in choices (a), (b), and (d).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An apartment house in which the declarant owns and lives in one of the units",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A dwelling with an adjacent vacant lot on which the owner later plans to build and rent the new addition",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A home that is presently under construction",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A single family residence owned as a tenant in common with another",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following must be recorded to be valid?",hint:"A homestead is the only one listed that must be recorded to be valid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Easement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real estate sales contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Homestead",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Lease",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would be a freehold estate?",hint:"The others are less-than-freehold estates.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Estate in fee",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Estate at will",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Periodic tenancy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Leasehold estate",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Four months ago a seller accepted an offer from a buyer to purchase her home. The contract was in writing. Later, the seller refused to complete the transaction. Under the statute of limitations, so his right to sue does not "outlaw," the buyer must file an action within:',hint:"Statute of Limitations on any written contract is 4 years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"90 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1 year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4 years.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Recordation of a deed provides which of the following?",hint:"Recording gives constructive notice.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Liens shown against property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Constructive notice",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Guarantees ownership",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Guarantees possessory ownership in the property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not an encumbrance?",hint:"A homestead is the only one which adds to the rights of the owner of the subject property. The others infringe or impose upon the benefit or advantage of others.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Homestead",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Lien",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Encroachment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Easement",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A couple purchased a lot for the purpose of building a home at a later date. When they were ready to build, who would they contact to see that all codes and restrictions were complied with?",hint:"Local building inspectors enforce the construction regulations while local health officers enforce the occupancy an sanitation regulations.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real estate broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Architect",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contractor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Local building inspector",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An option to buy is enforceable if:",hint:"A valid option requires actual consideration to pass between the parties. This may be merely a nickel or $1.00 as long as it passes to the optionor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the consideration is $10.00 but by agreement is not delivered.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"consideration is less than $10.00 but actually has passed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the optionee withdraws his offer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"there is mutuality of interest.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are measurements of land except:",hint:"Metes and bounds is a land description, not a land measurement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"front feet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"square foot.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"metes and bounds.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"acre.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What kind of notice does recording give?",hint:"The only way to give actual notice is to notify each person individually.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Actual",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Constructive",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b) are correct",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither (a) nor (b) is correct",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appurtenance is:",hint:"Transfers with the land. Stock in a mutual water company would be the water rights of the land and must transfer with the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an easement in gross.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"stock in a mutual water company.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Property is:",hint:"An estate of real and personal property can exist. A fixture is real property. If it is not real property then it would have to be personal property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"real if an estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"personal if a fixture.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"personal if not real.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is an estate for an indefinite duration?",hint:"An estate at will is the only less-than-freehold estate that is for an indefinite duration.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An estate at will",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An estate from period to period",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An estate for years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An estate at sufferance",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would be considered the least desirable tenant for a shopping center?",hint:"Since most rents in shopping centers are based upon percentage leases, the key tenants are the large dollar volume producers. Barber shops usually lend themselves to the neighborhood location and not the shopping centers.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Supermarket",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Barber shop",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Chain variety store",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Department store",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The law requires the county recorder to index grant deeds:",hint:"Deeds are indexed alphabetically according to grantor and grantee. Do not confuse indexing with filing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"according to phonetic filing system.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"according to date and time of recording.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"alphabetically according to grantor and grantee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"on microfilm records.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is the statute of limitations on filing an action for encroachment?",hint:"If not filed within 3 years from date of knowledge, his right to sue outlaws.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2 years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3 years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"4 years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5 years",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Elements of time, relationship, and interest are most relevant to:",hint:"No relationship required in joint tenancy or tenants in common. Elements of joint tenancy are possession, interest, time, and title. The only element required in a tenancy in common is possession.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"joint tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenants in common.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"community property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Bill Jones and Sally Jones, husband and wife, would most likely indicate title held as:",hint:"Any property acquired during marriage is presumed community property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"joint tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenants in common.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"community property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"tenants in partnership.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A licensee sells property to a young married couple and later learns they are both 17 years of age. This transaction could best be described as:",hint:"Married persons under the age of 18 are considered emancipated minors.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"illegal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Acquiring permissive use of another's land would be:",hint:"Must be hostile (without permission).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"adverse possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"prescription.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Losing title to land by the wearing away by action of the water would be:",hint:"Erosion is the gradual wearing away of the land by natural forces (air and water). One acquires title to land by accretion. One appeals to the U. S. Supreme Court on a Writ of Certiorari.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"accretion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"erosion.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"certiorari.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"erosion and certiorari.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Joint tenancy and community property have which of the following in common?",hint:"Right of survivorship means you cannot will your share. In community property, both spouses have a right to will 1/2 of the community property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Right of survivorship",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Equal interest",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The approval of sanitation facilities in a subdivision is under the control of the:",hint:"Construction regulations: local building inspector. Sanitation regulations: local health officer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"planning commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"local health officer.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"local building inspector.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"plumbing inspector.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Real property which houses a business constitutes for the lessee a(n):",hint:"The lessee holds a leasehold or less-than-freehold estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"less than freehold estate.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"freehold business.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interest in the property, but not an estate.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An estate of inheritance or perpetual estates are referred to as a(n):",hint:"The most complete form of ownership is an estate in fee, Since an owner may dispose of an estate in fee during his/her lifetime or after death by will, it is also known as an estate of inheritance or a perpetual estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"estate in fee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"life estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estate at will.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estate for years.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The written instrument used to create land restrictions for the benefit of lot owners in a new subdivision is:",hint:"Restrictions are commonly known as CC&Rs or covenants, conditions and restrictions. The CC&Rs for a new subdivision are listed in a recorded Declaration of Restrictions which gives each owner the right to enforce the CC&Rs.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"declaration of restrictions.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a blanket deed of restrictions.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an order of desist and refrain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a blanket quit claim deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A joint tenancy interest in real property would be changed to a tenancy in common interest by:",hint:"When there are two joint tenants, the sale of an interest to a third party terminates the joint tenancy because the third party is coming into the tenancy at a different time.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"death of one of three joint tenants.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"death of one of two joint tenants.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one of two joint tenants giving his interest to the other.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one of two joint tenants selling his interest to a third party.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lease that specifies that the lessee is to pay the real estate property taxes and the insurance cost, as well as the rent, is called:",hint:"Leases are classified by method of rent payments, such as gross, net, and percentage leases. In a net lease, the tenant pays an agreed-upon sum as rent, plus certain agreed-upon expenses per month (i.e. taxes, insurance and repairs).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"specific lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sandwich lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"net lease.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"percentage lease.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The holding of real property is:",hint:"The holder is the tenant.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"tenancy.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"tender.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"taken for granted.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following interests does the lessee hold?",hint:'Leasehold estates are "chattels real." They are also a less than-freehold estate.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Remainder estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Chattel real",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Less than freehold estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (b) and (c) above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Johannes gives a life estate to her sister for the life of Charlie, her sister's friend. The life tenant dies. What interest does Ms. Johannes hold in the property?",hint:"When Charlie dies, the estate will revert back to Ms. Johannes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Remainder interest",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Fee estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Reversionary interest",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which would not be a blanket encumbrance in a subdivision?",hint:"An assessment bond is taken on each individual lot.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trust deeds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subdivision lots improvement assessment bond",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Mechanics' liens",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Lessee is to lease as:",hint:"Vendee (buyer) in a land contract only holds an equitable interest. He is not the owner until he has paid for the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"optionee is to optionor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"vendee is to vendor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"vendee is to land contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"lessee is to lessor.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The holder of which of the following interests would have the least protection of his interests?",hint:"There are no implied warranties with this type of deed. A quit claim deed is generally used to clear some cloud on the title and, if not recorded, it would not serve this purpose.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A lessee holding a less-than-freehold estate, living on the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A quit claim deed, unrecorded",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A grant deed, unrecorded, living on the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A recorded grant deed, not living on the property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A claimant may get a homestead exemption on all of the following, except:",hint:"He cannot get a homestead exemption on the property unless he already lives there.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a property with a house under construction in which the claimant plans to live.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"joint tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an apartment, owner occupied, in an apartment complex.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Emblements include:",hint:"Also the right a farmer may have to harvest his crops after he has sold his property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the right of a tenant farmer to harvest his or her crops even though the lease may have expired.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the decorative fixtures on the outside of an apartment building.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trade fixtures.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following qualifies as artificial monuments?",hint:"Artificial (man-made).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Rocks and streets",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Streets and canals",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Trees and rocks",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"According to the laws of homesteads, a homestead would be invalidated by:",hint:"One can only have one homestead at a time. To abandon a homestead exemption on a piece of property, one must either sell the property or file an abandonment of homestead. Once he has done this he may file a new homestead exemption on his new residence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"moving to another state.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a prior recorded homestead.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"moving out of the homestead property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the homesteaded property being destroyed by fire.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following legal procedures is dependent upon first attaining a judgment?",hint:"After receiving a judgment, one may get a Writ of Execution to collect on that judgment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Unlawful Detainer Action",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Writ of Attachment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Writ of Execution",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Writ of Seizure",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not considered a leasehold estate?",hint:"Leasehold (less-than-freehold). An estate in fee is a freehold estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An estate in fee",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An estate for years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An estate for period",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An estate at will",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a lease is to be recorded, who must acknowledge it?",hint:"If a lease is for more than 1 year, it must be in writing and signed by the lessor (landlord). The lessee does not have to sign the lease.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The lessor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The lessee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The owner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would you associate with unlawful detainer?",hint:"This is used in removing someone from a less-than-freehold estate. Trustor, grantor, and trustee are all terms used in freehold estates.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trustor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lessor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Grantor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trustee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In order to invalidate a homestead in California:",hint:"This is the only automatic way to abandon a homestead. The only other way is to record an abandonment of homestead.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"move from the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"move from the property and take up residence in another state.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the house is 3/4 destroyed by fire.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sell the property and purchase two rental units.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'"A" receives a life estate for the life of "X." "A" dies before "X." The estate:',hint:'The estate vests in the heirs of "A" until "X" dies at which time the estate will revert to the original grantor.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"ceases to exist.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reverts to the original grantor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'vests in "X" for his life.',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'vests in the heirs of "A."',isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Three people own a piece of property as tenants in common. What can be determined from this ownership?",hint:"Tenants in common may or may not have equal interest. They may or may not have acquired interest at the same time.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Tenants own an equal interest",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Tenants own an unequal interest",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cannot determine the degree of interest ownership per tenant in common",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All tenants in common acquired interest at the same time",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A lien cannot be:",hint:'The word "performance" means "an act". A lien is not an act, it is an instrument used to collect money. A lien may be general, specific, or involuntary.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"general.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"specific.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"involuntary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a performance.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Considering condominiums, an elevator located in the building would be considered part of the:",hint:"Common or public areas include private roadways, water systems, septic systems, parks, elevators, recreation rooms, ponds and lakes, airport landing strips, trails, ocean access area.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"unit.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"common areas.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"project.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In one word, the contour of the surface of the land is called:",hint:"Topography is the various surface features or contours of the land that affect construction costs.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"grading.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"topography.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"geography.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"geology.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"After the court renders an order of judgment, the next instrument to be recorded to create a lien is:",hint:"A judgment by the court is the final determination of the rights of parties in a lawsuit. A judgment does not automatically create a lien. A summary of the court decision, known as an abstract of judgment, must be recorded with the county recorder to create a general lien.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Desist and Refrain order.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Abstract of Judgment.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Quiet Title Action.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under lease, the leasehold estate lies with the:",hint:"Lessor is the owner. He would have a freehold estate. The lessee holds the leasehold or less-than-freehold estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"lessor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lessee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neither (a) nor (c)",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a completion bond is involved, it is for the protection of the:",hint:"A completion bond is for the protection of the monied interest or the owner. The best choice available is the lender (monied interest). If this choice were not available it would be for the protection of the owner, which could be the subdivider or the builder.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"borrower.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"builder.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subdivider.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lender.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Real estate property can:",hint:"Real property can be willed, alienated (conveyed or sold), and it can also become personal property (i.e., growing crops are real property while growing and become personal property when harvested).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"become personal property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be alienated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be conveyed by will.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Constructive notice of a lien is given by recording a/an:",hint:"Lien is a money encumbrance. A deed of trust is the only answer listed that is a money encumbrance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"restriction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easements in gross.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"blanket set of restrictions covering a subdivision of 99 lots.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a deed of trust.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not eligible for a homestead?",hint:"Homestead is placed on the home in which one is residing. That must be his legal residence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A new home under construction",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An old home which was homesteaded by its previous owner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A condominium",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When personal property is attached to a building and becomes real property, it is known as:",hint:"Five tests of a Fixture: Acronym = “MARIA” (Method of attachment, Adaptation, Relationship of the parties, Intention, and Agreement of the parties).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a trade fixture.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a fixture.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a conditional appurtenant.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An agreement to sell community property, signed by the husband alone, is:",hint:"The wife has one year from the date of recording the deed to void the sale. If she does not void the sale it is valid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unenforceable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An old land registration system used in the State of California was called:",hint:"Torrens Title Insurance no longer used in California.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the Regions Title Insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Land Locators Insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"County Recorder's Insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Torrens Title Insurance.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In the language of real estate, which of the following terms does not belong with the others?",hint:"A second trust deed is subordinate to the first trust deed. To hypothecate is to give (personal property) in pledge as security for a debt. A trust deed (which is personal property) is given as security for the trust note. The one that does not belong is joint tenancy.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Joint tenancy",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Hypothecate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subordination",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Second trust deed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Real property is:",hint:"Real property is described as land, anything permanently attached to the land, anything appurtenant to the land or anything immovable by law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buildings.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all that is not personal property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"You agree to lease a property for 10 years for $12,000 total rent, at $100 per month. You pay the first and last months' rent of $200. Which of the following terms would be inappropriate in the lease?",hint:"This would be a straight lease, which has no need for an escalator clause. The escalator clause would be found in a graduated lease.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Condemnation conditions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Compliance with the federal laws",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Third party liabilities",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Escalator clause geared to the cost of living",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Emblements mean:",hint:"Growing crops that are cultivated annually for sale, and orchards in a commercial grove are called emblements. Emblements (the crops) are personal property, not the trees of plants they grow on.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the decorative fixtures on the outside of an apartment building.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fixtures.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the right of a tenant farmer to harvest his crops even though his lease may have expired.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The personal, revocable, and unassignable permission of authority to do one or more acts on the land of another possessing any interest therein is a(n):",hint:"A license is permission or authority to do a particular act on the land/property of another, usually on a nonexclusive basis. A license is a personal, revocable and nonassignable right.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"license.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"easement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"encumbrance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"option.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Informing a person that he should sell his property because non-whites are moving into the area and decreasing property values can be expressed by all of the following except:",hint:"Situation describes blockbusting which causes panic selling and is illegal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"blockbusting.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"panic selling.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"illegal conduct.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"legal conduct.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When a property is sold by the court, and the proceeds are divided among the owners, this is called a:",hint:"Definition: Partition action is a court proceeding to settle a dispute between co-owners about dividing their interests in real property. The court can physically divide either the property or the money derived from its sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"split action.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"divided interest action.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"partition action.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"reverse action.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Title vested as Juan Perez and Gertrudis Perez, husband and wife, will be presumed:",hint:'Title vested in "husband and wife" would be presumed community property.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"community property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"joint tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenancy in common.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a lease is to be recorded, it must be acknowledged before a proper official by the:",hint:"The lessor (landlord)owns the property and signs the lease to give possession and use to the lessee (tenant). Leases for longer than one year (1 year plus 1 day) must be in writing and must be signed by the lessor, but not necessarily by the lessee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"county recorder.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"notary public.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lessee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lessor.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A fee simple estate is most likely to be a:",hint:"Most likely is a fee simple absolute which is the maximum interest obtainable. If it were a fee simple defeasible, the title could be defeated which is not the maximum interest obtainable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leasehold.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"less-than-freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"maximum interest obtainable.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Title to schools, parks, libraries, and other publicly owned property is held as:",hint:"Property owned by one person or entity, such as a city or corporation, is known as sole and separate, or ownership in severalty.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"joint tenants.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"community property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenants in common.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"severalty.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The presence of a corporation seal would indicate:",hint:"Officer or the person that has tile authority to sign.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"recording.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ownership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the officer.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"partnership.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The most commonly accepted procedure for the enforcement of "C,C,&R\'s" is by:',hint:"The penalty for a breach of a CC&R is usually money damages or an injunction. An injunction is a court order forcing a person to do or not do an act, such as violating a private restriction.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lis pendens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"injunction.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"eminent domain.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How is a private restriction enforced?",hint:"The penalty for a breach of a CC&R is usually money damages or an injunction. An injunction is a court order forcing a person to do or not do an act, such as violating a private restriction.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Injunction",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Desist and refrain",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Attachment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Any of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A solemn declaration by a person whose religious beliefs forbid the taking of an oath is:",hint:"An affirmation is a declaration as to the truth of a statement, and is used in lieu of an oath by a person who objects for personal or religious reasons.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an affidavit.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an acknowledgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an affirmation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An affirmed statement sworn to is:",hint:"An affidavit is a sworn statement written down and made under oath before a notary public or other official authorized by law to administer an oath. Its purpose is to help establish or prove a fact, and it is a complete instrument within itself.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an affidavit.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an acknowledgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an affirmation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"delivered.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A husband may lease real community property without his wife's consent:",hint:"If for more than one year he must have his wife's consent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"if the property is in his name.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"up to one year.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"because he is the statutory manager of the community property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"if the lease is oral.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A lien established by court order would be:",hint:"Involuntary is by act of law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"verified.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unrecorded.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voluntary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"involuntary.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'The remedy of "unlawful detainer" would be used by the offended:',hint:"Unlawful detainer action is the legal remedy by a landlord (lessor) to remove a tenant (lessee) who is in default under the terms of the lease. It is also known as an action in ejectment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"holder of a note in default.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lessor.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"lessee.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In what form of ownership would you look to an individual's personal assets?",hint:"Definition: A partnership (an association of two or more persons carrying on a business for profit as co-owners) can hold title to real property (personal assets) in the name of the partnership, holding by tenancy in partnership and often vesting the title to said property in a trustee of a land trust.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Corporation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Limited partnership",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Partnership",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Investment trusts",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are required for fee simple title except:",hint:"Fee simple is of indefinite duration, freely transferable and inheritable. The fee may also be encumbered, either by voluntary or involuntary encumbrances.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"must be free of encumbrances.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"indefinite duration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"can be transferred.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"can be willed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are incorrect except:",hint:"Either spouse may homestead a property without the other spouse's consent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a lease has to be in writing if executed for a period of one year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a homestead is invalid if filed during a pending suit for judgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a wife can file a homestead even though her husband has not done so.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a deed is a lien but not always an encumbrance.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Riparian rights are:",hint:"Riparian rights are those rights the landowner has to the reasonable use of the water adjoining or abutting his land, running through his land and running under his land in known underground channels. Percolating waters are unchanneled underground water.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"never acquired by prescription.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"stock in a mutual water company found in the county recorder's records.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the right of the overlying landowner to the percolating waters beneath his lands.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are correct except:",hint:"Once removed it is movable and therefore personal property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"fixtures installed on real property by the mortgagee are subject to the primary mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a fence removed by the owner from real property and piled on the property is still real property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"trade fixtures, although permanently installed, are not considered real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"gas stoves installed in an apartment building are real property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Section number 13 is contiguous to:",hint:'The word "contiguous" means touching or abutting. Section number 13 touches sections 11, 12, 14, 23, and 24.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"sections 7, 8, 14, and 19.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sections 12, 24, 14, 11, and 23.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"sections 7, 8, 17, 19, and 20.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sections 10, 11, 12, 14, and 15.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The existence of an easement appurtenant requires all of the following except:",hint:"The dominant and servient tenements do not have to be joined at their borders.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"at least two tracts of land in separate ownership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ajoinment at their borders by the dominant and servient tenement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"transferability with the land as an incident thereto.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a benefit to one tract of land and a burden to another.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A person purchased a condominium unit. Which of the following is a part of his unit?",hint:"Choices (a) and (b) are areas owned in common.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Bearing wall",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Elevator",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Air space within his unit",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Deed restrictions are considered to be:",hint:"Deed restrictions are one of the types of encumbrances. They are enforceable by both the adjoining property owners and the original grantor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"encumbrances.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"general liens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"constructive liens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"enforceable only by the adjoining property owners.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are encumbrances except:",hint:"Encumbrances fall into two categories: Money encumbrances - liens, trust deeds, mechanic's liens, judgments & attachments, and tax liens & special assessments; and Non-money encumbrances - easements, restrictions, and encroachments.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"promissory notes.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"private restrictions.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"encroachments.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easements.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The authority given by law for a creditor to obtain a charge or a debt from a debtor is, in the broadest sense of the term, a:",hint:"The authority given by law or by court action is a judgment. An attachment, when allowed, is received prior to the judgment. When a judgment is recorded, it becomes a lien.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"judgment.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"judgment and attachment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A partnership may hold title to real property in:",hint:"Under the Uniform Partnership Act, a partnership can hold title to real property in the name of the partnership, holding by tenancy in partnership, and vested in a trustee (third party) for the partnership.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the name of the partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the name of any individual partner in the partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the name of a third party as trustee for the partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lien may be created by recording a:",hint:"A lien is a type of encumbrance that involves a money claim against the title.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"notice of non-responsibility.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deed of trust.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"easement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"restriction.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Of "indefinite duration" is a characteristic which is particularly descriptive of:',hint:"All fee simple estates are for an indefinite duration. An estate of inheritance is the only fee simple estate listed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an estate for years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a periodic tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate of inheritance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a less-than-freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Personal property may:",hint:"Personal property becomes real property when it becomes a fixture. It is taxable; therefore, it can be assessed. It can also be hypothecated (promised as security for a loan).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"become real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be assessed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be hypothecated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"If a man died intestate, his separate property would go to:",hint:"If there were only one child the separate property would be divided half and half. With more than one child it is divided 1/3 to the spouse and 2/3 to the children share and share alike.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"his wife alone.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/2 to his wife and 1/2 divided among his closest relatives.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/3 to his wife and 2/3 divided among his children, share and share alike if he had more than one child.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"his children alone.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following is incorrect in regards to a "metes and bounds" description?',hint:'The "metes" are measurements and the "bounds" are the boundaries.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Using a river as a boundary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Using a fence and edge of a farm as a boundary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Using rocks and trees as boundaries",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"Metes" are boundaries and "bounds" are measurements',isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is a lien?",hint:"A lien is a charge against the property whereby the property is made security for the payment of a debt. An attachment lien creates a lien on certain property of a defendant whereby it is held in custody until the court reaches a judgment. An encumbrance is an interest or a right in real property. Trust deeds, mortgages, and judgments are money encumbrances known as liens. Restrictions and easements are non-money encumbrances but are not liens. A homestead is neither an encumbrance nor a lien.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Zoning ordinances",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An attachment",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An encumbrance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A homestead",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Tan leased an apartment for five years. Six months later he moved out. The landlord may do any of the following, except:",hint:"The lessor cannot sue for the rent until it becomes due.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"try to find a new tenant and credit the rent to Mr. Tan's account.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leave the apartment vacant and immediately sue Mr. Tan for the remaining 4 1/2 years' rent.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"leave the apartment vacant and sue Mr. Tan for each installment as it becomes due.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"move into the apartment himself.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Sam Miller willed his property to "my favorite nephew, Harry Miller, and his wife, Mary Miller, jointly with right of survivorship." Harry and Mary took title as:',hint:"Tenants in common and tenants in partnership do not have the right of survivorship. Joint tenants may be any number but community property applies to spouses only.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"tenants in common.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"joint tenants.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"community property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"partnership.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Real Estate Commissioner has primary regulatory authority over subdivision matters concerning:",hint:"The Commissioner regulates aspects concerning the sale of subdivided lands to prevent fraud, including monies for promised improvements. He does not concern himself with the physical improvements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"alignment of streets within a tract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"design of the improvements to insure proper drainage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"financial arrangements to insure the completion of community facilities.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Myra gives her brother a life estate for his life, thereafter to revert back to Myra. He later gets married to Mona. Two years later he dies. What would become of the estate?",hint:"Reverts back to original grantor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It would be an estate in remainder",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It would be an estate in reversion",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Mona would inherit the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Myra would inherit the property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Art and Bud are partners. Art dies and leaves all of his estate to Charlie. Which of the following is correct?",hint:"A partner can will his share of the assets but the heir will have no right to the management of the business.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Bud and Charlie are now partners",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Charlie has the right to Art's share of the assets of the partnership but no right to the management of the business",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A partner cannot will his share of the business",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The seizing of property by the sheriff to be held as a security for a legal action is known as a(n):",hint:"A writ of attachment is the process by which the court holds the real or personal property of a defendant as security for a possible judgment pending the outcome of a lawsuit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Writ of Seizure.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Writ of Execution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Writ of Possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Attachment.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"For speculative purposes, an owner of land divided it into eight parcels in 1991. He sold two lots in 1991, two lots in 1992, took an option to purchase on one lot in 1993, and sold the remaining lots in 1994. When was he legally classified as a subdivider?",hint:"The date of subdividing was before any sales took place.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1991",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1992",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1993, if the option were exercised",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1994, if the option were not exercised",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are classified as subdivisions and subject to regulation by the Real Estate Commissioner except:",hint:"Land divided into five or more parcels and condominiums, co-ops, stock co-ops, and community apartment projects of five or more are all subdivisions. An apartment house would not come under subdivision law unless each individual apartment was offered for sale in which case it would become a community apartment project.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"land divided into more than four pieces.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a five-unit community apartment project.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a five-unit condominium project.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a twenty-one unit apartment house.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following elements of a subdivision law are administered by the Real Estate Commissioner?",hint:"Answer (a) comes under real property securities law. Answers (c) and (d) come under control of the local governing body.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The physical aspects, such as streets and sidewalks, of an out-of-state subdivision",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Adequate financial arrangements to ensure completion of community recreational facilities",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Approval of improvement contracts, and posting of adequate performance bonds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Statutory dedication of easements for streets",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following elements of a subdivision are regulated by local planning commissions under the state Subdivision Map Act?",hint:"Out-of-state subdivisions come under real property securities law. Approval of the preliminary public report is done by the commissioner. Answer (c) is not necessary at all.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The physical aspects, such as streets and sidewalks, of an out-of-state subdivision",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Approval of the preliminary public report",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Verification that the subdivider has a valid license issued by the Department of Real Estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Assurance that adequate provisions have been made for sewage disposal and flood control",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"It is said that the Commissioner's Public Report is the chief weapon against fraud in the sale of subdivided lands in California. All of the following are correct statements concerning the Public Report except:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all correct statements. Answer (d) is not. This would constitute a material change.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a broker may take a listing on and show property before the issuance of the Public Report.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a Preliminary Public Report issued by the Commissioner enables the subdivider to take reservations; however, it expires in one year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a Final Public Report expires in 5 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the option of 5 lots in a subdivision to one buyer does not constitute a material change in ownership.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is a correct statement concerning condominiums?",hint:"A condominium consists of a separate fee interest in a particular specific space (the unit), plus an undivided interest in all common or public areas of the development. All owners are allowed to use any of the facilities in the common area. Each unit owner has a deed, separate financing and pays the property taxes for their unit. Operations controlled by elected governing board.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:'The term "condominium unit" refers to a deeded separate interest in space in a residential, industrial, or commercial building',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Bearing walls, central air conditioning units, and elevators represent an undivided interest in common",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Rising land values tend to increase the condominium form of ownership and each unit is assessed separately and receives a separate tax bill",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above are correct statements",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is the least effectively enforced restriction?",hint:'A "minimum amount of improvements" is generally a deed restriction to be applied to future use of land. But choices (a), (b), and (c) are usually restrictions in the form of zoning laws and enforced by public authorities.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Minimum lot size",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Minimum room size",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Fence height limitations",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Minimum amount of improvements to be made",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is true concerning a township?",hint:"The boundaries of a township are its range and township lines. However, due to the curvature of the earth there is a distortion in each township's area as the range lines curve northward. Therefore, each township does not contain exactly 36 square miles. Each township contains 36 sections but they are not always equal in area. Some are called government sections and could not be less than the 640 acres of a standard section.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Always contains the same amount of land",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Always has 36 square miles",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Always has 36 equal sections",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Its boundaries are range and township lines",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would be the most favorable lease for an owner of an improved business property located in a rapidly growing area?",hint:"A percentage of the gross permits the lessor to participate in future growth of sales. A minimum rent protects him against a decline in sales. The lessee paying taxes protects him against future tax increases.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Percentage lease based on the gross income with a minimum rental guarantee and the lessee to pay the taxes",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Percentage lease based on net income with a minimum rental guarantee and the lessee to pay the taxes",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A straight long term lease at a fixed annual rental and the lessee to pay the taxes",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A year to year lease with the rental payment based on an annual pedestrian count",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, the item considered to be personal property is:",hint:"Personal property is movable. A trust deed is a piece of paper and movable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an installed water heater.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"installed fencing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"growing shade trees.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a trust deed.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The most practical way to create restrictions on all lots in a new subdivision is to:",hint:'Recording a copy of declaration of restrictions in the county where the property is located permits the subdivider to mention "subject to restrictions of record" in the deed of conveyance without spelling out all restrictions in the deed. This is the most practical way to do it.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"record a declaration of restrictions in the county where the subdivision is located.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"post them on the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"insert them in all deeds to the lots.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"publish them in a legal newspaper.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Referring to land descriptions:",hint:"All statements of fact. Metes and Bounds is a method of land description, not measurement. The three intersections in the State of California are Humboldt, Mt. Diablo, and San Bernardino.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"U. S. Government Survey, Recorded Track Map or Lot and Block System, and Metes and Bounds are all considered legal descriptions.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a Metes and Bounds description is not a measurement of land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"there are three intersections of base and meridian lines in California.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above are correct statements",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'If "A," "B," and "C" have property as joint tenants, and "B" sells his share to "W" and "A" dies leaving an heir, "S," which situation is correct?',hint:'Joint tenants can sell their share but cannot will it. When selling their share, the person receiving it holds as a tenant in common with the remainder of the joint tenants holding as joint tenants. Therefore, "A" and "C" were still joint tenants with "W" as a tenant in common. When "A" died, "C" received "A"\'s share by right of survivorship leaving "C" with a 2/3 interest and "W" with a 1/3 interest in the property, both holding as tenants in common.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:'2/3 goes to "C" and "W" with "S" as a tenant in common',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'1/3 goes to "C," 1/3 to "W," and 1/3 to "S" after court decision',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"C" and "W" have a tenancy in common',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Joint tenancy goes through probate",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The thing of which there may be ownership is called property. Property is divided into two classes-real and personal. All of the following are correct statements concerning property except:",hint:"Answers (b), (c), and (d) are true statements. Things immovable are real property. Personal property is anything movable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"things immovable by law are considered personal property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"sub-surface oil and gas are real property and the real property rights thereto may be deeded separately from the surface rights.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"personal property may become real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"growing crops may be real property or personal property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appurtenance is a type of real property. Which of the following would be classified as an appurtenance?",hint:"Answer (a) is the definition of appurtenance. Answer (b) is an easement which is always appurtenant to the land. Answer (c) is when there is no publicly owned water company and property owners of the community buy water through the purchase of stock in a mutual water company. This stock in the mutual water company goes with the land making it appurtenant.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Anything by legal right, used with the land for its benefit",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Rights of way over adjoining land",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Stock in a mutual water company",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Of the following which does not belong with the other?",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all freehold estates. An estate for years is a less than freehold estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Estate in fee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Estate of inheritance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Freely transferable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Estate of years",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A life estate is limited to the life of its owner, or the life of one or more designated persons. All of the following are correct statements except:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all rights of a life estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a life estate is a freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the holder of a life estate is entitled to all the rents and profits from the land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the holder may dispose of his life estate by sale or lease and encumber it.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"there may be only one estate existing in a life estate at the same time and under the same circumstances.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A leasehold is an ownership of the possessory rights in real property. Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning leaseholds?",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all incorrect. An estate at sufferance is when the lease is over and the lessee has no rights and must move if the lessor/landlord wishes him to.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A leasehold is classified as a freehold estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The maximum leasehold on urban property is 51 years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'The term "rent" indicates an estate from period to period',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"There is no notice required to terminate an estate at sufferance",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following best describes a severalty estate?",hint:"Severalty is sole ownership. Ownership resting in one person only. A corporation is a legal entity which is a legal person, and holds title to property in severalty.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It is a type of co-tenancy estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Even though a corporation has many individual stockholders it owns title in severalty",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An ownership of real property by more than one person such as three tenants in common each holding a 1/3 undivided interest would be classified as a severalty ownership",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A husband and wife hold real property in severalty",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following does not belong with the others?",hint:"In ownership under joint tenancy all interests must be equal and undivided. Also, all joint tenants have the right of survivorship.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Joint tenancy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Probate",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Survivorship",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Undivided interest",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Whether an item is a fixture or not is important when land is bought or sold, or when a lease expires. Of the following, which is a correct statement?",hint:"Fixtures are personal property that has been attached to the land so as to become a part of the land, thus making them real property. One exception, however, is trade fixtures are always personal property no matter how attached. Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all incorrect statements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A fixture is a type of personal property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A trade fixture is a type of real property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A mirror in an entry hall or a knickknack shelf in a kitchen are fixtures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The fact that an item is permanently attached to real property does not in all cases indicate that the item is a fixture",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A brother and sister hold title to real property as joint tenants. The sister gets married and deeds half her interest in the property to her husband. Her husband:",hint:'When a joint tenant conveys a portion of his interest, the joint tenancy is not affected insofar as the original remaining joint tenants are concerned. They continue as joint tenants to each other with the "stranger" holding as a tenant in common. However, when, as in this case, the remaining joint tenants no longer have an equal interest in the property, the joint tenancy is dissolved and it becomes a tenancy in common.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"owns no interest in the property as she may not deed an undivided interest in the property without her brother's consent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"would be a co-tenant in the property but would have rights of survivorship only as to a 1/3 interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"would be a joint tenant but only as to a 1/4 undivided interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"would be a tenant in common.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'A man and wife have title to real property vested as "John Jones and his wife Mary." This method of taking title would mean:',hint:"Property vested as John Jones and his wife Mary, unless otherwise stated, is presumed to be community property. Statement of fact answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the wife may not will her undivided 1/2 interest in the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a presumption that the property is held as joint tenants.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a presumption that title is held as tenants in common but without the right to will their interest by either spouse.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a presumption that title is vested as community property and either spouse may will his interest to whomever he chooses; however, if either spouse dies intestate the surviving spouse would inherit the deceased spouse's interest without probate.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"All of the following statements concerning title are correct except:",hint:"Title to land may be obtained by adverse possession which would be without the consent of the fee owner.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"title can be obtained without the use of a deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"title is classified as a bundle of rights and may exist in personal property as well as real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"title may not be transferred without the consent of the fee owner.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"title may be transferred from one person to another even though it is encumbered with a lien.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The recording system was established to show the sequence of transfers or other actions affecting property. All of the following are correct statements concerning recordation except:",hint:"Recording a deed imparts constructive notice, not actual notice.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"recording a deed does not affect its legality.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"public records may be inspected by anyone without an employee of the recorder's office being present.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"recording a deed imparts actual notice to all future purchasers.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a deed to real property that is recorded in a county other than that in which the property is located does not provide constructive notice.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'"A" deeds a property to "B" who takes possession of the property but fails to record his deed. "A" then deeds the same property to "C" who bought the property without inspecting it. However, "C" recorded his deed. The results would be:',hint:'The first party to buy and take possession of the land would be the rightful owner. Since "B" was in possession of the property it was "C"\'s duty to inspect the property for the rights to anybody in possession. If no one is in possession, then first to record is first to right.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:'"C" has a valid title because he recorded his deed.',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"B" and "C" would be tenants-in-common each to a 1/2 undivided interest.',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'there would be no title transfer and "B" and "C" would have to sue "A" separately.',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"B" has a valid title.',isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Deed restrictions are said to be in the form of a covenant or a condition. Which of the following would be a correct statement concerning covenants and conditions?",hint:"Penalty for a condition is more severe than a covenant. The penalty for violation of a covenant would result from a court suit for damages.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The penalty for violation of a covenant is more severe than that for violation of a condition",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The penalty for violation of a condition would result from a court suit for damages",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'Upon receiving his deed after the closing of escrow, the purchaser finds this statement in the deed: "Title subject to a recorded deed of trust in the amount of $12,000, current taxes, covenants, conditions, and restrictions in a declaration of restrictions recorded in Book 41483 Page 421 Official Records and an easement in favor of Pacific Telephone Corporation affecting said land for purposes of poles and conduits." From an analysis of the facts, which of the following is a correct statement?',hint:"The title is encumbered with a deed restriction. A utility easement is an easement in gross, not a restriction in gross. Answer (c) is the only correct statement. Taxes create a specific lien on March 1st of every year until paid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"His title is encumbered with a lien and an easement but not with a deed restriction",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The utility easement constitutes a restriction in gross",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The taxes create a specific lien on his title",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A fee simple estate may:",hint:"A fee simple estate may be willed, rented, is of an unlimited duration, and may be encumbered or borrowed against.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"not be willed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not be leased.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be of a definite duration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be encumbered.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lien:",hint:"Trust deeds and mortgages are voluntary liens. A lien is a money encumbrance. A restriction is a non-money encumbrance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"must be specific.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is classified as an encumbrance in the form of restriction on the title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in the form of a trust deed or mortgage is classified as an involuntary lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may be general or specific on real or personal property.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The California Code of Civil Procedure provides that persons furnishing labor or material for the improvement of real estate may file liens upon the property affected if they are not compensated. Such liens are referred to as mechanic's liens. All of the following are correct statements concerning mechanic's liens, except:",hint:"In a foreclosure sale the priority of a holder of a mechanic's lien over a holder of a trust deed or mortgage lien would be established by showing the contractor had begun his work prior to the recording of the trust deed or mortgage lien. The rest of the choices are correct.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a mechanic's lien must be recorded to be legally effective.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in a foreclosure sale the priority of a holder of a mechanic's lien over a holder of a trust deed or mortgage lien would be established by the date and time of recording of the respective liens.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the demolition of an old structure on a lot preparatory to building a new structure on the same lot often establishes the priority of mechanic's liens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the owner of real property could be financially responsible for payment of mechanic's liens even though he has paid the general contractor in full.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following statements concerning easements are correct except:",hint:"An easement does not have to be recorded.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"all easements are encumbrances but not all encumbrances are easements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"land with rights of ingress and egress over adjoining land is said to have an easement appurtenant that runs with the land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a purchaser of a servient tenement usually takes title subject to an easement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an easement must be recorded in order to give constructive notice to a subsequent purchaser of the existence of the easement.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Prescription is a method of acquiring an easement; adverse possession a method of acquiring title. Which of the following statements is correct?",hint:"Answer (a) would be an easement by statutory dedication. In adverse possession it is not necessary to establish residence, only to hold and occupy the land continuously for five years. In an easement by prescription, the user of the property must be hostile to the owner. In answer (c) the owner is giving permission to use the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Dedication of land for use by the public could result in creating an easement by prescription",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"In a claim of title by adverse possession, establishing residence on the property would be a necessary element",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Granting grazing rights in excess of five years on agricultural land could result in prescriptive rights to an easement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above are correct statements",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would be a good example of riparian rights?",hint:"Riparian rights is the right to a reasonable use of the water adjoining, abutting, or running through one's land or in known underground channels beneath the surface of one's land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Rights to water from a mutual irrigation district",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Absolute and exclusive rights to the middle of an adjacent river",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Reasonable use of non-adjacent water",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above are correct",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Restrictions on title to real property:",hint:"Statements of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"may be classified as public or private.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may be created by the County Board of Supervisors.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may be created by a subdivider before the sale of the property and would create an encumbrance on each lot in the subdivision.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above are correct",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Cities and counties may adopt zoning regulations to ensure that structures conform to specified standards as to character and location. All of the following are correct statements concerning zoning ordinances except:",hint:"R-3 generally refers to multiple dwellings or triplexes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"zoning regulations are classified as public restrictions and are created under police powers of the city or county.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"zoning laws affecting the use of property are classified as encumbrances on the title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'zoning ordinances vary from city to city; however, the symbol "R-3" generally refers to recreational use of property.',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"denial of zoning variances may be appealed to the city council or Board of Supervisors but not to the courts.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The State Housing Act:",hint:"State Housing Law outlines the minimum construction and occupancy requirements for dwellings (per Health and Safety Code Section 17910, et. seq.).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"sets minimum building standards.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may be adopted as a building code in an unincorporated area.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both (a) and (b) are correct statements",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"neither (a) nor (b) are correct statements",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"As a real estate licensee, you will often be asked to explain a Declaration of Homestead. All of the following are correct statements concerning this protection except:",hint:"A Declaration of Homestead is the recorded document that protects a homeowner from foreclosure by certain judgment creditors. It can be filed after the filing of a court action but must be filed before the filing of a judgment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"it does not protect the homeowner against mechanic's liens, tax liens, trust deeds, or mortgages.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"it may be declared on a resident-owner 21-unit apartment house.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"it may be declared on only one property of an individual; however, upon sale of the property and purchase of a new property a declaration may be recorded on the new property without a formal Declaration of Abandonment of the first Declaration of Homestead.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a declaration is not valid unless recorded prior to the filing of a court action.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Sole ownership of real property by an individual is ownership:",hint:'The legal term "severalty" as used in real estate is defined as "the quality or state of being individual or particular-distinctness, separateness. Also, a sole, separate, and ex-elusive possession, dominion, or ownership." An estate "in severalty" indicates sole ownership-by one person only.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"of an undivided interest in common.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in gross.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in severalty.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"in joint tenancy.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would affect a contractor or a sub-contractor in filing a mechanic's lien?",hint:"Any one of these three would have an affect on their statutory right to file a mechanic's lien.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Notice of completion",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Notice of non-responsibility",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Notice of cessation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following will a standard policy of title insurance insure against?",hint:"A standard policy covers recorded matters, forgery, and capacity, but never any unrecorded matters.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Forgery",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Unrecorded restrictions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Unrecorded easements",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Unrecorded liens",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A mechanic's lien can be filed by:",hint:"A mechanic's lien is for labor or material.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a plumber.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subcontractor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a supplier.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Fire insurance should allow the policy holder to:",hint:"Insurance provides indemnification against loss from a specific hazard or peril. Most insurance policies contain a pro rata liability clause that prevents the owner from collecting a greater amount than the actual loss.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"gain in the event of a claim.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"make at least 4 claims before cancellation of the policy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neither gain nor lose in the event of a claim.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"keep his loss to no more than $100,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a subdivider grants an easement to a utility company, the utility company holds:",hint:"When easements are given to utility companies, they hold an easement in gross. Statement of fact answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an easement by permission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a dominant tenement for life.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an easement in gross.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Buyer gives seller a purchase money second trust deed and note. Shortly afterward, buyer defaults in payments on the second trust deed. Seller can, in due course, bring court action and secure against buyer:",hint:"No deficiency judgment on a purchase money encumbrance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a deficiency judgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a reconveyance deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lease on real estate property is a(n):",hint:"A lease is for a definite duration and is properly described as an estate for years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"property lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estate for years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estate at sufferance.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The principals are each personally liable to creditors in:",hint:"No personal liability under corporation nor limited partnership.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"corporation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"partnership.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"limited partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Three of the following are alike. Which one which does not fit with the others?",hint:"A grant deed is not an encumbrance. The other three are encumbrances.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Easement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lien",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Judgment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Grant deed",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A notary public may legally notarize a document if it is:",hint:"Cannot notarize any instrument in which he has a personal interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a grant deed in which he is grantee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a mortgage in which he is mortgagee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a document being executed by a corporation of which he or she is an employee but he or she has no personal interest in the transaction.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an instrument in which he is a party.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The complete history of the ownership of property is referred to as:",hint:"Each instrument likened to the link in a chain. An accepted expression.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"abstract of title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"certificate of title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"chain of title.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"guarantee of title.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Plumber owned a lot that held an appurtenant easement over the neighboring property of Ms. Mars, giving him the right to run a sewer line across Ms. Mars property. If Mr. Plumber sells the lot to Mr. Sano, but does not mention the easement in his deed, the easement:",hint:'An appurtenance is defined as, "an incidental right attached to a principal property right and passing in possession with it." When Mr. Plumber transferred title to his lot to Mr. Sano he also transferred the appurtenant easement.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"remains with Mr. Plumber.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"transfers to Mr. Sano.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"reverts to Ms. Mars.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is lost by escheat.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not necessary to acquire title by adverse possession of unimproved land?",hint:"The requirement is to occupy, not necessarily to reside upon.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Minimum of five years' occupancy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Open and notorious use",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Color of title or claim of right",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Live on the property",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"After purchasing a home, Mr. Brown discovered that his neighbor's fence was 2 feet over the line on his property. His legal remedy is to bring a civil suit against:",hint:"Encroachment is a form of trespass and actionable in law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the title company from which he had purchased a standard policy of title insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"his neighbor, under the law of adverse possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the broker for failure to disclose the encroachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"his neighbor, for removal of the encroachment on grounds of trespass.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Personal property may be:",hint:"Any of the following apply with personal property. Personal property can be promised as security for a loan, it can be sold, it can be assessed for tax purposes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"hypothecated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"alienated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"assessed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A wife recorded a declaration of homestead on the community property without her husband's signature. Which of the following exemptions would the couple receive?",hint:'The law permits the wife to declare a homestead exemption on 1) her separate property, 2) the husband\'s separate property, and 3) the community property, all without the signature or consent of her husband. The "head of the household" exemption is $75,000; for disabled or persons 65 or over, the exemption is $100,000; and for all others $50,000.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Nothing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$75,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$45,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A homestead exemption has no effect on a:",hint:"A homestead exemption will not protect against 1) prior liens (those liens recorded before the homestead is recorded) and 2) secured liens (mortgages, trust deeds, mechanic's liens and the like).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mechanic's lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not necessary in a homestead declaration?",hint:"Length of residence is not required; know the three other requirements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Length of residency in California",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Residing on premises",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Name of spouse, if any",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Location or description of property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The recording of a homestead exemption does not always require identification of the:",hint:"Any of the others are required for identification on a homestead exemption.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"market value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"spouse (if married).",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"address.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"type of property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is true?",hint:"Recording does not make a deed valid, but creates the legal presumption that it has been delivered.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Recording a deed presumes delivery",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Recording makes a deed valid",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Delivery is not controlled by the intention of the grantor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A grantor need not have legal capacity",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"C.,C.,& R.s relates to:",hint:"Covenants, conditions, and restrictions are all in the category of restrictions.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"mechanic's liens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Commissioner's regulations.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"restrictions.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Building on the land of another is called an:",hint:"Encroachment is the illegal building, partially or wholly, on the land of another. It is a form of trespass. An encumbrance is a burden on the title.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"appurtenance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"encroachment.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"encumbrance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Unlawful Detainer action is for the offended:",hint:"Lessor files unlawful detainer after 3 day notice is properly given.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"lessee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lessor.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A lease is or may be:",hint:"A lease for even one month is still considered an estate for years. A lease is an estate in real property and, since you do not hold title under a lease, it is a less-than-freehold estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an estate for years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate in real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a less-than-freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When a lease is assigned, the assignee becomes a(n):",hint:"When a lease is assigned, the primary liability shifts to the assignee and he becomes a tenant. When a leased property is sublet, the primary liability remains with the original lessee and the person to whom the property is sublet becomes the sublessee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"tenant.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"lessor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"landlord.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"assignor.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would identify a rider?",hint:"A rider is an addition or an amendment to an existing document.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"People",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Amendment",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Encroachment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Donee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not considered an appurtenance?",hint:"A trade fixture remains personal property and is not an appurtenance. Note: Growing crops are personal property, not subject to real property taxation, but are appurtenant to the land while growing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Growing crops",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trade fixtures",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Fences",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trees",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When an insurance company cancels a policy, the refund is based on:",hint:"When the company cancels the refund is prorated. When the insured cancels the refund is short rated.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"pro rata.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"short rate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"forfeiture.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"full rebate.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The State of California does not recognize:",hint:"Joint tenancy, tenancy in common, and severalty are legal in California, but not estates of entirety.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"joint tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenancy in common.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estates in entirety.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"severalty estate.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not legally required of a lease?",hint:'"To let and demise" is a legal term but not legally required in a lease.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:'The legal expression "to let and demise"',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Signature of lessor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Description of property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Term of lease",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"One way to jointly hold title to real property is joint tenancy; another way would be:",hint:"Know 4 ways to hold real property jointly.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"tenancy in common.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"community property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenancy in partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Under a lease, who has the leasehold estate?",hint:"The lessor owns the property but the lessee has the leasehold estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Lessor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lessee",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Reversionary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Beneficiary",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is correct?",hint:"Just the opposite: Agriculture-51, city and non-agriculture-99.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Maximum lease on city property is 51 years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Maximum lease on agriculture property is 99 years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Maximum lease on non-agriculture is 51 years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A man and wife have a homestead exemption on their home. If the house were destroyed by fire, the exemption would be:",hint:"Only sale abandons the homestead exemption on the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"abandoned.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not abandoned.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"relinquished.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An easement that has been acquired by prescription may be terminated or extinguished by:",hint:"Any easement can be terminated by choices (a) and (b). One acquired by prescription can also be lost through non-use for five years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"merger of the dominant tenement and the servient tenement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"by written agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"by non-use for five years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The unities of possession, title, time, and interest are necessary in order to create which of the following types of ownership?",hint:"Remember that T.T.I.P. are unities of joint tenancy.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Tenancy in common",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Joint tenancy",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Community property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Severalty",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A Declaration of Restrictions is recorded by the:",hint:"In a condominium project, if there are restrictions imposed they are created and recorded by the project owner/developer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"project owner of a condominium project.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the unit owner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all unit owners in a condominium project.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Susan leases a residence from Mr. Schmaltz for a period of 4 months on a written lease. After the lease expires Susan retains possession of the property without the consent of Mr. Schmaltz. Susan holds:",hint:"The question itself states the definition of an estate at sufferance. Holding over after the expiration of a lease without the consent of the owner is an estate at sufferance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an estate at sufferance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an estate at will.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate for years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A Declaration of Homestead, if unrecorded, is:",hint:"A Declaration of Homestead, if unrecorded, has no effect at all. Therefore, it is void.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"effective against judgment creditor holder even though unrecorded.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under the provisions of the Interstate Subdivided Lands Act, can the buyer may rescind his offer within specified time limits, if he buys:",hint:"The law allows a buyer 14 days after signing a contract to purchase property in a land project to rescind the offer, with a full refund of any money paid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"land projects.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"condominium.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"stock cooperative project.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Franklin was given real property for the term of his natural life. Which of the following statements is incorrect?",hint:"A fee simple estate is the greatest interest one can hold in real property. A fee simple estate can be transferred by will, sold, or given away. Franklin holds a life estate which is a freehold estate even though it is only for his life and can only be willed if for the life of a third party. There is no third party hire; therefore, it could not be willed and is a lesser interest than fee simple.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Franklin has a freehold estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Franklin would have a fee simple estate",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The duration of this estate is only for the length of the life of Franklin",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The estate can be encumbered by Franklin, but only for the life of Franklin",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appurtenant easement is:",hint:"An appurtenant easement is an easement that may be created and is capable of being transferred. Hence, answer (d) is the best answer given.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"incapable of being transferred.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"incapable of being created.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a condition found in all grant deeds.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"capable of being transferred.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A perpetual estate or an estate of inheritance is the same as:",hint:"Another name for perpetual estate or an estate of inheritance is called an estate in fee simple, meaning the property may be transferred and willed and may be held indefinitely.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a grant estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate in fee simple.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a life estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Once a subdivider receives a final public report from the Real Estate Commission, that report is good for a period of:",hint:"The public report is valid for five years, with any material changes in the development reported to the commissioner, who then can issue an amendment to the original report.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"five years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"six years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"indefinitely.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A condominium is considered a subdivision if the airspace is divided into at least 5 units. This subdivision can be a(n):",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all correct; therefore, (d) is the best answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"industrial building.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commercial building.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"residential building.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The Street Improvement Act of 1911 allows land owners to do all of the following except:",hint:"According to the Street Improvement Act of 1911, land owners may not buy additional land for development.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"put in sewers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buy additional land for development as subdivision.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"improve sidewalks.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A lease to a lessee is comparable to that of:",hint:"A lease gives the lessee the right of possession and use of the property. Under a land contract the buyer also receives use and possession together with an additional right of future title.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a trust deed to a trustee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an affiant to a deponent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a land contract to the vendee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a mortgage to a mortgagee.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which term or terms would most completely commit the signers?",hint:"Jointly as a group and severally as individuals.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Individually",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Jointly",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Severally",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Jointly and severally",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When the state has given permission to a non-riparian rights owner of a farm to use a nearby lake, the owner has received this right by:",hint:"When the State of California gives permission to use nearby water supplies, they appropriate the right to the property owners that have requested the right to use the water.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"eminent domain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estoppel.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"percolation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appropriation.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Wright wants to make an improvement on his home that will not be in conformity with the deed restrictions for his neighborhood. If his neighbor wants to stop him from proceeding, he would obtain a(n):",hint:'The definition of the word "injunction" is a court order to restrain someone from doing a certain act.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"injunction.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"desist and refrain order.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"partition action.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"attachment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"It is said Real Estate has its own language. All of the following terms are closely related except:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) all relate to security devices in real estate. Tenants in common is a method of title vesting.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"alienation clause.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"hypothecation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"third trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenants in common.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following answers is incorrect in regard to a metes and bounds description?",hint:'The disadvantage of a metes and bounds description is its "lack of" simplicity.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An advantage of a metes and bounds description is its simplicity",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A metes and bounds description is a good method for describing irregular shaped parcels",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When there is not a recorded map of the property, metes and bounds is a good method to describe it",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"If there is a recorded map of the property, a metes and bounds description is still perfectly legal",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If you petition the City Planning Commission for a variance and it is rejected, which of the following would be true?",hint:"Definition: A variance is permission obtained from governmental zoning authorities to build a structure or conduct a use that is expressly prohibited by the current zoning laws; an exception from the zoning laws. Counties and/or municipalities generally enact their own zoning ordinances and requests for rezoning (i.e. a variance or exception to the zoning) may have to be directed toward a special zoning appeals board or other administrative body.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Appeal to the local city council or board of supervisors",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Accept the rejection and do nothing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Appeal to Superior Court",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Records at the county recorder's office are open for public inspection. Which of the following does not have to be accompanied by an employee of the county recorder's office when examining these public records?",hint:"Anyone can examine the public records of the County Recorder's office without being accompanied by a County Recorder's Office employee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Employees of the county recorder's office",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Attorneys",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Government officials",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"According to the Subdivided Lands Law of California, the Commissioner's Preliminary Report terminates:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) could immediately terminate a Preliminary Report according to Real Estate Commissioner's regulations.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"when the subdivider receives the Commissioner's Final Report.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"if any material change in the method of sales takes place.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one year from the date issued.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An easement is the right to use the land of another. With regard to easements, all of the following statements that appear are correct, except:",hint:'Be careful of this double negative. Even though the easement is unlocated, it is still "valid" because it was given by a deed.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an easement may be created by implication.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an unlocated easement given by the process of a deed is considered invalid.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a lessee may create an easement for a driveway over the land of another for ingress and egress purposes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assets, liabilities, and net worth are important items when running a business. The liabilities of a business are:",hint:"Answers (b), (c), and (d) are considered assets of a business.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"claims of the creditors.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"prepaid taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accounts receivable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cash on hand.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Considering the minimum building standards within a city, the state housing law is enforced by:",hint:"Local building inspectors enforce the construction regulations while local health officers enforce the occupancy and sanitation regulations.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"local planning commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"local building inspector.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"State Department of Housing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Department of Building and Safety.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume an easement appurtenant exists between two pieces of land which are separately owned:",hint:"The dominant tenement receives the easement, thereby benefiting from the easement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the servient tenement may revoke the use of the easement by giving proper notice.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the dominant tenement is benefited by the easement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the dominant tenement terminates due to separate ownership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"There are certain requirements to be met to make a homestead exemption valid. All of the following would cause a homestead to be invalid except:",hint:"In order for a homestead to be valid, you must live on the property at the time of recording the homestead. You may then rent the property and still keep the homestead in effect.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"renting the property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"recording a Declaration of Abandonment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"selling the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"transferring the title to the property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following may be homesteaded?",hint:"A homestead may be recorded on answers (b), (c), and (d). Therefore, answer (a) is the best answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"All of the following",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A duplex, half of which is owner occupied",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A condominium, residential",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A home in the country, including an adjoining gardening plot",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Easements are:",hint:"A non-money encumbrance is one that affects the use of property such as an easement, a building restriction, an encroachment or a lease.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"always appurtenant.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"possessory rights.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an encroachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an encumbrance.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"You are a subdivider and want to build a community apartment project or a condominium. You would comply with the Real Estate Commissioner's regulations when you plan to build how many units?",hint:"The Commissioner regulates subdivisions of five or more units.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"One",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Two",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Any amount",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Recording which of the following actions would give the least protection against a mechanic's lien?",hint:"Answers (b), (c), and (d) would have some effect on mechanics' liens. Answer (a) is a made-up answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Notice of accession",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Notice of completion",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Notice of non-responsibility",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Notice of cessation",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would not be an example of cloud on title?",hint:"Since the trust deed was not recorded, it would not create a cloud on title.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An unrecorded easement across the property for water use",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A trust deed that is paid off but not yet released from the records",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A locked-in clause in a trust deed that has not been recorded",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following best describes a less than freehold estate?",hint:"Answers (a) and (d) are freehold estates. Answer (b) describes a periodic tenancy. An estate for years is the only one that is a less than freehold estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Fee simple estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Estate from period to period",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Estate for years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Life estate",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If the lessee agrees to pay property taxes as well as rent, this would indicate a(n):",hint:"A net lease is on business property, whereby the tenant agrees to pay the rent and the taxes and insurance on the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"net lease.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"straight lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"percentage lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"acceleration lease.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A lessor and lessee agree to the terms and the lessor draws up a 5-year lease, signs it, and mails it to the lessee. The lessee does not sign it, but moves in and pays 2 months' rent. After 2 months, the lessee decides to move out and informs the lessor. Which of the following is true?",hint:"Lessee does not have to sign the lease to be bound to it as long as he either takes possession or pays rent in advance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"There is a valid lease as only the lessor has to sign",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"There is a valid lease as lessee had moved in and paid 2 months' rent",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The lease is invalid, as the Statute of Frauds states that a lease for more than 1 year must be in writing and signed by both the lessor and lessee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The lease is invalid as there is no contract to enforce",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is the primary tool used by a planning commission?",hint:"A planning commission is an official agency usually organized on the city, county, or regional level to develop a master (General) plan which is the basis of and sets all community development decisions (land use proposals). The land use proposals outlined in a General Plan are implemented in many ways - zoning being the best known and most frequently used tool.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Eminent domain",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Adverse possession",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Zoning",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"General plan",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Limitations on the use of joint tenancy applies to:",hint:'Since a corporation does not "die" there could be no right of survivorship, therefore, a corporation may not hold title as joint tenants.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"two or more persons.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"husband and wife.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"corporations.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A recorded lien that can be collected on any or all property is:",hint:"Answers (b), (c), and (d) are collectable on specified properties only.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"general.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"specific.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mechanic's.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tax.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'A "fee" in real estate pertains to:',hint:"A fee simple absolute estate is the greatest interest an owner can have in real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an estate of inheritance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an estate for years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate at will.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commission.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'New words and definitions are constantly being added to the real estate language. "Prima facia" means:',hint:'"Prima facia" refers to the primary first trust deed as evidence of the law of priorities. Of the answers given, the state exam prefers "primary evidence" as the correct answer.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"first in priority.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"primary evidence.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"front of the house.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"principal.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Real property acquired through accession would most likely be by:",hint:"If you lived next to a river and the edge of your property continues to get larger through the deposit of soil, this newly acquired property is a result of accretion and title to it becomes yours by accession.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"adverse possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accretion.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"dedication.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"prescription.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following statements of fact best matches the term "lien?"',hint:"Definition: A lien is an obligation to pay a money encumbrance that may be voluntary or involuntary.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Contract of leasing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of conveyance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of money",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Contract of pledge",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following statements of fact best matches the term "surrender?"',hint:"When a tenant voluntarily gives up a lease before the expiration of its term, it is know as surrender. A lease is a combination of both a conveyance and a contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Contract of leasing",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Contract of conveyance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of money",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of pledge",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following statements of fact best matches the term "judgments?"',hint:"Judgments are “money” encumbrances - final determinations by the court of the rights of parties in a lawsuit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Contract of leasing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of conveyance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of money",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Contract of pledge",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following statements of fact best matches the term "patent?"',hint:"Definition: A patent is the document used by the government to transfer (or convey) title to land instead of using a deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Contract of leasing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of conveyance",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Contract of money",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of pledge",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following statements of fact best matches the term "sandwich?"',hint:"A sublease transfers possession of a leased property to a new person called the sublessee, who is liable only to the sublessor (original tenant), who is primarily liable for paying the rent to the owner. This type of lease is called a sandwich lease: sublessee - sublessor - owner.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Contract of leasing",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Contract of conveyance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of money",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of pledge",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Regarding a lease, which of the below-mentioned items is an implied covenant?",hint:'The words "implied covenant" mean an "unwritten promise." Of the four answers given, "quiet enjoyment" would be covenant in a lease that would not appear in writing.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Tenancy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Term of lease",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Termination of lease",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Quiet enjoyment",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'An "unlawful detainer action" can be instituted in all of the following ways, except:',hint:"An unlawful detainer action can only be had in court, never at a trustee's sale (out of court).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"in court.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to obtain a writ of possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to evict a tenant who refuses to pay rent and to move.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at a trustee's sale.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'If the purchasers of real property have the title to the property placed in the name of "John Little and Mary Little, husband and wife," it is presumed that they hold title to the property as:',hint:"The fact that marital status is given as husband and wife and is not further designated as a joint tenancy places the holding as community property. You cannot have a joint tenancy unless the designation is spelled out in the deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"joint tenants.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"community property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"tenants in common.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"severalty.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An unlocated easement that is recorded is:",hint:"Even though the easement is unlocated, if it is recorded, it is valid. Example: Cut across my property anywhere to get to the street.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unenforceable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A government patent is which of the following?",hint:"A government patent is a deed that conveys title.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A conveyance",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A patent on land processing which the government invented",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A lien against real property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An encumbrance on real property imposed by the government",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following agencies mentioned, which has the authority to hear complaints of discrimination in housing?",hint:"Violations of discrimination in the sale, rental or financing of practically all types of housing are reported to the state Department of Fair Employment and Housing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real Estate Board",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Fair Relations Commission Board",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Department of Fair Employment and Housing",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Noro bought a property using a purchase money trust deed. A few years later he sold the property to Ms. Hassen for all cash. Which of the following would not be disclosed by the public records?",hint:"Since Ms. Hassen paid all cash for the property, there would be no need for a reconveyance deed to Ms. Hassen. Therefore, it would not appear on public records.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A grant deed to Mr. Noro",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The original trust deed that Mr. Noro used in purchasing the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A reconveyance deed to Mr. Noro",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A reconveyance deed to Ms. Hassen",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"As relating to real estate, a patent is:",hint:"A sovereign grant refers to the government patent deed which transfers title to government land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an invention.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"same as a land contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a sovereign grant.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Another name for a chattel real is:",hint:"Definition: An item of personal property which is connected to real estate; for example, a lease.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fixture.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lease.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When a person hires real property from its owner and is given an exclusive right to use, he or she is a:",hint:"A less-than freehold estate (also called a leasehold estate) is an estate owned by a tenant who rents real property, has exclusive possession and use for a fixed period of time.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"lodger.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"renter.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenant.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"licensee.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A corporation could hold title to real property with another in all except which of the following ways?",hint:"Since a corporation is a legal person and will never die, it cannot hold title as a joint tenant with another. There can never be a right of survivorship with a corporation if the corporation is never going to die. If the corporation holds title by itself, it is in severalty but if held with another it can be in common or in partnership.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Joint tenancy",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Tenants in common",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Partnership",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A receipt for a Preliminary Public Report must be kept by the subdivider for:",hint:"Before a developer can sell each lot in the project, he or she must give a copy of the Commissioner's Final Public Report to the buyer for approval. The buyer signs a receipt stating that it has been read and the seller (developer/subdivider) must keep a copy of the statement for three years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"3 years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"2 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"You are the owner of a residence and have homesteaded your property. One year later you sell this property and purchase another home in the same county and homestead this property. If a judgment were rendered against you at this time, which property would be protected by homestead?",hint:"Since the original property was sold, the homestead on that property was terminated. Therefore, the property that is now homesteaded is protected.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The second property",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The first property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both properties",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Answers (b) and (c) above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The basic regulations of the housing and construction industries in this state are accomplished by the:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) all regulate the housing and construction industries in the state; therefore, answer (d) is the best answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"State Contractors License Law.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"local building codes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Housing Act.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any or all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"C. C. R.'s are usually contained in which of the following documents?",hint:"If there are any covenants, conditions, and restrictions of record, they would be found in the deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Deeds",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Contracts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Listings",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume the telephone company has an easement on a property being sold by a broker but it is not mentioned in the grant deed. The easement is:",hint:"All easements are considered to be an encumbrance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an encumbrance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"telephone companies are not allowed easements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"invalid.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under the law, there are certain instruments that are not effective against mechanic's liens. Which of the following would be effective against a mechanic's lien?",hint:"Answers (b) and (c) would set time limits on the filing of mechanic's liens but would not be effective against them. However, a notice of non-responsibility is effective against mechanic's liens.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Notice of non-responsibility",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Notice of cessation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Notice of completion",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which is not considered real property?",hint:"Same as owning shares of stock in a corporation and is considered personal property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Mineral oil and gas rights",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Airspace over a property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Shares in a real estate syndicate owning real property",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Trees and shrubbery",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The majority of leases end by:",hint:"The majority of leases end by the expiration of the agreed-upon lease term or by mutual agreement between the landlord and tenant.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"eviction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reliction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"abandonment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"expiration of term.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"All of the following will terminate a lease except:",hint:"Other ways to terminate a lease are destruction of the premises, breach of conditions by either lessor or lessee, or eviction. A sale of the property during the term of the lease does not usually terminate the lease.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"expiration of term.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mutual agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"eviction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sale of the property.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Two friends can hold title together:",hint:"A fee simple estate is the greatest interest one can have in real property. It does not mean that two persons cannot hold title as joint tenants or as tenants in common. There is no reason why this interest may not be in a fee simple estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"as joint tenants in real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"as tenants in common in real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in a fee simple estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in any of the above ways.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The priority of a mechanic's lien dates from the commencement of the construction. A mechanic's lien need not be recorded to be effective.",hint:"The priority of any mechanic's lien dates from the commencement time of the work. All mechanic's lien holders are on a parity with each other but will precede any subsequent liens from the date construction begins; this means the first statement is true. A mechanic's lien must not only be recorded, but verified, to be effective. This makes the second statement false.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Both statements are true",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The first statement is true and the second statement is false",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The first statement is false and the second statement is true",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both statements are false",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"There are certain requirements for a valid Declaration of Homestead. All of the following are requirements of the law, except:",hint:"When declaring a homestead, it is not necessary to divulge the purchase price.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a verification as to the cost of the property when purchased.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a description of the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a statement showing the declarer is a single person, if that is the case.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a statement that the declarer is residing on the property when declaring the homestead.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Rebecca bought a home that did not meet existing building codes, but was allowed to use it as a non-conforming building under what clause of the building code?",hint:"If a building or part of a building was built before the building code existed, it may remain as is, or grandfathered, until any material change takes place. At that time it must be brought up to code.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Grandfather clause",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Due on sale clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subrogation clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"After-use clause",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Prescription is a method of acquiring which of the following?",hint:"Easements may be created in many ways. Prescription is one method of creating easements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Medical drugs from a pharmacist",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Easements",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Utility rights",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A lessor and lessee agree to the terms and the lessor draws up a 5-year lease, signs it, and mails it to the lessee. Lessee does not sign it, but moves in and pays 2 months' rent. After 2 months, lessee decides to move out and informs lessor. Which of the following is true?",hint:"Lessee does not have to sign the lease as long as he pays rent in advance or takes possession of the premises.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"There is an invalid lease as only the lessor has to sign",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"There is a valid lease, as lessee had moved in and paid 2 months' rent",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The lease is invalid, as the Statute of Frauds states that a lease for more than one year must be in writing and signed by both the lessor and lessee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The lease is invalid as there is no contract to enforce",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following does not belong?",hint:"Restrictions and easements are appurtenant. They run with the land and cannot be transferred from the land. A declaration of homestead protects the owner's equity in his home and can be transferred from the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Homesteading",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Restrictions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Easements",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Appurtenance",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A sister and brother can hold title together:",hint:"A fee simple estate is the greatest interest one can have in real property. It does not mean that two persons cannot hold title as joint tenants or as tenants in common, and there is no reason why this interest may not be in a fee simple estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"as joint tenants in real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"as tenants in common in real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in a fee simple estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in any of the above ways",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An appurtenance is:",hint:"Transfers with the land. Stock in a mutual water company would be the water rights of the land and must transfer with the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an easement in gross.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"stock in a mutual water company.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The individual who holds title to real property has possession of the land, has the right to dispose of it during one's life or upon death, and can impose a condition or restriction on its future use, is said to hold a:",hint:"A fee simple estate is the greatest interest one can hold in real property. It can be willed, sold, encumbered, given away, and restrictions can be placed upon it, limiting its future use.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"life estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fee simple estate.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"less than freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenancy in sufferance.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What transfers less than an entire leasehold, with the original lessee being primarily liable for the rental agreement?",hint:"A sublease transfers possession of a leased property to a new person call the sublessee. The original tenant, who is now the sublessor, is still primarily liable for paying the rent to the owner.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Sublease",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Sandwich lease",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Residential lease",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Assignment",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The opposite of "alluvium" is:',hint:"Alluvium is the deposit of sand or soil by accretion. Erosion is the gradual wearing away of soil through the action of running water.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"accretion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"substitution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"erosion.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"acceleration.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is considered to be personal property?",hint:'An existing mortgage is a piece of paper, which is movable, and is classified as personal property. Both easements and mineral rights are appurtenant to (means "belonging to") the land and are termed real property. Growing trees are attached to the land and are real property.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An easement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mineral rights",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An existing mortgage",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Trees growing in a forest",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The recording of a lease is usually paid for by the:",hint:"The lessee is the person that receives an estate for years and may want to record the lease as a matter of record. Keep in mind, the person who benefits from the recording pays for the recording.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"vendee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"grantor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lessee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"lessor.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A joint tenant can do which of the following regarding his interest in real property?",hint:"There is only one thing a joint tenant cannot do with his interest--will it.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Lease it",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sell it",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A joint tenant may do all of the following with his interest except:",hint:"The only thing a joint tenant cannot do with his interest is will it.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"lease it.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"will it.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"sell it.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"give it away.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A minor is:",hint:"Parties entering into a contract must have legal capacity to do so. A person must be at least 18 years of age, married, in the military, or declared emancipated by the court. A minor - a person under 18 years of age - is not considered legally capable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an incompetent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"someone under l8 years of age.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"someone under 2l years of age.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"someone emancipated.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Four widowers wish to buy a parcel of real property and hold title in such a way that, in the event of the death of the various parties, the last survivor would own it as his sole and separate property. To be certain of this, title should be held:",hint:"The right of survivorship exists in a joint tenancy holding. The marital status at the time of the purchase has no effect in this instance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"in severalty.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"as joint tenants.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"as tenants in common.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in fee simple.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A certain easement lies outside of and adjoins the land which it benefits. The land benefited would be the:",hint:"The owner of the easement controls the use of the adjoining land and dominates its use. The property subject to the easement serves the easement holder.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"dominant tenement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"servient tenement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"encumbered fee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"property subject to the easement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A landowner is advised that a railroad company plans to cross his property with a railroad line. If the landowner refuses, the railroad company can proceed by the use of:",hint:"The law delegates the right to eminent domain to public utility companies.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"police action.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"eminent domain.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"accretion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"partition action.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A lease beginning March 1, 1991, and terminating June 30, 1991, is:",hint:"A leasehold having a definite termination date is an estate for years, no matter how short the term.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a periodic tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate at will.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate for years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Condominium projects are expected to grow in demand in the future due to which basic factor?",hint:"Although high property taxes will force more individuals out of single family residences, the scarcity of land will be the major factor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Taxes",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Scarcity of land",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Comfort",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sociability",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How long does a landlord have to return unused portions of the security deposit after a tenant has moved out?",hint:"The landlord has 21 days after the tenant has moved to return all unused portions of the security deposit, with a written statement showing how the remainder was used (to clean, repair damage, replace windows, etc.).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"14 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"21 days",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"3 months",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4 months",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the sale of real property which of the following runs with the land?",hint:"All are appurtenant, incident to, and run with the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Easements",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Conditions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Stock in a mutual water company",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The maximum deposit allowed on an unfurnished property is not more than the amount of:",hint:"The maximum deposit allowed on an unfurnished property is not more that the amount of two months rent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"one month's rent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two months' rent.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"three months' rent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"four months' rent.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The right of the landlord to reclaim the property after the lease has expired is known as:",hint:"The landlord continues to own the property and has only given the tenant the right to use the property. Appropriation refers to taking a public thing for private use. Surrender refers to the tenant giving the leased property back to the landlord before the expiration of the lease.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"reversionary right.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"remainder.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"right of appropriation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"surrender.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A subdivider, after compliance with the Map Act and obtaining a Final Public Report, sells 5 lots to one person and gives an option to buy 5 lots to another person. By law he is required to:",hint:"Subdivider meets the requirements of both the Subdivision Map Act and the Subdivided Lands Law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"immediately notify the Commissioner of the sale and the option.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"immediately notify the Commissioner of the option only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"immediately notify the Commissioner of the sale only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"provide no further notice, because it is not required. He has complied with both laws governing subdivided lands.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Riparian is:",hint:"Riparian rights are to the reasonable use of water adjoining an owner's property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the doctrine of correlative user.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"absolute water rights of the adjoining land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the right of a landowner to the reasonable use of the adjoining water.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Recording a deed gives:",hint:"Recordation gives constructive, or public, notice.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"public notice.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"objective notice.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"actual notice.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"factual notice.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The legal seizure of property for debt before judgment is:",hint:"Seizure of property by court order before court action is a writ of attachment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"writ of execution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"writ of attachment.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"lis pendens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An executrix is appointed by the:",hint:"An executor is the man and the executrix is the woman named in the will of the deceased to handle the affairs of the deceased. If none is named or if there is no will, the court appoints an administrator.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"probate court.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"heirs of the deceased.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deceased's attorney.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deceased.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Under a normal month-to-month rental, how much notice must a tenant give when moving out?",hint:"A tenant who pays monthly rent payments must give 30-days written notice before moving out, unless there is an agreement otherwise.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"90 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"60 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30 days",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"10 days",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How often may a tenant make needed repairs and deduct the amount from the rent?",hint:"A tenant can make needed repairs and deduct them from the rent twice a year.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Never",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Once a year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Twice a year",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Three times a year",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The topography of land is the defining of its surface features. A subdivider must give consideration to the topography of the proposed subdivided lands because:",hint:"Irregularities refer to hills or slopes on the land. Homes with a view or at least not on the same level as the other homes in the same neighborhood usually are more desirable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"some irregularities in the surface are desirable.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"hilly or irregularly shaped lots reduce the cost of construction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a rolling terrain is more monotonous than a flat terrain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"elevated lots are subject to inundation in the winter.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A husband and wife owned their home as joint tenants. The husband signed an exclusive authorization and right to sell listing agreement with a broker without disclosing the manner of title holding in the property and without his wife's signature on the listing. In the event of a commission dispute, the broker:",hint:"The husband binds the community as statutory manager when he fails to disclose the joint tenancy holding.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"may bring action to force the wife to sell her interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may sue the husband separately in civil court for his commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"has no right to a commission because he failed to obtain the wife's signature on the listing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may bring court action against the community estate.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"One who holds property in joint tenancy with another or others may:",hint:"Read the choices carefully; you will find that (a) is the only possible answer. A joint tenant may not will his interest as indicated in (b). He may not own a lesser interest (c); all must be equal. He may sell his interest, or give it away, or encumber it during his lifetime, without the consent of the other joint tenants.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"sell his interest in the property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"will his interest in the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"hold a lesser interest than the other joint tenants.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not transfer his interest in any manner without the consent of the joint tenants.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume that a property was sold for $20,000 and the buyer assumed the existing first trust deed and note of $8,000, the existing second trust deed of $4,000, and executed a new third trust deed and note in favor of seller for $2,000. Shortly after the purchase, payments were not made on either the second trust deed or the third trust deed and the beneficiary of the second trust deed recorded a notice of default and sent a copy to the seller. Upon receipt of the notice, the seller could take action and obtain:",hint:'The seller already has a lien with his trust deed and note. Since he cannot obtain an attachment nor a judgment (this is a purchase money trust deed), the answer is "none of the above".',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a judgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A person hiring personal property is similar to:",hint:'Payment for the temporary possession or use of a house or other property is usually referred to as "rent." The word "hire" is used to mean the same thing.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a mortgagor executing a mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a lessee signing a lease.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a trustor signing a trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a buyer executing a trust deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All except one of the following terms is usually associated with the real estate profession. Which term does not belong in this group?",hint:"Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Estate for years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Fee estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Parol",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Life estate",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is an expense or loss to a homeowner in owning a home?",hint:"Interest that the homeowner might have earned from a bank savings account on his cash down payment and subsequent payments on the principal (his equity) cannot be considered a loss. If the value of the lot decreased, however, he has suffered a loss.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Interest lost in equity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Reduction in the value of the lot",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Appreciation due to painting",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Increase",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is an example of a freehold estate?",hint:"A fee estate is one example of a freehold estate. The others are not.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Fee estate",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Estate at will",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Period to period",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Leasehold",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A charge imposed on real property is called a(n):",hint:"A lien can be described as a charge on real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"encumbrance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"quitclaim.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lien.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"covenant not to impose encumbrances.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Legally and technically, property is defined as:",hint:"This is a definition of property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"freehold estates.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"things which buyers/sellers own.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"rights/interests which a person has in a thing owned.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"only personal property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Is a separate contract, in addition to the grant deed, required for the sale of stock in a mutual water company?",hint:"Stock in a mutual water company is an appurtenance (real property). It runs with the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Yes, stock is always personal property and must be transferred with a bill of sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No, stock in a mutual water company can not be sold",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Yes, because stock in a mutual water company is chattel real",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No, water company stock runs with the land",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The degree, quality, nature, and extent of interest a person has in the property defines an estate in real property. An estate:",hint:"There can be more than one estate in real property. For example, a landlord holds a fee simple estate at the same time the tenant holds a less than freehold estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is never held in perpetuity.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"can be held with another estate in the same property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"can only be created by a deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must always be received by a grant.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following describes only real property?",hint:"Real property is generally immovable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Able to be held as joint tenants",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Immovable",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Subject to depreciation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Can be willed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which is not an appropriate characteristic of a fee simple estate?",hint:"A fee simple estate may have encumbrances, as it is not always free of encumbrances.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It is always free of encumbrances",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It is indefinite duration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is transferable with or without consideration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is transferable by will",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mineral rights in land are:",hint:"Mineral rights in land are automatically transferred with the land, unless expressly excluded by a grantor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"automatically transferred.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"not leased.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"kept by the original owner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"conveyed apart from the surrounding land.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A fee simple estate may be described as:",hint:"A fee simple estate is the most interest one may hold in land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a title without limitations.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate for years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a life estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the most interest one may hold in land.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An estate of inheritance is a(n):",hint:"An estate in fee is another name for the estate of inheritance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"fee simple determinable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estate at sufferance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estate in fee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"probate estate.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Personal property can be:",hint:"Personal property can be alienated, hypothecated, or be changed into real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"alienated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"hypothecated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"changed into real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A grant deed that allows someone to retain property so long as alcohol is not consumed on the property is:",hint:'A fee simple defeasible has a clause in the deed (such as "no alcohol" on property), which, if violated, causes the property to revert back to the grantor.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"fee simple absolute.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estate in forfeiture.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fee simple defeasible.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"less than a freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A transfer of possession of real property, but not ownership, is called a(n):",hint:"A sublease transfers possession, but not ownership of real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sublease.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"security agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are real property except:",hint:"Leasehold estate in real property are the personal property of the lessee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"unextracted crude oil.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leasehold estates in residential real property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"uncultivated grove of trees.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easements appurtenant.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of these notices is important for a mechanic's lien?",hint:"All of these notices start the running of a limited period of time in which to file a mechanic's lien and are therefore very important.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Notice of non-responsibility",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Notice of cessation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Notice of completion",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'The right of "quiet enjoyment and possession" means the landlord must protect the tenant from:',hint:'The right of quiet enjoyment possession requires a landlord to defend a tenant from someone claiming "paramount title."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"all nuisance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"possession without disturbance from someone claiming paramount title.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all encumbrances.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Sam has a life estate and leases it to Tony on a 5 year lease. Sam dies 1 year later. The lease was valid for a total of:",hint:"A life tenant may lease out a life estate, but the lease terminates automatically when the life tenant dies.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1 year.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"5 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"0 years, as one cannot lease a life estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The correct method for a landlord to evict a delinquent tenant is by:",hint:"A landlord would bring an unlawful detainer action in court.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"giving him three days notice.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"giving him thirty days notice.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"calling the police.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"bringing a court action.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lien that covers all real property of the debtor in the county where it is recorded is called:",hint:"A general lien is a lien which encumbers all real property of the debtor in the county where it is recorded.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a lis pendens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a general lien.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a specific lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is considered to be both personal and revocable?",hint:"The license is the personal and revocable permission to do something on the land of another.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Encroachment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Easement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"License",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Option contract",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The time period when a lis pendens is effective is:",hint:"A lis pendens is effective once it is recorded. This includes the time before trial is held, until the lawsuit is dismissed, or until final judgment is rendered.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"before the trial is held.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"until the lawsuit is dismissed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"until the final judgment is rendered.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in any of the above situations",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Who is responsible for assuring completion of paved streets, utilities, and curbs in a new subdivision?",hint:"The developer usually has the responsibility for completing the streets, utilities, and curbs in a new subdivision.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The developer",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The city",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The county",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The federal government",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The primary purpose of a master plan is to show the location of:",hint:"The master plan usually shows all of these things and more.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"commercial, industrial, and residential districts.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"public streets.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"seismic safety zones.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"All of the following terminate easements, except:",hint:"The owner of the servient tenement does not have the power to revoke an easement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"destruction of the servient tenement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"merger of the dominant and servient tenement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"revocation by the owner of the servient tenement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"express release by the owner of the dominant tenement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A major difference between an easement and a license is that a license is:",hint:"The major difference between an easement and a license is that a license can be revoked.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"assignable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"with indefinite duration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"written.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"revocable.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What is the general purpose of a building code?",hint:"The general purpose of a building code is to provide minimum construction standards.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Assure utilization of skilled labor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Assure compliance with regulatory agencies",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Provide minimum construction requirements",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Guarantee cost effectiveness",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Individuals do not normally have:",hint:"Governments, not individuals, are given the power of eminent domain.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"ability to sever property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"riparian rights.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"power of eminent domain.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"reliction rights.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which is the least satisfactory in providing a legal description?",hint:"The property tax bill uses an assessors number, not a legal description.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The escrow instructions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A standard title insurance policy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A recorded grant deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A property tax bill for real property",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A condo owner's interest payments against the common area of his development:",hint:"In a planned development subdivision the owner has title to the unit and the land under it, together with membership in an association which owns common area. Each unit owner has a deed, separate financing and pays the property taxes for their unit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is his responsibility severally and jointly.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may be deducted from his taxes.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"are optional.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cause a reduction in the principal amount owed on his loan.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The court action used to evict a tenant who is in default is known as:",hint:"Unlawful detainer action or action in ejectment is the legal remedy to remove a tenant who defaults on the rent or refuses to give up the premises.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"surrender.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an ejectment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an unlawful detainer action.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"One joint tenant may dispose of her interest by all of the following, except:",hint:"A joint tenant may not will her interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"will",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"gift",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lease",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In order to create a valid joint tenancy, there is a requirement for:",hint:"A joint tenancy requires equal ownership interests.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:'the clause "with right of survivorship."',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a husband and wife relationship.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"equal ownership interests.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Unlike a joint tenancy, the tenancy in common requires only one unity, which is the unity of:",hint:"The only unity required for a tenancy in common is the unity of possession.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"time.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"possession.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When four persons own one piece of real estate in joint tenancy, they:",hint:"All joint tenants share one title.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"do not have equal shares.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have one title.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"allow their heirs to obtain their shares by will.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have each co-ownership with separate title.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'An "abstract of title" is:',hint:'An "abstract of title" is the written summary of the chain of title.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a standard form.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an exact duplicate of the standard title policy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is not available to the owner of the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a written summary of the chain of title.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Who signs a quitclaim deed?",hint:"Anyone who signs a deed can be called a grantor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The property owner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The occupant",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The grantor",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Implied covenants are not normally included in a:",hint:"The quitclaim deed contains no implied covenants.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"grant deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"quitclaim deed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"warranty deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all deeds include express warranties",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a judgment has been recorded, it provides:",hint:"Recording a judgment gives constructive notice.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"voidable notice",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"constructive notice",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"actual notice",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"contingent notice",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Jake sells his home to Jerry who sets up his residency but fails to record the deed. Jake then gives a deed to Sunny for the same home. What is the outcome?",hint:"The act of Jerry's taking possession gives constructive notice of his rights.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Sunny owns the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Jerry and Sunny are co-owners",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sunny has recourse over Jerry",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Jerry has title",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A valid written lease must include:",hint:"Each of the choices describes a necessary element of a valid lease.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"agreement to let, agreement to take delivery, and acceptance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"term, consideration, and description of the premises.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a landlord and tenant with the legal capacity to enter a binding contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'When a legal description begins with the phrase, "Beginning at a point on the southerly edge of J Street 200 feet easterly of the SE corner of the intersection of J and Main Street, and running thence ...," which of the following methods of land description is being used?',hint:"This is the language of a metes and bounds description, which utilizes accurate survey techniques to describe the perimeter of a parcel.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Recorded tract map system",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"U.S. Government Township and Range Survey System",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"U.S. Government Rectangular Survey System",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Metes and bounds",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In tenancy in common, there is always a unity of:",hint:"Remember, all four are unities in a joint tenancy; only unity of possession is in a tenancy in common.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"time.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"possession.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A man bought a house in a hurry and discovered, after escrow closed, that a neighbor's fence, built two years ago, was three feet over the property line on his side. The broker was unaware of this. If the two neighbors were unable to reach an amicable settlement, the:",hint:"Encroachment of a permanent structure upon the soil of another is defined as a permanent trespass. The owner has three years in which to bring a court action.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"buyer could sue the title company under a standard form of title insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buyer could sue the neighbor for encroachment based on trespass.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"neighbor has acquired title by adverse possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buyer could hold the broker responsible.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Big leased a property for five years to Ms. Kimball. During this lease term, Mr. Big died and it was discovered by Ms. Kimball that Mr. Big's interest was a life estate. The owner of the property would be correct in advocating which of the following?",hint:"All interests in property which are imposed upon a life estate come to a halt when the life estate ends.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Ms. Kimball's leasehold estate is valid for the length of the lease",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Ms. Kimball's interest was terminated upon Mr. Big's demise",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Mr. Big's devises would receive the fee title",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the owner has an estate in remainder",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The following words, "ambulatory," "legatee", and "codicil" would refer to which of the following?',hint:"Ambulatory means alterable. A legatee receives under a will. Codicil is an amendment to a will.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Will",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Charity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Easement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Statutory",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If you were called upon to list a property that was owned by an unincorporated church group, you would:",hint:"Check the by-laws and charter to establish who is authorized to employ the broker for and on behalf of the group.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"contact the person who was the president at the time the property was acquired.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have the group form a committee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"check the by-laws and charter.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is permitted to use the county recorder's office and records without the presence of the recorder's officer?",hint:"The records of the County Recorder's Office are open to the public and any party listed in choices (a), (b), or (c) is permitted to inspect the records.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Savings bank employees",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Members of tax assessor's office",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title company employees",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Any of these",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Landis owned two pieces of property and sold one parcel bordering on the road to Ms. Cowan, reserving in the deed an easement for ingress and egress to and from the remaining real property for himself. After 5 years of non-use, Landis attempted to use the easement, but was prohibited from doing so by Cowan. A court would rule in this case that:",hint:"Only an easement acquired by prescription may be lost through non-use.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the easement was forfeited because it was not used for 5 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the easement was still valid because non-use never terminates any type of easement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Ms. Cowan could institute a quiet title action on the easement and probably be successful.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the easement was still valid since it had been created by deed.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Four widowers wish to buy a parcel of real property and hold title in such a way that in the event of the death of the various parties, the last survivor would own it as his sole and separate property. To be certain of this, title should be held:",hint:"The right of survivorship exists in a joint tenancy holding. The marital status at the time of the purchase has no effect in this instance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"in severalty.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"as joint tenants.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"as tenants in common.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in fee simple.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An estate at sufferance would involve:",hint:"When a tenant stays on after the expiration of a lease against the will of the owner, the tenant holds an estate at sufferance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a lessee holding over without the consent of the landlord.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a tenant not making his payments during the term of his lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a lessor not living up to the terms of the lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A charge imposed on real property is called:",hint:"A lien may be called a charge on real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an encumbrance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a quitclaim.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a lien.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a covenant not to impose encumbrances.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The ownership rights and interest in real property are called:",hint:"Estates or fees describe the degree, quantity, nature, and extent of interest or ownership one has in real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"executory contracts.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estates or fees.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"land sales contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"liens.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The difference between real and personal property is that real property is:",hint:"The main difference between real and personal property is that real property is immovable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"held by two or more people as joint tenants.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"immovable.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"subject to depreciation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"capable of being willed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The term "riparian rights" refers to which of the following?',hint:"The owner of property bordering a stream or river has riparian rights or reasonable use of flowing water, providing it does not injure other riparian landowners.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Rights of the owner of property bordering a stream or river",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Rights of the owner of property bordering a forest",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Rights of the owner of property bordering a lake",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Rights of the owner of property bordering a meadow",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Shelving, cash registers, room partitions, or dressing room dividers in a business are known as:",hint:"Definition: Trade fixtures are items of personal property, such as shelves, cash registers, room partitions or wall mirrors, used to conduct a business.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"personal fixtures.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trade fixtures.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"fixtures.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"real property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Susan leases a residence from Mr. Sly for a period of 4 months on a written lease. After the lease expires, Susan retains possession of the property without the consent of Mr. Sly. Susan holds:",hint:"The question itself states the definition of an estate at sufferance. Holding over after the expiration of a lease without the consent of the owner is an estate at sufferance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an estate at sufferance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an estate at will.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate for years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is a less-than freehold estate?",hint:"Definition: The less-than-freehold estate (also called a leasehold estate) is owned by renters or tenants.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A life estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An estate of inheritance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A fee estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A leasehold estate",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Barbara grants to Peter a life estate, with the provision that upon the death of Peter, the property is to go back to Barbara. What kind of estate does Barbara hold?",hint:"Definition: Owner deeds property as a life estate to another person, which, upon that person's death, the property “reverts” to the owner. The other person is a “life tenant”, or the designated party on whom the life estate is based. The owner holds an “estate in reversion.”",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Estate in remainder",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Estate in reversion",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Fee simple qualified",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Life estate",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A homestead may be filed on real property wherever there are structural improvements. Which of the following properties would not be eligible for a homestead?",hint:"One of the requirements of a homestead is that you live on the property. A homestead may be filed on all of the other types of property listed in choices (a), (b), and (d).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An apartment house in which the declarant owns and lives in one of the units",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A dwelling with an adjacent vacant lot on which the owner later plans to build and rent the new addition",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A home that is presently under construction",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A single-family residence owned as a tenant in common with another",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appurtenance is:",hint:"Transfers with the land. Stock in a mutual water company would be the water rights of the land and must transfer with the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an easement in gross.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"stock in a mutual water company.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In absence of a will, the separate property of the decedent is divided:",hint:"It would be divided 1/2 to surviving spouse and 1/2 to one child. If there is more than one child, it is divided 1/3 to surviving spouse and 2/3 to children.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"equally among surviving spouse and children.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/2 to surviving spouse and 1/2 to the children.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/3 to surviving spouse and 2/3 to the children.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The term "et ux" means:',hint:'The term “et ux” is the Latin abbreviation for et uxor, meaning “and wife."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"without husband.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"and wife.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"nothing and is not used.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the sale of real property, which of the following runs with the land?",hint:"All are appurtenant, incident to, and run with the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Easements",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Conditions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Stock in a mutual water company",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are considered liens against real property except:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (d) are all liens used to collect money. Easements are not liens, they are considered to be encumbrances.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"unpaid real property taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"special assessment taxes that have gone to bond.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an easement appurtenant.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"recorded judgments.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you are a buyer and want to be protected against unrecorded encumbrances in the purchase of real property. You would:",hint:"The extended coverage policy covers the same items that an A.L.T.A. policy covers, but the extended coverage policy insures the buyer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"obtain a extended coverage policy.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"obtain a standard policy of title insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ask the seller to give you a written guarantee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"write this agreement in the standard deposit receipt.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An attachment lien is normally valid for a maximum period of:",hint:"An attachment is valid for three years, unless it is extended by order of the court.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"six months.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"three years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"four years.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. John gives a life estate to her sister for the life of Charlie, her sister's friend. The life tenant dies. What interest does Ms. John hold in the property?",hint:"When Charlie dies the estate will revert back to Ms. John.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Remainder interest",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Fee simple estate",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Reversionary interest",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In order for a homestead to be invalidated in California:",hint:"This is the only automatic way to abandon a homestead. The only other way is to record an abandonment of homestead.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"move from the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"move from the property and take up residence in another state.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the house is 3/4 destroyed by fire.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sell the property and purchase two rental units.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A license differs from an easement in that a license can:",hint:"A license right cannot be transferred or terminated. A license right may be revoked with cause where an easement may not be revoked. The key words to a license right are that it is personal, unassignable, and revocable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"be revoked.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"be transferred.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be terminated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Title vested as Bill and Wilma Bloom, husband and wife, will be presumed:",hint:'Title vested in "husband and wife" would be presumed community property.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"community property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"joint tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenancy in common.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A fee simple estate is most likely to be a:",hint:"Most likely is a fee simple absolute which is the maximum interest obtainable. If it were a fee simple defeasible, the title could be defeated, which is not the maximum interest obtainable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leasehold.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"less-than-freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"maximum interest obtainable.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which one of the following is not a type of concurrent ownership?",hint:"Ownership in severalty is ownership by one person or entity.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Joint tenancy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Tenancy in common",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Community property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Severalty",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'"A" leases property from "B" for a period of five years. During the five-year period, "B" dies. It now comes out that "B" held a life estate on the property and the owners in remainder want "A" out. "A" contends that the lease is still valid. Which of the following is correct?',hint:"Life estate in reversion.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The lease is valid for the remainder of the five-year period",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'The lease is void because "B" only held a life estate',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'The new owners have the right to want "A" out because the lease expired on "B"\'s death',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The authority given by law for a creditor to obtain a charge or a debt from a debtor is in the broadest sense of the term a:",hint:"The authority given by law or by court action is a judgment. An attachment, when allowed, is received prior to the judgment. When a judgment is recorded, it becomes a lien.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"judgment.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"judgment and attachment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following is incorrect in regards to a "metes and bounds" description?',hint:'The "metes" are measurements and the "bounds" are the boundaries.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Using a river as a boundary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Using a fence and edge of a farm as a boundary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Using rocks and trees as boundaries",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"Metes" are boundaries and "bounds" are measurements',isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Jones leased an apartment for 5 years. 6 months later he moved out. The landlord may do any of the following, except:",hint:"The lessor cannot sue for the rent until it becomes due.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"try to find a new tenant and credit the rent to Mr. Jones' account.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leave the apartment vacant and immediately sue Mr. Jones for the remaining 4-1/2 years' rent.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"leave the apartment vacant and sue Mr. Jones for each installment as it becomes due.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"move into the apartment himself.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What do community property and joint tenancy have in common?",hint:"With right of survivorship one cannot will his share. Both parties have a right to will their share of community property if they wish to. Both community property and joint tenancy have equal interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Right of survivorship",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Equal interest.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"There is a strict legal procedure of law for the attainment of a judgment. The legal procedure that is dependent on the rendering of a judgment is:",hint:"Answers (b) and (c) are awarded to the attainment of a judgment. Answer (a), a Writ of Execution, is awarded after a judgment is obtained; therefore, it is dependent upon a judgment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a Writ of Execution.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a preliminary injunction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a Writ of Attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Myra gives her brother a life estate for his life, thereafter to revert back to Myra. He later gets married to Mona. Two years later he dies. What would become of the estate?",hint:"Reverts back to original grantor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It would be an estate in remainder",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It would be an estate in reversion",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Mona would inherit the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Myra would inherit the property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property located at 147 James Street, Sacramento, California, which is near the corner of Broadway and 3rd Avenue and measures 140' x 200', is:",hint:"External characteristics of a property include location, size, corner influence, thoroughfare condition, exposure, orientation, plottage increment, shape, topography and soil, as well as quality of conveniences; availability of schools, shopping, public transportation, churches; and similarity of land use. These are also known as physical characteristics or a physical description.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a legal description.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a metes and bounds description.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a lot, tract, and map description.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a physical description.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lease where the lessee pays the property taxes is:",hint:"Leases are classified by method of rent payments. By definition, in a net lease, the tenant pays a agreed-upon sum as rent, plus certain agreed-upon expenses per month (i.e., taxes, insurance, and repairs).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a graduated lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a sandwich lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a net lease.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a net-net lease.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, all are considered real property except:",hint:'Answers (a) and (b) are considered appurtenant to real property, therefore considered real property. Mortgages, however, are pieces of paper, thereby "movable" items and hence personal property.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"easements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"riparian rights.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mortgages.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How is title perfected when property is acquired by adverse possession?",hint:"A person acquiring property by adverse possession must get a quiet title action in the court to obtain clear title to the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"By quiet title action",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"By a writ of execution",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"By prescription",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"By recording a deed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The Civil Code of California states: "The thing of which there may be ownership is called property." Property is divided into two classes: real and personal. All of the following are correct statements concerning property except:',hint:"Answers (b), (c), and (d) are true statements. Things immovable are real property. Personal property is anything movable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"things immovable by law are considered personal property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"sub-surface oil and gas are real property and the real property rights thereto may be deeded separately from the surface rights.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"personal property may become real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"growing crops may be real property or personal property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A joint tenant can do which of the following regarding his interest in real property?",hint:"There is only one thing a joint tenant cannot do with his interest. That is will it.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Lease it",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sell it",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A life estate is limited to the life of its owner or the life or lives of one or more designated persons. All of the following are correct statements except:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all rights of a life estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a life estate is a freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the holder of a life estate is entitled to all the rents and profits from the land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the holder may dispose of his life estate by sale or lease and encumber it.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"there may be only one estate existing in a life estate at the same time and under the same circumstances.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Assume the telephone company has an easement on a property being sold by a broker but it is not mentioned in the grant deed. The easement is:",hint:"All easements are considered to be an encumbrance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an encumbrance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"telephone companies are not allowed easements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"invalid.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"There are certain requirements for a valid declaration of homestead. All of the following are requirements of the law except:",hint:"When declaring a homestead, it is not necessary to divulge the purchase price.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a verification as to the cost of the property when purchased.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a description of the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a statement showing the declarer is a single person, if that is the case.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a statement that declarer is residing on the property when declaring the homestead.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would be least likely to include a legal description of a parcel of real estate?",hint:"Property tax bills use an assessor parcel number, not a legal description. The other documents will contain a legal description.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A grant deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A property tax bill",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Escrow instructions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A preliminary title report",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Whether an item is a fixture is important when land is bought or sold or when a lease expires. Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning fixtures?",hint:"Fixtures are personal property that has been attached to the land so as to become a part of the land, thus making them real property. One exception, however, is trade fixtures are always personal property no matter how attached. Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all incorrect statements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A fixture is a type of personal property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A trade fixture is a type of real property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A mirror in an entry hall or a knickknack shelf in a kitchen are fixtures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The fact that an item is permanently attached to real property does not in all cases indicate that the item is a fixture",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A brother and sister hold title to real property as joint tenants. The sister gets married and deeds half her interest in the property to her husband. Her husband:",hint:'When a joint tenant conveys a portion of his interest, the joint tenancy is not affected insofar as the original remaining joint tenants are concerned. They continue as joint tenants to each other with the "stranger" holding as a tenant in common. However, when, as in this case, the remaining joint tenants no longer have an equal interest in the property, the joint tenancy is dissolved and it becomes a tenancy in common.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"owns no interest in the property as she may not deed an undivided interest in the property without her brother's consent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"would be a co-tenant in the property but would have rights of survivorship only as to a 1/3 interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"would be a joint tenant but only as to a 1/4 undivided interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"would be a tenant in common.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'"A" deeds a property to "B" who takes possession of the property but fails to record his deed. "A" then deeds the same property to "C" who bought the property without inspecting it. However, "C" recorded his deed. The result would be:',hint:'The first party to buy and take possession of the land would be the rightful owner. Since "B" was in possession of the property it was "C"\'s duty to inspect the property for the rights to anybody in possession. If no one is in possession, then first to record is first to right.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:'"C" has a valid title, for he recorded his deed.',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"B" and "C" would be tenants-in-common each to a 1/2 undivided interest.',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'there would be no title transfer and "B" and "C" would have to sue "A" separately.',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"B" has a valid title.',isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'Upon receiving his deed after the closing of escrow, the purchaser finds this statement in the deed: "Title subject to a recorded deed of trust in the amount of $12,000, current taxes, covenants, conditions, and restrictions in a declaration of restrictions recorded in Book 41483 Page 421 Official Records and an easement in favor of Pacific Telephone Corporation affecting said land for purposes of poles and conduits." From an analysis of the facts, which of the following is a correct statement?',hint:"The title is encumbered with a deed restriction. A utility easement is an easement in gross, not a restriction in gross. Answer (c) is the only correct statement. Taxes create a specific lien March 1, of every year until paid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"His title is encumbered with a lien and an easement but not with a deed restriction",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The utility easement constitutes a restriction in gross",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The taxes create a specific lien on his title",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The California Code of Civil Procedure provides that persons furnishing labor or material for the improvement of real estate may file liens upon the property affected if they are not compensated. Such liens are referred to as mechanic's liens. All of the following are correct statements concerning mechanic's liens except:",hint:"In a foreclosure sale, the priority of a holder of a mechanic's lien over a holder of a trust deed or mortgage lien would be established by showing the contractor had begun his work prior to the recording of the trust deed or mortgage lien. The rest of the choices are correct.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a mechanic's lien must be recorded to be legally effective.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in a foreclosure sale, the priority of a holder of a mechanic's lien over a holder of a trust deed or mortgage lien would be established by the date and time of recording of the respective liens.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the demolition of an old structure on a lot preparatory to building a new structure on the same lot often establishes the priority of mechanic's liens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the owner of real property could be financially responsible for payment of mechanic's liens even though he has paid the general contractor in full.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Prescription is a method of acquiring an easement, and adverse possession a method of acquiring title. Which of the following statements are correct?",hint:"Answer (a) would be an easement by statutory dedication. In adverse possession, it is not necessary to establish residence, only to hold and occupy the land continuously for five years. In an easement by prescription, the user of the property must be hostile to the owner. In answer (c), the owner is giving permission to use the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Dedication of land for use by the public could result in creating an easement by prescription",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"In a claim of title by adverse possession, establishing residence on the property would be a necessary element",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Granting grazing rights in excess of five years on agricultural land could result in prescriptive rights to an easement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above are correct statements",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A corporation could hold title to real property with another in all except which of the following ways?",hint:"Since a corporation is a legal person and will never die, it cannot hold title as a joint tenant with another. There can never be a right of survivorship with a corporation if the corporation is never going to die. If the corporation holds title by itself, it is in severalty, but, if held with another, it can be in common or in partnership.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Joint tenancy",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Tenants in common",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Partnership",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Three of the following are quite similar. Which answer does not belong with the others?",hint:"Offer, acceptance, and rescission pertain to contract, title does not.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Offer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Acceptance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Rescission",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Three of the following are alike. Which does not fit with the others?",hint:"A grant deed is not an encumbrance, the other three are encumbrances.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Easement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lien",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Judgment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Grant deed",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Plumber owned a lot that held an appurtenant easement over the neighboring property of Ms. Marty, giving him the right to run a sewer line across Ms. Marty's property. If Mr. Plumber sells the lot to Mr. Sano, but does not mention the easement in his deed, the easement:",hint:'An appurtenance is defined as, "An incidental right attached to a principal property right and passing in possession with it."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"remains with Mr. Plumber.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"transfers to Mr. Sano.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"reverts to Ms. Marty.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is lost by escheat.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"After purchasing a home, Mr. Brown discovered that his neighbor's fence was 2 feet over the line on his property. His legal remedy is to bring a civil suit against:",hint:"Encroachment is a form of trespass and actionable in law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the title company from which he had purchased a standard policy of title insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"his neighbor, under the law of adverse possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the broker for failure to disclose the encroachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"his neighbor, for removal of the encroachment on grounds of trespass.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A wife recorded a declaration of homestead on the community property without the husband's signature. Which of the following exemptions would the community receive?",hint:'The law permits the wife to declare a homestead exemption on 1) her separate property 2) the husband\'s separate property and 3) the community property - all without the signature or consent of her husband. The "head of the household" exemption is $75,000; for disabled or persons 65 or over, the exemption is $100,000; and for all others $50,000.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Nothing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$75,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$45,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Northern Telegraph Company has secured the right to place telegraph lines across the back of various residential properties. They have acquired an easement:",hint:"Public utilities have easements that are not appurtenant to any one parcel. These are known as easements in gross and are the most common type of easement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"by prescription.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in gross.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"that can be canceled if not used in 5 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"known as a utility encroachment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"One way to jointly hold title to real property is joint tenancy, another way would be:",hint:"Know 4 ways to hold real property jointly.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"tenancy in common.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"community property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenancy in partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lien is:",hint:"A lien is a money encumbrance. Choices (a), (b), and (c) are non-money encumbrances.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an easement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a restriction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an encroachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An attachment is:",hint:"A writ of attachment or attachment lien is used before the court renders a judgment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a judgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a lien.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a fixture.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an assessment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The name of the court action used to evict a tenant who is in default is known as:",hint:"Unlawful detainer action or action in ejectment is the legal remedy to remove a tenant who defaults on the rent or refuses to give up the premises.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"surrender.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an ejectment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an unlawful detainer action.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume that a property was sold for $20,000 and the buyer assumed the existing first trust deed and note of $8,000, the existing second trust deed of $4,000, and executed a new third trust deed and note in favor of seller for $2,000. Shortly after the purchase, payments were not made on either the second trust deed or the third trust deed and the beneficiary of the second trust deed recorded a notice of default and sent a copy to the seller. Upon receipt of the notice, the seller could take action and obtain:",hint:'The seller already has a lien with his trust deed and note. Since he cannot obtain an attachment nor a judgment (this is a purchase money trust deed), the answer is "none of the above."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a judgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The right to possess, use, enjoy, encumber, and transfer real property are known as:",hint:"Property rights are the rights someone has in something and are know collectively as the bundle of rights.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"fee simple rights.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"bundle of rights.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"defeasible rights.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"rights of inheritance.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Real property includes all of the following except:",hint:"Real property is land, anything permanently attached to the land, anything appurtenant to the land or anything immovable by law. Land includes airspace, surface rights, mineral rights, and water rights.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"airspace.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"oil.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"minerals.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"water rights.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In a lease whose duration is greater than one year, what is not required?",hint:"Only the lessor is legally required to sign a written lease.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"In writing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Signatures from both the lessor and the lessee",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Termination date",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Amount of rent and the method of payment",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Sam has a life estate and leases it to Tony on a five year lease. Sam dies one year later. The lease was valid for a total of:",hint:"A life tenant may lease out a life estate, but the lease terminates automatically when the life tenant dies.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"one year.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"five years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"zero years as one cannot lease a life estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A court order to sell property after the final judgment in a lawsuit has been rendered is:",hint:"A writ of execution is the court order to sell property after final judgment in a lawsuit has been made.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a foreclosure.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a deficiency judgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a writ of execution.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an attachment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following terminate easements except:",hint:"The owner of the servient tenement does not have the power to revoke an easement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"destruction of the servient tenement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"merger of the dominant and servient tenement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"revocation by the owner of the servient tenement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"express release by the owner of the dominant tenement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Property owner Peter had an easement for ingress and egress through the property of his adjacent neighbor, Jonah. If Peter purchases Jonah's property, what will happen to Peter's easement through that property?",hint:"When two properties are owned by the same person, any easements that may have existed are terminated by the merger.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It will terminate by adverse possession",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It will terminate by merger",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It will terminate by prescription",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It will terminate by deed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The covenant of quiet enjoyment most directly relates to:",hint:"One example of possession of real property occurs when a lessee (tenant) moves in. There is an implied covenant (promise) with every lease agreement that the lessee is entitled to the quiet enjoyment and possession of property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"nuisances maintained on adjoining property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"possession of real property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"title to real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under the U.S. Government Survey method of land description, rows of townships that run north and south are called:",hint:"Range lines run north and south and are six miles apart.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"tiers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ranges.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"meridians.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"base lines.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An undivided interest in a condominium development:",hint:"Definition: A condominium consists of a separate fee interest in a particular specific space (the unit), plus an undivided interest in all common or public areas of the development.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"allows each fee owner to use only his or her share of the common area.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"allows each fee owner to use the entire common area.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"allows each fee owner to encumber his or her share of the common area.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"allows each fee owner to sell his or her share of the common area.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A person purchased a condominium unit. Which of the following is a part of his unit?",hint:"Choices (a) and (b) are areas owned in common.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Bearing wall",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Elevator",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Air space within his unit",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Most real estate syndicates are formed as:",hint:"The limited partnership is popular in the syndication of real estate ventures because it:\n1) permits investors having little capital to participate in real estate projects requiring considerable capital and management expertise, 2) restricts investors' liability to their contribution, and 3) permits “funneling” of tax benefits of real property ownership.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"corporations.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"investment trusts.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"joint ventures.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"limited partnerships.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A group of investors are forming a real estate syndicate and desire to limit the liability of the members in order to attract capital. They would form a:",hint:"Limited liability is available under all three types of real estate syndication. The one type where unlimited liability is a possibility is in a general partnership.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"corporation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real Estate Investment Trust.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"limited partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In what form of ownership would you look to an individual's personal assets?",hint:"Definition: A partnership (an association of two or more persons carrying on a business for profit as co-owners) can hold title to real property (personal assets) in the name of the partnership, holding by tenancy in partnership and often vesting the title to said property in a trustee of a land trust.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Corporation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Limited partnership",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Partnership",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Investment trusts",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the sale of real property which of the following runs with the land?",hint:"All are appurtenant, incident to, and run with the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Easements",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Conditions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Stock in a mutual water company",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A minor, 16 years of age and married, wants to purchase a home. Which of the following statements is true?",hint:"A married person under the age of 18 is an emancipated minor and can sign a valid binding contract to purchase, rent or lease real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"He cannot legally purchase and own a home",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"He can own a home but only if his parents or legal guardian co-sign",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"He can purchase and own a home",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Land acquired by accretion is by:",hint:"A gradual build-up of soil, or alluvium, by natural causes on property bordering a river, lake or ocean is called accretion. Alluvial deposits are an example of accession, a process by which there is an addition to property by the efforts of man or natural forces.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"adverse possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"eminent domain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accession.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following must have a termination date?",hint:"An estate for years can be for days, weeks or years and must mention an end date to be valid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Estate at sufferance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Life estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Estate for years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Periodic tenancy",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Graciela received a life estate from her father, with the provision that it revert to him upon her death. She may do all except which of the following with the property?",hint:"A life estate holder must pay the taxes, maintain the property, may collect all rents and kekep all profits for the duration of the life estate, and may encumber the property or dispose of it in any way except by will.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Sell it",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Will it",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Encumber it",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lease it",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following parties is personally liable for unpaid business debts?",hint:"The broker-owners of a partnership are jointly and severally liable for all business debts.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Stockholders in a corporation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All members of a general partnership",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Limited partners",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Investors in a real estate investment trust",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In order for a real estate licensee to handle the sale of a mobile home, it must be registered with the Department of Housing and Community Development for what length of time?",hint:"Previously, it was required that the mobile home be registered for more than one year, however, recent law has removed this restriction.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10 calendar days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1 year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No requirement",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"10 business days",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Tenants, Bob and Lisa Jones, allowed the children from the neighboring back lot to enter a gate in their backyard and travel through to the front yard in order to catch their school bus every weekday. By doing this, what have they created?",hint:"An easement is a right-of-way and can be granted by a tenant as long as it does not conflict the terms of the lease.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An encroachment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A leasehold estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A less-than-freehold estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An easement",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The Rio Dale school district officials discovered through neighborhood census data that the current elementary school could not support the expected increase in students within the next five years. They actively began pursuing the purchase of two city blocks in the oldest part of town. This is an example of:",hint:"Public School Districts and Utilities can exercise eminent domain as well as the government.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"encroachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"eminent domain.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"police power.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accretion.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Under the Quality Environmental Act, "a negative declaration" for a proposed subdivision would mean that it:',hint:"It will not have any significant effects on the environment and the developer will not have to pay for a full environmental impact report.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"has not been approved by the Real Estate Commissioner and all construction must stop.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is an environmental hazard and it must be disclosed to prospective purchasers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"will not have any significant effects on the environment and the developer will not have to pay for a full environmental impact report.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"has not been approved due to other environmental hazards in the area.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"For many years, the Corderro family has had the right to operate a gold mine on neighboring land. Immediately after the neighbor sold the land, the new owner fenced in the land and padlocked the gate. What should the Corderro family do?",hint:"The Corderros have an established interest in the property. They will seek the operation of the law to clear the cloud on the title.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Give a quit claim deed to the owner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"File a quiet title action with the courts",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Get a quit claim deed from new owner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Do nothing",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In tenancy in common there is always a unity of:",hint:"Remember, all four are unities in a joint tenancy, only unity of possession in a tenancy in common.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"time.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"possession.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When a tenant who legally possessed a rented property continues to possess the property after his or her right has ended, which type of tenancy is created?",hint:"A tenancy in sufferance is created when a tenant remains on a legally rented property after the legal lease term has expired. If the landlord accepts any rent from the tenant, it is seen as consent and the arrangement becomes a tenancy at will.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Periodic tenancy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Tenancy at will",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Estate for years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Tenancy in sufferance",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What is the term for a partnership consisting of two or more people, and having at least one limited partner, and at least one general partner?",hint:"A limited partnership consists of one or more general partners and one or more limited partners.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Limited partnership",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"General partnership",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Ostensible partnership",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Limited liability partnership",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A signed copy of the certificate of a limited partnership must be filed with the:",hint:"A signed copy of the certificate of limited partnership must be filed with the Florida Department of State.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Florida Department of State.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Governor of Florida.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"IRS.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Commerce Department.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A widow who owns a condominium unit holds a:",hint:"A freehold estate is an ownership interest for an indefinite period of time that can be inherited. The fact that the woman is a widow does not change her ownership status. A proprietary lease is associated with cooperatives. A tenancy by the entireties is a joint tenancy between a husband and wife.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"tenancy by the entireties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"proprietary lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"freehold estate.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"proprietary estate.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Illinois Land Sales Registration Act would apply to the sale of which of the following?",hint:"The Illinois Land Sales Registration Act applies to any improved or unimproved land outside of Illinois in subdivisions of 25 or more lots offered as part of a common promotion plan. Exempt from the Act are cemetery plots, lots of 20 or more unimproved acres, when land is purchased by 10 or fewer persons, and land improved with residential or commercial structures.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A subdivision with 20 lots",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A cemetery plot",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A 15-acre lot of unimproved land",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The purchaser of a _________receives fee ownership in real property and the right to use the property for a specified period of less than one year on a recurring basis of more than three years.",hint:"The purchaser of a timeshare estate receives fee ownership in real property and the right to use the property for a specified period of less than one year on a recurring basis of more than three years. The purchaser of a timeshare use receives the right to use an accommodation in a timeshare property for a specified period of less than one year on a recurring basis of more than three years, but the purchaser receives no ownership interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"timeshare estate",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"timeshare interest",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"timeshare use",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"timeshare property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is true of land trusts?",hint:"Land trust agreements are usually for 20-year terms, and typically give the beneficiary full power and control of the property. Using a trust to transfer property does not avoid the Illinois real estate transfer tax.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Transferring property with a trust is a good way to avoid the transfer tax",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Land trust agreements are usually for 20-year terms",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"They typically give the trustee full power and control of the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under the Illinois Real Estate Timeshare Act, the purchaser may rescind the offer to purchase within ____ days of signing and all earnest money must be returned in ____ days.",hint:"The purchaser has the right to rescind the contract within three business days of signing, and any down payment must be returned within 14 days.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2/7",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3/10",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3/14",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"4/14",isCorrect:!1}]}}]},{category:"Appraisal",id:4,list:[{questionText:"What a leased property would be expected to rent for under current market conditions if the property were vacant and available for rent is:",hint:"Economic rent is the amount a rental could bring in an open market.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"contract rent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"economic rent.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"commercial rent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"conditional rent.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The word "value," as used in appraising real property, is most nearly comparable to:',hint:"What a property is said to be worth is its value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cost.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"price.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"utility.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"worth.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When a house is placed on a lot to insure the maximum privacy from street noise, this is an example of:",hint:"Orientation is the placement of a building on its lot in relation to exposure to sun, prevailing wind, traffic and privacy from the street.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"orientation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"plottage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"assemblage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When the appraiser is concerned with depreciation in his appraisal report, the method he would use would be:",hint:"The first three methods are accelerated methods used for income tax purposes. Straight line can be used in appraisal or income tax work.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"sum of the digits.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"200% declining.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"150% declining.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"straight line.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A water closet is:",hint:"The toilet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a room where the water heater is kept.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"water in a well.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a plumbing fixture.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"used by a surveyor.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a house was built in 1948 and appraised in 1993, it:",hint:"In real estate terminology, a house that was actually 45 years old had a physical life of 45 years, making (b) the best answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"had an economic life left of 45 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"had a physical life of 45 years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"had an effective age of 45 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A nice yard, beautiful trees, and good neighbors usually increase the value of residential property. These things are known as:",hint:"An amenity is something pleasing or an attractive feature.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"amenities.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"bi-laterals.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"co-ordinates.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tangibles.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the appraisal of residential structures, the cost approach is best suited to:",hint:"Depreciation on older properties is the greatest source of inaccuracy in appraising. Multi-family dwellings are most properly appraised by the capitalization method.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"new properties.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"middle-aged properties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"older properties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"multi-family dwellings.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When the owner of a commercial property lists it for the purpose of selling, a cost that is most often overlooked is:",hint:"Probably because it is the least obvious and is often handled wholly or partially by the owner.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"economic obsolescence.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unsatisfactory floor plan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deferred maintenance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"management costs.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In California, taxes on real property are collected on an ad valorem basis. The term ad valorem most nearly means:",hint:"Definition: Ad valorem is a Latin prefix meaning “according to value.”",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"replacement value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"according to value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"fixed value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"utility value.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The square footage of a single family residence for appraisal purposes is computed by obtaining the:",hint:"Square footage would be measured by the outside perimeter of the house. It does not include the garage.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"outside measurement of the house and garage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"inside measurement of the house as a whole.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"outside measurement of the house only.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"inside measurement of each room and adding them together.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'There are three main causes of depreciation. Which of the following finds its origin in "social sources," which is the basis for the old axiom that "more houses are torn down than fall down?"',hint:"Social factors are factors outside the property, hence, economic obsolescence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Economic obsolescence",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Functional obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Straight line depreciation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Physical deterioration",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appraiser, in determining the value of real property, would give consideration to which of the following?",hint:"All of these have an influence on value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The desire of a person for the desired thing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The relationship of the value of the property in exchange for other property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Effective demand, as evidenced by purchasing power, and relative scarcity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The horizontal piece supporting the wall studs and the piece to which the studs are nailed is called the:",hint:"This is what the wall studs rest on.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"sole plate.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"floor joist.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sub flooring.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"foundation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The period of time in which an income property produces enough income to maintain itself and show a profit is known as its:",hint:"Definition: Economic life is the estimated period over which a building may be profitably used, and it is usually shorter than physical (actual) life.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"productive life.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"economic life.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"depletion life.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"construction period.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The quantity survey method, square foot method, and unit-cost-in-place method, are terms most directly related to real estate:",hint:"They come under the cost approach to appraising.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"finance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"management.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appraisal.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"leasing.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"To obtain the most accurate report of the actual gross income of an apartment, an appraiser should:",hint:"The persons indicated in choices (a) and (b) could be prejudiced.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"rely on the seller's statement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have seller's statement confirmed by the apartment manager.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"obtain a statement from each tenant as to the amount of rent he pays.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"contact the local apartment association.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The appropriate symbol to designate the zoning of a multiple unit apartment building is:",hint:'"R" is for residential. The "3" indicates multiple dwelling use.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A-3.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"C-3.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"M-3.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"R-3.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A real estate appraisal made by an M.A.I. is an estimate of value based upon:",hint:"Any appraisal is an estimate of value as of a specific date.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"replacement costs only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"analysis of data as of a specific date.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"income data collected over the past 6 months.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tax assessor's records over the past 5 years.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In analyzing a vacant parcel of land to estimate its value, the first logical step is to determine:",hint:"Until you first determine its highest and best use, other comparisons are futile.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"its listed price.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"price the owner paid for it.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"highest and best use.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"prices of comparable improved properties.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following is not a "non-property characteristic" used by an appraiser?',hint:"Price paid has nothing to do with the characteristics of the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Date of sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Borrower's qualifications for the loan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Original price paid by the seller",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Unusual financing",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a comparable property contains a feature not present in the subject property:",hint:"If a comparable property has a swimming pool and sold for $250,000, and the subject property has no pool, the value of the pool would be subtracted from the comparable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the comparable is adjusted to the subject property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the subject property is adjusted to the comparable property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"it may not be used as a comparable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the feature must be appraised separately.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How would the replacement cost of a warehouse be determined?",hint:"There are several methods to estimate the cost of a new building: Square-foot method; Cubic-foot method; Quantity-survey method; and Unit-in-place method.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Cost per square foot",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost per square inch",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost per cubic foot",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Cost per cubic inch",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appraiser has been requested to appraise a residential home. Although the home is actually 10 years old it is in excellent condition, so the appraiser places its age at 6 years. This would be known as:",hint:"Actual age is the real age of the building. Effective age is not determined by the actual age of a building, but by its condition and usefulness.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"actual age.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"effective age.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"undepreciated age.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"remaining life.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Trend is defined by appraisers as a process of change:",hint:"This is defined in A.I.R.E.A.'s handbook.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"discounted during appraisal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"which can be observed on national levels.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"created by a chain of cause and effect.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"caused by economic and political actions affecting the market.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When do real estate values decline?",hint:"Actually before and during a recession.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Before a recession",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"After a recession",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"During a boom",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"During a period of stability",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The "depth table rule" is mostly used in appraising:',hint:"Definition: Depth tables are used by tax assessors seeking to achieve uniformity in assessment practices when estimating the value of commercial properties.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"industrial property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commercial property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"residential property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In the field of real estate, the terms "quantity survey," "unit-cost in place," and "square foot" apply to:',hint:"Reproduction or cost of replacement approach to appraising uses these terms.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"finance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appraising.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"management.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leasing.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are considered forces of value. Which is least important in its effect on value?",hint:"The clue word is least important. Original cost has very little effect on value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Social forces and demands",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Original cost",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Economic considerations",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Government regulations",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Water that is drinkable and is not contaminated is said to be:",hint:"Local health officers may determine if water is potable (safe to drink) or requires a percolation test.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"potable.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"privity.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"alluvium.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"avulsion.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would be considered economic obsolescence?",hint:"A mental hospital built in a new up-scale neighborhood is an external or economic force that would cause a loss in value for the homes nearby.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A newly remodeled home in a deteriorating neighborhood",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A home in need of repairs",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A mental hospital built in a new up-scale neighborhood",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A home painted purple and yellow",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appraiser's opinion of value of a property may be lowered by nearby nuisances. When this occurs, it is known as:",hint:"Economic obsolescence is caused by factors outside the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"functional obsolescence.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"economic obsolescence.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"financial obsolescence.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"physical obsolescence.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If two nearby homes cost the same to build, but one is worth considerably less than the other, the cause would be:",hint:"The condition of the property or out of date style will affect the value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"social obsolescence.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"political obsolescence.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"economic obsolescence.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"functional obsolescence.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Appraisers using the observed condition method to appraise a property would consider all except:",hint:"Political obsolescence is not an appraisal term.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"physical deterioration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"economic obsolescence.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"political obsolescence.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"functional obsolescence.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The period of time when an income producing property generates income in excess of its expenses is known as:",hint:"Definition: Economic life is the estimated period over which a building may be profitably used.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"economic life.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"social life.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"political life.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"functional life.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When an appraiser raises the capitalization rate on income property, he must realize that he implies a:",hint:"He implies a greater risk; therefore, he demands a greater return.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"greater return.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"greater gross income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"greater net income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"greater risk.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The appraisal approach using income from property as a basis for determining its value would be concerned with which of the following characteristics of the income?",hint:"These are the three factors of income that an appraiser examines in determining the rate of return on an investment and establishes the capitalization rate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Quantity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Durability",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Quality",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Present worth and future benefits of property are concerned with:",hint:"Present worth and future benefits helps determine appraised value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"current book value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appraised value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"residential property only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"replacement cost.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The term "functional utility" most nearly means the:',hint:"Definition: Functional utility is the combined factors of usefulness with desirability.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"desirability and usefulness of the property are such that it would be easily marketable at the asked price.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"utility value is related to its functional use.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"outdatedness of the property could be easily corrected.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"building has long since passed its usefulness.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The term "walk-up" refers to:',hint:"A walk-up is an apartment of more than one story with no elevator.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"apartments.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"restaurants.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"planned developments.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the appraisal of real property, using the capitalization approach, the overall capitalization rate applicable to the income in interpreting value would take into consideration which of the following?",hint:"Definition: Capitalization is the determination of the amount, reliability and durability of the income stream as made by the appraiser.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"All of the following",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Durability of income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Quality of income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Quantity of income",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What would be the most accurate way of telling the age of a single family residence?",hint:"This is a statement of fact as to the most accurate way.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The owner's information supplied in the listing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Personal inspection of the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Check the tax assessor's records",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Consult the county recorder's office",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The real estate appraisal field is a very complex and detailed area of gathering many facts concerning a specific piece of property. Which of the following would be of most importance to an appraiser?",hint:"The date of the inspection is the date of valuation and would be of most importance to the appraiser.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The date escrow closed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The date the deed is signed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The date the appraiser inspected the property",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The date the agreement to purchase was signed by both buyer and seller",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following four choices, which would be the correct formula used to figure the value of a piece of income property?",hint:"Income divided by rate equals value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"I divided by R = V",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"I x R = V",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"R divided by I = V",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"I divided by V = R",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Demand being equal:",hint:"Definition: Increasing supply or decreasing demand will reduce the price in the market. Reducing supply or increasing demand will raise the price in the market. The less there is of something, the higher the cost; the more there is, the lower the cost.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"prices increase as availability decreases.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"as the availability decreases so do prices.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"prices increase as availability increases.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"prices decrease as availability decreases.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In the appraising process, the term "highest and best use" often comes into play. This can best be defined as:',hint:"The principle of highest and best use, which is based on the reasonable use of real property at the time of the appraisal, produces the greatest net return to the land and/or the building over a given period of time",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"developing a lot so as to contribute to the best interest of the community.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"producing the greatest net return on the investment over a given period of time.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"developing a lot so as to produce the highest gross income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following types of value would be approximately the same as market value?",hint:"Utility value is the personal opinion of value by the current owner. Book value is the price paid less depreciation. Insurance value is based on the cost approach of appraising. Speculative value is approximately the same as market value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Book value",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Speculative value",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Insurance value",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Utility value",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The amount of money left over after an owner of an income producing property has paid all of his expenses, including principal and interest payments, is called:",hint:"Definition: Cash flow is the net income generated by a property before depreciation and other non-cash expenses.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"gross income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"net income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"taxable income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cash flow.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When a person acquires certain assets, he must determine the salvage value of those assets. Before calculating his future depreciation on these assets, the salvage value would:",hint:"The salvage value of an asset (improvement) limits the total amount of depreciation that may be claimed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"decrease the allowable depreciation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"increase the allowable depreciation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"would have no affect on the allowable depreciation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"either (b) or (c) above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Unearned increment means:",hint:"Unearned increment is an increase in value to real property that comes about from forces outside the influence and control of the property owner, such as a favorable rezoning or a favorable shift of population in the neighborhood.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"value decreases.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"value increases due to population increase.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a return on money invested that was anticipated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The relationship between "the thing desired and the potential purchaser" is best defined as:',hint:"The utility and scarcity on one side and the demand on the other side is what decides the value of a piece of property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the relationship between demand and value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the present worth as opposed to future income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the relationship between utility and value.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In estimating value on a single family residence for fire insurance, which method of appraising would the appraiser apply?",hint:"The cost approach estimates the replacement or reproduction cost of an existing building as of the appraisal date. Replacement cost is the cost of restoring a property to its previous condition or replacing it with something of like-kind and quality.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Income approach",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost approach",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Market data approach",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Studs located inside of a wall are supported by the:",hint:"Definition: Studs are vertical 2” x 4” boards inside walls that rest upon and are supported by a sole plate (usually a 2” x 4” board).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"floor joints.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"floor studs.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sole plate.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"headers.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Cash flow is:",hint:"Cash flow is the spendable income from an investment after deducting from gross income all operating and fixed expenses, including principal and interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"gross rental minus operating expenses minus payments on principal and interest.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"gross rental minus operating expenses minus cost of doing business.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"gross rental minus operating expenses only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Effective age:",hint:"Definition: Effective age is not determined by the actual age of a building, but by its condition and usefulness.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is equal to, or less than, the actual age.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is never equal to, but may be less than the actual age.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may be more or less than the actual age.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"is always less than the actual age.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following types of depreciation would be most difficult to calculate accurately?",hint:"Economic obsolescence--a loss of value due to extraneous factors (factors outside the property itself, such as adverse zoning, misplaced improvements, and change of locational demand).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Economic obsolescence",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Functional obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Physical deterioration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Physical depreciation",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The income remaining after cost of labor and management have been paid is called:",hint:"The principle of surplus productivity is the net income that remains after the proper costs of labor, organization, and capital have been paid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"principle of progression.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"principle of decreasing returns.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"theory of surplus productivity.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"To arrive at the valuation of an amenity type property, an appraiser would use:",hint:"Amenities, meaning the good things that make the property desirable. Comparison or market data approach would be the method of appraising to be utilized.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"market data approach.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"land residual approach.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ground rent approach.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"capitalization of net income approach.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following types of depreciation would be the most difficult to estimate?",hint:"This comes about from social factors, which are the hardest to estimate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Physical deterioration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Functional obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sum-of-the-digits",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Economic obsolescence",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The fastest and most accurate method of appraising a library would be:",hint:"Libraries are not very often sold; therefore, you could not utilize the comparison approach. There is no incomes, therefore, you cannot utilize the capitalization approach. Cost approach would be the one to be utilized.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"comparison approach.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cost approach.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"capitalization of net income approach.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A gross multiplier is least likely to be used in the appraisal of:",hint:"It is very often used on commercial, income, and manufacturing property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"commercial property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"income property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"vacant land.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"manufacturing property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"One of the main reasons that condominium projects are to grow in demand in the future is:",hint:"Because land cost is increasing, if the builder were to build more condominium units on a given piece of land, he would reduce the cost of land per unit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"no yard upkeep.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"higher property taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"land value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"utility value.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Most appraisers use the _____________ when appraising a new building:",hint:"Cost or reproduction approach. Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"capitalization approach",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"land residual technique",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"economic rent technique",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cost approach",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following appraisal methods would require the appraiser to determine a separate value of the land?",hint:"The third step of the cost approach is to add the current value of the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Market data",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Capitalization of net income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"FHA firm commitment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost approach",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Demand is a very important element of value. In order for demand to be effective, it must be implemented by:",hint:"Demand is how many people want the property. If they do not have the purchasing power, the demand is worthless.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"need.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cost analysis.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"purchasing power.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Parallel timbers that support the load of the ceiling and the floor are called:",hint:"Definition: Parallel boards supporting floors or ceilings are called joists. The boards supporting them are girders, beams or bearing walls.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"rafters.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"floor boards.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"restraining boards.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"joists.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What approach to value tends to set the upper limit to value?",hint:"Reproduction cost represents the cost of reproducing the subject property, which is normally more expensive than merely replacing the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Comparison",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Reproduction cost",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Replacement cost",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (b) and (c) above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the case of residential properties, there is an increase in the demand for lots with:",hint:"Frontage is the length of a property along a street.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"more depth.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"wider frontage.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"city view.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When an appraiser adjusts the income of an apartment property for vacancies and loss of rent, the resulting figure is:",hint:"Gross income minus vacancy factor equals effective gross income.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"effective net income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"effective gross income.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"capital loss.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"retirement of rent schedule loss.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would cause a home to be considered substandard?",hint:"Leaking roof is an obvious sign of a problem; the others are future problems.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Old electrical wiring",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Older architecture",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Leaking roof",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"View obstructed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The urban renewal program involving demolition, clearance, and reconstruction of entire areas is generally called:",hint:"Urban renewal is a process of upgrading deteriorated neighborhoods through clearance and redevelopment, rehabilitation and the installation of new public improvements, or through modernization of existing ones.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"rehabilitation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"conservation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"redevelopment.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"reclamation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An example of economic obsolescence is:",hint:"Over supply would make the property worth less from outside factors.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"poor room layout.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"over supply.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"leaking roof.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"no parking.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If you fix up a building which you own, without changing the interior or exterior design, this would be an example of:",hint:"Rehabilitation is the restoration of a property to its former or improved condition without changing the basic design or plan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"rehabilitation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"renovation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"remodeling.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"restoration.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Urban industrial property is usually sold by:",hint:"Industrial property is usually sold by area in square feet or acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"front foot.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"area.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"depth.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"square yard.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Jones built a house with four bedrooms and one bath. When work was completed, the property had depreciated immediately from what cause?",hint:"Out of date design would be functional obsolescence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Functional obsolescence",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Economic obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Social obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A bearing wall in a residence would most likely be:",hint:"",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a wall with windows.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a wall with windows and doors.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a wall with no windows or doors.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a wall that determines which direction the property faces during construction.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A board foot is exactly:",hint:"Any combination of 144 cubic inches.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:'2" x 6" x 12".',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'3" x 4" x 12".',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'12" x 12" x 1".',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of these",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The typical height of a ceiling in a single family residence is (give the closest answer):",hint:"Residential ceiling height measurements: Minimum = 7.5 feet; Normal = 8 feet (96 in.).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"110 inches.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"7' 4\".",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"96 inches.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"9 feet.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker Jones appraised two similar commercial properties. Both were leased on a long term basis. One was a hardware store and the other was a post office. Compared to the hardware store, the capitalization rate on the post office was:",hint:"Because the post office would be more stable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"higher.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lower.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the same.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"higher or lower on different dates.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"It was discovered when checking the basement of a house that there were cracks along the foundation in two directions. This is most likely because:",hint:"Foundation settlement can cause internal stresses that weaken a structure. Differential settlement produces unsightly cracks in floors, exterior walls, and ceilings. Most structures experience some settlement. While most foundation problems can be corrected, repair work is usually expensive.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the floor joists are too weak.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the concrete is deteriorating.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the walls are too heavy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the house is settling.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The difference between the way an appraiser looks at depreciation and the way an accountant looks at depreciation is:",hint:"The book depreciation calculated by an accountant is not the depreciation considered by the appraiser. An appraiser subtracts the estimate of accrued actual (not book) depreciation on the building from the cost to build new.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an accountant is interested in book depreciation and an appraiser is interested in actual depreciation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an appraiser is interested in book depreciation and an accountant is interested in actual depreciation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accountants deal in theory and fact and appraisers do not.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appraisers deal in theory and fact and accountants do not.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A couple is looking at houses and turns one down because they felt the price of the home was too high. This is based on what principle of real estate?",hint:"The principle of substitution is the basis of the appraisal process. Explained simply, value is set by the cost of getting an equally desirable substitute.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Conformity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Anticipation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Substitution",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Insofar as the ratio of improvements to land, which would most likely give the greatest depreciation?",hint:"This would be the most expensive construction which means more improvement value, therefore, more depreciation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Industrial property valued at $100,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Commercial property valued at $100,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Apartment property valued at $100,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Agricultural property valued at $100,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A multi-storied apartment building that contains no elevator is called:",hint:"Definition: A walk-up is an apartment building of more than one story with no elevator.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a flat.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a walk up.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a tenement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a cold water flat.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which would affect the value of single family homes in a neighborhood?",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) would all be examples of the principle of conformity which will not effect the value of the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Same ethnic group",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Families with approximately the same income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Homes with about equal value",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Area with fair quality homes mixed with good quality homes",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Economic obsolescence is generally considered:",hint:"Since economic obsolescence is a form of depreciation that occurs on your property due to surrounding properties, conditions such as adverse zoning introduced into the community, it is generally considered incurable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"curable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"incurable.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"outdated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"According to appraisal theory, which is the most desirable corner for a retail business?",hint:"Due to the action of the sun and considering the shady side of the street, the southwest corner is the most desirable for pedestrian foot traffic.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Southeast",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Northwest",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Southwest",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Northeast",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What would happen to the value of a commercial property whose depth is extended beyond that of neighboring lots?",hint:"The deeper the lot, the greater the front foot value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Value would increase per square foot",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Value of lot would decrease",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Value per front foot would increase",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Value per square foot would decrease and value of the lot would decrease",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The concept of fair market value:",hint:"The price a property would bring if freely offered on the open market, with both a willing buyer and a willing seller, and used in the appraisal of single family residences is known as fair market value - or objective value (since it may be determined by actual data).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is used in the appraisal of single family residences.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is the price the property will bring on the open market.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"involves a willing buyer and willing seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above are correct",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'Appraisers speak of "the highest and best use." Of the following, which is related to this expression?',hint:"The principle of highest and best use is based on the reasonable use of real property at the time of the appraisal, which is most likely to produce the greatest net return to the land and/or the building over a given period of time.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A starting point for an appraisal",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Greatest net return",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'The terms "net income" and "net spendable income" are used in reference to income property. Which of the following is a correct statement concerning these terms?',hint:"Net income is the result obtained by subtracting expenses of operation from effective gross income. Net spendable income is the result obtained by subtracting finance payments from the net income, and is used with a capitalization rate to determine value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Net income is the result obtained by subtracting a vacancy factor from gross income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Net spendable income is the result obtained after subtracting expenses of operation from effective gross incomes",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Net spendable income is the result obtained when financing payments are subtracted from net income",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Net spendable income is used with a capitalization rate to determine value",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning the comparison method of appraisal?",hint:"The sales comparison approach is the one most easily understood and commonly used by real estate agents. It is easily applied for the sale of single family homes and is best for single family homes or condominiums and vacant lots.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It is the quickest and easiest method",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is the simplest method and easiest for a beginner to learn",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is often used to appraise unimproved land",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above are correct",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is a correct statement concerning the cost method?",hint:"The cost approach tends to set the upper limit of value for a property. It is not difficult to estimate the replacement cost of new structures, but it is difficult to estimate depreciation in older buildings. The cost approach is also used with unique or one-of-a-kind buildings where it is difficult to find comparables.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It sets the upper limit of value",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'Little difficulty is encountered in estimating the replacement cost of "new" structures',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Serious difficulties often arise in obtaining an accurate computation of accrued depreciation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above are correct statements",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following statements is correct concerning the income approach?",hint:"Statements of fact",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"it requires the determination of net income before interest and amortization but after deduction of operating expenses",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an appropriate capitalization rate must be determined",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"it is not applicable to owner-occupied homes because benefits of amenities are difficult to measure in terms of dollars",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above are correct",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would be the most important factor in determining the value of a single family residence?",hint:"Location is the most important factor influencing value, as far as highest and best use.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Location and neighborhood",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Square feet of livable area",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Its most recent selling price",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Its original cost of construction",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The reproduction cost method:",hint:"You appraise by cost of reproducing the improvements and then appraise and add the land value to the cost. It is used most effectively on new properties. It would be used to appraise an athletic stadium. Income approach requires an accurate estimate of expenses.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"requires a separate appraisal of the land.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"is most effectively used on older properties where a history of costs may be obtained.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"would not be used in appraising an athletic stadium as this type of structure is seldom replaced.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"requires an accurate estimate of operation expenses.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The income method would be used when appraising:",hint:"Any investment or income property that shows an income.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a shopping center.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a medical building under long term lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a hotel.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A gross multiplier:",hint:"The Gross Rent Multiplier is income (calculated annually or monthly) received before any expenses are deducted.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is a quick indication of value chiefly used on new properties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may be expressed as a monthly or annual gross multiplier.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"is the most accurate method of appraising older income properties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"requires a determination of net spendable income.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The economic life of an income property is:",hint:"Economic life is that period which the property produces an income to the owner. Physical life is until the building falls down. Physical life would be longer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a determination of its actual past history of producing income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"shorter than its physical life.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"determined by ground rent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"either shorter or longer than physical life depending on the type of property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Referring to the capitalization rate used in the income method:",hint:"If the risk is high the investor will demand a higher rate of return, thereby making the value of the property lower.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the higher the risk, the higher the rate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the higher the rate, the lower the value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the lower the rate, the higher the value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above are correct statements.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Depreciation is defined as a loss of value due to any cause. It is also classified as curable and incurable. Of the following statements concerning depreciation, which one is correct?",hint:"Answer (a) is economic obsolescence-incurable. Answer (b) is functional obsolescence-incurable. Answer (c) is unearned increment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A massive cornice on a roof is an example of physical deterioration-curable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Bad architectural design is an example of functional obsolescence-curable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Population pressures forcing price upward in an inflationary spiral is an example of economic obsolescence-incurable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Bearing walls sagging beyond a 30-degree angle is an example of physical deterioration-incurable",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Functional obsolescence:",hint:"Poor architectural design and style can contribute to functional obsolescence (a type of depreciation), as can lack of modern facilities, out-of-date equipment, changes in styles of construction or changes in utility demand.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"causes a more rapid decline in value than physical deterioration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"can be caused by changes in style and design.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both (a) and (b) are correct",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"neither (a) nor (b) is correct",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Economic obsolescence is said to be extraneous, caused by environmental or economic changes. Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning economic obsolescence?",hint:"Answer (a) is physical deterioration. Answer (b) is functional obsolescence. Answer (c) is a statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Deferred maintenance causes economic obsolescence.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Poor architectural design results in economic obsolescence.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Value loss due to proximity to a major highway causing noise and traffic hazards will create economic obsolescence.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above is correct.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The market value of a 15-year-old residence is most commonly determined by:",hint:"Market data or comparison approach in appraising a residence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cost of replacement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"listing price.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"selling price of comparable residences.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"capitalizing the net income.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The prime factors of value are:",hint:"There are many factors of value, but the four most important are utility, scarcity, demand, and transferability.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"price and terms.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"frontage and depth.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"size and location.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"utility, scarcity, demand, and transferability.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An appraisal method used to establish land value whereby the appraiser attributes part of the property's value to the land and part to the building, is called:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all interchangeable words as defined in the question itself.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"distribution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"allocation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"abstraction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'The term "potable" refers to:',hint:"Local health officers may determine if water is potable (safe to drink) or if it requires a percolation test.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"sewers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"septic systems.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"water.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"land.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Vertical supporting members in a wall rest upon:",hint:"The vertical supporting members are wall studs.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the joists.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the sole plate.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the girders.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the header.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following does not belong with the others?",hint:"Penny serves as a measurement in nail length. Hip, pitch, and gable all refer to roofs.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Hip",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Pitch",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Penny",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Gable",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following statements concerning construction terms are correct except:",hint:"Answers (b), (c), and (d) are all statements of fact. Plaster is not dry wall.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"plaster is considered dry wall.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"wainscoting refers to the finishing of the upper half of a wall with different material than the lower half.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a party wall must be on the line between two adjoining properties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sheathing may be found on the roof or the sides of a frame structure.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would not be contiguous?",hint:"Contiguous means touching. Floor joints and ceiling joists run parallel to each other and never touch.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Fire stop and stud",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Footing and foundation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Floor joists and ceiling joists",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Anchor bolt and mudsill",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'A usual definition of "highest and best use" includes the words:',hint:"The highest and best use generates the greatest net return.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"income properties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"net return.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"ground rental.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"assessed value.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The relationship of cost per square foot between a one story and two story house is:",hint:"Because there is one foundation, one roof and one set of plumbing leads.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"no difference.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two story house costs more.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two story house costs less.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"one story house costs less.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"You would most likely find the best kept homes in a neighborhood where:",hint:"Pride of ownership in direct ratio to owner's equity.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the owners all earn about the same income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"about 20% of the homes are rentals.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"no down payment is required to purchase a home.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all owners are required to pay a substantial down payment.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The square footage in a home is usually determined by:",hint:"Outside measurements of house.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"inside dimensions of house.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"outside dimensions of a house.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"dimensions of house and garage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"inside measurement of rooms of the house.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If topography is considered in connection with development of a residential subdivision, experience has shown that:",hint:"Desirable but more expensive because of the cost of engineering and grading.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"land with a rolling topography can be developed more cheaply than flat land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"some contour is desirable in a residential subdivision.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"rolling hills and varied topography are considered to result in a monotonous landscape for a residential subdivision.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above is true.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The most important factor listed below, in determining the value of a home, is:",hint:'This is the "willing buyer-willing seller" concept.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"rental income potential.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"availability of interested buyers.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"floor design.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"amenities.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In appraising an unimproved lot, one would logically first determine:",hint:"Used in evaluating vacant land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"highest and best use.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"value of surrounding lots.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"price asked by owner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cost of lot.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A party wall is:",hint:"Do not confuse with partition or bearing wall.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a wall on the property line of adjoining properties, used by both parties.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a wall between apartment units, used by the adjoining tenants.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a wall that bears the weight of structure between two unsupported areas in a single structure.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Percolation refers to:",hint:"The action of the drainage water in the leach lines of a septic system.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"septic system.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"water mains.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sewer lines.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is an appraisal approach?",hint:"Comparison is called market data, reproduction is called cost approach, capitalization approach is called income.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Market data",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The closest meaning to value is:",hint:"Value includes present and future worth.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"price.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"worth.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"cost.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"use.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What appraisal approach would be used on a residential duplex for fire insurance purposes?",hint:"Fire insurance rates are based on cost to reproduce the improvements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Comparison",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Market data",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is the highest member in a frame house?",hint:"The board at the peak of the roof to which the rafters are nailed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Ridgeboard",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Mud sill",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Header",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Rafter",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A professional appraiser, in arriving at the value of an income producing property, may use:",hint:"Property residual, capitalization of net income, and land residual are all techniques used by appraisers to appraise income property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"property residual technique.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"capitalization of net income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"land residual technique.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Negligent care of a building is called:",hint:"Physical deterioration (a type of depreciation) can come from wear and tear, negligent care (sometimes called deferred maintenance), damage by dry rot or termites, or severe changes in temperature. It may or may not be curable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"replacement maintenance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"non-effective maintenance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"utility maintenance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deferred maintenance.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would pay the lowest percentage lease?",hint:"Definition of a percentage lease: The higher the gross volume, the lower the percentage lease and vice versa. Of the choices given, a chain grocery store would probably have the highest gross volume. Therefore, the lowest percentage lease.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A chain grocery store",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A parking lot",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A department store",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A hardware store",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which one is not a cause of depreciation?",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all causes of depreciation, which is loss of value from any cause. Answer (d), sinking fund, is not a cause of depreciation but is a method of calculation depreciation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Outdated fixtures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Wear and tear",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Economic obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sinking fund",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lesser valued property will be worth more because of the presence of a greater valued property nearby. This is known as the principle of:",hint:"Definition: The principle of progression means a lesser-valued property will be worth more because of the presence of greater-valued properties nearby.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"progression.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"regression.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"conformity.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"balance.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'"Depth tables" are used by:',hint:'"Depth Tables" are used by appraisers when appraising commercial lots that vary from the normal depth.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the Department of Water and Power.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appraisers.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"mutual water companies.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The most important factor that would influence the value of a home is:",hint:"Demand, being one of the elements of value, would definitely influence the value of a house. Answers (a), (b), and (d) would not necessarily influence the value of a house.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"construction quality.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"floor plan of the house.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"demand by qualified buyers.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"loan-to-value ratio.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Value is set by the cost of getting an equally desirable substitute. This is a simple explanation of the principle of:",hint:"The principle of substitution is the basis of the appraisal process. Explained simply, value is set by the cost of getting an equally desirable substitute.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"highest and best use.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"substitution.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"change.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"supply and demand.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The word "potable" refers to:',hint:'The definition of the word "potable" is liquids that are drinkable.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"water.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"easement rights.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the rights of parties in possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mineral and oil rights.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would be most beneficial in preventing economic obsolescence on income property?",hint:"Economic obsolescence is due to surrounding outside economic factors changing, thereby decreasing the value of your property. Therefore, answer (a) would be most beneficial in preventing economic obsolescence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"All of the surrounding buildings were prospering",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Proper management running the building efficiently",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Excellent maintenance on the building",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following best describes a footing?",hint:"A footing is an extended part of foundation at the base or bottom of a foundation wall, pier or column.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Concrete slab placed in the ground upon which the foundation rests",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A measurement used to describe a lot size",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A concrete slab that rests upon the foundation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The economic life of an average frame building is:",hint:"State exam opinion answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"20 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"45 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"40 years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"35 years.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The best wood to use to ward off termites is:",hint:"General knowledge - statement of fact",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cedar.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"redwood.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Douglas Pine.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Douglas Fir.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Another name for a cul-de-sac is:",hint:"A cul-de-sac is a street that has only one way in and the same way out. It is a dead-end street.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"dead-end street.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"key lot.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interior lot.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"flag lot.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The value of income property is usually:",hint:"Income property would be valued by the capitalization of net income.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"determined by what a buyer will pay for the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"based on capitalization of net income.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"gross income multiplied by gross multiplier.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reproduction cost of the improvements only.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"To appraise an amenity an appraiser would probably use the:",hint:"An amenity type property is anything that will enhance the value of the property making it desirable to the buyer. This type of property is appraised by comparing it with similar properties.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"reproduction cost approach.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"capitalization of net income approach.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"market comparison.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Unearned increment most nearly means:",hint:"Unearned increment is an increase in value to real estate that comes about from forces outside the control of the owners, such as a favorable increase in population.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"increase in value due to increase in population.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"increase in value due to renovation of property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"decrease in value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unearned earnings in income property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When appraising income producing properties, the appraiser is concerned with the effective gross income. Which of the following, with respect to effective gross income, is the appraiser concerned with?",hint:"The effective gross income is the total annual income from the property minus any vacancy or rental losses.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Functional obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Physical deterioration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Interest on the loans",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Vacancy",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following equals gross rentals minus operating expenses minus principal and interest payments?",hint:"Spendable income is the amount the investor has left to spend after making all deductions.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Spendable income",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Pro-rated income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Net income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"There are four essential elements of value. Which of the following is not an essential element?",hint:"Cost is defined as an expenditure for labor or materials. This has nothing to do with the value of property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Cost",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Utility",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Scarcity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Transferability",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A good example of the most incurable functional obsolescence is:",hint:"In order to correct closely aligned pillars one could run into major structural strength situation. This could be quite costly.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"outdated lighting fixtures.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"closely aligned pillars inside of a store.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"outdated heating.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"outdated storefront.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"4 - 3 - 2 - 1 is a familiar term used in a general real estate practice. This refers to:",hint:"This is an old assessing formula whereby 40% of the land value was in the first 1/4 of the depth, 30% in the second 1/4.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"financing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"corner lots in a subdivision.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fractional description of a lot.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appraising vacant land where the lots vary in depth.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following formulas would establish the value of income property?",hint:'I stands for "income," R stands for "rate," V stands for "value." Income divided by capitalization rate equals value.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"I x R = V",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"R divided by I = V",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"V divided by R = I",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"I divided by R = V",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Utility value is best described as:",hint:"The definition of utility value is the usefulness of the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"use value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"replacement value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"market value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Demand is one of the four elements of value. In order for demand to be effective, it must be implemented by:",hint:"Without purchasing power, no matter how great the demand for a commodity, property would not sell.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"utility value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"exchange value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"purchasing power.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which is the closest to highest and best use?",hint:"The definition of highest and best use is: To improve a lot in such a way that it will produce the greatest net income.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Gross income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Greatest net income",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"100% location",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Southwest corner of an intersection",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The capitalization approach includes the "return of" and "return on" the investment. What does "return of" mean?',hint:'"Return of" capital is to recapture the money invested. This is accomplished through depreciation.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Replacement reserves",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Financing cost",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Depreciation method",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Electricity expense",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Wood members that are used to brace floor joists are:",hint:"Definition answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"studs.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"brace joists.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"bridging.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"support joists.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Accrued depreciation is a term used in the real estate appraisal field. Which of the following methods would accrued depreciation have its greatest effect on?",hint:"The cost approach subtracts accrued depreciation from new replacement cost to determine the current value of the improvements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Market data approach",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost approach",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Capitalization of net income approach",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Market comparison approach",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If you were asked to appraise an industrial piece of property, which of the following would be most important to you?",hint:"To appraise an industrial piece of property the appraiser must take into consideration the location of the property in relation to transportation, housing, parking, etc.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The location of the property",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The adjacent property owners",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The value of the building alone",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the appraisal field of real estate, there are many ways an appraiser can arrive at a capitalization rate. Which of the following could be used to determine a capitalization rate?",hint:"The Band of Investment theory is a method of developing a capitalization rate by applying mortgage rates and equity rates of comparable properties.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Progressive inflation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Opinions of local bankers",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The band of investment theory",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Reservations based upon recent sales",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Relating to the appraisal field, the stages of "development and old age" and "progression and regression" are parts of what concept?',hint:'All four words in the question relate to the theory of "change" as to the appraising concept of real property.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Distribution",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost of living index",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Change",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If you were asked to prepare newspaper ads for a home in a nice quiet area, $500,000 price range, you would appeal to:",hint:"Opinion answer of the state exam. We agree with their answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"prestige.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"higher income families.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pride of ownership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"If you were asked to appraise a piece of property with a worthless building on it, in order to arrive at the value of the lot and determine its highest and best use, you would:",hint:"To determine the value of a lot for its highest and best use, an appraiser always deducts any cost of demolition that must take place in order to make that lot vacant once again.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"appraise the existing building, then deduct value of land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ignore worthless building completely.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subtract the cost of removing the worthless building from the current value of the lot.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"use the building residual technique.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Economic obsolescence is best described as:",hint:"Since economic obsolescence takes place outside of the affected property (next door adverse zoning), it is neither curable nor incurable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"inherent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"curable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"incurable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sociological and political changes in the area.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Net income is reflected in which of the following statements?",hint:"A profit and loss statement reflects the net income or sum arrived at after deducting from the gross income the expenses of a business or investment (including taxes, insurance and allowances for vacancy and bad debts. Net income is what the property will earn in a given year's operation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Closing statement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Financing statement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Profit statement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Profit and loss statement",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The use of a percolation test would be used in which of the following cases?",hint:'The word "percolation" refers to water; therefore, answer (c) is correct.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Population survey",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Investigative title search",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"To determine the absorption of water",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"To determine the flavor of coffee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is a bolt which is usually buried in the foundation to tie down the mud sill?",hint:"The anchor bolt is embedded in a concrete foundation and attaches the mud sill to the foundation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Foundation bolt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Anchor bolt",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Mud sill bolt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Permanent bolt",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is an acre of ground less dedicated streets, alleys, etc.?",hint:"A commercial acre is the area remaining from an acre of newly subdivided land after deducting the area devoted to streets, sidewalks, alleys, curbs, etc. Also know as a buildable acre.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Commercial acre",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Usable acre",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subdivided acre",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Loveless built a quality custom home in an area where the surrounding homes were valued at $120,000. His home cost $350,000 to construct. He will suffer a loss of value due to:",hint:"A good example question regarding the theory of regression.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"reliction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"retribution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"renovation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"regression.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following types of depreciation would be most difficult to cure?",hint:"Economic obsolescence-a loss of value due to extraneous factors (factors outside the property itself, such as adverse zoning, misplaced improvements, and change of locational demand).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Economic obsolescence",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Functional obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Physical deterioration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Physical depreciation",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not an allowable expense in computing net income for income tax purposes?",hint:"When reporting income for tax reasons you would not estimate vacancies as you do in appraising property. You must report actual income.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Interest on the loan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Reserves for depreciation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Vacancy factor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Social security taxes paid for a manager",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following statements has the most significance in relation to a bearing wall?",hint:"A bearing wall supports a vertical load in addition to its own weight and should be considered when remodeling.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It is parallel to the floor joists and headers",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It will determine the direction the house faces",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It will have no doors nor windows",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It should be considered prior to remodeling",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A roof that inclines from four sides is a:",hint:"Definition: A hip roof is a pitched roof with sloping sides and ends (all four sides).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"gable roof.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"gambrel roof.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trussed roof.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"hip roof.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The market value of a 15-year-old residence is determined by:",hint:"Market data or comparison approach in appraising a residence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cost of replacement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"listing price.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"selling price of comparable residences.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"capitalizing the net income.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The most accurate record of the gross income of a retail grocery business would be shown by the:",hint:"No sales tax on groceries. The most accurate record would be reflected in the state income tax return.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"amount of sales tax paid to the State Board of Equalization.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"owner's listing on the business.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"broker's estimate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"owner's state income tax return.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The type of wood-destroying insect that causes the greatest amount of damage to real property is the:",hint:"Termites are the most destructive type of wood destroying insects. The subterranean type that lives in the soil and enters into the foundation of a home do more damage than the flying type known as the dry wood termite.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"beetle.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"silverfish.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"dry wood termite.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subterranean termite.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following appraisal approaches would tend to set the upper limits of value?",hint:"The cost approach tends to set the upper limit of value for a property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Cost approach",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Market comparison approach",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Capitalization method",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Comparable sales method",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The value of the best property in a neighborhood is adversely affected by a substandard property nearby. This can be described as the principle of:",hint:"The principal of regression says that the value of the best property in a neighborhood is pulled down when a substandard property is built nearby.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"balance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"regression.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"contribution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"progression.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When two properties are identical or highly-similar most buyers focus on lower price. This principle is called.",hint:"The principle of substitution says the buyer will not pay more for a property than other similar properties sell for in the area. Where two properties are similar, most buyers focus on the lower price.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Substitution",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Highest and best use",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Productivity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Diminished use",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What contributes most to the maintenance of value in a well-planned community?",hint:"Conformity to land use objectives contributes to value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Conformity to proper land use objectives",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Prevention of major street construction",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Nonconforming improvements",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Improper orientation",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under the principle of substitution, one assumes that one property may be substituted for another in terms of:",hint:"The principle of substitution assumes that one property may be substituted for another in terms of income, use, or structural design.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"use.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"structural design.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In the situation where no prudent person would pay more for a piece of land than others, which of the following principles would be best applied?",hint:"The principal of substitution assumes that no prudent person would pay more for something than other prudent people.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Balance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Conformity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Intervention",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Substitution",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In the definition of highest and best use, one would likely find the phrase:",hint:"The highest and best use is the use which will create the highest net return on money invested.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"net return.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"gross income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"depreciation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"integration.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appraiser determines an estimate of value based upon what date?",hint:"This is the best available answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The date the purchase contract is signed",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The date escrow was opened",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The date the loan was funded",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The date the deed is recorded",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appraiser's primary concern when analyzing real property is:",hint:"Marketability and acceptability are the primary concerns.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"marketability and acceptability.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"functionality.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"supply and demand.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In the cost approach to appraisal, the phrase "reproduction cost" is different from "replacement cost" in that "replacement cost" measures the:',hint:'The "replacement cost" of a building is the cost to build a comparable structure in terms of utility (comparable usefulness).',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"total cost to replace the building.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"original cost.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"present cost using utility.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"present cost to build an exact replica.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is the definition of value to an appraiser?",hint:"These are all accepted definitions of value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Relationship of desirous persons and things desired",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Ability of one commodity to command other commodities",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Present worth of future benefits arising out of ownership of property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following causes real estate prices to go up?",hint:"An oversupply diminishes value (price) while an undersupply (or increased demand) increases value (price).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Supply and demand are the same",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Supply is greater than demand",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Demand is greater than supply",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Demand is not an issue",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An owner of an apartment building is considering an extensive modernization program. He should put his highest emphasis on:",hint:"The net effect on income is more important than the other factors.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cost.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"history of vacancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"potential increase in real property taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"net effect on income.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A licensee must make an adjustment between the comparable and the subject property because:",hint:"The appraiser adjusts the comparable to the subject property because two properties are rarely identical.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"property eventually must increase in value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"property depreciates.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two properties are rarely similar concerning everything.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"property eventually decreases in value.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A specific purpose property is appraised using which appraisal approach?",hint:"Hospitals, churches, etc. are specific purpose buildings. They are appraised by the cost approach.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Market data",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Capitalization/income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Land residual",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appraiser will seriously consider all of the following in arriving at an opinion of value, except:",hint:"Assessed value has little or no impact on appraised value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"property identification.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"definition of value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"highest and best use.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"assessed value.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The upper limits of value are determined by which approach?",hint:"The reproduction approach generally sets the upper limit on value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Market data",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Reproduction",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Substitution",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The price a property would bring if freely offered on the open market, with both a willing buyer and a willing seller is:",hint:"The price a property would bring if freely offered on the open market, with both a willing buyer and a willing seller, and used in the appraisal of single family residences is known as fair market value - or objective value (since it may be determined by actual data).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"fair market value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"tax value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"transfer value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subjective value.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When would the cost approach to appraisal be most appropriately used?",hint:"The cost approach to appraisal is most appropriate for appraising new property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"New property",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Middle-aged property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Old property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Multi-family property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The first step in the appraisal process is:",hint:"The appraisal process is made up of four main steps: (1) state the problem; (2) gather data (general and specific); (3) decide on the appraisal method to be used; and (4) reconcile or correlate the data for a final value estimate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"correlation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"define or state the problem.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"select the method of appraisal to be used.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"get title report.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When two or more contiguous parcels owned by one person have an increased value, above the value of the individual lots, this is called:",hint:"Plottage is an added value obtained when two or more contiguous lots come under common ownership.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"value increase.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"dual ownership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"plottage.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"severalty ownership.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Depreciation, as used in the cost approach to appraisal, may be defined as:",hint:'"Depreciation" for appraisal purposes means loss in value from any cause.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"realized recapture of accrued income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a loss in value from any cause.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"wear and tear of the improvements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a loss in the value of the land.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A real estate appraiser will determine the capitalization rate by:",hint:"Capitalization rate is determined by: market comparison, band of investment, or summation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"band of investment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"summation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"market comparison.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When the value of real property increased because of an increase in population, this could be classified as:",hint:"An unearned increment is an increase in value due to no effort on the part of the owner, such as an increase in population.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"economic valuation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"economic obsolescence.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unearned increment.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A bare lot would most likely be appraised using which of the following principles?",hint:"Value is set by the cost of getting an equally desirable substitute.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Principal of land use",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Principal of substitution",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Principal of correlation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Principal of net distribution",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which method of appraisal would a licensee use to appraise a restaurant?",hint:"The income approach to appraisal is the best method to appraise a restaurant.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Market data approach",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost approach",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Income approach",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Any of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A residential property that is 15 years old has an average projected physical life of 40 years. This particular property has been superbly maintained and appears as if it were just 5 years old. This represents the concept of:",hint:"The effective age of an improvement reflects how well it has been maintained by the owner. A well maintained structure may have an effective age which is far less than its physical age.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"effective age.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"physical age.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"actual age.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"progressive age.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a building earns sufficient income to justify its continued operation, this is called:",hint:"The economic life of an improvement is the period of time in which the building earns sufficient income to justify its continued operation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"earning life.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"productive life.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"economic life.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'"CRV" is a common phrase used in the financing of real estate. The CRV is issued by the:',hint:"Certificate of reasonable value is the VA appraisal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Federal National Mortgage Association.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Veteran's Administration.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Federal Housing Administration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"California Department of Veteran's Affairs.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'There are three main causes of depreciation. Which of the following finds its origin in "social sources," which is the basis for the old axiom known in social circles that, "more houses are torn down than fall down?"',hint:"Social factors are factors outside the property, hence, economic obsolescence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Economic obsolescence",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Functional obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Straight line depreciation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Physical deterioration",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The age of a single family residence could best be determined by the:",hint:"The tax assessor will adjust his assessed value when improvements have been completed on unimproved property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"type of architecture.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"condition of the house.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"size of trees in the rear yard.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"County Assessor's records.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Ingress and egress are terms used in:",hint:'Access by which to "go in" and "go out" across the property of another.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"appraisal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easements.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"land measurements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"construction.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a house were built in 1948 and appraised in 1993, it:",hint:"In real estate terminology, a house that was actually 45 years old had a physical life of 45 years, making (b) the best answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"had an economic life left of 45 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"had a physical life of 45 years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"had an effective age of 45 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The quantity survey method, square foot method, and unit cost-in place method, are terms most directly related to real estate:",hint:"They come under the cost approach to appraising.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"finance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"management.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appraisal.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"leasing.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If all things are equal, the cost to construct a 2-story dwelling (same square footage) would be:",hint:"Since the property has the same square footage, considering the size of the roof, and the bathrooms being built above each other, the cost of the plumbing would be less; therefore, answer (b) is the best answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"more than the cost of construction of a 1-story dwelling.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"less than the cost of construction of a 1-story dwelling.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the same as the cost of construction of a 1-story dwelling.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which one would be the least important feature in establishing the value for industrial acreage?",hint:"Since we are dealing with industrial acreage, the fertility of the soil would have the least importance in determining the value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Topography",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Top soil",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Fertility",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Subsoil",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'There are three main causes of depreciation. Which of the following finds its origin in the term, "social forces," which is the basis for the old axiom that, "more houses are torn down than fall down?"',hint:"Changes in the social or economic make-up of the neighborhood, zoning changes, over-supply of homes, under-supply of buyers, recession or legislative restrictions can cause economic obsolescence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Economic obsolescence",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Functional obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Straight line depreciation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Physical deterioration",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"On appraising a residential property, which of the following would have the least effect on the appraiser's estimate?",hint:"Appraising takes into consideration its worth now, not what it cost originally.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Interior and exterior condition of an older house",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The average age of similar homes in the neighborhood",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The original cost of the building",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The size and contour of the lot",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In the field of real estate, the terms "quantity survey," "unit-cost-in-place," and "square foot" apply to:',hint:"Reproduction or cost of replacement approach to appraising uses these terms.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"finance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appraising.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"management.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leasing.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would be considered the least desirable tenant for a shopping center?",hint:"Since most rents in shopping centers are based upon percentage leases, the key tenants are the large dollar volume producers. Barber shops usually lend themselves to the neighborhood location and not the shopping",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Supermarket",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Barber shop",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Chain variety store",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Department store",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following was never a method of calculating accelerated depreciation?",hint:"(b), (c), and (d) were accelerated methods that were allowed in prior years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Straight line",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Sum-of-the-digits",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"150% of the declining balance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"200% of the declining balance",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Elevation sheets are used by builders. Which of the following best illustrates what an elevation sheet would reveal?",hint:"Definition: An elevation sheet is a drawing that shows front and side exterior views of a building as it will be when finished.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Exterior sides of the building after all structural work is completed, showing heights, widths, windows and doors, and many other details",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The overall height of the building",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The terrain of the land as opposed to street levels",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The height of curbs as related to flood control",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Capital turnover in real estate investments:",hint:"Due to the high cost and fixity of location, real estate does not turnover as frequently as other commodities.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"are slower than the average commodity.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"is about the same as in other commodities.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"are faster than in the stock market.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is about average with other commodities.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following qualifies as artificial monuments?",hint:"Artificial (man-made).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Rocks and streets",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Streets and canal",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Trees and rocks",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The number of times a given item will sell in a given period of time is known as:",hint:"Turnover is the frequency with which real property in a given area is sold and resold.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"turnover.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"goods sold.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"inventory decrease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Two appraisers, one using a capitalization rate of 11% and the other one 10%, both agree that the net income of a building was $9,020. The higher capitalization rate made the price of the building:",hint:"First appraiser used 10%; $9,020 divided by 10% = $90,200. The second appraiser used 11%. $9,020 divided by 11% = $82,000. The defference is $8,200. Divide the difference $90,200, which is 9% rounded.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"higher by 9%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lower by 4%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$902 lower.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lower by 9%.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"For street improvements, lots are assessed according to:",hint:"According to county regulations, assessments for street improvements are based upon the front foot dimensions of the lot.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"front foot.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"square footage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"market value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"performance.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In one word, the contour of the surface of the land is called:",hint:"Topography is the various surface features or contours of the land that affect construction costs.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"grading.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"topography.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"geography.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"geology.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Most appraisers use the _____________ when appraising a new building.",hint:"Cost or reproduction approach. Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"capitalization approach",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"land residual technique",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"economic rent technique",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cost approach",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The building residual technique of appraising is directly related to the:",hint:"Property residual, building residual, and land residual are all related to capitalization of net income approach.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cost approach.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"capitalization of net income approach.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Inwood and Outwood approach.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the appraisal of commercial property, the most overlooked item of expense is:",hint:"Expenses are generally classified as being either fixed or variable. Fixed expenses include property taxes, insurance and utilities. Variable expenses include management and maintenance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"management costs.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"janitorial expenses.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"expenditures for repainting.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following has never been a method of depreciation?",hint:"Assemblage is the process by which plottage is obtained.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Assemblage",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Straight line depreciation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"150% declining balance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"200% declining balance",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When appraising income producing properties, the appraiser is concerned with the effective gross income. Which of the following with respect to effective gross income, is the appraiser concerned with?",hint:"The effective gross income is the total annual income from the property minus any vacancy or rental losses.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Functional obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Physical deterioration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Interest on the loans",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Vacancy",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'"Depth tables" are used by appraisers when appraising:',hint:"Depth tables are used when appraising commercial property when the lots vary in depth.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"commercial property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"residential property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"real property loan securities.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"desert property, in search of water.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The "adjusted cost basis" includes what additions to the "cost basis?"',hint:"When the cost of capital improvements is added to the original cost basis, the result is the adjusted cost basis.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Vacancy factor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost of improvements",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Depreciation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost to purchase",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In making a real estate appraisal, which of the following dates would be the most important to the appraiser?",hint:"The appraiser is most concerned with the date of the inspection. The date of the inspection is the date of valuation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The date of the escrow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Date the agreement to purchase was signed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Date the deed was transferred",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Date the property was inspected by the appraiser",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"How are the improvements and the land valued when using the cost approach?",hint:"The value of the land is determined using the principles of substitution and the value of the improvements is determined using the cost approach.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Separately, using the principle of substitution",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Separately by more than one approach",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Together, using the principle of highest and best use",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Together, using the market value approach",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Smith built a house with four bedrooms and one bath. When work was completed, the property had depreciated immediately from what cause?",hint:"Out of date design would be functional obsolescence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Functional obsolescence",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Economic obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Social obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker Jones appraised two similar commercial properties. Both were leased on a long term basis. One was a hardware store and the other was a post office. Compared to the hardware store, the capitalization rate on the post office was:",hint:"Because the post office would be more stable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"higher.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lower.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the same.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"higher or lower on different dates.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Regarding the ratio of improvements to land, which would most likely give the greatest depreciation?",hint:"This would be the most expensive construction which means more improvement value. Therefore, more depreciation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Industrial property valued at $100,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Commercial property valued at $100,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Apartment property valued at $100,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Agricultural property valued at $100,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not one of the four elements of the value of real property?",hint:"The acronym “DUST” defines the four elements of the value of real property: Demand, Utility, Scarcity, and Transferability.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Demand",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Utility",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Scarcity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Snyder just bought a used apartment building. For income tax purposes, what method of depreciation should she take?",hint:"Straight line depreciation is the only method of depreciation available for property bought since 1987.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"150% declining balance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"200% declining balance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sum-of-the-years digits",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Straight line",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Relating to the appraisal field, growth, decline, progression, and regression are parts of what concept?",hint:'All four words in the question relate to the theory of "change" as to the appraising concept of real property.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Distribution",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost of living index",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Change",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Should you be asked to appraise a piece of property with a worthless building on it, in order to arrive at the value of the lot and determine its highest and best use, you would:",hint:"To determine the value of a lot for its highest and best use, an appraiser always deducts any cost of demolition that must take place in order to make that lot vacant once again.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"appraise the existing building, then deduct value of land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ignore worthless building completely.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subtract the cost of removing the worthless building from the current value of the lot.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"use the building residual technique.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Appraisers speak of the highest and best use. Of the following, which is related to this expression?",hint:"The principle of highest and best use is based on the reasonable use of real property at the time of the appraisal, which is most likely to produce the greatest net return to the land and/or the building over a given period of time.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A starting point for an appraisal",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Greatest net return",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'The terms "net income" and "net spendable income" are used in reference to income property. Which of the following is a correct statement concerning these terms?',hint:"Net income is the result obtained by subtracting expenses of operation from effective gross income. Net spendable income is the result obtained by subtracting finance payments from the net income, and is used with a capitalization rate to determine value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Net income is the result obtained by subtracting a vacancy factor from gross income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Net spendable income is the result obtained after subtracting expenses of operation from effective gross incomes",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Net spendable income is the result obtained when financing payments are subtracted from net income",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Net spendable income is used with a capitalization rate to determine value",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An apartment was purchased for $175,000. The terms of purchase were $125,000 cash and a purchase money deed of trust for the balance. The land was valued at $60,000. What would the adjusted cost basis of the property be after it is fully depreciated?",hint:"Only the improvements are depreciated; therefore, after the property has been fully depreciated, the adjusted cost basis would still be the original value of the land, $60,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The remaining balance on the purchase money deed of trust",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$115,000, the value of the improvements",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$60,000, the value of the land",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It would have no adjusted cost basis as it is fully depreciated",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning the comparison method?",hint:"The sales comparison approach is the one most easily understood and commonly used by real estate agents. It is easily applied for the sale of single family homes and is best for single family homes or condominiums and vacant lots.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It is the quickest and easiest method",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is the simplest method and easiest for a beginner to learn",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is often used to appraise unimproved land",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above are correct",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning the cost method of appraisal?",hint:"The cost approach tends to set the upper limit of value for a property. It is not difficult to estimate the replacement cost of new structures, but it is difficult to estimate depreciation in older buildings. The cost approach is also used with unique or one-of-a-kind buildings where it is difficult to find comparables.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It sets the upper limit of value",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Little difficulty is encountered in estimating the replacement cost of new structures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Serious difficulties often arise in obtaining an accurate computation of accrued depreciation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above are correct statements",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning the income method of appraisal?",hint:"Statements of fact",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It requires the determination of net income before interest and amortization, but after deduction of operating expenses",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An appropriate capitalization rate must be determined",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is not applicable to owner-occupied homes because benefits of amenities are difficult to measure in terms of dollars",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above are correct",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Depreciation is defined as a loss of value due to any cause. It is also classified as curable and incurable. Of the following statements concerning depreciation, which one is correct?",hint:"Answer (a) is economic obsolescence--incurable. Answer (b) is functional obsolescence--incurable. Answer (c) is unearned increment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A massive cornice on a roof is an example of physical deterioration--curable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Bad architectural design is an example of functional obsolescence-curable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Population pressures forcing price upward in an inflationary spiral is an example of economic obsolescence--incurable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Bearing walls sagging beyond a 30-degree angle is an example of physical deterioration--incurable",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Economic obsolescence is said to be extraneous, caused by environmental or economic changes. Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning economic obsolescence?",hint:"Answer (a) is physical deterioration. Answer (b) is functional obsolescence. Answer (c) is a statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Deferred maintenance causes economic obsolescence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Poor architectural design",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Value loss due to proximity to a major highway causing noise and traffic hazards will create economic obsolescence",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above is correct",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The market value of a 15-year old residence is most commonly determined by:",hint:"Market data or comparison approach in appraising a residence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cost of replacement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"listing price.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"selling price of comparable residences.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"capitalizing the net income.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appraisal method used to establish land value whereby the appraiser attributes part of the property's value to the land and part to the building is called:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all interchangeable words as defined in the question itself.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"distribution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"allocation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"abstraction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When purchasing a business opportunity, a buyer, in addition to cash flow, would be most interested in:",hint:"Annual net income is income after all debts have been paid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"goodwill.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"location.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"annual gross income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"annual net income.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"If a building extends beyond the land of its owner and covers some land of an adjoining property, what is created?",hint:"If a permanent improvement such as a fence, wall, driveway or roof extends over the lot line into adjacent property owned by another person, it is known as an encroachment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An encumbrance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An encroachment",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An easement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Prescription",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In buying a commercial building (property), the buyer is concerned that all costs be considered in determining net income. One of the most easily over-looked costs, which may later result in a sudden and substantial outlay on the part of the owner, is:",hint:"The other factors are well known to income property investors.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"deferred maintenance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"management costs.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"improper floor plans.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"poor locations (economic obsolescence).",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not classified as obsolescence?",hint:"This is an example of physical deterioration.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Poor floor plan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Massive cornices",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Old fashioned kitchen fixtures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Worn out roof",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An increase in value of real property is known as:",hint:"The opposite of depreciation is appreciation, or an increase in value for a specific property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"depreciation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appreciation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"deferred maintenance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leverage.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In deciding the value of industrial property, which of the following would be the least vital?",hint:"Fertility of soil has no value in industrial property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Topography",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subsoil",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Plottage",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Fertility",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Value is created, maintained, modified, and destroyed by all of the following except:",hint:"The relationship of the following four forces - physical characteristics, economic influences, political or governmental regulations, and social ideals - creates, maintains, modifies, and destroys value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"physical forces.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"social forces.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"personal forces.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"political forces.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which principle of valuation says that value is set by the cost of getting an equally desirable substitute?",hint:"The principle of substitution is the basis of the appraisal process. Explained simply, value is set by the cost of getting an equally desirable substitute.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Principle of conformity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Principle of supply and demand",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Principle of highest and best use",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Principle of substitution",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When two properties are identical or highly-similar, most buyers focus on lower price. This principle is called:",hint:"The principle of substitution says the buyer will not pay more for a property than other similar properties sell for in the area. Where two properties are similar, most buyers focus on the lower price.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"substitution.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"highest and best use.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"productivity.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"diminished use.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the cost approach to appraisal, the phrase reproduction cost is different from replacement cost in that replacement cost measures:",hint:'The "replacement cost" of a building is the cost to build a comparable structure in terms of utility (comparable usefulness).',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the total cost to replace the building.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the original cost.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the present cost using utility.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the present cost to build an exact replica.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is an example of economic obsolescence?",hint:"An oversupply of like properties in the neighborhood is an example of economic obsolescence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A leaky roof",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No parking",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An oversupply of like properties",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A severely deteriorated bearing wall",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'"Depreciation," as used in the cost approach to appraisal, may be defined as:',hint:'"Depreciation" for appraisal purposes means loss in value from any cause.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a realized recapture of accrued income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a loss in value from any cause.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"wear and tear of the improvements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a loss in the value of the land.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A residential property that is 15 years old, has an average projected physical life of 40 years. This particular property has been superbly maintained and appears as if it were just 5 years old. This represents the concept of:",hint:"The effective age of an improvement reflects how well it has been maintained by the owner. A well maintained structure may have an effective age which is far less than its physical age.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"effective age.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"physical age.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"actual age.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"progressive age.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The age of a house can be determined most accurately by inspecting the:",hint:"Annual assessments of all taxable property appear in the Assessment Roll or Tax Roll, a public record maintained by the City or County Assessor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"physical condition of the house.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"architectural style of the house.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tax assessor's records.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"recorded subdivision map.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Regarding past and future depreciation it is true that the:",hint:"Straight line depreciation is a method under which improvements are depreciated at a constant rate throughout the economic age or estimated useful life of the improvement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cost to cure method of estimating depreciation mainly focuses on future depreciation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"straight-line method of depreciation may be used to measure past or future depreciation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"cost approach deals with accruals for past and future depreciation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"income approach provides for accrued depreciation in projecting net income into future income.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In which of the following is the appraiser estimating the value of the land by considering it as fully developed to its highest and best use, then deducting the cost of development?",hint:"By definition.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Land residual method",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Development method",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Comparative approach",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Building residual technique",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under real estate law an appraisal would be required:",hint:"The requirement of an appraisal is to try to minimize the potential for fraud or misrepresentation in the sale of property located out-of-state being offered to Californians.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"in any sale of real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in the sale of subdivided land located out-of-state being offered for sale in the State of California.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"whenever land is subdivided in California.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in the use of a land contract for the sale of property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Developer Stone is thinking of building a neighborhood shopping center. The population concentration needed for the area is:",hint:"Shopping centers' population requirements:\nNeighborhood shopping center (5,000-10,0000 population required)\nMajor shopping center or mall (50,000- )",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5,000 to 10,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"20,000 to 30,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30,000 to 50,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"75,000 to 100,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If economy was experiencing a down-turn, who would be the least affected?",hint:"People will usually always have need for these services.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Medical/dental office",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Industrial park",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Production plant",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Chain mall",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the appraisal process the first step is to:",hint:"1. define the problem, 2. reconcile, 3. set opinion of value",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"define the problem, second is to set the opinion of value, and the final step is to reconcile.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reconcile, second is to define the problem, and the final step is to set the opinion of the value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"define the problem, second is to reconcile, and the final step is to set the opinion of value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"set opinion of value, second is to define the problem, and the final step is to reconcile.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An appraisal has been requested for a residential home. The homeis actually 10 years old but because it has been exceptionally cared for, the appraiser places its age at 6 years. This would be known as:",hint:"Actual age is the real age of the building. Effective age is not determined by the actual age of a building, but by its condition and usefulness.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"actual age",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"effective age",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"undepreciated age",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"remaining life",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Sometimes a real estate appraiser uses a gross rent multiplier to determine property value. An appraiser can determine the gross rent multiplier by:",hint:"A gross rent multiplier, when multipled by the total annual rents, will give a rough estimate of a property value that can then be compared with other like properties. It is a means of quickly converting gross rent into market value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"dividing the sales price by the net monthly income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"multiplying the gross income by the capitalization rate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"dividing the sales price by the capitalization rate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"dividing the verified sales price of the property by the gross monthly rental",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Slanted boards that support the roof boards and shingles are called:",hint:"Rafters are slanted boards of a roof that are designed to support the roof boards and shingles.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"studs",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"eaves",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"rafters",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"joists",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When making his or her assessment of value, the appraiser must physically inspect the property every _____ to ensure the tax roll meets all the requirements of law.",hint:"The real property appraiser must inspect the property every three years to ensure the tax roll meets all the requirements of law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"three years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"five years",isCorrect:!1}]}}]},{category:"Finance",id:5,list:[{questionText:'The terms "blank, restricted, and qualified" refer to:',hint:"Signing the owner's name on the reverse side of a negotiable instrument such as a check or promissory note is a method of transferring title and is called an endorsement. A blank endorsement guarantees payment to subsequent holders or the note or check. In insurance policies, a restricted endorsement acknowledges the policy coverage. In FHA loans, a qualified endorsement will indicate that the loan is insured under the National Housing Act.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"endorsement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you own a piece of real property with a fixed income and you discover a very serious inflationary trend in the economy. How would this affect your equity in the property?",hint:"Historically, real property has shown a consistent growth in value and remains the best hedge against inflation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Value of your equity would increase",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Value of your equity would remain the same",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"You would not be affected by this inflationary trend at all",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Value of your equity would decrease",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following instruments are commonly recorded except:",hint:"Instruments are formal legal documents such as contracts (mortgage or lien), deeds, or wills which are relied on as the basis, proof or support of anything else. A promissory note is evidence of a debt.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"promissory note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lien.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"CRV is a common phrase used in the financing of real estate. CRV is issued by the:",hint:"Certificate of Reasonable Value is the VA appraisal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Federal National Mortgage Association.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Veteran's Administration.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Federal Housing Administration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"California Department of Veteran's Affairs.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A down payment of $1,000 for the purchase of an apartment house valued at $690,000 is a good example of:",hint:"The definition of leverage can be viewed as using a small down payment to purchase as much property as possible.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"plottage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leverage.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"highest and best value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Ms. "A" purchased a piece of property for $200,000, incurring a 30 year loan for $180,000. Inflationary trends caused the dollar to decrease in value. Who would benefit?',hint:"Trustor--Borrower.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trustee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trustor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Beneficiary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mortgagee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A client contacts you to give you a listing. You look at his papers and discover that he is purchasing the property on a contract of sale. The contract contains no acceleration clause and there are no restrictions in the contract of sale prohibiting resale or assignment. One of the following is the most nearly correct statement. Your client could:",hint:'In (a) he can sell his interest without paying off the existing contract. In (c) and (d) he cannot give a deed of any kind because, as the "equitable owner" only, he has no title to convey.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"sell his interest in the property but only after first paying off the existing contract of sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sell or assign his rights but not his duties without approval of the contract seller.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:'properly give a warranty deed to the property to the purchaser providing the deed recited "subject to the existing contract of sale."',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"properly give a grant deed to the property to the purchaser.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under a land contract or a conditional contract of sale, the seller would not normally initiate a legal action based upon:",hint:"The right to record is protected by law and an agreement to give it away is unenforceable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"specific performance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"damages.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an agreement not to record.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"You are in default on a note secured by a trust deed. If the trustee acts promptly exercising the power of sale, what is the approximate time in which foreclosure can be completed?",hint:"Three months plus 21 days--approximately 4 months.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"One month",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Three months",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Four months",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"One year",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The majority of real estate loans are made by institutional investors. Which of the following would be classified as an institutional investor?",hint:"Institutional lenders include banks (not bank trust departments), savings and loans, and insurance companies.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trust department of a bank",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Insurance company",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"University",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mortgage investment company",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A seller takes back a trust deed and note as part of the purchase price and the buyer immediately defaults. What action could the seller take?",hint:"The seller could only foreclose since no deficiency judgment is possible on a purchase money trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Attachment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Writ of execution",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Deficiency judgment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'Request trustee to record a "Notice of Default"',isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When applying for an FHA loan, which of the following would be given the least credit in determining the qualifications for the loan?",hint:"Overtime pay is too uncertain to be given much credit by FHA.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Husband's salary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Wife's salary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Outstanding debts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Husband's overtime",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lender receiving a trust deed as security for a loan would be given the best protection by the:",hint:"Lenders consider the property value their prime protection, particularly when the property is the security for the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"credit of the buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"value of the property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"increase in the value of money.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A promissory note that provides for the payment of interest only during the term of the note is known as:",hint:"If interest only is paid during the term, the principal will be paid in one lump sum. This type of note is called a straight note.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an installment note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a straight note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an amortized note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a non-interest bearing note.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not a negotiable instrument?",hint:"To be negotiable, it must be a promise to pay. The trust deed is only the security for the promise to pay.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Promissory note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trust deed",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Installment note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Personal check",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is true?",hint:"Trustor may reinstate the loan up until 5 days before a trustee's sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A mortgage may be reinstated within 1 year following the sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The trust deed may be redeemed during the 3 months following notification of defaults",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The trust deed may be reinstated up until 5 days before a trustee's sale",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is an institutional lender?",hint:"Insurance companies are identified as institutional lenders. The others are non-institutional lenders.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Mortgage company",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real estate investment trust",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Insurance companies",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under federal law, a real estate investment trust must consist of:",hint:"To qualify as a real estate investment trust it must consist of at least 100 members, not necessarily more than 100 members.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5 persons or less.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5 persons but less than 100.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at least 100 persons.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"more than 100 persons.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a contractor receives the money from a construction lender in stages of his construction, it is called an:",hint:"The lender may withhold portions of the loan until certain stages of construction have been accomplished, but he is obligated to finally advance the full amount of the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"obligatory advance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"optional advance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"open end mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"progressive financing.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A person can borrow money on personal property with a:",hint:"The security agreement has replaced the chattel mortgage where personal property is used as security for a loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"bill of sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"chattel mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"security agreement.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Discount points paid for a loan would affect the:",hint:"Discount points paid for a loan are considered interest that is paid in advance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"principal amount.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interest paid on the loan.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"impounds.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In real estate financing, lenders will sometimes find it necessary to refer to "nominal rate" when granting a loan. This means:',hint:'The word "nominal" stems from the word "name" and is the rate named in the note.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"that the rate of interest in the final granting of the loan will be greater than the commitment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"points will be required because the rate required by the lender would exceed the legal rate of interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the term used by lenders when the maximum rate of interest allowed by law is obtainable on financing a property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"it is the rate of interest specified in the promissory note.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'In real estate financing, reference is sometimes made to "take out loans." This refers to:',hint:'A "take out loan" is the long term financing that replaces the interim construction loan. It "takes" the construction lender "out" of the financing picture.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"net amount after points and prepaid interest are deducted.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a blanket encumbrance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a construction loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"long term loan taken out after construction.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'Mr. Small sells his house for $10,000 and takes back a trust deed and note for $5,000. Needing cash, he immediately sells the trust deed and note at a discount to Mr. Big for $3,500, assigning the trust deed and endorsing the note "without recourse." If trustor defaults before making any principal payments, disregarding costs of collection, by which method would buyer of the first trust deed get the greatest amount in the shortest period of time?',hint:"The fact that Mr. Smith sold this purchase money encumbrance at a discount in order to obtain ready cash does not change the face value of the note.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Foreclosure by trustee's sale to collect $3,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sue for specific performance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Recover from Mr. Small because the transaction was usurious",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Foreclosure by trustee's sale to recover $5,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When a trust deed is properly prepared and executed, the power of sale of the secured property is given by the:",hint:"Naked or legal title, along with power of sale, is conveyed through the trust deed by trustor to trustee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"beneficiary to the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buyer to the trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor to the lender.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor to the trustee.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In new construction financing, the lender will usually release the final payment to the borrower when the:",hint:"The lender does not usually release the final payment until the mechanic's lien period expires.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"owner has accepted the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lien period has expired.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"work has been completed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"notice of completion has been recorded.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man had a second trust deed for $200,000. He sold it to a friend for $150,000. In the language of real estate practice, this would be known as:",hint:"Trust deeds and notes sold for less than the unpaid balance are said to be sold at discount.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a prepayment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"hypothecation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"usury.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"discounting.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A primary source of funds for residential financing is:",hint:"By far the largest source in California.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the Federal Home Loan Bank.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"savings banks.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the Federal Housing Administration.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The trustor under a trust deed is the party who:",hint:"The trustor is the one who borrows the money and therefore, promises to pay back the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"lends the money.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"receives the note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"holds the property in trust.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"signs the note as maker.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Will needs $2,000 to close an escrow. He holds a $6,000 note secured by a second trust deed on a farm. Manny agrees to lend him the necessary amount if Will puts up the note as security. This type of security is known as a:",hint:'"Pledge" is the depositing of personal property by a debtor with a creditor as security for a debt.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"pledge.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"chattel mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"purchase money mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subordination clause.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mortgage companies, which operate primarily as mortgage loan correspondents of life insurance companies, mutual savings banks, and others, are usually regulated by:",hint:"Mortgage companies operating primarily as mortgage loan correspondents are not considered to be institutional lenders and are not subject to the same controls. Organized under state laws, they are subject to minimum supervision.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"federal law.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"state law.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"county ordinances.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Federal Housing Administration.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"After a notice of default has been recorded, what is the maximum time during which a trustor can reinstate his loan?",hint:"Trustor may reinstate a loan up until 5 days before a trustee sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"One year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"120 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3 months",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Any time up until 5 days before a trustee sale",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Consideration can be:",hint:"Covenants are promises and we know that consideration can be money, services, or promises. It can also be love and affection.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"money.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"services.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"covenants.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'The "Loan Brokerage Law" requires the broker to retain a copy of the loan broker\'s statement in his office files for a period not less than:',hint:"Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1 year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4 years.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Subordinate is most opposite to:",hint:"Subordinated loan will come second. Opposite would be superior or first.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"superior.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"inferior.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subrogation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"novation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A long term loan to be issued by one lender upon completion of the interim construction financing by another lender is known as a:",hint:"Takeout loan takes out the construction loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"discount loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"redemption loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"takeout loan.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"renewal loan.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who signs a deed of reconveyance?",hint:"Reconveying legal title back to the trustor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trustor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trustee",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Beneficiary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mortgagee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The least complicated loan to assume would be:",hint:"There are two federal agencies and one state agency that help make it possible for people to buy homes they would never be able to purchase without government involvement (the FHA and the VA, and the Cal-Vet loans). Ease of assumption by the FHA is described in “Loans” chapter.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"institutional.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cal-Vet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"FHA.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"savings bank.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A federal act that provides protection against foreclosures of real property owned by a person in the service is:",hint:"The SSCRA (Soldiers and Sailors Civil Relief Act) is a federal law designed to protect persons who enter military service with mortgaged property from losing their property. If they are unable to pay their loan obligations due to the down-scaling of pay after entering the military service, the court has wide discretionary powers to protect the defaulting military service person.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Serviceman's Readjustment Act of 1944.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Soldiers and Sailors Civil Relief Act.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Moratorium Relief Act of 1968.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Release of Obligation Act of 1947.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A subdivider's final map has been approved, but he has not received the Commissioner's Final Report. The maximum number of parcels that may be used to secure a loan before the loan is a blanket encumbrance is:",hint:"When more than one lot is used as security under one loan, it is considered to be a blanket encumbrance. One lot only could be used as security for the loan. Using more than one constitutes a blanket encumbrance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"2.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The largest number of home loans are made by:",hint:"Currently savings and loan associations and savings banks are the largest single resource for residential mortgage credit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"savings banks.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Veteran's Administration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"FHA.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commercial banks.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"You, as an agent, have sold a home for which you negotiated a first loan with a bank and a second loan to be taken back by the seller. You have been requested to record a Request for Notice of Default. This is usually to protect:",hint:"The purpose of a request for notice of default is if the trustor defaults on the first loan, the trustee of the first loan must notify the beneficiary (lender) of the second loan of the trustor's default.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trustee of the first loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee of the second loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor of the second loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"beneficiary of the second loan.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which instrument is most valuable to a buyer who may fall on temporary hard times or default on payments?",hint:"Mortgage would give the buyer more time to redeem himself.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"First trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Second trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Financing agreement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mortgage",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A subdivider purchased 10 acres at $20,000 per acre. He paid $20,000 as a down payment. The balance was to be in the form of a straight note secured by a first trust deed. The said trust deed contained a release clause providing that, upon each payment of $20,000, one acre would be released free and clear. The subdivider subsequently paid $40,000 on the principal and received a release on two acres of land free and clear. By this transaction, the percentage of his equity in the encumbered property would do which of the following?",hint:"The equity is the difference between the market value of the encumbered acreage and the amount of the loan.|10 acres valued at $20,000 each - $18,000 loan = $2,000 equity per acre;|8 acres valued at $16,000 each - $14,000 loan = $2,000 equity per acre;|$2,000 equity = 1/9 = $18,000 loan;|$2,000 equity =1/7 = $14,000 loan;|His equity has increased from 1/9th to 1/7th of the encumbered property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Increase",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Decrease",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Stay the same",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Decrease when the first four lots were released and increase when the last six are released",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A lender's fee required of a buyer to obtain an FHA loan is called an:",hint:"One of the costs in setting up a home equity line of credit is similar to that which a borrower pays when he or she buys a home. It is an application fee (or lender's fee).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"accommodation fee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"originating fee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"acceptance fee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"application fee.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An individual wishes to borrow money and is advised by the lender that he will only accept a negotiable instrument as security for the loan. Which of the following documents is not a negotiable instrument?",hint:"A trust deed is a security device, not a negotiable instrument.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A check",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A draft",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A trust deed",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A promissory note",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mortgages and trust deeds are considered:",hint:'A "chattels real" is a lease.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"personal property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"chattels real.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estates.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is the maximum loan available on a VA loan?",hint:"Means Certificate of Reasonable Value. This is the appraised value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"80% of appraisal",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"90% of appraisal",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$45,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Amount on CRV",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A property is in the process of foreclosure. If selling under the power of sale clause of a trust deed, the trustee must wait 3 months before:",hint:"Foreclosure on a Trust Deed by (non-judicial) Trustee's Sale proceeds as follows:\n1) The lender (beneficiary) notifies the borrower (trustor) of default and requests the trustee to record a notice of default; 2) Anyone recording a Request for Notice must be notified of the default; 3) The trustee must wait at least three months after recording the notice of default before advertising the trustee sale.; 4) The trustee advertises a Notice of Sale once a week for three weeks (21 days) and posts a notice of sale on the property; and 5) The trustee holds the sale and issues a trustee's deed to the highest bidder.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"publishing a notice of intention to sell the property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"publishing a notice of foreclosure on the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"recording a notice of default.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who benefits when there is a subordination clause in a trust deed?",hint:"This enables the trustor to subsequently borrow money on the property giving a first trust deed as security for the loan, the previous trust deed then being subordinated to second position.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trustor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Trustee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Beneficiary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mortgagee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Seller takes back a purchase money first trust deed on a home. The buyer sometime later has to take out a second trust deed with a bank and later defaults on both loans. Which of the following is a true statement?",hint:"There is no deficiency judgment allowed on a purchase money loan. The loan from the bank is hard money and therefore a deficiency judgment would be allowed as long as the bank foreclosed through court action.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Seller can get a deficiency judgment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Bank can get a deficiency judgment",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"No one can get a deficiency judgment on a trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b) are correct",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many points is a buyer/borrower limited to paying on FHA Loans?",hint:"As of 10/1/83, FHA loan points can be negotiated between buyer and seller.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"One",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Two",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Four",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No limitation",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When a trust deed is properly executed, the power of sale is given by the:",hint:"Trustor (borrower) to the trustee. This gives the trustee the power to sell the property if the trustor defaults.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trustor to the trustee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"trustor to the beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"beneficiary to the trustee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Bone wishes to purchase a piece of industrial property and apply for a large first trust deed loan to help him purchase the property. The lender is most interested in:",hint:"The lender would probably be interested in all of these; however, he would be most interested in answer (b).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the appraised value of the land and the improvements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the financial condition and credit standing of the individual or company applying for the loan.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the amount of the demand for the product being manufactured on the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Most construction loans are made by:",hint:"Savings and loan associations prefer home loans. Life insurance companies prefer commercial loans.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"savings banks.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commercial banks.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"life insurance companies.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both (a) and (c) above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'An "assignment of rents" clause in a trust deed would most likely benefit:',hint:"An assignment of rents permits the lender to collect any rents from the tenants and apply them to the loan while the property is under foreclosure proceedings.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"beneficiary.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"trustee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lessee.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'"Loan to value ratio" indicates which of the following relationships?',hint:"The loan to value ratio is the percentage of appraised value to the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Assessed value to the market value of the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Loan value to the insured value",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Loan value to the appraised value",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Loan value to the sales price",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Norris purchased a piece of property for $200,000, incurring a 30 year loan for $180,000. Inflationary trends caused the dollar to decrease in value. Who would benefit?",hint:"Trustor--Borrower.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trustee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trustor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Beneficiary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mortgagee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who would pay the points on a Cal-Vet loan?",hint:"There are no points on a Cal-Vet loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The buyer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The lender",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following institutions invests most of their funds in home loans?",hint:"An opinion answer of the state exam. We agree with their opinion.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Insurance companies",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mortgage companies",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Federal savings banks",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Private individuals",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The type of interest charged on home loans is:",hint:"The interest charged on most real estate loans is simple interest - interest which is paid only on the principal owned.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"compound interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"straight interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"simple interest.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"renewed interest.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Real estate syndicates have recently come under the jurisdiction of the Real Estate Commission. A real estate syndicate can operate as a:",hint:"Real estate syndicates may operate as partnerships, corporations, or real estate investment trusts.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"all of the following.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"real estate investment trust.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"corporation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you are a real estate licensee acting on behalf of a group of investors who have formed a real estate syndicate and desire to limit the liability of the members. These investors would probably form a:",hint:"In answers (a), (b), and (c) the investors' liability would be limited.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"limited partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"corporation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"real estate investment trust.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Most real estate syndicates are:",hint:"It is not general partnerships because this is usually involved in a corporate entity. It would not be corporations because this insures limited liability for the investors but is seldom utilized in modern syndicates. Limited partnerships combine nearly all of the advantages of the corporate/partnership forms. Limited partnerships are one of the most frequently selected for real estate syndicates.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"general partnerships.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"limited partnerships.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"corporations.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Interest paid on the principal and on the amount of simple interest is referred to as:",hint:"Compound interest is interest paid on the original principal and also on the accrued and unpaid interest which accumulates as the debt matures.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"straight.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"simple.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nominal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"compound.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Considering construction financing, the lender will usually release the final payment to the borrower when:",hint:"Lenders usually withhold the last 10% of the loan until the lien period has expired, thereby protecting themselves to a degree if a mechanic's lien foreclosure sale were instituted.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the lien period has expired.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"notice of completion is recorded.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"work has stopped for 30 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In 1968 a new organization was formed to assume many of the functions of the Federal National Mortgage Association. This organization also works hand in hand with the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). This organization is known as:",hint:"Answers (b) and (c) are the two names used for this organization that are explained in the question itself.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"F.N.M.A.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Ginnie Mae.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Government National Mortgage Association.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both (b) and (c)",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Under the Truth in Lending Law, when a borrower wishes to borrow money (not on a first trust deed loan to purchase the property) and agrees to use his residence as security for the loan, how many days has he to rescind his offer?",hint:"The right to rescind or cancel a real estate loan applies to most consumer credit loans (not for purchase of construction of the borrower's residence), and the borrower has a right to rescind the agreement until midnight of the third business day after the promissory note is signed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3 days",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"No set time limit",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"One week",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Most of the junior loans that are available today are secured through:",hint:"One way to get the needed financing is for the buyer to obtain a secondary loan through an outside source, such as a mortgage lender, private investor or even the seller of the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"private lenders.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"state chartered savings banks.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"federal chartered savings banks.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"federal national mortgage associations.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The factor exerting the greatest influence on interest rates pertaining to first trust deed loans is:",hint:"When money is not avavilable to lend, the price (interest rate) for borrowing it will be higher.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"demand.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the cost for arranging state bond issues.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the economic condition of the country.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the availability of loan funds.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"There are many differences between mortgages and trust deeds. All of the following are differences except:",hint:"In a trust deed, bare legal title is conveyed to the trustee. In a mortgage, title is maintained by the borrower (mortgagor). A trust deed has 3 parties and a mortgage has 2 parties. In a trust deed and a mortgage the security is held by the lender.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"conveyance of title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the number of parties involved in the instrument.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"security for the loan is held by the lender.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An impound account on a loan benefits the:",hint:"Impound accounts are to protect the lender and the property. Their purpose is to insure the lender that the property taxes and insurance will be paid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"borrower.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lender.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"FHA.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Following a trustee sale, the money is dispersed in the following manner:",hint:"Money from a trustee sale is paid out as follows: 1) trustee's fees, costs and expenses of the sale; 2) any tax and assessment liens that are due and owed; 3) prioritized trust deeds, mortgages and mechanic's liens; and 4) the defaulting borrower.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"first trust deed, second trust deed, cost and expenses of sale, balance to the trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cost and expenses of sale, first trust deed, second trust deed, balance to the trustor.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"equity in property to trustor, first trust deed, second trust deed, cost and expenses of sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee's decision as to disbursing the funds.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A first trust deed has a clause in it referring to a previously recorded instrument; that instrument would be a:",hint:"A fictitious trust deed refers to the part of a trust deed that may list restrictions, clauses, etc., but, to save recording costs for the many pages that might exist, are simply referred to in the recorded trust deed as part of the original document, but not part of the recordation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"subordination clause agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fictitious trust deed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"primary evidence first trust deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'When a loan is "called" by the beneficiary, this means:',hint:"Definition: “Calling” a loan is a clause in a mortgage or trust deed that gives the mortgagee or beneficiary (lender) the right to accelerate payment of the entire note due.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the borrower has the right to pay off the balance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the lender accelerates all monies due.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the beneficiary and the borrower have agreed to the terms of the loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A loan may be made current (reinstated) up to______prior to the foreclosure sale:",hint:"During the time between recording the notice of default and the trustee sale (a minimum three months and 21 days, the trustor may bring current (reinstate) the loan up to five business days prior to the trustee's sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5 days.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"4 days.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A loan secured by several properties is a:",hint:"A trust deed or mortgage that covers more than one parcel of property may be secured by a blanket loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"shared equity loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"roll-over loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"installment loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"blanket loan.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are parties to a trust deed except:",hint:"There are three parties to a trust deed: the borrower (trustor), lender (beneficiary) and a neutral third party called a trustee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"vendee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"trustee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When there is more than one borrower on a promissory note, the lender will include the term:",hint:"Jointly and severally means all borrowers are liable for the entire loan amount together or individually.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"due on sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"power of sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"no grace period.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"jointly and severely.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A written promise to pay or evidence of a debt is called a:",hint:"A written agreement between a lender and a borrower to document a loan is called a promissory note.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"promissory note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"reconveyance deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"grant deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a loan is secured by a borrower's residence, a prepayment penalty is not allowed after:",hint:"A prepayment penalty is not allowed on a loan against the borrower's residence after the loan is seven years old.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"4 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"7 years.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following are synonymous?",hint:'Construction and interior loans are "short term" loans. They would be taken out by a take-out loan.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Take-out loan and construction loan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Construction loan and interim loan",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Interim loan and take-out loans",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Construction loan and open end loan",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"To bring current and restore is to:",hint:"As in reinstating a loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"pledge.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"usury.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reinstate.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"redeem.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'At times when money is considered "tight":',hint:"When money is tight, interest rates generally go up. A VA loan will always charge more points than a conventional loan. A buyer can only pay one point on a VA or FHA loan; however, if money is tight, the seller may agree to pay all the points in order to make the sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a seller may have to pay for all the points in order that the buyer may obtain an FHA loan.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a buyer may have to pay all the points when obtaining a VA loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a VA loan charges less points than a conventional loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interest rates generally go down.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In searching the files of the county recorder's office, you could most likely tell a first trust deed from a second trust deed by:",hint:"Most likely. The exception would be if it had been subordinated.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"reading of the document.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"information received from the recorder.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reading the contents of the document.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"time and date of recording.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In purchasing a house, which of the following methods of financing could be accomplished without a down payment?",hint:"The others demand some down payment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"FHA",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cal-Vet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"VA",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Conventional",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A borrower on a new loan is required to advance $412.00 for an impound account. He would do so for the benefit of:",hint:"An impound account is an account into which money is paid by the borrower to insure the payment of taxes and fire insurance when due. Most beneficiaries/lenders require this of borrowers/trustors. Hence, answer (b) is the best answer given.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the trustor only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the trustor and the beneficiary.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"F.N.M.A.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the trustee.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A hard money loan is:",hint:"Hard money loans are given to existing owners of real property for any purpose other than buying real property. Usually considered a personal loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a loan of money when money is hard to get.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a loan made to the trustor to help him purchase a piece of real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a loan of cash to an existing owner of real property to buy an automobile.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Another name for a wrap-around loan is:",hint:"Definition: A wrap-around mortgage (loan), or an all-inclusive trust deed, is a type of seller financing (wrapping an existing loan with a new loan, and allowing the borrower to make one payment for both loans).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"swing loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"shared appreciation loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reverse annuity loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all inclusive trust deed.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A real estate financing device which a seller can use to transfer equitable title to a buyer is known as:",hint:"It is most commonly referred to as a land contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a land contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an agreement of sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a conditional sales contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A trustee's sale is related to:",hint:"There are two ways to foreclose: by trustee's sale and by judicial process. Foreclosure is the legal procedure used by lenders to terminate all rights, title and interest of the trustor or mortgagor in real property by selling the property and using the sale proceed to satisfy the liens of creditors.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"yard sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"foreclosure.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"installment sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deficiency judgment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which one of the following most clearly identifies a "sophisticated investor?"',hint:'The "sophisticated investor" attempts to use as much leverage as practical. Leverage means use of credit.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"One who pays all cash",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"One who uses as much of another's money as possible",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"One who uses equal amounts of cash and financing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"One who makes a large down payment and pays interest only on the loan",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What type of contract does a veteran receive in a Cal-Vet purchase?",hint:"The California Department of Veterans Affairs sells bonds to purchase homes and then sells the homes to qualified California veterans using a land sale contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mortgage",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Land contract",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Any of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The power of sale is given to the trustee by the:",hint:"Borrower (trustor) irrevocably grants and conveys to trustee, in trust, with power of sale, the property in the event of default by the borrower.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"vendor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A legal procedure used to terminate the rights and title of the trustor in real property by selling the encumbered property and using the sale proceeds to pay off creditors:",hint:"Definition: Foreclosure is the legal procedure used by lenders to terminate all rights, title and interest of the borrower (trustor) in real property by selling the property and using the proceeds to satisfy the liens of creditors.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"subordination.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"foreclosure.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"deficiency judgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unlawful detainer action.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following does not belong?",hint:"FHA I cannot be used for the purchase of a home. Its primary function is for remodeling or alterations to existing improvements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"VA",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cal-Vet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Conventional",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"FHA I",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"FHA uses MPR in connection with loans they insure. MPR means:",hint:"Both FHA and VA financing impose housing and construction regulations through their roles as federal home building financing programs. As a prerequisite to participation, these programs require that the involved house meet Minimum Property Requirements (MRPs).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"maximum percentage rate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"minimum percentage rate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"minimum property requirement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"maximum property requirement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Disregarding down payments, which of the following loans requires the smallest escrow charges?",hint:"There are no escrow charges as is no escrow on a Cal-Vet loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"FHA",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"VA",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cal-Vet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Conventional",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Most real estate syndicates operate as a:",hint:"The limited partnership is popular in the syndication of real estate ventures because it:\n1) permits investors having little capital to participate in real estate projects requiring considerable capital and management expertise, 2) restricts investors' liability to their contribution, and 3) permits “funneling” of tax benefits of real property ownership.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"joint tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"limited partnership.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Nonpayment of a debt is called:",hint:"Definition: Failure to pay a debt or nonperformance of a duty or obligation that is part of a contract is known as default.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"default.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"defeasance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deficiency.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"defray.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A veteran applies for a loan to purchase a home. He requests that the loan be processed as a guaranteed loan by the Veterans Administration. A Veterans Administration appraiser, in processing the CRV for the loan, would be most concerned with:",hint:"Any appraiser of real property is concerned only with the value of the property. He does not concern himself with credit, loans, interest, etc.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the credit rating of the borrower.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the neighborhood in which the home is located.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the loan to value ratio of the requested loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the veteran's access to additional funds.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Dunn bought a house. The seller took back a second trust deed and note. Mr. Kirk later buys the property subject to the loan. If Mr. Kirk immediately defaults, the seller:",hint:"In California and a few other states, the mortgagee cannot recover a deficiency judgment on a purchase-money mortgage; these states have enacted so-called antideficiency legislation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"may get a deficiency judgment against Mr. Dunn.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may get a deficiency judgment against Mr. Kirk.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may get a deficiency judgment against Mr. Dunn and Mr. Kirk.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cannot get a deficiency judgment because it was a purchase money loan.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What kind of a promissory note has an interest rate that varies upward or downward over the term of the loan?",hint:"Definition: A note whose interest rate is tied to a movable economic index is called an adjustable note (or adjustable rate mortgage).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Straight note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Partially amortized installment note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Fully amortized installment note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Adjustable note",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The lender under a deed of trust is called:",hint:"Beneficiary - the lender under a deed of trust.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"beneficiary.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"assignee.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is a junior trust deed?",hint:"Any trust deed that is recorded after a first trust deed, with less priority than that first trust deed, is a junior trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A loan recorded before a first trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A loan recorded after a first trust deed",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A loan made by a mortgage broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A loan made by a minor",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume a husband and wife are going to purchase a piece of real property. Which of the following would carry the least weight in granting the loan for the purchase of the property?",hint:"Since the husband may or may not receive overtime working pay, lending institutions, when granting loans, do not take this into consideration.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Husband's overtime pay",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Wife's salary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Down payment mentioned on the deposit receipt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The appraisal of the property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which type of government financing insures lenders against loss?",hint:"the FHA insures lenders against loss; the VA guarantees lenders against loss.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"VA",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"HUD",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cal Vet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"FHA",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What provides the most security to the lender of a junior loan?",hint:"Loan to value ratio refers to the percentage of the value of the property the loan amount is. For example, if the value of the property is $100,000 and the loan amount is $80,000, the loan amount is 80% of the value. The lower the percentage, the less risk to the lender or the holder of a 2nd, 3rd, etc. trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Prepayment penalty",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Notice of default",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Loan to value ratio",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Request for foreclosure",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The maximum FHA and VA loan amounts:",hint:"The FHA maximum loan amounts vary from one county to another. (VA maximum loan amounts also vary from one region to another because they are determined by a Certificate of Reasonable Value (an appraisal of reasonable value for the property in the area in which it is located).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"may not be changed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"vary in different regions of the country.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"are the same everywhere.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"depend on the buyer.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In real estate, "reserves" is another name for:',hint:"Impounds or reserves are accounts required by some lenders to hold one year's taxes and insurance in advance when a buyer obtains a new loan. The buyer prepays the impound or reserve account.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"impounds.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"assessment tax overpayment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"escrow account.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trust account.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Article 7 of the Real Estate Law provides that interest on a loan may not be charged:",hint:"Review these requirements of Article 7 concerning when interest may begin on a loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"prior to the date of the note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"until the proceeds of the loan have been made available to the borrower.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"until the proceeds of the loan have been deposited in escrow.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above are requirements of Article 7",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What clause is used to change the priority of a financial instrument?",hint:"A subordination clause is one in which the holder of a trust deed permits a subsequent loan to take priority.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Alienation clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subordination clause",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:'"Or more" clause',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Acceleration clause",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is the borrower on a trust deed?",hint:"The trustor is a borrower in a trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Grantor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Grantee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trustor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Trustee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Federal National Mortgage Association was created under Title III of the National Housing Act for the purpose of:",hint:"The Federal National Mortgage Association (FNMA) is nicknamed Fanny Mae and was created to stabilize the mortgage market.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"lending money on Title II loans when the bank will not.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buying Title II loans to keep the market sound.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"buying Title I home improvement loans.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following statement does not belong with the others?",hint:"Conventional loans are not insured by a governmental agency and have higher interest rates. The one that does not belong is an FHA loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Not insured by a governmental agency",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Higher interest rate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"FHA loan",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Conventional loan",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mortgage markets are classified as primary and secondary markets. Of the following statements concerning these markets, which is correct?",hint:"Primary mortgage market deals with loans directly to the original borrower. Secondary mortgage market deals with the paper (trust deeds and mortgages) being bought and sold in the open market. Answer (c) is the only correct statement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Secondary financing is generally obtained in the secondary market",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A lender wishing to reduce his holding of FHA and VA loans would probably sell them on the primary mortgage market",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mortgage companies are primarily engaged in the primary market",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Lenders in the primary mortgage market are not permitted to engage in secondary mortgage market activities",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"As a condition of granting a loan, a lender will often charge discount points. All of the following are correct statements concerning discount points except:",hint:"This is the only incorrect statement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"FHA and VA regulations forbid the lender to charge discount points when their agencies insure or guarantee the loan.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"if a lender charged 6 discount points on a 6-3/4% loan, the effective interest rate would be approximately 7-1/2%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"discount points are considered an interest expense.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in a tight money market the number of discount points demanded by lenders tends to increase.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following does not belong with the others?",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (d) all refer to VA loans. CRV (certificate of reasonable value) is the appraisal of the house for VA. 100% of the CRV can be obtained on a VA loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"CRV",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Highest loan-to-value ratio",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"FHA",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"No down payment",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A purchase money loan is a(n):",hint:"Any loan made at the time of a sale, as part of that sale, is known as a purchase money loan. When a seller carries the paper on the sale of his or her home, it is also called a purchase money loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"loan received from a mortgage broker.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"equity loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"loan made at the time of the sale whose proceeds go to the seller.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"loan whose proceeds go to the buyer.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A hard money loan is one made in exchange for:",hint:"Definition: A hard money loan is one made in exchange for cash, as opposed to a loan made to finance the purchase of a home.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cash.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a novation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Land contracts, also referred to as installment contracts, are commonly used when the purchaser does not have sufficient cash to take title and pay the balance of the purchase price. Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning a land contract?",hint:"The contract of sale is a financing instrument with many names. It may be called an installment sale contract, a contract of sale, an agreement of sale, a conditional sales contract, a contract for deed, or a land sales contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It normally involves a third-party lender",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A purchaser may never assign his interest in the property prior to full payment of the purchase price",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An agreement prohibiting the recording of the contract is enforceable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is a security device",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The buyer under the terms of a land contract is referred to as:",hint:"Vendee is the buyer or purchaser. In a land contract the buyer is known as the equitable owner.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"vendee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"equitable title owner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"purchaser.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is correct concerning financial statements?",hint:"By definition.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Assets - liabilities = net worth",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Liabilities + net worth = assets",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Gross sales - cost of goods sold = gross profit",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above are correct",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The value remaining in a property after payment of all liens is:",hint:"Equity is defined as the difference between the value of the property and any outstanding loans or the initial down payment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"collateral.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"remainder.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"equity.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"intrinsic.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following does not apply to a mortgage transaction?",hint:"Answers (a), (c), and (d) all apply to a mortgage transaction. A trustee is used in a trust deed, not in a mortgage.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trustee",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Hypothecation",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A deed of trust is the most common method of financing the purchase of real property in California. All of the following are correct statements concerning a trust deed except:",hint:"The trust deed is held by the beneficiary as prime security for the loan. The promissory note is security for nothing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the chief purpose of a trust deed is to create a lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a trust deed may be foreclosed without court action or approval.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a trust deed has no redemption period.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the promissory note is held by the beneficiary as his prime security for the loan.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning a trust deed and note?",hint:"The trustor is the owner/borrower. The beneficiary is the lender. The trust deed is held by the beneficiary. Naked legal title is held by the trustee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The trust deed is held by the trustee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The trust deed is acknowledged by a notary public",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The beneficiary holds naked legal title; however, the trustee has the power of sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The trustor to beneficiary relationship is not a fiduciary relationship but merely that of a borrower and lender",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"There are two instruments involved in a security transaction involving a trust deed-the trust deed and the promissory note. Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning these instruments?",hint:"The promissory note is negotiable, not the deed. The trust deed is the security and never worthless. Answer (c) is the only correct statement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The trust deed is worthless without the promissory note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The trust deed is negotiable in the ordinary course of business",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The promissory note is the instrument used to bring a deficiency action to court",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A promissory note is non-negotiable in the secondary mortgage market",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are correct except:",hint:"A trust deed is signed by the trustor, not the trustee. The rest of the answers are correct.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a reconveyance deed is signed by the trustee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a trustee's deed is signed by the trustee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a trust deed is signed by the trustee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a trust note is signed by the trustor.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A subordination clause:",hint:"A builder purchases raw land on a first trust deed inserting a subordination clause so that when he builds he can get a new first trust deed making the first one become second.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is of primary benefit to the beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"would prevent the sale of a property subject to the existing loan unless it were waived by the lender.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"would be of no value in a second trust deed as it is presently in a subordinate position.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is very often used in the purchase of raw land by a builder.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Notes are said to be negotiable and non-negotiable. Which of the following best defines a negotiable note?",hint:"The maker signs a note and the payee endorses it.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"If it is endorsed without recourse it is non-negotiable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An alienation clause in the note would make it non-negotiable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"If a note is secured by a trust deed the note is negotiable but the trust deed is non-negotiable",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"To be negotiable a note must be endorsed by the maker",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'A "seasoned loan" in a lender\'s portfolio would indicate:',hint:"A loan with a stable history of payments made by the borrower.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the time of year it was made.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"maturity date.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"established record of prompt payments.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"after first payment is made.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is a swing loan?",hint:"A swing loan is a short term loan used while a seller is waiting for his or her home to sell, but must close an escrow on the next home.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A long term loan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A temporary loan made on a borrower's equity in his or her home",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A construction loan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A loan using playground equipment as security",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man purchased a residence for $125,000. He deposited $115,000 cash, and a note secured by a deed of trust for the balance of the purchase price. Three years after the closure of escrow he executed a second deed of trust on the property to secure a loan he used to purchase an automobile. Considering the above facts which is a correct statement?",hint:"The second deed of trust is on a hard money loan and may therefore get a deficiency judgment. The first trust deed is on a purchase money loan and therefore may not get a deficiency judgment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The beneficiary of the first trust deed may foreclose in the event of default but has no recourse to a suit for a deficiency",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The beneficiary on the second deed of trust may not sue for a deficiency judgment because it is classified as a purchase money trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both beneficiaries have the right of foreclosure and to sue for any deficiency they suffer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither beneficiary has any right to sue after the foreclosure as they have received their full rights under a trust deed relationship",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning a junior trust deed?",hint:"The holder of a second trust deed usually records a request for notice of default on the first trust deed when recording the second. A second trust deed may be a purchase money loan or a hard money loan. The holder of a second deed of trust may bid on his own foreclosure sale. Answer (b) is a statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The holder of a second trust deed may not record a request for notice of default until the holder of the first trust deed has recorded his notice of default",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The holder of a junior trust deed would most likely make the payments for the trustor on a delinquent first trust deed and start his own legal proceedings",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A second trust deed is always classified as purchase money",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The holder of a second deed of trust may not bid on his own foreclosure sale",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following best expresses your understanding of the terms "assume" and "subject to?"',hint:"There is no deficiency judgment allowed on a purchase money loan. When a buyer assumes an existing loan he is primarily liable for the note. The seller is secondarily liable. When the buyer takes title subject to an existing loan, the seller is liable and the buyer is not liable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"When a buyer assumes a purchase money loan he takes the liability for any deficiency that may occur in a foreclosure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When a buyer takes title subject to an existing loan he takes no liability for the note",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"When a buyer takes title subject to an existing loan he takes secondary liability for the note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When a buyer assumes an existing loan he does so with the consent of the beneficiary; however, the seller retains the primary liability on the note",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A holder in due course is one who has taken a negotiable instrument that is complete and valid on its face, has become the holder before it was overdue and taken it in good faith without knowledge of defect in the title. Under which of the following circumstances would a person taking a negotiable instrument not be classified as a holder in due course?",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) would all be classified as holders in due course. If the note is not signed by the maker it is not negotiable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Taking a note endorsed in blank, that is, where the holder simply signs his name on the back of the note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Taking a straight note on which payment is not due for two years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Taking a note that is made payable to bearer rather than to the order of a specific person",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Taking a note properly endorsed by the payee but not signed by the maker",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A man bought a home for $160,000 and paid $16,000 down. Later, the value of the property rose to $170,000. This is an example of:",hint:"Leverage is the use of borrowed funds in financing, with anticipation of increase in value to produce a profit on your own money and the borrowed funds.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"escalation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"plottage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leverage.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"assemblage.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The transfer of property to a lender to be held as security for repayment of a debt; lender takes possession of property:",hint:"An example of a pledge would be when a trust deed and note are used as security for a loan and the holder gives up possession of the note and trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"hypothecation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pledge.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"novation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subordination.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The process of depositors removing funds from savings is called:",hint:"The process of disintermediation began in the late 1970s when depositors began removing their funds from the savings and loans and putting it into investments that paid a higher rate of interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"deficiency.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"disintermediation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"deregulation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"default.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The seller under a land contract may:",hint:"To prevent fraud on the buyer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"encumber the property for any amount a lender agrees to loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not encumber the property, because the buyer has title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not encumber the property in excess of the amount due on the contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"not sell the property under any circumstances.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A clause in a loan document describing certain events that would cause the entire loan to be due is called:",hint:"Definition: An acceleration clause allows a lender to call the entire note due, on occurrence of a specific event such as default in payment, taxes or insurance, or sale of the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"assumption clause.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subordination clause.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"or more clause.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"acceleration clause.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A device commonly used to secure a loan on personal property is called:",hint:"Definition: A security agreement is the document commonly used to secure a loan on personal property, much as a trust deed secures a loan on real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"security agreement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"financing statement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"bill of sale.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would distinguish between a first and second trust deed?",hint:"First to record is first in right.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Date of recording",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"County recorder's permission",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Term of each loan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Amount of each loan",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An advantage of an investment in income property over an investment in shares of stock is:",hint:"No depreciation allowed on stock certificates for income tax purposes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"appreciation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"depreciation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"capital gains.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under the California Veterans' Farm & Home Purchase Plan, the purchaser would initially receive which of the following?",hint:'Cal-Vet sells on land contract; state retains title as a "security device."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Grant deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Warranty deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Land contract",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"State deed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Using borrowed money to the greatest extent possible is called:",hint:"When a buyer invests a small down payment and obtains a loan to purchase property, he or she is using the lender's money to finance the sale. This is known as leverage - the use of borrowed capital to buy real estate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"warehousing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"intermediation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leverage.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"regulation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The rule of thumb for lenders is 1 point of each 1/8 of 1% interest that they are not allowed to charge. If FHA increased the maximum interest rate from 6% to 6-3/4%, this would reflect a reduction of:",hint:"If the interest rate were increased 3/4%, that would mean 6 points the lender would not need to collect. 3/4 of 8 equals 6.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"8 points.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6 points.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"4 points.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2 points.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A notice of trustee's sale may be recorded:",hint:"The trustee must wait at least three months after recording the notice of default before advertising the trustee sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"three months after a notice of default is recorded.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"two months after a notice of default is recorded.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one month after a notice of default is recorded.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one week after a notice of default is recorded.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The minimum time frame for a foreclosure under a deed of trust is:",hint:"The minimum time between recording the notice of default and the trustee sale is three months and 21 days (3 months after recording the Notice of Default the trustee advertises a Notice of Sale once a week for three weeks [or 21 days].)",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"6 months and 21 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5 months and 21 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4 months and 21 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3 months and 21 days.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A father needed money to send his son to college. He borrowed the money from the bank and gave a first trust deed on his home. Later, he sold his home subject to the first trust deed and took a second trust deed as part of the purchase price. In the event of default on both trust deeds, which of the following is true?",hint:'The purchaser bought "subject to"--does not have liability; the father will have liability. Second trust deed is a purchase money trust deed for which a deficiency judgment is not allowed.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The bank could obtain a deficiency judgment against the purchaser of the home",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The bank could obtain a deficiency judgment against the father",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The father could get a deficiency judgment against the purchaser on the second trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Title to real property would immediately pass to the purchaser under which of the following contracts?",hint:"All of these contracts are conditional sales contracts whereby the seller retains title until the terms of the contract are met. At that time a deed is given and title passes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Land Contract of Sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Installment Sales Contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Agreement of Sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following loans would not be insured by FHA nor VA?",hint:"Only qualified lending institutions are eligible for FHA insurance or VA guarantee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Federal bank",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Insurance company",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Institutional lenders",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Private lenders",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When purchasing a property under the California Farm and Home Purchase Act, would it be possible to obtain secondary financing at the time of purchase?",hint:"Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Yes, but only if purchaser is a wounded veteran or a widow of a qualified veteran",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No, no secondary financing is allowed under this program",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Yes, secondary financing is allowed at the time of purchase and all during the loan period",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Yes, but the house must appraise for at least 10% more than the purchase price",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a Cal-Vet Loan is paid off during the first 5 years, the penalty (service charge) would be:",hint:"Cal-Vet loans do not have a pre-payment penalty.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"no penalty.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The primary mortgage market is where lenders make loans directly to the:",hint:"Definition: The primary mortgage market is where lenders make mortgage loans by lending directly to borrowers.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"secondary market.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"borrowers.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"FED.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"FHFB.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which agency holds the deed on a Cal-Vet loan?",hint:"The agency is the Department of Veteran Affairs.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Veterans Administration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Department of Veterans Affairs",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Lending Institution",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State of California",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man sold his home for $25,000 and took back a first trust deed and note for $9,000. He is now in need of some cash and wants to use the trust deed as security for the loan with the bank. This type of loan transaction would be known as:",hint:"Using personal property (the trust deed) as security for a loan is considered a pledge, similar to the pawn broker's holding the property for loan security.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"pledge agreement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reconveyance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"release of payment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following requires mutual mortgage insurance?",hint:"Mutual Mortgage Insurance is part of the FHA loan program.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Veterans Administration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cal-Vet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"FHA",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Federal Savings and Loan Association",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Payments of FHA loans are:",hint:"FHA loans are fully amortized over the life of the loan, which means that each payment goes to reduce the principal until it is fully paid off without a balloon payment. Since each payment includes interest, the total payments are calculated to be the same equalized each month.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"unamortized.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"equalized.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"horizontal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fluctuating.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If you desire to borrow money against an existing trust deed that you own, you would be asked to sign a:",hint:"To give up possession of personal property (trust deeds) as security for a loan, one must sign a pledge agreement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"pledge agreement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"secondary trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"chattel mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Edna Hall is a farmer and needs to raise additional working capital and wishes to encumber her growing crops. If the lending institution is agreeable to this, Ms. Hall would be asked to sign a:",hint:"Since the chattel mortgage has been replaced by a financing statement, when money is borrowed against growing crops, a financing statement must be signed by the borrower.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"financing statement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"growing crops chattel mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"straight financing mortgage.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A down payment of $1,000 for the purchase of an apartment house valued at $690,000 is a good example of:",hint:"The definition of leverage can be viewed as using a small down payment to purchase as much property as possible.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"plottage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leverage.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"highest and best value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A check is:",hint:"Definition: A negotiable instrument is a written unconditional promise or order to pay a certain amount of money at a definite time or on demand.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a negotiable instrument.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a promissory note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a holder in due course.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a trust deed used as security for a loan.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following best describes a promissory note?",hint:"Remember, any kind of a note in real estate is considered to be evidence of a debt/loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A note that carries no personal guarantee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A note that is guaranteed by a government agency",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Primary evidence of a loan",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would require at least 100 people for their organization?",hint:"REITs invest in an assorted mix of real estate and mortgage investments as a group, with a minimum of 100 investors required.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real estate investment trusts",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Corporations",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Partnerships",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Joint tenancy estate",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you purchase a piece of property and execute a trust deed to the lender. In this situation you are:",hint:'The word "execute" means "to make," therefore, when one executes a trust deed that person is the maker of the note and deed.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the holder in due course.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the maker of the note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the holder of the note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under the Truth in Lending Law, the dollar amount of the finance charge is not required:",hint:"EXEMPT: business loans (tractor) also commercial and agricultural loans. NOT EXEMPT: consumer and all real estate loans require a disclosure.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"on first trust deeds to be used for the purpose of financing the purchase of the borrower's dwelling.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"on the purchase of a farm tractor.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"on household furnishings.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Beneficiaries prefer purchase money trust deeds because they have priority over:",hint:"Purchase money trust deeds are recorded just before title passes to the buyer. Therefore, beneficiaries are protected against subsequent buyer's liens--except tax liens, which take priority over all other forms of liens.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"buyer's liens at the time of purchase.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"tax liens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all liens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not a proper procedure on a financial statement?",hint:"Read these answers carefully. To get the profit of a business one must subtract the expenses of the business from the income of the business, not from the assets of the business.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Income - expenses = profit",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Assets - liabilities = net worth",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Expenses + net income = gross income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Assets - expenses = profit",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In Real Estate there are many differences between trust deeds and land contracts. One of the disadvantages of a land contract to a buyer is:",hint:"Land Contracts are considered to be the least desirable method of financing property. Hence, answers (a), (b), and (c) could be considered disadvantages to the buyer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the possibility that the buyer would not get the title free and clear of loans.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"if the seller dies there might be litigation to obtain the title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lending institutions view land contracts as poor collateral.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Assume you purchased a piece of property for $200,000 and economic factors caused the dollar to inflate. Who would benefit?",hint:"Inflationary trends cause property to increase in value; therefore, the buyer would benefit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The lending institution",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"You, the buyer",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a loan broker secures a hard money second loan for $16,300:",hint:"Article 7 of the Business and Professions Code limits the charges on hard money junior loans of less than $20,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the Real Estate Law limits the maximum charges.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the Real Property Security Law limits the maximum charges.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the maximum costs are limited by the Business and Profession Code.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What would determine a first trust deed?",hint:"Since all trust deeds appear on the surface to be the same in wording, the distinguishing mark would be the county recorder's stamp in the right hand corner as to the exact time of recording. In other words, first one to record is the right one in right, thereby a first trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The date of the trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Date of recording",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The largest dollar amount",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A holder in due course would be successful against a defense of:",hint:'Lack of consideration to the maker is considered a "personal defense" which is not good against a holder in due course.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"incapacity of the maker.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lack of consideration to the maker.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"forgery of the maker's signature.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the interest rate of the note exceeded the usury law limitations.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Funds used to finance the California Veterans Farm and Home Purchase Program come from:",hint:"Unlike other government financing, the Cal-Vet program funds and services its own loans. Funds are obtained through the sale of State General Obligation Bonds.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"state funds backed by federal funds.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"state bonds.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"home loan back corporations.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"state pension funds.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A mortgage that may be increased without rewriting the mortgage is known as:",hint:"Definition: An open-end mortgage (or loan) is essentially a revolving line of credit. An additional amount of money may be loaned to a borrower in the future under the same trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a pledged mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"obligatory advanced mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an amortized mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an open end mortgage.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In a construction loan situation, the lender agrees to an obligatory advance agreement which states that the contractor will receive funds as the construction progresses. The contractor will receive the final payment:",hint:"The major type of lending activity funded by commercial banks is for short-term (or interim) construction loans, whereas standby commitments and takeout loans (permanent loans that pay off a construction loan) are arranged by mortgage companies for large investors such as insurance companies.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"when the building is completed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"immediately upon recordation of a Notice of Completion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one month prior to completion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"when the lien period has expired.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The Truth in Lending Law is contained in the:",hint:"The Consumer Credit Protection Act of 1968 was landmark legislation that launched Truth-in-Lending disclosures of the terms and costs of consumer credit - creditors had to state the cost of borrowing in a common language so that the consumer could determine what the charges are, compare the costs of loans, and shop for the best credit deal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Federal Brokers Act.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Business and Profession Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"California State Consumer Protection Act.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Federal Consumer Credit Protection Act.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Of the following answers, which best describes a seasoned note?",hint:"A seasoned loan is a loan borrowed by someone who has a stable and consistent history of payments under the terms of the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A brand new note with the payments pre-set",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"History of payments on the note",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An amortized note for a minimum ten-year period",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Long term loans to be issued by one lender upon completion of the interim construction financing by another lender are known as:",hint:'Construction financing is usually paid off after the building has been completed by refinancing the property on a long term loan. The lender on the construction financing is "taken out" of the picture with the new loan.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"discount loans.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"take out loans.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"redemption loans.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"renewal loans.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A reconveyance deed is an instrument used daily in the real estate profession. These deeds are signed and executed by the:",hint:"The trustee signs and records a Deed of Reconveyance to show the debt has been repaid and to clear the lien from the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"grantor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following parties benefits the most from the recordation of a Request for Notice of Default?",hint:"A request for a Notice of Default is for the beneficiary of the second trust deed. This way if the first trust deed is in default, the holder of the second trust deed must be notified so that he may protect himself.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The trustee of the second trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The trustor of the second trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Beneficiary of the second trust deed",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Trust deeds and mortgages are considered to be:",hint:"Trust deeds and mortgages are personal property because they are movable pieces of paper.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"personal property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"promissory notes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estates in real estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A promissory note which provides for the payment of interest only during the length of the note is:",hint:"Definition: A straight note is a promissory note in which payments of interest only are made periodically during the term of the note - with one principal payment due upon maturity.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an amortized note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a straight note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an installment note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a due and payable note.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are considered liens against real property except:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (d) are all liens used to collect money. Easements are not liens, they are considered to be encumbrances.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"unpaid real property taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"special assessment taxes that have gone to bond.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an easement appurtenant.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"recorded judgments.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a seller wanted to relieve himself of the primary liability for payment of a trust deed and note, he must find a buyer who is willing to:",hint:'When a trust deed is "assumed" by the buyer, the liability then shifts to the "buyer."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"assume the trust deed and note liability.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"sign a release agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"take title subject to the trust deed and note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"take title contingent upon the trust deed and note.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A(n) ____________ is a person who is an innocent purchaser of a negotiable note without knowledge of any defect:",hint:"Definition answer for a holder in due course.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"receiver of the trust",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"original payee of the note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"holder in due cause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"holder in due course",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Insurance companies represent one of the major sources of conventional loans. Insurance companies:",hint:"Insurance companies are one of the major sources of mortgage funds in the United States, but are careful to loan money on better type properties. Because of their U.S. wide operation, they use correspondents a great deal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"restrict their operations to the immediate area of their home office.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"loan funds on better type properties.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"have only a minor portion of investments in mortgages and trust deeds.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"generally do not use the services of loan correspondents.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A real estate syndicate usually takes the form of:",hint:"Most real estate syndicates take the form of a limited partnership so as to avoid the dual taxation that is imposed on corporations.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"severalty ownership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"limited partnership.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"investment trust.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tenants in common.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The person that can never secure a second trust deed by using his home as security for the loan is one who is using:",hint:"Cal-Vet financing uses a land contract whereby the State holds the title until the final payment is made. Since the State holds the title, the buyer cannot use a trust deed since he must give his title intrust to a trustee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Cal-Vet financing.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"FHA financing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"GI financing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"conventional financing.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"There are many differences between trust deeds and mortgages. The main difference is:",hint:"The period of redemption for a mortgage is one year after a court foreclosure. None allowed on trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"rights of parties in possession as to renting the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"redemption.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"amounts of money that can be borrowed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"number of years money can be borrowed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Truth in Lending Law applies to all real estate loans except:",hint:"Business, commercial, and agricultural loans are exempt from the Truth-in-Lending Disclosures.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"personal loans.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two-unit income property to be owner occupied within a year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"business loans.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"family loans.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"You purchase a negotiable note and have no knowledge of any defects. You are known as:",hint:"Definition answer for a holder in due course.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the new trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the new mortgagor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the holder in blank.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the holder in due course.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Considering a 25-year amortized loan, the longer the term of the note the:",hint:"If you were to borrow $1,000 for five years, as opposed to borrowing $1,000 for two years, naturally the monthly payments would be smaller.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"lower the interest rate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"higher the interest rate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lower total monthly payment.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"higher total monthly payment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'A "hard money loan" is considered to be:',hint:"The definition of a hard money loan is the actual deliverance of cash to the borrower by the lender.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a loan from a commercial lender wherein the proceeds are credited to the borrower in cash.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the same as a purchase money loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a loan for money in a hard market.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"I = P x R x T has to do with which of the following?",hint:"I stands for interest, P stands for principal, R stands for rate of interest, T stands for time of the loan. Naturally, all of these refer to real estate loans.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Land descriptions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real property taxes",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Insurance prorations in escrow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real estate loans",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A mortgagor is one who:",hint:"Mortgagor (borrower) signs the promissory note.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"sells the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"signs the note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"holds the trust.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"takes a mortgage.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the lending business, many terms are synonymous. All of the following terms are not synonymous, except:",hint:"Construction loans and interim loans are interchangeable terms.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"interim loan-construction loan.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"take out loan-construction loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interim loan-take out loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"amortized progressive loan-take out loan.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"There are many agreements that could be placed in promissory notes that would prohibit the borrower from doing certain things. An agreement that would prohibit the borrower from paying off the loan before the maturity date is called a:",hint:"A lock-in clause prohibits borrowers from paying off a loan in advance. It is not allowed on residential units of less than four units.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"prevention clause.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lock-in clause.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"defeasance clause.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"release clause.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following ways would a corporation typically use to acquire additional equity capital?",hint:"When corporations find themselves in the need of money, they usually sell common stock to increase their equity capital.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Borrow money from a private lender",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sell more common stock",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Buy bonds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sell equity share holding bonds",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When money is said to be tight, which of the following would provide the best form of investment?",hint:"When the money market is tight, interest rates on trust deed securities tend to increase drastically; therefore, they would be a good form of investment during a tight money market.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real property trust deed securities",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Government issued bonds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Unsecured promissory notes",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Savings account at your local bank",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following courses of action would the Federal Reserve Board take during an elongated period of "tight money?"',hint:"Answers (a), (b), (c), and (d) are all courses of action taken by the Federal Reserve Board to help alleviate tight money conditions in the country.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Any of the following",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Purchasing large blocks of government bonds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lower the reserve requirements of bank members",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Decrease the discount rate for bank members",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following statements of fact best matches the term "satisfaction?"',hint:"When the debt is satisfied or repaid in full, the beneficiary signs a request for Full Reconveyance and sends it to the trustee requesting the trustee to send title back to the borrower using a Deed of Reconveyance. (A contract of conveyance is created between the beneficiary and the trustee.)",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Contract of leasing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of conveyance",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Contract of money",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of pledge",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The most important factor in the qualification of a buyer for a loan is his:",hint:"Several risk factors are taken into consideration when evaluating a borrower for a loan, such as the borrower's debt-to-income level, employment history, type of property and assets.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"number of dependents.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"savings account.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"adequacy of income.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"type of job.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the course of offering a note for resale, Mr. Kim, an investor, explains that the note contains an alienation clause. This one fact would:",hint:"If an investor buys a trust deed that contains an alienation clause and the property resold, the balance due on that trust deed is immediately due and payable to the investor. This fact tends to make a trust deed and note more negotiable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"prevent transfer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not be acceptable or legal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reduce the face value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"make the note more negotiable.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Who benefits the most from the issuance of a notice of default on a second trust deed?",hint:"The holder of a second trust deed (beneficiary), when notified of a default, may take steps necessary to protect his investment (second trust deed).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Beneficiary",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Trustee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trustor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Trustor is to beneficiary as:",hint:"Borrower-lender.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"lessee is to lessor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"vendee is to vendor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mortgagor is to mortgagee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you purchased a home on a land contract of sale two years ago. Last year the property was completely demolished by an earthquake. According to the provisions of the Uniform Vendor and Purchaser Risk Act of 1947, which of the following would best state the position of you and the seller?",hint:"Unless the purchase agreement provides otherwise, the risk of loss does not pass from vendor (seller) to vendee (buyer; you) until either legal title or possession has passed to the vendee. Once title or possession passes to the vendee, the vendee must pay the full purchase price if all or part of the property is destroyed without fault of the vendor, or is taken by eminent domain.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It would be the seller's obligation to restore the improvements of the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Earthquakes are not covered by the above mentioned law",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Since you, the buyer, have taken possession, even though you do not have the legal title, are liable and must continue to make payments on the land contract",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Answers (a) and (b) above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Gold sold his home for $180,000 to Mr. Smith and accepted a first trust deed for $80,300. The property was later resold to Mr. Johnson who did not make his monthly payments. Mr. Gold:",hint:"A lender cannot get a deficiency judgment against a borrower if the loan is a purchase money loan secured by either a trust deed or a mortgage.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"could get a deficiency judgment against Mr. Smith.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"could get a deficiency judgment against Mr. Johnson.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"could not get a deficiency judgment because it was a purchase money trust deed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"could not get a deficiency judgment against Mr. Smith because he no longer had possession of the property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A fiduciary relationship may be terminated by:",hint:"Answers (b), (c), and (d) all terminate a fiduciary relationship.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"all of the following",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"revocation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"death.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"agreement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Financing statements are to be filed with:",hint:"Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"City Attorney's Office.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Secretary of State.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"County Board of Equalization.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Board of Equalization.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A fast rule of thumb way for mortgage companies to figure out the monthly interest payment on loans at 7.2% interest would be:",hint:"If you were to divide 7.2% by 12 months the answer would be 0.006 which is equivalent to 1 month.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"multiply the principal by 0.006.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"multiply the interest by 0.072.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"divide the principal by 12, then multiply by 0.072.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"divide the principal by 0.12 and multiply by 0.0072.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are considered promotional notes except:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all considered promotional notes by definition. Answer (d) is not a promotional note.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a note executed as a means of financing the first purchase of an improved property and being subordinated to another trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a trust deed note on unimproved real property which is subordinate or may become subordinate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a second trust deed and note on unimproved lots, 29 months old and subordination.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a Pennsylvania subdivider selling lots in California using Warranty Deeds.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mortgage warehousing makes reference to which of the following?",hint:"Mortgage warehousing refers to interim loans by commercial banks to non-bank lenders made on mortgage securities. Financial institutions occasionally buy these securities for their mortgage portfolios.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A large building where mortgages are kept",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mortgage portfolios",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Mortgage syndication",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Combining mortgages and trust deeds",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Trust deeds are said to outlaw in:",hint:"Promissory notes do outlaw, but trust deeds never outlaw since they have conveyed title to the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"never.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"three years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"five years from the date of execution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"three years from the date of the last payment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following forms would be required when selling a promissory note served by a trust deed in which an appraisal of the real property is compulsory as in regards to the real estate code?",hint:"When a note is a real property security, an appraisal is required.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A deposit receipt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An agreement of sales",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A real property security agreement",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An exclusive authorization and right to sell agreement",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"You have a customer that is interested in purchasing a home using his G.I. benefits. You have located a most desirable home for which the owner is asking $120,000. It has been appraised by the V.A. for $118,000. If the customer wants to purchase the home and use his G.I. benefits, you should advise him that:",hint:"V.A. permits a veteran to purchase a home for a price that exceeds the C.R.V. but he must pay cash for the amount in excess of the C.R.V.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"he cannot buy this home since the appraised value is less.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"he can pay more than $118,000 and use his G.I. benefits but must pay cash for the excess above the $118,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"you will reduce your commission in half and have the owner reduce his price to $119,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker Table negotiates a hard money second trust deed for Paul in the amount of $7,500. Table charges Paul $2,500 commission for his service. Which of the following is a correct statement as to this transaction?",hint:"A real estate broker negotiating loans subject to the Real Property Loan Law is limited by law in the amount that may be charged as a commission. The maximum commission that the broker could charge for a $7,500 second trust deed with a five-year term would be 15%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It is not legal because it is usurious",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Broker Table cannot collect his commission",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Broker Table can collect his commission",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Broker Table can only collect the legal commission of 15%, which is $1,125",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'In real estate financing, lenders will sometimes find it necessary to refer to "nominal rate" when granting a loan. This means:',hint:'The word "nominal" stems from the word "name" and is the rate named in the note.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"that the rate of interest in the final granting of the loan will be greater than the commitment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"points will be required as the rate required by the lender would exceed the legal rate of interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the term used by lenders when the maximum rate of interest allowed by law is obtainable on financing a property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"it is the rate of interest specified in the promissory note.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'Under the provisions of FHA the borrower is required to pay the "non-recurring" closing costs unless the seller agrees to pay part or all of them. Which of the following are not considered "non-recurring" closing costs?',hint:"These are recurring costs, paid each year or on a regular basis.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Credit information costs and loan points (fees)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Structural, pest control fees, and FHA appraisal fees",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Drawing and escrow fees; title search and title insurance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Currently due property taxes and hazard insurance on property",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An individual wishes to borrow money and is advised by the lender that he will only accept a negotiable instrument in exchange for the loan. Which of the following documents is not a negotiable instrument?",hint:"A trust deed is a security device. Unless coupled with a promissory note it is not a negotiable instrument.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A check",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A draft",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A trust deed",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A promissory note",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A loan that may be increased without rewriting the note and trust deed is known as a(n):",hint:"An open-end loan is essentially a revolving line of credit. An additional amount of money may be loaned to a borrower in the future under the same trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"pledged mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"obligatory advanced loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"amortized loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"open end loan.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A borrower was notified that the payment on his FHA loan was increased $4.00 per month. This was probably due to:",hint:"FHA regulations require the beneficiary to collect impound payments for taxes and insurance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an increase in the interest rate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an increase in the tax rate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an increase in the insurance rate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an increase in impounds for either taxes or insurance.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The largest loans would most likely be made by a(n):",hint:"Insurance companies are major suppliers of money for large commercial loans to developers and builders. They usually don't make construction loans, but do make takeout loans (permanent loans that pay off construction loans) on large properties.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"mutual savings bank.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commercial bank.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"federal bank.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"insurance company.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is the borrower on a trust deed note?",hint:'The borrower would be the owner, therefore, the trustor. Remember that any word ending in "or" indicates the owner.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Grantor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Grantee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trustor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Trustee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under the Article 7 of the Real Estate Law, any loan other than trust deed taken back by a seller, made by any person and secured directly by a lien on real property which provides for installment payments and the term of which is less than six years, shall require substantially equal installment payments over the period of the loan with the final payment not payable until the maturity date thereof. This section of the law:",hint:'The answer to the question is contained in the statement to the question. You will note that the law applies to loans of "less than 6 years," so it will not apply to a 6-year loan. Article 7, Section 10244.1',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"applies to all real property loans.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"means you must have monthly payments on the loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"does not apply to a 6-year loan.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"requires a mortgage broker license when negotiating such a loan.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Lending institutions are limited as to the amount that they can lend, the types of loans, and the length of the loans. Because of certain limitations, some lenders are not interested or are unable to give construction loans, but are willing to issue long term financing after the construction is completed. Long term loans to be issued by one lender upon completion of the interim construction financing by another lender are known as:",hint:'Construction financing is usually paid off after the building has been completed by refinancing the property on a long term loan. The lender on the construction financing is "taken out" of the picture with the new loan.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"discount loans.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"take out loans.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"redemption loans.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"renewal loans.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act regulates:",hint:"RESPA, passed in 1974, is a federal loan disclosure law which helps protect buyers or borrowers who obtain federally related loans - FHA, VA or conventional loans that are sold to FNMA, GNMA, or FHLMC.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"credit practices.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"FNMA, GNMA, FHLMC, and other federally controlled secondary mortgage market institutions",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"loan closing practices.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"closing practices for real property sales.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In construction lending, the lender will usually release the final payment to the building contractor when the:",hint:"In construction loans, the lender holds the final payment until the lien period has expired to be sure that there will be no mechanic's liens filed against the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"owner has recorded the notice of completion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lien period has expired.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"job has been completed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mechanic's lien has been recorded.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Anyone who sells a second trust deed for less than its value is:",hint:"A loan is discounted whenever it is sold for less than the face amount or current loan balance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"leveraging an investment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"liquidating a piece of real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"discounting a note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"subordinating a debt.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Liquidation of an obligation most nearly means:",hint:"Liquidation is another word for the amortization of a debt.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"annexation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"amortization.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"acceleration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"condemnation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The loan which allows the terms of the interest rate to increase or decrease over time is called a(n):",hint:"A variable interest rate loan allows the interest rate to increase or decrease over time.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"secured loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interim loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fixed rate loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"variable interest rate loan.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The primary mortgage market is where lenders make mortgage loans directly to:",hint:"The primary mortgage market is where lenders make mortgage loans by lending directly to borrowers.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"veterans.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mortgage bankers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"borrowers.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the secondary market.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When using a purchase money trust deed, the trustor:",hint:"The trustor (borrower) signs the promissory note and trust deed, then gives them to the beneficiary (lender).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"receives a promissory note for the amount borrowed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lends money to the beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"signs the promissory note trust deed and gives it to the beneficiary.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"only signs the trust deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Francesca and Robert bought their first home, qualifying for a 30 year loan. The lender required regular equal payments of sufficient size and number to pay all interest on the loan and reduce the amount owed to zero by the loan's maturity date. What kind of loan did they probably have?",hint:"A loan characterized by regular, periodic payments of fixed amounts, to include both interest and principal, and which pays off the debt completely by the end of the term (or at the loan's maturity date) is a “fixed-rate” fully amortized loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Partially amortized loan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ARM",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Fully amortized loan",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Interest only loan",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mac is a homeowner who has failed to make payments on a trust deed for two months. The trustee has recorded a notice of default. What does Mac have?",hint:"The trustor has the right to reinstate the loan until 5 days before the trustee sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Right of redemption",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Right of reinstatement",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Loan moratorium rights",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A problem--he has lost his opportunity to stop foreclosure",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Bob purchased an existing loan from a lender for $13,500. At the time he purchased the loan it had just been created and had a loan balance of $15,000. The borrower never made a payment on the loan and Bob decided to foreclose. What is the maximum amount that Bob can foreclose for?",hint:"When a loan is discounted, the loan amount does not change. Bob can foreclose for the full amount of the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$13,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An investor who purchased an existing loan has no right to foreclose",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$13,500 minus the trustee fee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A note payable interest only is called a(n):",hint:"A straight note: a note which requires no principal payments during the life of the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"straight note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"amortized installment note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nonnegotiable note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"adjustable rate note.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is the most expedient way to foreclose when a trustor defaults on a real estate loan?",hint:"A trustee sale is the most expedient way to foreclose. It takes about four months.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A sheriff's sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An execution sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A judicial foreclosure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A trustee sale",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The person who loans money secured by trust deed on a parcel of real property is called a:",hint:"The beneficiary is the lender in a trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mortgagor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"beneficiary.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In a court foreclosure sale on a trust deed:",hint:"The trustor (borrower) in a court foreclosure on a trust deed has a limited right of redemption after the property is sold.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the procedure is the same as a trustee sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the trustor has a redemption period.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a court foreclosure is illegal in California.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the procedure for a court foreclosure is usually faster than for a trustee sale.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Upon foreclosure sale by way of trustee sale, a trustee must wait at least three months before:",hint:"The trustee must wait at least three months after recording the notice of default before she can publish the notice of trustee sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the foreclosure is final.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"issuing a reconveyance deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"publishing the notice of trustee sale.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"conducting the trustee sale.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a lender accepts a deed in lieu of foreclosure, the lender:",hint:"When a lender accepts a deed in lieu of foreclosure, the lender assumes all junior liens against the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"must also have the power of sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must take ownership of property free and clear of all liens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must go to court and get deficiency judgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"assumes junior loans.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What provides the most important protection for a lender on a junior trust deed?",hint:"The borrower's equity in the property is the most important concern to a lender making a junior loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The borrower's income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The borrower's credit rating",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The borrower's equity in the property",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A release clause in a mortgage allows:",hint:"A release clause in the mortgage allows some of the properties to be released from a blanket encumbrance when part of the debt is paid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the lender's option to extend.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the release of a guarantor from further liability under specified conditions.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"portions of the security to be released from a mortgage lien when multiple properties are being used to secure the loan.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the mortgagor to be released from liability.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In order for a seller to relieve herself of primary liability when allowing the buyer to "take over" her existing loan, she must find a buyer who will:',hint:'When a buyer "assumes" the existing loan, the buyer becomes primarily liable for the debt. This would relieve the seller from primary liability.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"assume the trust deed and note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"sign a release agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'buy the property "subject to" the existing loan.',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"she seller is never relieved from primary liability.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Jane offers to purchase Stan's property for $139,000. Jane takes title subject to a VA loan. What is the effect on liability?",hint:'When a buyer purchases "subject to" a loan, the seller (Stan) remains liable for the loan.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Jane is primarily liable for the loan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Stan and Jane are both liable for the loan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Stan is liable for the loan",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Neither Jane nor Stan is liable for the loan",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A clause in a trust deed that declares the total unpaid balance due and payable upon default is called:",hint:'A clause in a trust deed that declares the total unpaid balance due and payable upon default is called an "acceleration clause."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a forfeiture clause.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an escalator clause.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an elevator clause.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Any loan payment that is significantly larger than any of the other payments is called a(n):",hint:"The last installment, called a balloon payment, is much larger than any of the other payments because it includes all of the remaining principal and interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"final payment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"balloon payment.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"credit payment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"installment payment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In a promissory note and trust deed signed by two or more co-borrowers, when one of the co-borrowers defaults, what is the liability?",hint:"Each of the co-borrowers on a loan will be held jointly and severally liable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Personal and corporate liability",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All are together liable as individual borrowers",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Each is jointly and severally liable",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Each is individually and severally liable",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a trust deed is sold, the parties use an escrow in order to:",hint:"The purpose of an escrow is to make sure that conditions and terms are met prior to the completion of the transaction.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"obey the California Civil Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"make sure that conditions and terms are met prior to the settlement of the transaction.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"obey the real estate law.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a seller carries back a note secured by a trust deed from the buyer, the seller becomes the ___, and the buyer becomes the ___.",hint:"There are three parties to a trust deed: the borrower (trustor), the lender (beneficiary) and a neutral third party called a trustee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"beneficiary, trustor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"trustor, beneficiary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee, trustor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor, trustee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man can borrow money on personal property with a:",hint:"The security agreement has replaced the chattel mortgage where personal property is used as security for a loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"bill of sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"chattel mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"security agreement.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'In real estate financing, lenders will sometimes find it necessary to refer to "nominal" rate when granting a loan. This means:',hint:'The word "nominal" stems from the word "name" and is the rate named in the note.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"that the rate of interest in the final granting of the loan will be greater than the commitment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"points will be required as the rate required by the lender would exceed the legal rate of interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the term used by lenders when the maximum rate of interest allowed by law is obtainable on financing a property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"it is the rate of interest specified in the promissory note.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'The terms "blank, restricted, and qualified" refer to a(n):',hint:"Hint: Signing the owner's name on the reverse side of a negotiable instrument such as a check or promissory note is a method of transferring title and is called an endorsement. A blank endorsement guarantees payment to subsequent holders or the note or check. In insurance policies, a restricted endorsement acknowledges the policy coverage. In FHA loans, a qualified endorsement will indicate that the loan is insured under the National Housing Act.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"endorsement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In real estate financing, reference is sometimes made to "take out loans". This refers to:',hint:'A "take out loan" is the long term financing that replaces the interim construction loan. It "takes" the construction lender "out" of the financing picture.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"net amount after points and prepaid interest are deducted.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a blanket encumbrance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a construction loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"long term loan taken out after construction.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'Mr. Smith sells his lot for $10,000 and takes back a trust deed and note for $5,000. Needing cash, he immediately sells the trust deed and note at a discount to Mr. Brown for $3,500, assigning the trust deed and endorsing the note "without recourse." If trustor defaults before making any principal payments, disregarding costs of collection, by which method would buyer of the first trust deed get the greatest amount in the shortest period of time?',hint:"The fact that Mr. Smith sold this purchase money encumbrance at a discount in order to obtain ready cash does not change the face value of the note.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Foreclosure by trustee's sale to collect $3,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sue for specific performance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Recover from Mr. Smith as the transaction was usurious",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Foreclosure by trustee's sale to recover $5,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mortgage companies which operate primarily as mortgage loan correspondents of life insurance companies, mutual savings banks, and others are usually regulated by:",hint:"Mortgage companies operating primarily as mortgage loan correspondents are not considered to be institutional lenders and are not subject to the same controls. Organized under State laws, they are subject to minimum supervision.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"federal law.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"state law.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"county ordinances.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Federal Housing Administration.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man had a second trust deed for $2,000. He sold it to a friend for $1,500. In the language of real estate practice, this would be known as:",hint:"Trust deeds and notes sold for less than the unpaid balance are said to be sold at discount.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a prepayment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"hypothecation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"usury.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"discounting.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following may not be a "blanket encumbrance,as it applies to subdivisions?',hint:"Property tax liens are not blanket encumbrances. Each lot in a subdivision stands on its own.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Mortgage",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real property taxes",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Mechanics' liens",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In checking trust deed documents in the county recorder's office, you will find that the recorded deed of trust refers to standard clauses contained in a previously recorded trust deed. This previously recorded trust deed is known as a:",hint:'Nearly all deeds of trust used by banks, escrow and title companies are the "short form." This merely recites the trustor\'s name, the trustee, describes the property, and has a place for signature. The terms of the trust deed are not printed in the short form but refer to an original deed of trust recorded in each county, and it is identified as a fictitious deed of trust. This lists all the terms and conditions in detail.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"prima facia deed of trust",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"short form deed of trust",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"master deed of trust",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fictitious deed of trust",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Wesley needs $2,000 to close an escrow. He holds a $6,000 note secured by a second trust deed on a farm. The bank agrees to lend him the necessary amount if Wesley will put up the note as security. This type of security is known as a:",hint:'"Pledge" is the depositing of personal property by a debtor with a creditor as security for a debt.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"pledge.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"chattel mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"purchase money mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subordination clause.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Several homes in a tract were sold and title was conveyed by a grant deed. Under the normal procedure, what type of deed would have been requested of the beneficiary if the property had been burdened by a blanket deed of trust?",hint:"This instrument would partially reconvey the title to the trustor in return for a proportionate partial payment on the trust note balance, thus releasing a specified lot or lots from under the blanket.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Grant deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Quitclaim deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Reconveyance deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Partial reconveyance deed",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mr. McCormick can secure a loan with the term of 15 years or 30 years. If he chooses the longer term loan, he will have the following advantage:",hint:"The longer the term, the lower the amortized payments.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"lower total interest cost.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"higher total payment on principal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lower total monthly payment.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"lower term of payment on principal.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The purchaser of a home under the California Veteran's Farm and Home Purchase Act acquires possession through a:",hint:"The state purchases the property and sells it to the veteran on a land contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"grant deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"quitclaim deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"land contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"special state deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Edna is a farmer and needs to raise additional working capital and wishes to encumber her growing crops. If the lending institution is agreeable to this, Edna would be asked to sign a:",hint:"Since the chattel mortgage has been replaced by a financing statement, when money is borrowed against growing crops, a financing statement must be signed by the borrower.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"financing statement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"growing crops chattel mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"straight financing mortgage.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Interest is a very important part of the lending business. Interest calculated on the total amount of the principal, plus accumulated interest, is referred to as:",hint:"The question itself defines compound interest, exactly.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"straight interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"compound interest.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"simple interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accumulated interest.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following loans is exempt from the Federal Truth-in-Lending Law on the basis of the type of loan itself?",hint:"Business loans and agricultural loans are exempt from the Federal Truth-in-Lending Law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An agricultural loan",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"FHA loan to buy a home",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A VA loan to refinance a veteran's home",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$25,000 loan from a credit union for home improvement purposes",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The largest loans would most likely be made by a(n):",hint:"Commercial loans, which are usually the largest loans, are usually made by an insurance company.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"mutual savings bank.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"commercial bank.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"federal savings bank.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"insurance company.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Three of the four following real estate terms are closely associated. Which of the four terms does not belong with the group?",hint:"Individuals claim many things, but they are not necessarily liens. A trust deed and judgment would be liens.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lien",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Judgment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Claim",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"You, as an agent, have sold a home for which you negotiated a first loan with a bank and a second loan to be taken back by the seller. You have been requested to record a Request for Notice. This is usually to protect:",hint:"The purpose of a Request for Notice is if the trustor defaults on the first loan the trustee of the first loan must notify the beneficiary (lender) of the second loan of the trustor's default.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trustee of the first loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee of the second loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor of the second loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"beneficiary of the second loan.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A subdivider purchased 10 acres at $20,000 per acre. He paid $20,000 as a down payment. The balance was to be in the form of a straight note secured by a first trust deed. The said trust deed contained a release clause providing that, upon each payment of $20,000, one acre would be released free and clear. The subdivider subsequently paid $40,000 on the principal and received a release on two acres of land free and clear. By this transaction the percentage of his equity in the encumbered property would do which of the following?",hint:"The equity is the difference between the market value of the encumbered acreage and the amount of the loan.|10 acres valued at $20,000 each - $18,000 loan = $2,000 equity per acre.|8 acres valued at $16,000 each - $14,000 loan = $2,000 equity per acre.|| $2,000 equity = 1/9 $2,000 equity = 1/7| $18,000 loan $14,000 loan|| His equity has increased from 1/9th to 1/7th of the encumbered property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Increase",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Decrease",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Stay the same",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Decrease when the first four lots were released and increase when the last six are released",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under Article 7 of the Business and Professions Code, Division 4, Part 1, Chapter 3, how much commission can a loan broker charge to negotiate a junior loan for $4,500 to be repaid in a period of 5 years?",hint:"15% for a period of 3 years or more.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"15%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Does not apply",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Interest paid on the principal amount and the accrued interest due on the loan is referred to as:",hint:"An exact definition. When interest is paid on accrued interest it is called compound interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"simple interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"compound interest.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"cumulative interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deferred interest.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When calculating value using a capitalization rate, which item is not deductible in calculating net income?",hint:"Only the expenses directly attributable to property are deductible, not personal expenses. Principal and interest payments on a loan would be personal expenses.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Taxes",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Interest on loan payments",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Depreciation reserve on furniture",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Management costs",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Seller takes back a purchase money first trust deed on a home. The buyer sometime later has to take out a second trust deed with a bank and later defaults on both loans. Which of the following is a true statement?",hint:"There is no deficiency judgment allowed on a purchase money loan. The loan from the bank is hard money and therefore a deficiency judgment would be allowed as long as the bank foreclosed through court action.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Seller can get a deficiency judgment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Bank can get a deficiency judgment",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"No one can get a deficiency judgment on a trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b) are correct",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Everyone is required to have a real estate license when he or she performs certain real estate acts. In which of the following sales does the Real Estate License Law apply?",hint:"In order to handle the sale of a real property security, a real estate broker's license is necessary.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real property securities",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Selling two trust deeds every year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"One promotional note sale, seasoned for more than three years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A(n) ____________ is a person who is an innocent purchaser of a negotiable note without knowledge of any defect:",hint:"Definition answer for a holder in due course.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"receiver of the trust",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"original payee of the note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"holder in due cause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"holder in due course",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Who gives the power of sale to a trustee in a trust deed?",hint:"The trustor, or the borrower, gives the trustee naked legal title by signing the trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Beneficiary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trustor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Lender",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Escrow holder",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In a nonjudicial foreclosure, how long must trustees wait after recording the notice of default before advertising the trustee's sale?",hint:"The trustee must wait at least three months after recording the notice of default before advertising the trustee sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"At least 1 week",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"At least 3 months",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"At least 6 months",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"At least 1 year",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are real property securities, except:",hint:"A promotional note is only regulated as a real property security if it is less than 3 years old. After 3 years it may be sold like any other loan, without special regulation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a guaranteed note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a promotional note created 37 months ago.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a out-of-state subdivision.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a guaranteed real property sales contract, offered for sale through a real estate broker.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Sloan wishes to purchase a piece of industrial property and apply for a large first trust deed loan to help him purchase the property. The lender is most interested in:",hint:"The lender would probably be interested in all of these; however, he would be most interested in answer (b).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the appraised value of the land and the improvements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the financial condition and credit standing of the applicant for the loan.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the demand for the product being manufactured on the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Real estate syndicates have recently come under the jurisdiction of the Real Estate Commission. A real estate syndicate can operate as:",hint:"Real estate syndicates may operate as partnerships, corporations, or real estate investment trusts.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"all of the following.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a real estate investment trust.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a corporation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Constructive notice of a lien is given by recording a:",hint:"Lien is a money encumbrance. A deed of trust is the only answer listed that is a money encumbrance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"restriction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easements in gross.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"blanket set of restrictions covering a subdivision of 99 lots.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a deed of trust.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In the language of real estate, which of the following terms does not belong with the others?",hint:"A second trust deed is subordinate to the first trust deed. To hypothecate is to give (personal property) in pledge as security for a debt. A trust deed (which is personal property) is given as security for the trust note. The one that does not belong is joint tenancy.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Joint tenancy",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Hypothecate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subordination",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Second trust deed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A first trust deed has a clause in it referring to a previously recorded instrument. That instrument would be a:",hint:"The fictitious trust deed would be one in which the trustor was misnamed and therefore a new trust deed would have to be written referring to the original or fictitious trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"subordination clause agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fictitious trust deed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"primary evidence first trust deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The word "tender," as used in contract law, means:',hint:"Definition: A tender of performance is an offer by one of the parties to carry out his or her part of the contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"money only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"promissory note only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an offer of money or performance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Points on a Cal-Vet loan are paid by:",hint:"There are no points in a Cal-Vet loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the lender.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the Department of Loan Approvals.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the borrower.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"There are many differences between trust deeds and mortgages. The main difference is:",hint:"The period of redemption for a mortgage is one year after a court foreclosure. None allowed on trust deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"rights of parties in possession as to renting the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"redemption.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"amounts of money that can be borrowed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"number of years money can be borrowed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is a non-money encumbrance?",hint:"Definition: A non-money encumbrance is one that affects the use of property such as an easement, a building restriction, an encroachment or a lease.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Easement",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Trust deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mechanic lien",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Judgment",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a loan is secured by a borrower's residence, a prepayment penalty is not allowed after:",hint:"A prepayment penalty is not allowed on a loan against the borrower's residence after the loan is seven years old.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"4 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"7 years.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Who benefits from a prepayment penalty?",hint:"The beneficiary is the lender; the prepayment penalty is required because of the loss of projected long term interest income to the lender from the term of the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Beneficiary",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Trustor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trustee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Borrower",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Soldiers and Sailors Civil Relief Act is of the greatest interest to:",hint:"The Soldiers and Sailors Civil Relief Act stops the Statute of Limitations from running while the individual is in the service. This is true whether the principal to the deed of trust is in the service or out of the service waiting to sue someone in the service.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"soldiers and sailors during war.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"land developers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"real estate licensees.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the principal to a deed of trust.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A borrower on a new loan is required to advance $412.00 for an impound account. He would do so for the benefit of:",hint:"An impound account is an account into which money is paid by the borrower to insure the payment of taxes and fire insurance when due. Most beneficiaries/lenders require this of borrowers/trustors. Hence, answer (b) is the best answer given.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the trustor only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the trustor and the beneficiary.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"F.N.M.A.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the trustee.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A first trust deed held by ABC Insurance Company was assumed by the buyer. The seller was agreeable to taking back a note secured by a second trust deed. At first he wanted the note to be paid off in 2 years. The buyer refused but later agreed to a provision that the note become due and payable in the event the property is sold, conveyed or alienated. Which of the following clauses is most applicable?",hint:"It would actually be an alienation clause, which is a type of acceleration clause.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Acceleration",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Subordination",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Safety",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Appurtenant",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following does not belong?",hint:"Conventional loans do not involve government participation in the form of insuring or guaranteeing the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"VA",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cal-Vet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Conventional",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"FHA",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A purchaser under a sale-leaseback transaction would be least interested in:",hint:"He would probably be somewhat interested in all of these, but he would be least interested in the depreciated book value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the location of the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the seller's depreciated book value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a general well-constructed building.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the credit of the prospective seller.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Disregarding down payments, which of the following loans requires the lowest escrow charges?",hint:"There are no escrow charges on a Cal-Vet loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"FHA",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"VA",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cal-Vet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Conventional",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Dunn bought a house. The seller took back a second trust deed and note. Mr. Kirk later buys the property subject to the loan. If Mr. Kirk immediately defaults, the seller:",hint:"In California and a few other states, the mortgagee cannot recover a deficiency judgment on a purchase-money mortgage; these states have enacted so-called antideficiency legislation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"may get a deficiency judgment against Mr. Dunn.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may get a deficiency judgment against Mr. Kirk.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may get a deficiency judgment against Mr. Dunn and Mr. Kirk.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cannot get a deficiency judgment because it was a purchase money loan.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"New words and definitions are constantly being added to the real estate language. Prima facia means:",hint:'"Prima facia" refers to the primary first trust deed as evidence of the law of priorities. Of the answers given, the State exam prefers "primary evidence" as the correct answer.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"first in priority.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"primary evidence.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"front of the house.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"principal.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the lending business many terms are synonymous. All of the following terms are not synonymous, except:",hint:"Construction loans and interim loans are interchangeable terms.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"interim loan--construction loan.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"take out loan--construction loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interim loan--take out loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"amortized progressive loan--take out loan.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following courses of action would the Federal Reserve Board take during an elongated period of "tight money?"',hint:"Answers (a), (b), (c), and (d) are all courses of action taken by the Federal Reserve Board to help alleviate tight money conditions in the country.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Any of the following",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Purchasing large blocks of government bonds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lower the reserve requirements of bank members",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Decrease the discount rate for bank members",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the course of offering a note for resale, Mr. Kim, an investor, explains that the note contains an alienation clause. This one fact would:",hint:"If an investor buys a trust deed that contains an alienation clause and the property resold, the balance due on that trust deed is immediately due and payable to the investor. This fact tends to make a trust deed and note more negotiable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"prevent transfer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not be acceptable or legal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reduce the face value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"make the note more negotiable.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Generally, franchisors raise most of their funds from:",hint:"Franchisors would normally receive money from loans, stock sales, and franchise fees.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"real estate investment trusts.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"federal and state franchise loan programs.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"financing from banks and insurance companies, together with money from the sale of stock and service fees from franchisees.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"public investment trusts and endowments.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker negotiated a hard money $4,000 note secured by a second deed of trust with a term of 4 years, for a client. Considering the above transaction, which of the following is a correct statement?",hint:"Commission allowed on a note for less than $8,000, secured by a second deed of trust for a term of 4 years, is 15%. 15% of $4,000 is $600.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"There would be no limit placed upon the commission the broker could charge",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"His maximum legal commission would be $600",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"His maximum legal commission would be $400",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"His maximum legal commission could be 5% of the note or $325, whichever was greater",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following statements does not belong with the others?",hint:"Conventional loans are not insured by a governmental agency and have higher interest rates. The one that does not belong is an FHA loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Not insured by a governmental agency",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Higher interest rate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"FHA loan",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Conventional loan",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"There are two instruments involved in a security transaction involving a trust deed - the trust deed and the promissory note. Of the following, which is a correct statement concerning these instruments?",hint:"The promissory note is negotiable, not the deed. The trust deed is the security and never worthless. Answer (c) is the only correct statement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The trust deed is worthless without the promissory note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The trust deed is negotiable in the ordinary course of business",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The promissory note is the instrument used to bring a deficiency action to court",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A promissory note is non-negotiable in the secondary mortgage market",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Regarding a foreclosure on a trust deed, which is a correct statement?",hint:"There is no redemption period on a trust deed. It is referred to as a reinstatement period. The redemption period is on a mortgage and it comes after the sale. Although a trust deed is usually not foreclosed through court action, if there is going to be a large deficiency judgment involved, the beneficiary may choose to foreclose through court action.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The trustor has a redemption period of 3 months after receiving a notice of default",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The trustor has a redemption period of 21 days during the publication period",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A trust deed does not entitle the beneficiary to a judicial foreclosure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"If a trustor pays off the entire loan while under foreclosure proceedings, he is entitled to a reconveyance deed from the trustee",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Notes are said to be negotiable and non-negotiable. Which of the following is true about a negotiable note?",hint:"The maker signs a note and the payee endorses it.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"If it is endorsed without recourse, it is non-negotiable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An alienation clause in the note would make it non-negotiable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"If a note is secured by a trust deed, the note is negotiable, but the trust deed is non-negotiable",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"To be negotiable, a note must be endorsed by the maker",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A holder in due course is one who has taken a negotiable instrument that is complete and valid on its face, became the holder before it was overdue, took it in good faith and without knowledge of defect in the title of the negotiator. Under which of the following circumstances would a person taking a negotiable instrument not be classified as a holder in due course?",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) would all be classified as holders in due course. If the note is not signed by the maker, it is not negotiable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Taking a note endorsed in blank, that is, where the holder simply signs his name on the back of the note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Taking a straight note on which payment is not due for two years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Taking a note that is made payable to bearer rather than to the order of a specific person",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Taking a note properly endorsed by the payee but not signed by the maker",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Noro bought a property using a purchase money trust deed. A few years later he sold the property to Ms. Hassen for all cash. Which of the following would not be disclosed by the public records?",hint:"Since Ms. Hassen paid all cash for property, there would be no need for a reconveyance deed to Ms. Hassen. Therefore, it would not appear on public records.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A grant deed to Mr. Noro",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The original trust deed that Mr. Noro used in purchasing the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A reconveyance deed to Mr. Noro",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A reconveyance deed to Ms. Hassen",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"During the inflationary periods here in the United States, the dollar value is decreased. This would best be evidenced by:",hint:"When cost of living index goes up the dollar decreases in value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the cost of living index rising.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the cost of living index decreasing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"increase of interest rates by private lenders.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"NAR increasing its fees.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mortgage warehousing makes reference to which of the following?",hint:"Mortgage warehousing refers to interim loans by commercial banks to non-bank lenders made on mortgage securities. Financial institutions occasionally buy these securities for their mortgage portfolios.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A large building where mortgages are kept",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mortgage portfolios",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Mortgage syndication",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Combining mortgages and trust deeds",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Buyer gives seller a purchase money second trust deed and note. Shortly afterward, buyer defaults in payments on the second trust deed. Seller can, in due course, bring court action and obtain against the buyer:",hint:"No deficiency judgment on a purchase money encumbrance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a deficiency judgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a reconveyance deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The principals are each personally liable to creditors in:",hint:"No personal liability under corporation nor limited partnership.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"corporation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"partnership.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"limited partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The seller under a land contract, not recorded, may:",hint:"To prevent fraud on the buyer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"encumber the property for any amount a lender agrees to loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not encumber the property, because the buyer has title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not encumber the property in excess of the amount due on the contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"not sell the property under any circumstances.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker negotiating a loan under Article 7 with a controlled institution is not required to fill out a broker's loan statement if he is charging a commission which is not more than:",hint:"The broker must provide a broker's loan statement for every loan negotiated by a broker.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following best describes a promissory note?",hint:"When a loan is made, the borrower signs a promissory note which states that a certain amount of money has been borrowed. The promissory note, then, is the evidence of the debt.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A note that carries no personal guarantee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A note that is guaranteed by a government agency",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Primary evidence of a loan",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man bought unimproved property and executed a first trust deed for 10 years. He plans to build on the property within 2 years. The lack of which clause in the first trust deed could cause him future concern?",hint:"Without a subordination clause in the first trust deed, he could not obtain a subsequent construction loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Alienation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subrogation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subordination",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Acceleration",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"You have a customer that is interested in purchasing a home using his G.I. benefits. You have located a most desirable home for which the owner is asking $120,000. It has been appraised by the V.A. for $118,000. If the customer wants to purchase the home and use his G.I. benefits you should advise him that:",hint:"V.A. permits a veteran to purchase a home for a price that exceeds the C.R.V. but he must pay cash for the amount in excess of the C.R.V.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"he cannot buy this home since the appraised value is less.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"he can pay more than $118,000 and use his G.I. benefits but must pay cash for the excess above the $118,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"you will reduce your commission in half and have the owner reduce his price to $119,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In making an offer to purchase Lincoln's property, the Shermans insert the following clause: \"Purchase price to be $100,000. Offer conditioned upon buyers obtaining a VA loan to be secured by the property in the amount of $100,000 for 30 years payable approximately $805 per month including interest at 9% per annum plus taxes and insurance.\" Which of the following most nearly represents the buyers' possibilities in this purchase transaction?",hint:"All of the choices are possibilities.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"If the $100,000 loan cannot be obtained, the buyers may require a return of their deposit and cancel the transaction",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"If the $100,000 loan cannot be obtained, the parties may renegotiate the terms of the purchase if mutually agreeable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"If the maximum loan obtainable on the property is $90,000, the buyers could complete the purchase by making a $10,000 cash down payment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The buyers may choose any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A primary source of funds for residential mortgage financing is:",hint:"The other three do not make residential loans.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Federal Home Loan Bank.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Federal Savings and Loan Corporation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"savings banks.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Federal Housing Administration.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not correct regarding a Broker's Loan Statement?",hint:"Must be kept 4 years. The other three are correct.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It must be kept 3 years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It must be approved by a Real Estate Commissioner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It must state amount actually received by borrower",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It must state costs and commissions",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under Article 7 of the Business and Professions Code, how much commission can a loan broker charge to negotiate a hard money junior loan for $4,500 to be repaid in a period of 5 years?",hint:"15% for a period of 3 years or more.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"15%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Does not apply",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a borrower does not pay on a loan secured by a trust deed, what must be recorded to start foreclosure?",hint:"To start foreclosure, first the beneficiary (lender) notifies the trustor (borrower) of default and requests the trustee to record a notice of default.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Notice of unlawful detainer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Notice of default",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Notice of sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Notice to vacate",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Lili and Cal wanted to buy investment property using as little of their own money as possible, and borrowing the rest. This is an example of:",hint:"Definition: Leverage is the use of borrowed capital to buy real estate, and is a process that permits the buyer to use little of one's own money and large amounts of someone else's.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"tight money.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"disintermediation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leverage.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"discounting.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following requires a judicial foreclosure?",hint:"Default on a mortgage, unless the mortgage includes a power of sale clause, requires a court (judicial) foreclosure.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Mortgage",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Land contract with power of sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"AITD",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trust deed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man sold his property for $25,000 and took back a first trust deed and note for $9,000. He is now in need of some cash and wants to use the trust deed as security for the loan with the bank. This type of loan transaction would be known as:",hint:"Using personal property (the trust deed) as security for a loan is considered a pledge, similar to the pawn broker's holding the property for loan security.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"pledge agreement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reconveyance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"release of payment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Liquidation of an obligation means:",hint:"Liquidation is another word for the amortization of a debt.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"annexation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"amortization.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"acceleration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"condemnation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The relationship between effective and nominal interest is that:",hint:"Effective interest is what the buyer pays; nominal interest is what is specified in the note.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"effective interest is what the buyer pays. Nominal interest is what is named in the loan application.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"effective interest is what the buyer pays. Nominal interest is what is named in the advertising.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"effective interest is what the buyer pays. Nominal interest is what is specified in the note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"there is no difference.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The right or power to sell property in the event of default under the terms of the trust deed are given by:",hint:"The trustor (borrower) gives the trustee the power to sell the property in the event of default.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trustee to trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buyer to beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buyer to seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor to trustee.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Doug is a homeowner who has failed to make payments on a trust deed for two months. The trustee has recorded a notice of default. What does Doug have?",hint:"The trustor has the right to reinstate the loan until five days before the trustee sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Right of redemption",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Right of reinstatement",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Loan moratorium rights",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A problem, he has lost his opportunity to stop foreclosure",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A note payable interest only, is called a:",hint:"A straight note is a note which requires no principal payments during the life of the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"straight note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"amortized installment note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nonnegotiable note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"adjustable rate note.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a borrower fails to pay, it is known as:",hint:"Definition: Default is failure to pay a debt on a contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"redemption.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reinstatement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"default.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"devise.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is the system of lending institutions, private investors, and government credit agencies that buys pools of loans from loan originators?",hint:"The secondary mortgage market is the buying and selling of existing mortgages.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Federal reserve system",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Federal banking system",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Secondary mortgage market",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Primary mortgage market",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A secured real property loan usually consists of:",hint:"The debt is evidenced by a promissory note. The lien is created by a deed of trust, which is a security device.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a financing statement and trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the debt and the lien.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"FHA or PMI insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a security agreement and a financing statement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a loan is fully amortized by equal monthly payments of principal and interest. The amount(s) applied to the principal:",hint:"A fully-amortized fixed-rate note describes a loan with an interest rate that is fixed and payments that are level for the life of the loan. During the early amortization period, a large percentage of the monthly payment is used for paying the interest. As the loan is paid down, more of the monthly payment is applied to the principal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"remains the same.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"decreases while the interest payment increases.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"increases while the interest payment decreases.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"increases by a constant amount.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Gerald, who is a 17-year-old minor, wishes to purchase a home. This can be done legally when:",hint:"Cal-Vet allows minors who are on active duty with any of the armed forces of the United States to purchase a home using the Cal-Vet program, if otherwise qualified.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"buying a home under the Cal-Vet program.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"buying a home only under FHA or DVA.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"seeking any type of conventional financing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who holds the title to a property bought with a Cal-Vet entitlement?",hint:"Upon application for a CalVet loan and approval of the borrower and property, the Department of Veterans Affairs purchases the property from the seller, takes title to the property and sells to the veteran on a contract of sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The veteran",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The trustee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The California Department of Veterans Affairs",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The Veteran's Administration",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Investors with a small amount of capital can pool their resources to buy real estate through:",hint:"Pooling the funds of many investors, investment companies may specialize in certain types of investments or industries, such as income stock or growth stocks or Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the stock market.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a Real Estate Investment Trust (REIT).",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"foreclosure trusts.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"savings banks.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A corporation formed for the purpose of owning property is called a:",hint:"Definition: A corporation formed for the purpose of owning property is known as a stock cooperative.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"joint tenancy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"partnership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"REIT.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"stock cooperative.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The Truth-in-Lending Law requires a disclosure statement be given to the consumer. This statement includes:",hint:"The Truth in Lending Act requires lenders to disclose the important terms and costs of their loans, including the annual percentage rate, finance charge, the payment terms, and information about any variable-rate feature.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a description of the security interest retained and used for the loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a listing of all items included in the finance charge.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the annual percentage rate, fully spelled out.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A collection service is trying to collect a note at the insistence of a holder in due course. The maker of the note could use as a real defense:",hint:"A material alteration of a note (e.g., the face of the note is changed from $500 to $5,000) is an example of a real defense for a maker (borrower) of a note. The maker can refuse to pay the holder in due course (investor and owner of the note) for this reason.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"that there was fraud in the inducement of the note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"that there was no consideration to the maker.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"that the face of the note was materially altered.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The word "tender," as used in contract law, means:',hint:"Definition: A tender of performance is an offer by one of the parties to carry out his or her part of the contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"money only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"promissory note only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an offer of money or performance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The term "liabilities," in business transactions, refers to:',hint:"Liabilities would refer to bills to be paid (claims of creditors).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"assets.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accounts receivable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"claims of creditors.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"net loss on business incurred.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Olden received an option from Mr. Gnu on a piece of property valued at $1,000,000. As consideration for this option, Ms. Olden gave Mr. Gnu $10.00 in cash. The option is:",hint:"There is no law requiring any specific amount for consideration on an option. Whatever is agreeable among the parties is acceptable. If Mr. Gnu accepts the $10.00, then the option is valid and binding.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"invalid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unenforceable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If I = PRT, what does P represent?",hint:"I = PRT; P = I divided by R x T; R = I divided by P x T. (I = interest, P = principal, R = rate, T = time.)",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"P = R divided by T x I",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"P = T divided by I x R",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"P = I divided by R x T",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"P = I divided by R",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"To buy a car, a man executed a second trust deed and note on his home for $2,400, payable 77.00 per month, including interest at 6%. When he sold his home, he paid off the entire loan balance of $1,989.50. What was the total face amount of the principal on the loan?",hint:"The face amount of the loan is the amount of the original amount on the note.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2,400",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2,772",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,989.50",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who usually pays the 1% FHA fee?",hint:"Current deposit receipts advise that sellers shall pay these fees and there are other fees not allowed to be paid by the buyer. Offer price may exceed listing price to compensate seller for this charge.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Seller",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Buyer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lender",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A holder in due course is an innocent party who purchased a:",hint:"A holder in due course is an innocent party who purchased a negotiable instrument without knowledge of any defects.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"negotiable instrument without knowledge of any defects.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"non-negotiable instrument without knowledge of any defects.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"negotiable instrument with knowledge of defects.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"non-negotiable instrument with knowledge of defects.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker, Jenny Johnson, was approved for the $200,000 bank loan that she needed to open up her real estate office, as long as she agreed to keep $20,000 in a savings account at the bank at all times during the term of the loan. This is known as:",hint:"Keeping a certain amount in an account at the bank for the term of a loan is called a compensating balance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"compensating balance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"security deposit.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"collateral.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"risk control.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An advance fee submitted to a mortgage broker to pay for processing of the loan is:",hint:"An example could be a request for payment to cover the cost of appraisal services.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"legal if under $200.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"legal if approved by the DRE and kept in a broker trust account until needed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"illegal per RESPA.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"legal if it is a flat fee that is the same for every applicant.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Community Development Agency (CDA) is funded by tax allocation bonds from increases in area property taxes from redevelopment activities. This process is known as:",hint:"This is an example of tax increment financing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"tax roll.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ad valorem tax.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"assessment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tax increment financing.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A due-on-sale clause in a promissory note would most likely not be enforced by a lender under which condition?",hint:"If foreclosure is expected, a lender will reduce their losses by agreeing to an assumption of the loan with a new approved buyer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"When a new loan at a higher rate of interest can replace an existing one..",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When inflation happens and there are more buyers than sellers",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When deflation happens and there are more homes for sale than buyers",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"When inflation causes values of real estate to increase quickly",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The "subprime" Secondary Market is the securitization of mortgages pooled from Wall Street Investment bankers. These "subprime" loans:',hint:"Also, these loans will not be guaranteed by GNMA. Conventional lenders at one time chose not to participate in these loans, but are participating now to the higher interest rates on these loans. Many loans are from low down payment mortgages for buyers with poor credit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"do not qualify for sale to FNMA or FHLMC.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"are guaranteed by GNMA.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"will not be carried by a conventional lender.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have low interest rates.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Package trust deeds provide collateral for a loan. What type of property is packaged?",hint:"Both real and personal property may be used as collateral.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Personal property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real property and personal property",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Real property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"First Savings bank granted a construction loan in a five-stage plan for the development of a new local mall. When would the last payment be made?",hint:"A mechanic's lien has priority over any other liens filed after the beginning of labor of delivery of materials. If a mechanics line were filed with a subsequent foreclosure, the mechanic's lien would be paid first.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"After shoppers began to purchase in the stores",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Upon the filing of a mechanic's lien",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"After the mechanic's time lien has expired",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"After work is completed",isCorrect:!1}]}}]},{category:"Transfer",id:6,list:[{questionText:"Which of the following is permitted to use the county recorder's office and records without the presence of a recorder's officer?",hint:"The records of the county recorder's office are open to the public and any party listed in choices (a), (b), or (c) is permitted to inspect the records.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Bank and savings and loan employees",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Members of tax assessor's office",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title company employees",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Any of these",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When the size of beach property increases because of the permanent withdrawal of the sea, this is:",hint:"Reliction refers to a recession of water from the usual watermark or waterline causing an increase of the land. Land which was once covered by water becomes uncovered.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"coercion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"progression.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"regression.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reliction.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Avulsion is:",hint:"Avulsion is the loss of land as a result of its being washed away by a sudden or violent action of nature.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the gradual deposit of soil by moving waters which increases land area.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the sudden detachment or tearing away of the land by action of the water.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"alluvion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An easement can be obtained by prescription. This is most nearly like:",hint:"As with acquiring title through adverse possession, the use that results in an easement by prescription must be adverse, hostile, open, notorious and continuous for the statutory period.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"adverse possession.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"eminent domain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Insurance is:",hint:"Definition: Insurance is indemnification against loss from a specific hazard or peril.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"substitution of a certainty for an uncertainty.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"compensation in the event of a certain event.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an agreement written by an insurance company.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Fire insurance should allow the policy holder to:",hint:"Insurance provides indemnification against loss from a specific hazard or peril. Most insurance policies contain a pro rata liability clause that prevents the owner from collecting a greater amount than the actual loss.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"gain in the event of a claim.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"make at least 4 claims before cancellation of the policy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neither gain nor lose in the event of a claim.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"keep his loss to no more than $100,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Escheat results from:",hint:"Escheat is a legal process in which property reverts to the state because the deceased owner left no will and has no legal heirs. An heir is a person who is directly related to the deceased.\nChoice (a) is not correct because the deceased may have heirs.\nChoice (b) is not correct because the deceased could have a will in which he or she named a beneficiary who is not an heir (relative).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an estate with no will.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate with no heirs.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neither a nor b",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both a and b",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What section is due north of section 8?",hint:"A township is divided into 36 sections - each measuring one mile by one mile - that are numbered, starting with section 1 in the northeast corner, and continuing in a snake-like manner to section 36 in the southeast corner.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"13",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Each row of townships running north and south in conjunction with a true meridian is more commonly known as:",hint:"Starting at the intersection of a chosen principal meridian and baseline are imaginary vertical lines called range lines (every 6 miles east and west of the meridian to form columns called ranges).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a section.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a range.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a tier.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When the Real Estate Commissioner intends to rescind approval of a subdivision:",hint:"The Real Estate Commissioner may issue a desist and refrain order to stop violations of the subdivision law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an injunction is issued.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a desist and refrain order is issued.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the developer's license is revoked.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A condominium is similar to an apartment in that:",hint:"Both the owner of a unit in a condominium and a tenant renting an apartment have an estate in real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"each occupant in each unit has an estate in real property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the person in each unit has a fee interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the local tax assessor must assess each property separately.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is permitted to use the county recorder's office and records without the presence of the recorder's officer?",hint:"The records of the County Recorder's Office are open to the public and any party listed in choices (a), (b), or (c) is permitted to inspect the records.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Savings bank employees",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Members of tax assessor's office",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title company employees",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Any of these",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When land is acquired by accretion it is known as:",hint:"Definition: The acquisition of title to additional land as a result of alluvial deposits along the banks of streams by accretion is known as accession.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"adverse possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"eminent domain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accession.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When tenants in common do not agree on matters pertaining to the property, which of the following is a remedy?",hint:"Definition: Partition action is a court proceeding to settle a dispute between co-owners (joint tenants or tenants in common) about dividing their interests in real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A lawsuit for specific performance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The tenant in common with the largest share prevails",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A partition action",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A lawsuit for money damages",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A homeowner's exemption is:",hint:"A property owner may claim a Homeowner's Exemption in California on a residence that is both owned and occupied at 12:01 am on January 1. The exemption reduces the assessed value of the residence by $7,000 and reduces the tax bill by at least $70.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$7,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$7,500.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,500.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Escrow companies normally base their prorations on a year consisting of:",hint:"As a matter of convenience, escrow companies use a 30-day month, hence, a 360-day year.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"350 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"355 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"360 days.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"365 days.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The value of the best property in a neighborhood is adversely affected by a substandard property nearby. This can be described as the principle of:",hint:"The principal of regression says that the value of the best property in a neighborhood is pulled down when a substandard property is built nearby.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"balance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"regression.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"contribution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"progression.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In one word, the contour of the surface of the land is called:",hint:"Topography is the various surface features or contours of the land that affect construction costs.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"grading.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"topography.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"geography.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"geology.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An old land registration system used in the State of California was called:",hint:"Torrens Title Insurance is no longer used in California.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Regions Title Insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Land Locators Insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"County Recorder's Insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Torrens Title Insurance.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An appraisal method used to establish land value whereby the appraiser attributes part of the property's value to the land and part to the building is called:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all interchangeable words as defined in the question itself.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"distribution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"allocation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"abstraction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Three of the real estate terms listed below are closely associated. Which one does not fit in this group?",hint:"An offer may be accepted or rejected. An option keeps an offer open. Title refers to how property is owned.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Offer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Acceptance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Rejection",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is a requirement of a valid deed?",hint:"Acknowledgment is only required when recording, which is not required for a valid deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Recordation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Acknowledgment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Granting clause",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In his duties with respect to subdivisions, the Commissioner is concerned with the term "compacted" in reference to which of the following?',hint:"A documented report on soil conditions including filled ground may be demanded by the Commissioner. Earth fill would be compacted.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Expansive soil",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Earth fill",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Size of lots",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Water content of lumber used in construction",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An option to buy is enforceable if:",hint:"Actual consideration must pass to the optionor, regardless of how small.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the consideration is $10, but by mutual agreement, is not delivered.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"consideration is less than $10, but actually has passed to the optionor.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the optionee withdraws his offer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"there is mutuality of interest.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When title to real property, which is encumbered by a deed of trust, is transferred as the result of a sale, it is always necessary to:",hint:"Encumbered property may be conveyed and this is usually done with a grant deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"obtain the permission of the beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pay off the balance of the trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have the grantor deliver a deed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"refinance completely.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A subdivider grants a 5-foot easement across the rear of 40 lots to a utility company. The utility company holds a(n):",hint:"Easements of this type, which have no dominant tenement appurtenant thereto, are defined as easements in gross.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"dominant tenement for life.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"servient tenement by dedication.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easement in gross.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"easement by condemnation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following transfers automatically with the land?",hint:"Water rights, rights to reasonable use of airspace and mineral rights are all part of real property and go with the sale of the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Personal property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mineral rights",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Fructus industriales",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trade fixtures",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under the Map Act, control of subdivisions is made the concern of the:",hint:"City Council or County Board of Supervisors.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"local city and county authorities.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"State Land Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Commissioner of Corporations.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A father names his son as a grantee in a deed which he put in his safe deposit box with a note to give the deed to his son in the event of death. Which of the following would be questionable?",hint:"The deed must be delivered within the grantor's lifetime.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Capacity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Delivery",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Recording",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Acknowledgment",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which instrument requires a listing or inventory of buildings on real property that are to be sold, conveyed, or insured?",hint:"Neither a land contract, grant deed, nor standard coverage policy form of title insurance require a listing of the buildings or improvements. Usually a legal description is all that is required.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A land contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A grant deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A.L.T.A.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'The following words "ambulatory," "legatee," and "codicil" refer to which of the following?',hint:"Ambulatory means alterable. A legatee receives under a will. Codicil is an amendment to a will.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Will",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Charity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Easement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Statutory",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The law provides that it is unlawful for any person to effect or attempt to effect a sale of a non-exempt franchise for another unless such person is a:",hint:"Three groups of people are authorized to sell franchises: 1) the franchisor or agent (the person identified in the application for offering); 2) a person licensed by the Department of Real Estate as a broker or salesperson; and 3) a person licensed by the commissioner of corporations as a broker/dealer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"real estate broker.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"real estate salesperson employed by a real estate broker.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"broker-dealer under the Corporate Securities Law of 1968.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Adams made a deposit on the purchase of a property. During the escrow, the seller learned of a highway rerouting which would greatly enhance the value of his property. He instructed the broker to return the deposit to the buyer. Ms. Adams refused to accept the deposit. Her most unlikely course of action would now be:",hint:"Choices (a) , (b), or (c) could give Ms. Adams some degree of remedy. To rescind unilaterally (grudgingly give in) would gain her nothing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"to institute a civil action for specific performance against the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to institute a civil action for dollar damages.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to accept a settlement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a unilateral rescission.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Broker Nelson listed and negotiated the sale of a house of Mr. and Mrs. Welles. After the deed had been signed, the escrow officer called Broker Nelson and informed her that the sellers were under 18 years of age. The deed was:",hint:"Married persons under the age of eighteen are considered emancipated minors.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"invalid.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Alienation expressed as a meaning is most completely opposite to:",hint:"Alienation is the transferring of property to another. Acquisition is the receiving of property from another.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"acceleration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subordination.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"acquisition.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"subrogation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An option without consideration is:",hint:"Unless actual consideration passes to the optionor, the contract cannot be enforced.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"illegal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"enforceable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"invalid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unenforceable.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A person designated, in a written power-of-attorney, to legally act for another in his stead is typically called a(n):",hint:"Any person may give another the authority to act on his or her behalf. The legal document that does this is called a power of attorney. The person holding the power of attorney is an attorney-in-fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"fiduciary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"principal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"attorney-in-fact.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"agent.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Several homes in a tract were sold and title was conveyed by a grant deed. Under the normal procedure, what type of deed would have been requested of the beneficiary if the property had been burdened by a blanket deed of trust?",hint:"This instrument would partially reconvey the title to the trustor in return for a proportionate partial payment on the trust note balance, thus releasing a specified lot or lots from under the blanket.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Grant deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Quitclaim deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Reconveyance deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Partial reconveyance deed",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Two people entered into a long term real estate contract. After one year had elapsed, they decided to write a new contract replacing the old one. This would be an example of:",hint:"Definition: Novation is the substitution by agreement of a new obligation for an existing one.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"rescission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subrogation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"novation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"accession.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A contract created under duress is:",hint:"Capable of being void or valid. However, only the innocent party has the right to use duress as a defense to the contract and have it voided.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"invalid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"unenforceable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Bulk transfer is found in the:",hint:"Bulk sales, or the sale of a substantial part of the inventory of a business, are regulated by Division 6 of the UCC (Uniform Commercial Code).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real Estate Law.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Business and Professions Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Uniform Commercial Code.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Government Code.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The sale of a mobile home may be handled by a real estate agent when the transfer of ownership is made by way of a:",hint:"Real estate agents can only sell mobile homes which are considered real property and are located in established mobile home parks. They may be listed and sold in the same manner as any other residence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"bill of sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"purchase order.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"promissory note.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deed.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A licensed real estate broker is successful in securing a buyer for a property who is ready, willing, and able to buy. The offer is accepted and signed by both parties and escrow is opened. During the escrow period, the title company discovers that the seller is a single minor under the age of 18 and notifies the broker and the escrow holder. Under these circumstances the contract is:",hint:"A contract made by a minor is considered voidable by the minor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unenforceable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"outlawed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Some printed contracts contain handwritten portions. Which of the following is most correct?",hint:"Generally, when using preprinted forms: . . . handwritten clauses and insertions take precedence over the typed and preprinted material.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The printed portion takes precedence over the handwritten portion",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The handwritten portion takes precedence over the printed portion",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both the handwritten and printed portions are of equal importance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Oral agreements subsequent to signing the contract will prevail",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are contracts except:",hint:"A grant deed is not a contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"open listing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"escrow instructions.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"grant deed.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In which of the following situations would a deed be invalid or void?",hint:"If a deed is forged it is void no matter who possesses it.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"When executed by a person serving a prison term",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A forged deed in the hands of a bonafide purchaser",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"If the grantee is 17 years of age and unmarried",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When there is no monetary consideration for the deed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The following terms are closely associated with real estate. Which does not belong with the others?",hint:"Offer, option, and rejection are terms regarding contracts.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Offer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Option",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Rejection",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The escrow company acts as:",hint:"Escrow is an independent contractor that acts as agent for both buyer and seller.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an independent contractor.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"agent for the buyer only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"agent for the seller only.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"representative of the real estate broker.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The instrument used in the sale of a business which is comparable to a grant deed in the sale of a home is called:",hint:"Grant deed conveys title to real property and a bill of sale conveys title to personal property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a financing statement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a bulk transfer statement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a bill of sale.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a security agreement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An existing contract is replaced by an entirely new contract. This is known as:",hint:"Definition: Novation is the substitution by agreement of a new obligation for an existing one.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"subrogation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"rescission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"novation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"assignment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not necessary to create a contract?",hint:"Performance comes after you have a binding contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Offer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Acceptance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Performance",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Consideration",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are necessary for a valid contract except:",hint:"Some oral contracts are valid also. The others are all required.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"in writing.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"for a legal purpose.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"capacity to contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"consideration.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Mr. "A" gave Mr. "B" an option to buy his ranch. This burdened the ranch with:',hint:"An option is a contract to offer to sell.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a fiduciary agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an involuntary lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a contract to offer to sell.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an offer to enter into a contract.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A house is to be sold in probate. The bid submitted to court for confirmation is $200,000. The first minimum overbid would be:",hint:"The first minimum overbid must exceed the bid submitted for confirmation by 10% on the first $10,000 and 5% of the remainder.|$10,000 x 0.10 = $1,000;|$190,000 x 0.05 = $9,500;|$200,000 + $1,000 + $9,500 = $210,500.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$200,001.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$210,500.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$225,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$230,500.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In absence of a will, the separate property of the decedent is divided among the surviving spouse and two children:",hint:"It would be divided 1/2 to surviving spouse and 1/2 to one child. If there is more than one child, it is divided 1/3 to surviving spouse and 2/3 to children.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"equally among surviving spouse and children.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/2 to surviving spouse and 1/2 to the children.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/3 to surviving spouse and 2/3 to the children.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A deed:",hint:"A deed conveys title without recording. It may be recorded in any number of counties and recording it gives constructive notice, not actual notice.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cannot be recorded in more than one county.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"need not be recorded to convey title.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"that is recorded does not give the grantor protection of recording by law if a quit claim deed is used.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"that is recorded gives actual notice that title has been conveyed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A contract need not be in writing to be enforceable under the law. A verbal contract is called:",hint:'A verbal contract is called a "parol contract."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"parol contract.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"expressed contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a notice of intention to sell is not recorded and published, who is liable for the debts of the business?",hint:"Any bulk sale that takes place without complying with the requirements of the Bulk Transfer Law is considered valid between the buyer and seller, but fraudulent and void against creditors. This means creditors have recourse against the buyer because he or she holds the security for the\ndebt(s).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Buyer",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Seller and buyer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither seller nor buyer",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Alienation is most opposite to:",hint:"Alienation is to alienate, convey, or sell. The opposite would be to acquire.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"ad valorem.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"acceleration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"acquisition.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"amortization.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A subdivider, who is not licensed, may do all of the following except:",hint:"He and his wife can sell their own property. He can hire two brokers but unless he is a broker he cannot hire a real estate salesperson to sell the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"sell all of the lots himself.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"hire two brokers, at the same time, to sell the subdivision for him.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"hire a real estate salesperson to sell the lots.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"have his wife hold open houses on the weekends.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"During escrow, there are many items known as recurring costs. Which of the following would be handled as a recurring cost?",hint:"Recurring costs are those costs which are incurred in escrow and will recur again after taking possession of the property, such as property taxes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A policy of title insurance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost for appraising the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Escrow charges",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Property taxes",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A voidable contract is:",hint:"A voidable contract is one that is valid on its face until it is voided by the injured party.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"invalid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"valid until voided.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An attorney-in-fact can do all of the following things, except:",hint:"The attorney-in-fact has no power to act for his principal until the power of attorney is recorded.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"sign his principal's name.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"perform acts of a general power of attorney.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deal in real property without recording his general power of attorney.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"encumber his principal's property with a trust deed naming another as the beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A void contract is one that is:",hint:"Void, meaning no good, is not enforceable in a court of law since it does not contain the legal essentials necessary to create a valid contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"authorized.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"rescindable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not enforceable by law.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"not in writing.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Escrow companies act as the agents for:",hint:"An escrow holder, otherwise known as an escrow company, or some other eligible person, acts as a neutral agent of both buyer(s) and seller(s).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"buyers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sellers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both buyers and sellers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An on-site analysis for a policy of title insurance would be required for:",hint:"An on-site analysis would be necessary for an extended coverage policy since it covers rights to parties in possession along with matters not of public records.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a standard policy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an extended coverage policy on a farm.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both a and b",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither a nor b",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Wills play a very important part in the transfer of title to real property. Which of the following would not be a party to a will?",hint:"When someone dies testate (with a will) the deceased is called the testator, the executor is the person named in the will to distribute the estate, and the devisee is the person to whom real property is willed. The administrator is the one appointed by the court to distribute the estate when there is no will.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Testator",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Executor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Administrator",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Devisee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Profit and loss statements are used to ascertain:",hint:"Definition: A profit and loss statement reveals the net income (the gross income less the expenses) of the business over a certain time (generally calculated before accounting for depreciation).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"net income.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"gross income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"balance of statements as furnished to escrow.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"gross sales.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In what document is a "safety clause" found?',hint:"Definition: A safety clause (also known as an extender clause) is found in most listing forms and provides that the listing will continue for a set period of time and would be renewable until the parties agree to terminate it.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Deposit receipt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Transfer disclosure statement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Closing statement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Listing",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A contract obtained by duress is:",hint:"Definition: A contract entered into under duress is not enforceable against the forced party, and is voidable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"invalid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A nonillusory instrument is a:",hint:"A contract that is binding and enforceable, has all the basic elements required by law, and is definite in its terms is a nonillusory instrument or valid contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"definitive but not binding instrument.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"definitive and binding contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"non-definitive and binding contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"definitive instrument which becomes a binding contract when executed.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A grant deed:",hint:"A grant deed transfers title to real property. It has two implied warranties. Answer (c) is one and the other is it implies there are no encumbrances other than those revealed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"can be used for the transfer of real and personal property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"implies no encumbrances.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"implies title has not been previously conveyed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"gives a conditional transfer of title.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What event does not terminate an agency?",hint:"Since the broker owns the listing, only the death of the listing broker, not the listing agent, would terminate the listing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Death of listing agent (not broker)",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Full performance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Expiration of term",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Destruction of listed property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An executory contract is a:",hint:"Completely performed is executed. Something remaining to be performed is executory.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"contract that has been completely performed by both parties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"contract between executives.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"contract where something remains to be done by one or both parties.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"binding contract.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A minor, 16 years of age and married, wants to purchase a home. Which of the following statements is true?",hint:"A married person under the age of 18 is an emancipated minor and can sign a valid binding contract to purchase, rent or lease real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"He cannot legally purchase and own a home",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"He can own a home but only if his parents or legal guardian co-sign",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"He can purchase and own a home",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In dealing with a sale with a land contract subject to a blanket encumbrance containing a release clause, funds are deposited in an account approved by the Real Estate Commissioner for the protection of:",hint:"The funds are impounded to protect the purchaser under the contract. Purchaser-vendee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"vendor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"vendee.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"To bid on property in a probate sale, the offer must be at least _______ of appraised value in order to be confirmed by the probate court:",hint:"A summary of Probate Court Procedures includes the following: An offer to purchase must be for at least 90% of the appraised value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"75%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"80%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"90%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"100%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Where are the termite inspection and clearance reports filed?",hint:"Anyone can get a copy of the pest control report by requesting it from the Structural pest Control Board and by paying a fee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Secretary of State",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Structural Pest Control Board",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Department of Etymology",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Local building inspector",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a minor signs a contract, it is:",hint:"Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"legal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"legal if purchased through a guardian with consent of the court.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"legal if it is not caught at time of minority or shortly thereafter.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"legal, because anyone can purchase property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A purchaser under a sale-leaseback transaction would be least interested in:",hint:"He would probably be somewhat interested in all of these, but he would be least interested in the depreciated book value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the location of the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the seller's depreciated book value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a general well-constructed building.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the credit of the prospective seller.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The selling price is shown on a buyer's closing statement as:",hint:"Selling price on buyer's closing statement is debit buyer. It would be credited to the seller on the seller's closing statement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"credit buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"debit seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"credit seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a debit buyer.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Failure to perform a duty to fulfill a promise made is considered a:",hint:"A breach of contract is a failure to perform on part or all of the terms and conditions of a contract (promise to pay).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"cancellation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"breach.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"illegal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Another name for a sheriff's deed is a(n):",hint:"Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"court deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"administrator's deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deputy's deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"marshall's deed.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Personal property left by will is called:",hint:"A gift of money or personal property by will is a bequest or legacy.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"codicil.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ambulatory.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"legacy.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"testate.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume all necessary instruments, properly executed and delivered, concerning a sale of real property were placed into escrow. It later develops that the escrow instructions signed by the buyer and the seller contained terms in conflict with the original deposit receipt:",hint:"When escrow instructions are signed by both buyer and seller and placed in escrow, we have a valid and binding contract. Since the escrow instructions are the latest contract signed by both parties, these contracts would prevail.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the original deposit receipt prevails.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a new deposit receipt would have to be drawn up by both parties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the escrow instructions would prevail.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the sale would be voided.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A sale of property is considered transfer of title by:",hint:"Voluntary is by act of the party. Involuntary would be by act of law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"descent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"will.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"involuntary alienation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voluntary alienation.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A broker is preparing a deposit receipt. Which of the following can be disregarded for the moment and be decided during the escrow period?",hint:"Answers (a), (c), and (d) must be decided before escrow.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Manner of payment of assessment bonds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Manner of taking title",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Payment of title insurance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Financing arrangements",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Listings are often confused with options. Which of the following is a correct statement concerning these contracts?",hint:"Definitions of listings and of options clearly indicate the answers are all correct.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A listing creates a fiduciary relationship, an option does not",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An option requires consideration to be a valid contract and the listing also requires consideration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The owner may be sued for performance on an option but a suit for specific performance cannot be instituted on a listing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above are correct",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A listing:",hint:"Fair market value is the most probable price that a property would bring if offered for sale for a reasonable period of time in a competitive market where both buyer and seller are fully informed and neither one is acting under duress. The broker works with the owner to set a listing price that is realistic, but it usually has more to do with what the owner BELIEVES he can obtain than with the actual fair market value of the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"tends to set the fair market value of the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"should be taken at a price much higher than fair market value if that price is what the owner insists upon.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"usually reflects the highest price an owner believes he can obtain for his property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"is not of much importance in the success of a real estate broker's business as he earns commissions only on what the office actually sells.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume an offer has been accepted and the acceptance has been communicated to the buyer. The buyer then changed his mind and decided not to purchase the property. Which of the following is true?",hint:"If the buyer backs out of this purchase contract the seller is entitled to sue for liquidated damages.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The broker could sue the buyer as for the commission",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The broker could not sue the buyer for a commission but could bring suit to require performance of the contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller could sue for liquidated damages, if the parties agreed to liquidated damages in the contract",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above are correct statements",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a broker accepts a deposit from a buyer making an offer to purchase real property, the authority for his action is contained in which of the following agreements?",hint:"The listing agreement establishes the agency relationship between owner and broker and contains the terms and authority of the agent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Deposit receipt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Earnest money agreement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Listing agreement",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Escrow agreement",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Hammer, a building contractor, and Jones, a Realtor, wish to purchase a business property. To do so:",hint:"The fact that both men have state licenses of a different type does not prevent them from purchasing property together. However, they would have to do so as principals.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"they may engage in real estate acts together only as principals.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Hammer needs a real estate license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"they will need a partnership real estate license.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"they will need a partnership contractors' license.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"After the State of California has gained title by the process of escheat, then sells the property, the buyer receives a:",hint:"Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"State Controller's deed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"sheriff's deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"executor's deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Administrator's deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A contract is defined as a deliberate agreement between competent parties, upon legal consideration, to do or not to do some legal act. All of the following are correct statements concerning contracts except:",hint:"In order for a contract to be legally binding and enforceable, there are four requirements:\n1) legally competent parties, 2) mutual consent between the parties, 3) lawful objective, and 4) sufficient consideration.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an offer and valid acceptance are essential to a binding real estate contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a contract signed by an unmarried 18-year-old may be valid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an agreement for the sale of real property to be used expressly for an illegal purpose is void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a real estate contract signed on Sunday is voidable.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"At the time a real estate contract is entered into by a married couple under the age of 18, it is considered to be:",hint:"A married person, even though under the age of 18 years of age, is considered by California Law to be an emancipated minor (treated for contract purposes as an adult).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"enforceable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unenforceable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following which is most correct concerning the Statute of Frauds?",hint:"The Statute of Frauds states which contracts must be in writing to be enforceable. Its main function is for the prevention of fraud.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Misrepresentation in the making of a contract violates the statute",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It classifies most oral real estate contracts as unenforceable",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It classifies an oral agreement between brokers to share a commission as unenforceable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Violations of this statute are prosecuted by the district attorney in the county where the alleged violation occurred",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Suits for specific performance or damages and unilateral rescission are legal remedies for breach of contract. Of the following statements referring to these remedies, which is correct?",hint:"All are incorrect statements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"In a breach of contract for the purchase of a residence, a suit for specific performance is the most practical procedure for the broker to follow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"In a breach of contract for the sale of land after the discovery of major oil resources, the most likely procedure to be followed by the purchaser would be a suit for damages",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"In a breach of contract to purchase a residence, liquidated damages is a seldom used remedy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following does not belong with the others?",hint:'Buyer must have a clearance receipt from the State Board of Equalization in purchasing a business, or under "successor\'s liability" he is responsible for payment of all unpaid sales tax. The State Franchise Tax Board collects state income tax.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"State Board of Equalization",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Successor's liability",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Clearance receipt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Franchise Tax Board",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A bill of sale:",hint:"Vendor is the seller. He must sign the bill of sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"need not be in writing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is a security device.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must be acknowledged and recorded.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must be signed by the vendor.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following best describes a financing statement?",hint:"It is made out by the lender and recorded with the Secretary of State as a lien on personal property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It is submitted to a lender when applying for a loan secured by real property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is a security agreement",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It must always be recorded with the county recorder to be effective",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is used to alienate personal property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The selling price of a home would appear on the closing statement as:",hint:"A closing statement is a detailed cash accounting of a real estate transaction . . . showing all cash received, all charges and credits made, and all cash paid out in the transaction.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a charge to the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a credit to the buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a charge to the seller and a credit to the buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a debit to the buyer and a credit to the seller.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"For an option to be valid, the consideration:",hint:"The amount is incidental, as long as it actually passes to the optionor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"must be more than $10.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"can be less than $10.00 but must actually pass.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"no consideration needed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the promise of consideration is sufficient.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"After all necessary instruments and instructions have been submitted and proceedings started, the escrow can be canceled by:",hint:"Broker cannot instruct escrow. Neither death nor insanity terminates escrow.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"broker telling escrow to terminate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"death or incapacity of the parties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"expiration of time period of escrow.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'A listing contract has the statement, "The undersigned broker agrees to use diligence in procuring a buyer." This is used for what following reason?',hint:"Mutual exchange of promises: bilateral contract. Promise for an act: unilateral.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Means nothing and is not required",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"To make it a bilateral contract",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"To make it a unilateral contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who is named in a will to deal with the distribution of an estate?",hint:"An administrator is named by the court if there is no will or no executor/executrix is named.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Administrator",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Codifier",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"County coroner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Executrix",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A married man died without leaving a witnessed will. However, after his death, his wife found a statement naming his son as executor and expressing his wishes for the disposition of his estate. It was dated three years previously and was entirely written and signed by him in pencil. This would mean:",hint:"A handwritten unwitnessed will is a holographic will and is legal. Real property is always probated in the state where located.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an administrator would be appointed to preserve his estate until the completion of probate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"his death would be classified as intestate and his wife would be executrix of the estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"his will would be classified as nuncupative and his wife would receive his estate without probate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"his death would be classified as testate; however, any real property would have to be probated in whatever state it is located.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The most common method of a buyer assuring himself he is receiving a marketable title is a(n):",hint:"Generally, a title insurance policy protects the insured against losses arising from title defects (“hidden risks”) as in the following: forged documents such as deeds, mortgages; undisclosed heirs; mistaken legal interpretation of wills; misfiled documents; confusion arising from similarity of names; incorrectly given marital status; mental incompetence, etc.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"grant deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"escrow.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"standard policy of title insurance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'"A" enters into an agreement to sell a property to "B." "A" deposits a grant deed naming "B" as grantee in escrow. Escrow is closed and the deed delivered to "B." "A" and "B" then decided to rescind the sale. What is the proper procedure to be followed to effect the rescission?',hint:'When using escrow, the escrow does not close, nor title transfer, until the new deed is recorded. Once a deed is recorded a new deed is required for conveyance. "B" would actually have to sell the property back to "A."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:'"B" should endorse the deed and return it to "A"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"B" should reopen escrow and have the deed certified as "canceled" and have the escrow redeliver it to "A"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"B" need only destroy the deed after return of his consideration',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is necessary to create a valid deed?",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are not necessary to make a deed valid. Description of the property is necessary to make a deed valid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Recording",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Recording and acknowledgment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Date and statement of considerations",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Description of the physical property",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"With respect to deeds:",hint:"A grant deed only implies two warranties. A quit claim deed conveys all interest known and unknown by the grantor. A trust deed is used as security for a loan, not for conveying property. The only correct answer is (c).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a grant deed must state two warranties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a quitclaim deed does not move the entire present interest in the title owned by the grantor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a recorded deed is presumed delivered and accepted.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a trust deed is the most common method of conveyance in real property purchased in California.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When considering the purchase of a policy of title insurance, a buyer should be aware that:",hint:"Answers a, b, and c are all true statements about title insurance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the standard policy does not cover encroachments or parties in possession with an unrecorded claim to the title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the standard policy insures him against defects in the chain of title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the extended coverage insures him against unrecorded risks with an exception of governmental regulations concerning occupancy and use.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A deed must:",hint:"Neither legal description nor signature of the grantee on a deed. The only time a grantor's signature need be witnessed is when he cannot read or write.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"legally describe the property being conveyed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be signed by a legally competent grantee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be acknowledged by the grantor witnessed by a notary public, clerk of a court or other person competent to take an oath or affirmation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would represent a distinction between a grant deed and a quit-claim deed?",hint:"The requirements of a valid Grant Deed include: after-acquired title (any benefits that come to the property after a sale must follow the sale and accrue to the new owner); words of granting such as grant or convey must be within the deed; and have two implied warranties by the grantor - 1. The grantor has not already conveyed title to any other person, and 2. The estate is free from encumbrances other than those disclosed by the grantor. A quitclaim deed contains no warranties and transfers any interest the grantor may have at the time the deed is signed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"After-acquired title",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'The word "grant"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Implied warranties",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In a transfer of title through an escrow agent the deed would be acknowledged by the:",hint:"Definition: The grantor is the person conveying the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"grantor.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"grantee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"escrow agent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"notary public.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is a correct statement?",hint:"Definition answer of a partition action.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A deed when delivered is presumed to be recorded",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A deed exception is the withholding of rights in the property from the grant",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A partition action is a court proceeding to sever a co-tenancy in real property",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following items is not included in the bill of sale of a retail business?",hint:"A bill of sale transfers ownership of personal property such as inventory of stock, trade name, fixtures, and equipment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Inventory of stock",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Assignment of leasehold",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Trade name",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"List of fixtures and equipment",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An attorney-in-fact under a general power of attorney can do everything except:",hint:"Cannot be involved in any act which would reflect a personal benefit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"sign his principal's name.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"encumber the property with another individual as beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deal with his principal's property for his own benefit.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Three of the following are quite similar. Which one which does not go with the others?",hint:"Offer, acceptance, and rescission pertain to contract, title does not.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Offer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Acceptance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Rescission",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Proration of taxes, insurance, and interest are based on a:",hint:"12 times a 30-day month. Use 30-day month or 360-day year.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"360-day year.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"365-day year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"366-day year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Valid consideration in a contract can be:",hint:"Although the basic concept of consideration is the mutual exchange of promises, consideration may be the payment of money, the performance of an act or a promise (covenant).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"money.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"services.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"promises.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A prospective buyer of a business opportunity would be most interested in the:",hint:"In gauging the financial condition of a business, a buyer will look at two financial statements. One of these will be the balance sheet which shows the assets and liabilities of the business and the net worth. Of more importance to the buyer, however, will be the profit and loss statement which reflects the net profit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"gross sales of the business.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"net profit of the business.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"turnover.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"net worth of the business.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A Notice of Intent to Sell was not recorded or published when a business opportunity was sold. If this were to happen, the primary responsibility for the debts of the business would lie with the:",hint:"If the transferee (buyer) does not comply with the requirements of Division 6 of the Uniform Commercial Code by recording and publishing a public notice of sale, he would have the primary responsibility for the debts of the business.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buyer.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"broker.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lessor.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under the bulk sale provisions of Division 6 of the Uniform Commercial Code, the publishing and recording requirements are intended to alert which of the following to the intended transfer?",hint:"The intent of the Bulk Sale Law is to warn the creditors of the potential or possible transfer of goods.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Broker who is handling transaction",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Creditors",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Vendors",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Vendee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"To be valid, a bill of sale would not have to contain:",hint:"A bill of sale is used to transfer the title to personal property. This type of instrument is not recorded and would not have to be acknowledged.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the name of the buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an acknowledgment.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"description of the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the signature of seller.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are items commonly found in a balance sheet except:",hint:"The total amount of sales (also referred to as the gross income) would be found on the profit and loss statement, not the balance sheet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"goodwill.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"equipment used for deliveries.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"prepaid expenses.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sales.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"To record a deed it must be:",hint:"These two demands of the law do not apply to the validity of the deed, but do apply to recording.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"acknowledged.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"state on its face the name and address of the person to whom the tax statement is to be mailed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neither",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A man bought unimproved property and executed a first trust deed for 10 years. He plans to build on the property within 2 years. The lack of which clause in the first trust deed could cause him future concern?",hint:"Without a subordination clause in the first trust deed, he could not obtain a subsequent construction loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Alienation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subrogation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subordination",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Acceleration",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An executrix is appointed by the:",hint:"An executor is the man, the executrix is the woman, named in the will of the deceased to handle the affairs of the deceased. If none is named, or if there is no will, the court appoints an administrator.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"probate court.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"heirs of the deceased.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deceased's attorney.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deceased.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An auction was held to sell some property from an estate. A buyer at the auction would be the:",hint:"Definition: An offeror (buyer) is the party who makes an offer (a contract to purchase) to the offeree (one who receives the offer).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"offeror.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"offeree.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A title plant refers to the records of property in a:",hint:"A title plant contains the records of the real property a title company services in the specific county.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"county.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"subdivision.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"condominium.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"community project.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which one of the following clauses is always in a deposit receipt?",hint:"The other clauses may be in a deposit receipt, but there is always an executory clause--which is a promise to be performed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Alienation clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subordination clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subrogation clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Executory clause",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would have the most influence in establishing fire insurance rates?",hint:"Fire insurance rates are based on the hazards and fire prevention facilities in the area.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The insurance company",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The insurance commissioner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The location of the property",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The zoning",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under the Bulk Sales Law, the minimum time to close the sale after the publication of notice of sale is:",hint:"The Uniform Commercial Code requires 12 business days publication prior to sale. Therefore, this period of time would have to elapse between publication and sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5 business days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"7 business days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"12 business days.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"20 business days.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In a buyer's closing statement, the purchase price is:",hint:"In a buyer's closing statement: Credit the buyer with everything he has coming. Debit the buyer with everything he owes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a seller's debit.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buyer's debit.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"seller's credit.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buyer's credit.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who has primary responsibility for property inspections?",hint:"The seller must disclose anything that would affect the value of the property and is therefore in the best position to inspect the property or have it inspected.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The buyer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The escrow agent",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The kind of deed given by the government on the original transfer of government land to the original grantee is called:",hint:"Definition: A patent is an instrument that conveys real property from the state or federal government to an individual.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"original deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Controller's deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"warranty deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"patent.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Recission of contract would mean that the contract is:",hint:'Definition answer for the word "recission."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"subrogated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"terminated.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"changed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'If you are asked to figure the net worth of a business, you would treat an "account payable" as:',hint:'The key word in this question is "payable." Hence, something that is to be paid; therefore, since it is to be paid, it is classified as a liability.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"none of the following",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an asset.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a liability.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a credit.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In which of the following would "privity" most likely exist?',hint:'The definition of the word "privity" is a contractual relationship between two parties that may have the same rights to a piece of property. An example would be the relationship between lessor-lessee, in regards to possession rights of the property.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Legal disputes",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Agency agreements",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contractual relationship",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"To determine the value for a business, which of the following items found on a financial statement would you pay least attention to?",hint:"Answers (a), (c), and (d) would influence the value of a business. The cost of goods sold would not.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Gross income receipts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost of inventory goods sold",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Inventory on hand",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cash on hand",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you are a buyer and want to be protected against unrecorded encumbrances in the purchase of real property. You would:",hint:"The extended coverage policy covers the same items that an A.L.T.A. policy covers, but the extended coverage policy insures the buyer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"obtain a extended coverage policy.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"obtain a standard policy of title insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ask the seller to give you a written guarantee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"write this agreement in the standard deposit receipt.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following would be found in the credit column of a buyer's closing statement except:",hint:"Prepaid rents, first trust deeds, and second trust deeds would appear in the credit column for the buyer. The purchase price, of course, would be a debit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"purchase price.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"prepaid rents.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"first trust deed that is assumed by buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"newly executed second trust deed to seller.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, short rate refers to:",hint:"Example: If a three-year policy cost $600 and it was canceled at the end of the first year, less than $400 would be refunded, or short rate applied.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"interest on trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accrued depreciation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"insurance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"prepaid rents.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'To remove a "financing statement" from the public records you would record a:',hint:"According to the Secretary of State, to release a financing statement from the records when the debt has been paid in full, a Termination Statement is filled.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"satisfaction statement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reconveyance statement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"financial statement release.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"termination statement.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A standard title insurance policy will insure against:",hint:"Forgery is the only one covered under CLTA standard title insurance; it does not cover unrecorded encumbrances and liens and never covers government regulations.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"forgery in the chain of title.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"unrecorded encumbrances and liens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"government regulations.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A negligent or intentional wrongful act arising from breach of duty created by law and not contract is a:",hint:"A violation of a legal right, or a civil wrong such as negligence, libel, nuisance, trespass, slander of title, or false imprisonment is a tort.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"tort.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"judgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"execution.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An attorney-in-fact:",hint:"Definition: An attorney-in-fact is 1. The person holding the power of attorney; or 2. A competent and disinterested person who is authorized by another person to act in his or her place in legal matters.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is a person authorized to legally act on behalf of another.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"must be appointed by the court.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must be authorized by a notary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must have a law degree.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In probate court matters concerning the sale of a recently deceased person's real property, the commission for the sale is set by:",hint:"All matters of probate court are set by the court.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the administrator.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the court.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the executor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the broker.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The real estate laws regarding the sale of business opportunity properties states that an owner of a retail store may not use as security for a loan:",hint:"If the stock in trade is sold, there would be no security for the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"equipment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fixtures.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"stock in trade.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"notes receivable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A copy of a standard termite report may be obtained from the:",hint:"Anyone can get a copy of the pest control report by requesting it from the Structural Pest Control Board and paying a fee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Commissioner of Real Estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Department of Termite Control.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Structural Pest Control Board.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If the deposit receipt and the escrow instructions fail to mention the date the buyer is to take possession of the property, which of the following would prevail?",hint:"When no other date is mentioned, possession of the property is given on the close of escrow.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"One day before the close of escrow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"On the close of escrow",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Within 5 days after close of escrow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Which of the following statements of fact best matches the term "alienation?"',hint:"Property is acquired by transfer when, by an act of the parties or law, title is conveyed, or transferred. Real property may be transferred, or alienated by private grant, public grant, public dedication or operation of law (a court action).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Contract of leasing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of conveyance",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Contract of money",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Contract of pledge",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Simon purchased a new home. The risk of loss due to vandalism or for damage by fire passes to Ms. Simon:",hint:"The responsibility of loss or vandalism passes from one party to another only according to the agreement between the two parties. This is a statement of factual law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"upon agreement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"during escrow.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"after escrow closes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"with the person in possession.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who normally pays for a policy of title insurance when a buyer purchases a new home?",hint:"Most lenders in California demand the protection of a policy of title insurance and make the borrower (trustor) pay for the policy.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trustee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Trustor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Beneficiary",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Lender",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'"Laches" deals with which of the following?',hint:'Definition answer for the word "laches."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Mechanic's lien",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Construction",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Unnecessary delay",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Tax evasion",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"CLTA and ALTA policies of title insurance holders are not insured against:",hint:"No policy of title insurance insures against zoning.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"chain of title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"forgery.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"parties in possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"zoning limitations.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When a buyer makes a contract to purchase real property and he acts to fulfill the terms of his contract, this would be a:",hint:'An offer by one of the parties in a contract, to carry out his part of the contract, is called "tender."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"time is of the essence clause.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tender.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"covenant.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"executory action.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The words "bailment" and "laches" are used in real estate. Bailment is which of the following?',hint:"By definition",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Unnecessary delay in asserting one's rights",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The posting of bail to insure one's temporary freedom",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A possessory interest in personal property as security for the performance of an act",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Filing a law suit",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An executory contract is a contract that:",hint:"An executory contract is a contract that must be performed or must be executed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"has been fully performed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"has been executed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is to be executed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The promise given in return for an offered promise in a bilateral contract is:",hint:"Consideration can be money, property, or a promise.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"acceptance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"obligatory trust.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"partial performance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"consideration.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"On a seller's closing statement, which of the items mentioned below must appear as a debit?",hint:'Since rent was prepaid in advance, the buyer must be given credit for this amount; hence, "debit the seller." Although it is common occurrence that seller pays for termite inspection there is no law to that effect and therefore it is not a must that seller pays for termite inspection. This is strictly an agreement between the buyer and seller.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"None of the following",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Termite inspection",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Prepaid rent",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both (b) and (c)",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A grant deed, to be effective, must be recorded, and to record a deed, it must be acknowledged by the grantor:",hint:"Since a valid and effective deed need merely be delivered but not recorded, the first statement is false. Since a deed is a document that must be acknowledged by the grantor to be recorded, the second statement is true.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"both statements are true",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the first statement is true and the second statement is false",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the first statement is false and the second statement is true",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"both statements are false",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In absence of a will, the separate property of the decedent is divided:",hint:"It would be divided 1/2 to surviving spouse and 1/2 to one child. If there is more than one child, it is divided 1/3 to surviving spouse and 2/3 to children.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"equally among surviving spouse and children.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/2 to surviving spouse and 1/2 to the children.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/3 to surviving spouse and 2/3 to the children.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Red passed away intestate. His property can only be sold, if it is sold by the administrator of the estate:",hint:"According to the laws of probate court proceedings, the court must approve of the purchase price and terms of sale before the sale can be completed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"to the person who bids the most at an auction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"after the court has approved the terms of sale and the price.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"with a 20% minimum down payment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Legally, a grant deed must:",hint:"One of the five requirements of a valid deed is the name of the grantee. The other three answers given are not necessary.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"name the grantee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"show escrow instructions.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"guarantee chain of title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have a due date.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In an option, which party has a choice about whether to exercise the option or not?",hint:"The buyer (optionee) is the only one who has a choice, once the contract is signed and the consideration given. The option does not bind the optionee to any performance - he or she does not have to exercise the option.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Optionor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Optionee",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Seller",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a person dies without any heirs and no will, what happens to their estate?",hint:"Escheat is a legal process in which property reverts to the state because the deceased owner left no will and has no legal heirs. However, the state must wait five years before trying to claim the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It is sold to the highest bidder",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It escheats to the state",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It is sold at a trustee's sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It becomes state property 2 years after the death",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When real property is transferred by private grant, the instrument most commonly used to convey the property is:",hint:"When property is transferred by private grant a written instrument such as a contract, deed or will is used. The kinds of deeds commonly used for private grants include: grant deed, quitclaim deed, gift deed, and warranty deed. In California, the grant deed is the most frequently used instrument to transfer title.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"grant deed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"gift deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"quit claim deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The law requires a seller to reveal any information that would be important to the buyer regarding the condition of the property in what document?",hint:"The Transfer Disclosure Statement form requires sellers to disclose known property defects, which are not limited to the physical aspects of the property but also include items such as zoning violations and nuisances in the area.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Mello Roos Statement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Statement of Compliance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Transfer Disclosure Statement",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Pest Control Inspection Statement",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What kind of sales are affected by bulk transfer laws?",hint:"There are certain legal requirements that must be met in the sale of a business. They include the Uniform Commercial Code, the Bulk Transfer Act, California Sales and Use tax Regulations, and the Alcoholic Beverage Control Act.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Exchanges of residential income property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Business opportunity",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Personal residence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Commercial",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The instrument by which a trustee conveys the bare legal title back to a trustor when a trustor has paid off a trust deed is a:",hint:"The trustee signs and records a Deed of Reconveyance to show the debt has been repaid and to clear the lien from the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"quitclaim deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"grant deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reconveyance deed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"warranty deed.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The law requires the county record to index grant deeds:",hint:"Deeds are indexed alphabetically according to grantor and grantee. Do not confuse indexing with filing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"according to phonetic filing system.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"according to date and time of recording.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"alphabetically according to grantor and grantee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"on microfilm records.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a property is sold by the court, and the proceeds are divided among the owners, this is called a:",hint:"Definition: Partition action is a court proceeding to settle a dispute between co-owners about dividing their interests in real property. The court can physically divide either the property or the money derived from its sale.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"split action.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"divided interest action.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"partition action.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"reverse action.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not covered by the CLTA extended policy of title insurance?",hint:"No title insurance policy will insure against government regulations concerning occupancy (zoning).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Parties in possession on an unrecorded land contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Reservations in government patents",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Encroachments revealed by a survey",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Governmental regulations concerning occupancy and use",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would not terminate an offer to purchase real property?",hint:"An offer to purchase is terminated by death. However, after a valid acceptance an offer ripens into a contract to purchase. Real estate purchase contracts are not terminated by death or insanity.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Notice of revocation by the buyer prior to notice of acceptance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Acceptance by seller after acceptance date",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Conditional acceptance by the seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Death or insanity of either party after acceptance",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Title to real property would pass to the purchaser under which of the following contracts?",hint:"All of these contracts are conditional sales contracts whereby the seller retains title until the contract is paid off. At that time a deed is given and title passes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Land Contract of Sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Installment Sales Contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Agreement of Sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following statements is correct? Escrow cannot be completed or terminated:",hint:"Read this type of question carefully. Since you are to find the correct statement, read each statement to see if it is correct. Escrow cannot be terminated by answer (c).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"by mutual agreement of the parties to escrow.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"when all terms of the escrow instructions have been complied with.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"by the broker advising the escrow holder to cancel the escrow.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above are correct",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Consideration paid for the use of a property is called:",hint:"A tenant takes possession and use of a property in return for rent payment. Rent is payment or consideration for the use of a property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"good faith deposit.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"rent.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"earnest money.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interest.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The transfer of the entire leasehold interest in a lease from the original lessee to another party is a(n):",hint:"An assignment is the transfer of the entire leasehold estate to a new person, called an assignee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"club sandwich lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sandwich lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sublease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"assignment.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'A deed that contains the following wording, "I, Richard Good hereby grant to Becky Sugar, Lot 5, Block 24, Tract 1009, recorded in Book 124, page 3, Official Maps and Records of Los Angeles County," and is signed and dated by Richard Good, would indicate that:',hint:"The transfer of title by the use of a grant deed usually transfers a fee estate and carries the two implied warranties. Any other type of estate would need a further statement showing the type of estate being transferred, i.e., life estate, estate in remainder, etc. A grant deed needs only the name of the grantee, a description of the property, a granting clause and a signature of the grantor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"title is given without any warranties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a fee simple estate is granted.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a life estate is being given.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an estate in reversion is being granted.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In a lease whose duration is greater than one year, what is not required?",hint:"Only the lessor is legally required to sign a written lease.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Writing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Signatures from both the lessor and the lessee",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Termination date",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Amount of rent and the method of payment",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A buyer buys land in a land project, but subsequently changes her mind. When may the buyer obtain a refund on her deposit?",hint:"The buyer of a parcel of land in a land project has 14 calendar days to request a refund.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Up to 3 calendar days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Up to 5 calendar days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Up to 10 calendar days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Up to 14 calendar days",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The verification and recordation of the document is required to create a valid:",hint:"A mechanic's lien is the only one of these documents which must be verified and recorded in order to be valid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"notice of default.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"judgment attaching real property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mechanic's lien.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A court order to sell property after the final judgment in a lawsuit has been rendered is:",hint:"A writ of execution is the court order to sell property after final judgment in a lawsuit has been made.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a foreclosure.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a deficiency judgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a writ of execution.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an attachment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Alienable title means that the title:",hint:"Alienate is to transfer title to property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is encumbered.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"can be conveyed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"cannot be conveyed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cannot be legally encumbered.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A standard policy insures against:",hint:"The standard title policy insures against a recorded deed that was not properly delivered and/or accepted. The other choices are only covered by an extended title policy.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"encroachments.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"claims of persons in possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"prescriptive easements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"recorded deed that was not properly delivered and accepted.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Most buyers get what type of title insurance?",hint:"Most buyers of homes get a standard title insurance policy.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Certificate of title",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Leasehold",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ALTA",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Standard title insurance policy",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An ALTA title insurance policy guards against all of the following except:",hint:"Neither the standard policy or ALTA policy protect against zoning.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an unrecorded mechanic's lien.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an unrecorded easement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"zoning regulations.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"rights of parties in possession.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mia is owner of a home which she has agreed to sell to Peter. A preliminary title report which was prepared during escrow shows:",hint:"A preliminary title report will show the existing loan with Mia as trustor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"exact same information as found in Peter's future standard title policy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"information about a deed of trust with Mia as trustor.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the new trust deed with Peter as trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"title vested in Peter.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In a standard title policy, what is not considered as one of the normal procedures?",hint:"A survey of the property is not one of the normal procedures when issuing a standard coverage policy.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The determination of the amount of insurance coverage",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Investigation of title",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A survey of the property",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A review of prior deeds",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not essential to a valid deed?",hint:"A deed does not have to be acknowledged in order to be valid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Acknowledgment",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Granting clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Competent parties",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Grantor's signature",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The main purpose of a deed is to:",hint:"The main purpose of a deed is to provide evidence of the change of title or transfer of interest in property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"identify grantor and grantee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"provide evidence of the change of title or transfer of interest.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"provide evidence of terms.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to provide a written instrument that can be recorded.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The acknowledgment of a deed can be taken by:",hint:"An employee of a corporation which is buying real estate may take an acknowledgment from the grantor, so long as the employee is a notary and does not have a personal interest in the transaction.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the person granting the deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a notary who is also the mortgagee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an employee of a corporation buying property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the grantor only.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A grant deed requires which of the following in order to be valid?",hint:"A granting clause is one of the requirements of a valid deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The grantee's signature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A recital",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An acknowledgment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A granting clause",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In making a decision to issue a standard title insurance policy, a title insurance company is most concerned with:",hint:"A title company would be most interested in the chain of title when issuing a standard title insurance policy.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the grantee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the chain of title.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"boundary lines of the property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The item that would appear on the debit side of the buyer's closing statement is:",hint:"The purchase price is a debit on the buyers closing statement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the purchase price.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"prepaid rents.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unpaid property taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following items are normally prorated at the close of escrow, except:",hint:"Interest on unsecured loans will not be prorated at close of escrow.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"homeowner's insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"property taxes and assessments.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"delinquent interest on unsecured loans.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"interest and impounds.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"During escrow, the escrow officer received two structural pest control reports. The escrow officer should:",hint:"The escrow officer must let the buyer and seller decide which termite report to use.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"contact the inspection company to ask which report is best.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"notify the buyer and sell and obtain written instructions as which report to use.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"use the report which found the most infestation and damage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"use the report which found the least infestation and damage.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following may a minor be able to undertake without court approval?",hint:"A minor may acquire real property by gift or inheritance without court approval.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Acquisition of real property through gift or inheritance",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Give valid power of attorney to encumber property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sell real estate through a guardian",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The California Civil Code requires a disclosure statement be delivered by the:",hint:'The transferor (seller) of four or less residential units must deliver the "transfer disclosure statement" to the transferee (buyer).',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"probate court.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"trustee to trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"transferor to transferee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"husband to wife.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A voidable contract remains binding until it has been:",hint:"A voidable contract is valid until it is rescinded (voided).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"invalidated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"rescinded.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"discovered.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"qualified.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A contract has been executed when it has been:",hint:"A contract has been executed when it has been completely and fully performed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"signed, notarized and recorded.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"entered into under the jurisdiction of the probate court.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"completely and fully performed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"signed under threat of death.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are essential to the validity of a contract, except:",hint:"Payment of money is not required for the validity of a contract. Promises can be the consideration.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a meeting of the minds.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the adequate capacity of the parties to the contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the payment of money.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a legal purpose.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Statute of Frauds requires which of the following contracts to be in writing?",hint:"A contract which is not to be performed within one year of its making must be in writing in order to be enforceable under the Statute of Frauds.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An employment contract to represent the seller of a business opportunity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A contract selling a business opportunity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A contract which is not to be performed within one year of its making",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A nine month lease",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In order to have a binding contract between the buyer and seller, it must:",hint:"All contracts must have been offered and accepted in order to be binding.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"have been offered and accepted.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"be recorded.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"contain acknowledgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When damages are not adequate, each of the following may request specific performance, except the:",hint:"The broker may not seek specific performance from the principal. The broker's remedy is to sue for damages.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"buyer from the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"attorney in fact for one of the principals.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"seller of a large parcel of land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"broker from the principal.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Brad sold his house to Jerry, who did not record the deed, but moved in. Brad then sold the same property to George, who reviewed the county recorder's records, but did not look at the property. Brad gave George a deed, which was recorded. Which of the following would be true concerning title to the property?",hint:"Although Jerry did not record the deed, he took possession by moving in. Possession of the property by Jerry gives constructive notice. Since George recorded after Jerry took possession, he had constructive notice of Jerry's rights.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Jerry and George are co-owners of the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"George now owns the property because he recorded his deed and Jerry did not",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"George has recourse against Jerry for failure to record",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Jerry maintains title",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A title company conducts a title search by searching the records of the:",hint:"All of these offices may be searched by a title company when conducting a title search.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"county recorder's office.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"county clerk's office.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"federal land office.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The added protection of an ALTA title insurance policy over a CLTA policy is in guarding against:",hint:"An ALTA policy includes a survey and would protect against a property line dispute.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"existing liens and encumbrances of record.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an invalid deed in the chain of title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an error in the sequence of recording trust deed loans.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a dispute over property lines which would be disclosed by a survey.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Loss of title results from:",hint:"Erosion results in loss of title. Accretion is the addition of land by depositing, due to action of water. Certiorari is a writ from superior court, calling for records. Prescription is a method of obtaining an easement, not title.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"erosion.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"prescription.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accretion.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"certiorari.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A prospective buyer obtained a three-month option on a parcel of real property by paying $300 to the owner. All of the following are true except:",hint:"An option does not create a legal interest in the property for the optionee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the option is a unilateral contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'the optionor is totally restricted by having received "valuable" consideration with the option.',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the option imposes no obligation on the optionee to buy the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the optionee has created a legal interest in the property.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The receipt for a Subdivision Final Public Report must be kept on file by the subdivider or his agent for a minimum of:",hint:"A subdivider must keep a copy of the final public report for three years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"one year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"three years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"four years.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'In his duties with respect to subdivisions, the Real Estate Commissioner is concerned with the term "compacted" in reference to which of the following?',hint:"A documented report on soil conditions including filled ground may be demanded by the Commissioner. Earth fill would be compacted.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Expansive soil",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Earth fill",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Size of lots",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Water content of lumber used in construction",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Real Estate Law defines a planned development as which of the following?",hint:"A planned development containing 5 or more lots is defined as a subdivision. A condominium project containing 2 or more units, a stock cooperative having 2 or more shareholders, and a community apartment project containing 2 or more apartments are other forms of subdivisions.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A condominium project",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A co-op apartment project",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A subdivision",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A community apartment project",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Statute of Frauds requires that all of the following contracts must be a record in writing to be enforceable except:",hint:"An oral agreement to split a commission is enforceable at law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an agreement allowing a broker to sell real estate for compensation.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a lease agreement of one year to commence one month after date of execution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an agreement to sell land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an agreement between two brokers to split a commission.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When title to real property, which is encumbered by a deed of trust, is transferred as the result of a sale, it is always necessary to:",hint:"Encumbered property may be conveyed and this is usually done with a grant deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"obtain the permission of the beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pay off the balance of the trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have the grantor deliver a deed.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"refinance completely.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In a city, compliance to the State Housing Act is enforced by the city:",hint:"The Building Inspector makes sure that the building complies with local and State building codes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"engineer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"police department.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"planning commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"building inspector.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"All of the following statements concerning condominiums are true except:",hint:"The County Tax Assessors issue separate tax bills to each unit owner covering his interest. All the other choices are true.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"real property taxes must be billed to the entire project and prorated by the project manager.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the unit ownership can be deeded for indefinite duration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"condominium ownership may be in residential, industrial, or commercial property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'there is non-severability of the "in-common" and "separate" interests."',isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The party who is responsible for the enforcement of sanitation and sewage requirements in a subdivision is the:",hint:"It is the Health Department's duty to approve the adequacy of the sanitation facilities of a new subdivision.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"local building inspector.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"health department.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"local planning commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who places the restrictions in a deed to a condominium unit in a new subdivision?",hint:'Deed restrictions are normally placed in the deed by the subdivider-the original grantor. "Project developer" is the term used for the subdivider of a condominium project.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Local planning commission",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Project developers",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Elected governing board",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Unit owners",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Recording a deed:",hint:"Recording does not make a deed valid, but establishes the legal presumption that the deed was delivered. Recording gives constructive notice.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"presumes delivery.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"gives actual notice.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"validates a deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How long must a structural termite report be held on file by the Structural Pest Control Board in Sacramento?",hint:"A termite report is not demanded by law, but if one is issued, it must be filed in Sacramento and kept on file for two years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"One year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Two years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Three years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Four years",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Consideration is to a contract as endorsement is to a:",hint:"Endorsement is the symbol of consideration for the negotiation of a promissory note.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"trust deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"promissory note.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"land contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"option.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is the least enforceable requirement of a subdivision improvement?",hint:"The other choices are common and enforceable. It would be very difficult to enforce a requirement stating one had to spend a certain amount of money in the improvements as one may be able to build just as beautiful and big a house as someone else and for less money.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A minimum dollar value",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A minimum lot size",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A minimum area requirement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A maximum height restriction",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An option is different from other contracts, such as conventional or conditional sales contracts. The difference is due to what characteristic of an option?",hint:"Mutuality of obligations would mean that both parties are obligated to perform, which is the case with most contracts. An option does not have mutuality of obligations in that only the optionor is obligated to perform, not the optionee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Irrevocability",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mutuality of obligations of the parties",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Non-mutuality of obligations of the parties",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both (b) and (c) are correct",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following statements is true with respect to planning commissions?",hint:"Members of the Planning Commission should be knowledgeable in the field of real estate and city planning, but this is not a prerequisite for being a member. The members are appointed and it is their job to develop a master plan and advise the City Council in this area.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"All members are elected",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Members must have had real estate or subdivision experience",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"They are authorized to give advise to the city council on subdivisions",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Members must be real estate brokers",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Alienation expressed a meaning most completely opposite to:",hint:"Alienation is the transferring of property to another. Acquisition is the receiving of property from another.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"acceleration.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subordination.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"acquisition.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"subrogation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Real Estate Commissioner's Subdivision Final Public Report expires:",hint:"Matter of law, unless there is a material change.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"one year from the date of the report.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"never, unless a material change occurs.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"five years from the date of the issuance of the report.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"three years from the date of the issuance of the report.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Escrow companies normally base their prorations on a year consisting of:",hint:"As a matter of convenience, escrow companies use a 30-day month, hence, a 360-day year.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"350 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"355 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"360 days.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"365 days.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not necessary to a valid deed?",hint:"The first three choices are requirements. Acknowledgment is necessary for recording but not for validity.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Capacity to convey and pass title",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"In writing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Granting clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Acknowledgment",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"If a subdivider grants an easement to a utility company, the utility company holds:",hint:"When easements are given to utility companies, they hold an easement in gross. Statement of fact answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an easement by permission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a dominant tenement for life.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an easement in gross.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The topography of land is the defining of its surface features. A subdivider must give consideration to the topography of the proposed subdivided lands because:",hint:"Irregularities refer to hills or slopes on the land. Homes with a view, or at least not on the same level as the other homes in the same neighborhood, usually are more desirable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"some irregularities in the surface are desirable.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"hilly or irregularly shaped lots reduce the cost of construction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a rolling terrain is more monotonous than a flat terrain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"elevated lots are subject to inundation in the winter.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Street Improvement Act of 1911 allows land owners to do all of the following except:",hint:"According to the Street Improvement Act of 1911, land owners may not buy additional land for development.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"put in sewers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buy additional land for development as subdivision.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"improve sidewalks.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A buyer must bring a lawsuit for breach of written contract against a seller within:",hint:"The Statute of Limitations requires lawsuits for breach of a written contract to be filed within four years of the breach.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"6 months.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1 year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4 years.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What must be disclosed to purchasers under the Alquist-Priolo Special Studies Act?",hint:"The Alquist-Priolo Special Studies Act requires a subdivider to disclose if the property is near certain earthquake faults.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Location of toxic waste sites",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Water quality reports",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Location of flood hazard zones",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Location of earthquake fault lines",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The California State Housing Act, which contains minimum code requirements, is found in the:",hint:"The State Housing Law outlines minimum construction and occupancy requirements. Local building inspectors enforce the construction regulations and local health officers enforce the occupancy and sanitation regulations (Health and Safety Code Section 17910, et seq.).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"State Contractor's Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Uniform Commercial Code.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Health and Safety Code.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Fair Housing Act.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A remedy in court compelling a vendor to execute a deed in pursuance of a valid written contract is known as:",hint:"Compelling him to specifically perform as agreed to in the contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"foreclosure.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"specific performance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"execution.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"equity of redemption.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A subdivider's final map has been approved, but he has not received the Commissioner's Final Report. The maximum number of parcels that may be used to secure a loan before the loan is a blanket encumbrance is:",hint:"When more than one lot is used as security under one loan, it is considered to be a blanket encumbrance. One lot only could be used as security for the loan. Using more than one constitutes a blanket encumbrance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"2.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The following terms are closely associated with real estate. Which does not belong with the others?",hint:"Offer, option, and rejection are terms regarding contracts.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Offer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Option",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Rejection",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A gift of real property by will is a:",hint:"Bequest is a gift of personal property by will.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"demise.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"devise.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"legacy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"bequest.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following must be recorded to be valid?",hint:"A homestead is the only one listed that must be recorded to be valid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Easement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real estate sales contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Homestead",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Lease",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Four months ago a seller accepted an offer from a buyer to purchase her home. The contract was in writing. Later, the seller refused to complete the transaction. Under the Statute of Limitations, so his right to sue does not "outlaw," the buyer must file an action within:',hint:"Statute of Limitations on any written contract is 4 years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"90 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1 year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4 years.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Recordation of a deed provides which of the following?",hint:"Recording gives constructive notice.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Liens shown against property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Constructive notice",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Guarantees ownership",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Guarantees possessory ownership in the property",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A licensee sells property to a young married couple and later learns they are both 17 years of age. This transaction could best be described as:",hint:"Married persons under the age of eighteen are considered emancipated minors.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"illegal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The Street Improvement Act of 1911 allows how long to pay for an assessment before it goes to bond?",hint:"30 days, not 1 month.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30 days",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1 month",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"60 days",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The approval of sanitation facilities in a subdivision is under the control of:",hint:"Construction regulations: local building inspector. Sanitation regulations: local health officer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"planning commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"local health officer.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"local building inspector.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"plumbing inspector.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following covers Federal Fair Housing laws?",hint:"The Rumford Act is the State Fair Housing Law.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Rumford Act",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"13th Amendment to the U. S. Constitution",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Unruh Civil Rights Act",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title VIII, Civil Rights Act of 1968",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A solemn declaration by a person whose religious beliefs forbid the taking of an oath is:",hint:"An affirmation is a declaration as to the truth of a statement, and is used in lieu of an oath by a person who objects for personal or religious reasons.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an affidavit.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an acknowledgment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an affirmation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. and Mrs. Kay owned property in joint tenancy. Mrs. Kay had a daughter, Gloria, by a previous marriage, and Mr. Kay had a son, George, by a previous marriage. In her will, Mrs. Kay left her share of the property to the children in equal shares. This means:",hint:"Joint tenancy has right of survivorship, and, therefore, the joint tenants cannot will their share. The decedent's share automatically goes to the surviving joint tenants.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Mr. Kay would receive 1/2 and the children would share the other half equally.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Gloria would receive Mrs. Kay's estate and share it with George.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mr. Kay would receive 1/3, Gloria 1/3, and George 1/3.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mr. Kay would receive the entire estate.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Individual ownership of individual lots and common ownership of other areas would be:",hint:"Ownership of individual lots and common ownership of other areas would be a planned development project.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a standard subdivision.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a planned development project.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a co-op project.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a condominium.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Division 6 of the Uniform Commercial Code pertaining to bulk transfers of goods in California is for the protection of:",hint:"The purpose of the Bulk Transfer Act is to protect the creditors of a person who sells a business.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both the buyer and the seller.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"creditors.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In considering a bilateral contract, the offered promise bargains for receipt of a returned promise. If the return promise is given, it is considered:",hint:"Consideration for a contract need not be money. It may be a promise.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an option.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a consideration.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a unilateral agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"According to the Subdivision Law of California, the Commissioner's Preliminary Report terminates:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) could immediately terminate a Preliminary Report according to Real State Commissioner's regulations.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"when the subdivider receives the Commissioner's Final Report.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"if any material change in the method of sales takes place.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one year from the date issued.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Usually, an escrow officer is authorized to:",hint:"Typical escrow instructions authorize escrow officers to call for the funding of the buyer's loan in order to close escrow. Escrow officers are not authorized to do the other choices.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"determine which financing is best for the buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"change the escrow instructions when asked to by the selling agent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"call for the funding of buyer's loan.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"choose the pest control company.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The meaning of the word "waiver," as it is applied to real estate contracts, most nearly means:',hint:'The word "waiver," as applied to a real estate contract, most nearly means a unilateral act and its legal consequences. One party "waives" the right to have another party perform in the contract.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"estoppel.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unjust enrichment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a unilateral act and its legal consequences.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"It is unlawful for someone to sell any franchise that is regulated by the Franchise Investment Law unless such person has made application to the Corporations Commissioner or is licensed by the:",hint:"A person licensed by either the Real Estate Commissioner, or the Corporations Commissioner may sell a franchise.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Franchise Tax Board.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Corporations Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"either (a) or (c) above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An option to buy real estate become a mutually binding contract, when:",hint:"An option to purchase becomes a mutually binding contract when the optionee (buyer) exercises the right to buy.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the option is given to the optionee by the optionor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the optionee exercises the right to purchase.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the consideration for the option is given.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above happens.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"During escrow, there are many items known as recurring costs. Which of the following would be handled as a recurring cost?",hint:"Recurring costs are those costs which are incurred in escrow and will recur again after taking possession of the property, such as property taxes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A policy of title insurance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost for appraising the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Escrow charges",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Property taxes",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following interests does the lessee hold?",hint:'Leasehold estates are "chattels real." They are also a less than-freehold estate.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Remainder estates",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Chattel real",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Less than freehold estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (b) and (c) above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A condo owner's interest payments against the common area of his development:",hint:"In a planned development subdivision the owner has title to the unit and the land under it, together with membership in an association which owns common area. Each unit owner has a deed, separate financing and pays the property taxes for their unit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is his responsibility severally and jointly.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may be deducted from his taxes.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"are optional.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cause a reduction in the principal amount owed on his loan.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'"A" receives a life estate for the life of "X." "A" dies before "X." The estate:',hint:'The estate vests in the heirs of "A" until "X" dies, at which time the estate will revert to the original grantor.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"ceases to exist.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reverts to the original grantor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'vests in "X" for his life.',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'vests in the heirs of "A."',isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An attorney-in-fact can do all of the following things, except:",hint:"The attorney-in-fact has no power to act for his principal until the power of attorney is recorded.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"sign his principal's name.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"perform acts of a general power of attorney.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deal in real property without recording his general power of attorney.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"encumber his principal's property with a trust deed naming another as the beneficiary.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A broker took a listing for 90 days. During the term of the listing, the owner was declared mentally incompetent. The listing contract is:",hint:"Incapacity on the part of either of the parties to an employment contract will make it void.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"binding.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"enforceable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An agreement to sell community property, signed by the husband alone, is:",hint:"The wife has one year from the date of recording the deed to void the sale. If she does not void the sale, it is valid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unenforceable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Olden received an option from Mr. New on a piece of property valued at $1,000,000. As consideration for this option, Ms. Olden gave Mr. New $10.00 in cash. The option is:",hint:"There is no law requiring any specific amount for consideration on an option. Whatever is agreeable among the parties is acceptable. If Mr. New accepts the $10.00, then the option is valid and binding.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"invalid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unenforceable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"One of the main reasons that condominium projects are expected to grow in demand in the future is:",hint:"Because land cost is skyrocketing here in California, if the builder were to build more condominium units on a given piece of land, he would reduce the cost of land per unit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"no yard upkeep.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"higher property taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"land value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"utility value.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. and Mrs. Flowers made an offer to purchase a house, which was accepted. The escrow was to close in 30 days. Just before the closing, the owner changed his mind and decided not to sell. Which of the following is not an alternative for the buyer?",hint:"All except a writ of execution are remedies for breach of contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"They may rescind the contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"They may file a writ of execution",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"They may file an action for specific performance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"They may sue the seller for money damages",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The term "liabilities," in business transactions, refers to:',hint:"Liabilities would refer to bills to be paid (claims of creditors).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"assets.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"accounts receivable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"claims of creditors.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"net loss on business incurred.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In a city, compliance to the State Housing Act is enforced by:",hint:"He makes sure that the building codes of the State Housing Act are complied with.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"planning commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"health officer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"city building inspector.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"resident FHA authority.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Gambling debts are dischargeable:",hint:"As a general rule, the discharge in bankruptcy affects a debtor's personal obligations but does not destroy liens against the debtor's property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"in bankruptcy.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"by the loser.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"by court order.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at a trustee's sale.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In real estate contracts, the consideration must be sufficient relative to value in order to win a lawsuit seeking:",hint:"Specific performance is an equitable remedy. Therefore, the judge must be convinced that the consideration is sufficient for the value of the property. A judge may refuse to grant specific performance if she feels the contract is unfair.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a lis pendens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"specific performance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an attachment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"damages.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Informing a person that he should sell his property because non-whites are moving into the area, decreasing property values, can be expressed by all of the following except:",hint:"Situation describes blockbusting which causes panic selling and is illegal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"blockbusting.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"panic selling.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"illegal conduct.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"legal conduct.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A person designated in a written power-of-attorney, to legally act for another in his stead is typically called a(n):",hint:"Any person may give another the authority to act on his or her behalf. The legal document that does this is called a power of attorney. The person holding the power of attorney is an attorney-in-fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"fiduciary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"principal.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"attorney-in-fact.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"agent.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume zoning laws were recently changed to permit you to construct a two-story dwelling on your vacant lot, but the deed you received for the lot contained a restriction against building a two-story dwelling on the lot. Which would prevail?",hint:"Even though zoning laws would permit you to construct a two story dwelling on your lot, the deed restrictions would still prevail. In other words, deed restrictions supersede zoning changes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The new zoning changes",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The application for a variance permit",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The deed restrictions",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"To bid on property in a probate sale, the offer must be at least the amount of the appraised value in order to be confirmed by the probate court, which is:",hint:"A summary of Probate Court Procedures includes the following: An offer to purchase must be for at least 90% of the appraised value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"75%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"80%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"90%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"100%.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An escrow may be terminated by all of the following except:",hint:"The agent is not a party to the escrow and has no right to terminate it.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"running of time limit allowed for escrow.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"full performance and closing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"instruction by the selling real estate agent.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"mutual consent of parties.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a man died intestate, his separate property would go to:",hint:"If there were only one child the separate property would be divided half and half. With more than one child, it is divided 1/3 to the spouse and 2/3 to the children, share and share alike.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"his wife alone.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/2 to his wife and 1/2 divided among his closest relatives.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/3 to his wife and 2/3 divided among his children, share and share alike if he had more than one child.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"his children alone.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Real Estate Commissioner has primary regulatory authority over subdivision matters concerning:",hint:"The Commissioner regulates aspects concerning the sale of subdivided lands to prevent fraud, including monies for promised improvements. He does not concern himself with the physical improvements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"alignment of streets within a tract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"design of the improvements to insure proper drainage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"financial arrangements to insure the completion of community facilities.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume all necessary instruments concerning a sale of real property were placed into escrow. It later develops that the escrow instructions signed by the buyer and the seller contained terms in conflict with the original deposit receipt. Which of the following statements is true?",hint:"The escrow instructions would prevail because it is the most recent agreement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The original deposit receipt prevails",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A new deposit receipt would have to be drawn up by both parties",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The escrow instructions would prevail",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The sale would be voided",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The real estate law regarding the sale of business opportunity properties states an owner of a retail store (hardware) may not use as security for a loan:",hint:"If the stock in trade is sold there would be no security for the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"equipment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fixtures.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"stock in trade.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"notes receivable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When property taxes are prepaid, how would they appear in the escrow closing statement?",hint:"Taxes are paid twice yearly; if a taxpayer sells his property during the time for which he has already paid property taxes, he will be credited for the amount through escrow.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Debit to the seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Credit to the seller",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Debit to the state",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Credit to the buyer",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When there is a dispute between a buyer and seller over the deposit, escrow would file:",hint:"If an escrow agent cannot get the buyer and seller to agree on the disposition of the deposit money, the recourse is to file an interpleader action asking the court to accept the money and distribute it to the rightful claimant.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an unlawful detainer action.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a partition action.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an execution action.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an interpleader action.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When a state official sells his home, which of the following must be given to the buyer?",hint:"A transfer disclosure statement is required for all sellers of real property (1-4 residential units) in California.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Trustee disclosure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Transfer disclosure statement",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Promissory note",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Termite report",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Fire insurance should allow the policy holder to:",hint:"Insurance provides indemnification against loss from a specific hazard or peril. Most insurance policies contain a pro rata liability clause that prevents the owner from collecting a greater amount than the actual loss.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"gain in the event of a claim.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"make at least 4 claims before cancellation of the policy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neither gain nor lose in the event of a claim.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"keep his loss to no more than $100,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following statements about escrow procedures is true?",hint:"Escrow agents are dual agents for both buyer and seller until the close of escrow. After close, they become the separate agent of either party.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A broker can never escrow a transaction",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When the escrow requirements have been met, the escrow agency changes from a dual agency to a separate agency",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"When the escrow holder receives signed instructions, it is said to be a complete escrow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The purpose of escrow is to have the escrow officer act as an arbitrator of disputes between the buyer and seller",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Scott executes a deed to Bob and records it. Later, Scott seeks to void the sale, claiming that there had been no delivery to Bob. Why will Scott lose?",hint:"Recording a deed creates a legal presumption of delivery and acceptance. Scott will lose the argument unless he can overcome this presumption.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Bob is in possession of the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Delivery is presumed with recording",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A recorded deed is always valid",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Recording establishes the priority of the deed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would have priority?",hint:"Government liens (assessment, property tax, etc.) have priority over all other liens.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A first deed of trust recorded March 14, 1992",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A homestead recorded April 1, 1992",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An assessment lien for street improvement, recorded April 5, 1992",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An unrecorded mechanic's lien",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A written summary of that chain of title prepared by a title insurance company is called:",hint:"A summary of the chain of title is called an abstract of title.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an affidavit of title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an extended coverage title insurance policy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an abstract of title.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a trust deed is sold, the principals usually use an escrow in order to:",hint:"The purpose of an escrow is to have a neutral third party make sure the conditions and terms are met prior to release of the money and closing of the escrow.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"obey the law.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be a formal witness for the transaction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"provide a legal recourse against the escrow company should there be any dispute between the principals.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"make sure the conditions and terms are met prior to the closing of the escrow.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"For speculative purposes, an owner of land divided it into 8 parcels in 1991. He sold two lots in 1991, two lots in 1992, took an option to purchase on one lot in 1993, and sold the remaining lots in 1994. When was he legally classified as a subdivider?",hint:"The date of subdividing was before any sales took place.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1991",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1992",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1993, if the option were exercised",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1994, if the option were not exercised",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are classified as subdivisions and subject to regulation by the Real Estate Commissioner except:",hint:"Land divided into 5 or more parcels and condominiums, co-ops, stock co-ops, and community apartment projects of 5 or more are all subdivisions. An apartment house would not come under subdivision law unless each individual apartment was offered for sale, in which case it would become a community apartment project.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"land divided into more than 4 pieces.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a five-unit community apartment project.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a five-unit condominium project.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a twenty-one unit apartment house.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following elements of a subdivision law are administered by the Real Estate Commissioner?",hint:"Answer (a) comes under real property securities law. Answers (c) and (d) come under control of the local governing body.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The physical aspects, such as streets and sidewalks, of an out-of-state subdivision",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Adequate financial arrangements to ensure completion of community recreational facilities",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Approval of improvement contracts, and posting of adequate performance bonds",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Statutory dedication of easements for streets",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following elements of a subdivision are regulated by local planning commissions under the state Subdivision Map Act?",hint:"Out-of-state subdivisions come under real property securities law. Approval of the preliminary public report is done by the commissioner. Answer (c) is not necessary at all.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The physical aspects, such as streets and sidewalks, of an out-of-state subdivision",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Approval of the preliminary public report",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Verification that the subdivider has a valid license issued by the Department of Real Estate",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Assurance that adequate provisions have been made for sewage disposal and flood control",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"It is said that the Commissioner's Public Report is the chief weapon against fraud in the sale of subdivided lands in California. All of the following are correct statements concerning the Public Report except:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all correct statements. Answer (d) is not. This would constitute a material change.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a broker may take a listing on and show property before the issuance of the Public Report.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a Preliminary Public Report issued by the Commissioner enables the subdivider to take reservations. However, it expires in one year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a Final Public Report expires in 5 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the option of 5 lots in a subdivision to one buyer does not constitute a material change in ownership.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is a correct statement concerning condominiums?",hint:"A condominium consists of a separate fee interest in a particular specific space (the unit), plus an undivided interest in all common or public areas of the development. All owners are allowed to use any of the facilities in the common area. Each unit owner has a deed, separate financing and pays the property taxes for their unit. Operations controlled by elected governing board.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:'The term "condominium unit" refers to a deeded separate interest in space in a residential, industrial or commercial building',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Bearing walls, central air conditioning units, and elevators represent an undivided interest in common",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Rising land values tend to increase the condominium form of ownership and each unit is assessed separately and receives a separate tax bill",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above are correct statements",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Recording a deed gives:",hint:"Recordation gives constructive notice.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"constructive notice.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"objective notice.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"actual notice.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"factual notice.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which is most correct concerning the Statute of Frauds?",hint:"The Statute of Frauds states which contracts must be in writing to be enforceable. Its main function is for the prevention of fraud.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Misrepresentation in the making of a contract violates the statute",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It classifies most oral real estate contracts as unenforceable",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It classifies an oral agreement between brokers to share a commission as unenforceable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Violations of this statute are prosecuted by the district attorney in the county where the alleged violation occurred",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Smith owns a single family residence in which he resides. He trades with Brown for another residence which Brown is renting to a tenant. Both parties intend to use their newly acquired properties for rental income. Which of the following is true?",hint:'Brown is exchanging an income property for an income property; therefore, exchanging "like for like." Smith is NOT.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Smith can negotiate a tax-deferred exchange",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Brown can negotiate a tax-deferred exchange",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both parties can negotiate a tax-deferred exchange",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither can negotiate a tax-deferred exchange",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Title to real property would immediately pass to the purchaser under which of the following contracts?",hint:"All of these contracts are conditional sales contracts whereby the seller retains title until the contract is paid off. At that time, a deed is given and title passes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Land contract of sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Installment sales contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Agreement of sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A married man died without leaving a witnessed will. However, after his death his wife found a statement naming his son as executor and expressing his wishes for the disposition of his estate. It was dated three years previously and was entirely written and signed by him in pencil. This would mean:",hint:"A handwritten unwitnessed will is a holographic will and is legal. Real property is always probated in the state where located.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an administrator would be appointed to preserve his estate until the completion of probate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"his death would be classified as intestate and his wife would be executrix of the estate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"his will would be classified as nuncupative and his wife would receive his estate without probate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"his death would be classified as testate. However, any real property would have to be probated in whatever state it is located.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In respect to deeds:",hint:"A grant deed only implies two warranties. A quit claim deed conveys all interest known and unknown by the grantor. A trust deed is used as security for a loan, not for conveying property. The only correct answer is (c).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a grant deed must state two warranties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a quitclaim deed does not move the entire present interest in the title owned by the grantor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a recorded deed is presumed delivered and accepted.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a trust deed is the most common method of conveyance in real property purchased in California.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would represent a distinction between a grant deed and a quit claim deed?",hint:"The requirements of a valid Grant Deed include: after-acquired title (any benefits that come to the property after a sale must follow the sale and accrue to the new owner); words of granting such as grant or convey must be within the deed; and have two implied warranties by the grantor - 1. The grantor has not already conveyed title to any other person, and 2. The estate is free from encumbrances other than those disclosed by the grantor. A quitclaim deed contains no warranties and transfers any interest the grantor may have at the time the deed is signed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"After acquired title",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'The word "grant"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Implied warranties",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The recording system was established to show the sequence of transfers or other actions affecting property. All of the following are correct statements concerning recordation except:",hint:"Recording a deed imparts constructive notice, not actual notice.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"recording a deed does not affect its legality.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"public records may be inspected by anyone without an employee of the recorder's office being present.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"recording a deed imparts actual notice to all future purchasers.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a deed to real property that is recorded in a county other than that in which the property is located, does not provide constructive notice.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Gable conveys title to his son by grant deed. He gives the deed to his friend Laker to be held until Gable's death. Upon Gable's death there would most likely be a question concerning:",hint:"Delivery must be done during the grantor's lifetime.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"recording.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"competence of grantee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"delivery.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"consideration.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Cities and counties may adopt zoning regulations to ensure that structures conform to specified standards as to character and location. All of the following are correct statements concerning zoning ordinances except:",hint:'In zoning, the symbol "R" stands for residential property. R-3 would be multiple units.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"zoning regulations are classified as public restrictions and are created under police powers of the city or county.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"zoning laws affecting the use of property are classified as encumbrances on the title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'zoning ordinances vary from city to city. However, the symbol "R-3" generally refers to recreational use of property.',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"denial of zoning variances may be appealed to the city council or board of supervisors but not to the courts.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"As relating to real estate, a patent is:",hint:"A sovereign grant refers to the government patent deed which transfers title to government land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an invention.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"same as a land contract.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a sovereign grant.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Financing statements are to be filed with:",hint:"Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"City Attorney's Office.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Secretary of State.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"County Board of Equalization.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Board of Equalization.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A receipt for a Preliminary Public Report must be kept by the subdivider for:",hint:"Before a developer can sell each lot in the project, he or she must give a copy of the Commissioner's Final Public Report to the buyer for approval. The buyer signs a receipt stating that it has been read and the seller (developer/subdivider) must keep a copy of the statement for three years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"3 years.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"2 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Real Estate Law being exact and specific includes legal aspects. In legal aspects:",hint:"The person who receives the title in real estate law is called the grantee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"deeds must be recorded to transfer title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the receiver of title is called the grantee.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"open listings must contain termination dates.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The basic regulations of the housing and construction industries in this state are accomplished by the:",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) all regulate the housing and construction industries in the state; therefore, answer (d) is the best answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"State Contractors License Law.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"local building codes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Housing Act.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any or all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A grant deed, to be effective, must be recorded. To record a deed, it must be acknowledged by the grantor.",hint:"Since a valid and effective deed need merely be delivered but not recorded, the first statement is false. Since a deed is a document that must be acknowledged by the grantor to be recorded, the second statement is true.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Both statements are true",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The first statement is true and the second statement is false",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The first statement is false and the second statement is true",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both statements are false",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Constructive notice of the transfer of ownership of real property is given by means of:",hint:"By definition. Recording an instrument gives constructive notice.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"posting a notice on the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"running an ad in the local newspaper.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"notifying all parties involved in the transfer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"recording the deed.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When an existing contract is replaced by an new contract, with the intent to replace the existing contract, it is called:",hint:"Novation is when the parties mutually agree to replace an existing contract with a new contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"assignment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"rescission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"novation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"rehabilitation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Upon inspection, a pest control company finds no evidence of termite infestation. However, they do find conditions which may lead to infestation. Whose responsibility is it to pay for correcting these conditions?",hint:"The seller is responsible only for termite damage present at the time of inspection. Any preventative action is the responsibility of the buyer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The seller in all cases",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The buyer in all cases",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller and the buyer, each paying half",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The buyer, only if he chooses to have the condition corrected",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A contract obtained through duress, is:",hint:"The injured party has the option to void the contract; therefore, it is voidable.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"good.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unenforceable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following contracts must be in writing to be enforceable?",hint:"An agreement to answer for the debt of another must be in writing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A lease for one year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A listing to lease for one year",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An agreement by a buyer to assume an existing loan secured by a deed of trust",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"An agreement between brokers to share a commission",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who may sell new mobile homes?",hint:"",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Any real estate licensee",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Only a real estate broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Only the owner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Specially licensed mobile home dealers",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A notary public may legally notarize a document if it is:",hint:"Cannot notarize any instrument in which he has a personal interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a grant deed in which he is grantee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mortgage in which he is mortgagee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a document being executed by a corporation of which he is an employee but he has no personal interest in the transaction.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"an instrument in which he is a party.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following state agencies has the power to investigate and take legal action to prevent acts of discrimination in housing accommodations in California because of race, color, religion, national origin, or ancestry?",hint:"The Department of Fair Employment and Housing investigates housing discrimination complaints in California.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real Estate Commission",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Labor Commission",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Department of Fair Employment and Housing",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Division of Housing",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is true?",hint:"Recording does not make a deed valid, but creates the legal presumption that it has been delivered.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Recording a deed presumes delivery",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Recording makes a deed valid",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Delivery is not controlled by the intention of the grantor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A grantor need not have legal capacity",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would identify a rider?",hint:"A rider is an addition or an amendment to an existing document.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"People",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Amendment",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Encroachment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Donee",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An 18-year-old wife bought property with her separate funds and instructed escrow to vest title in her 17-year- old husband and herself as community property. The purchase contract was:",hint:"If the purchaser has legal capacity the sale is valid. In whom the title is vested does not affect the legality of the sale. The title could vest in a 3-year-old child.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"unenforceable.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"After obtaining a listing from a corporation, all the officers were killed in an accident. The listing is:",hint:"Death of the officers does not affect the listing contract made with the corporation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"valid.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voidable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"invalid.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A supplementary tax bill indicates:",hint:"Upon a change in ownership of real property, unless the change is between spouses, a new assessment is made based on 1% of the new purchase price. A supplementary tax bill will be sent to the new owner, reflecting the change in taxes as of the date of transfer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"change in taxes as of the date of transfer of ownership of real property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"no change in ownership.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tax-deferred exchange.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"new partnership.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following will a standard policy of title insurance insure against?",hint:"A standard policy covers Recorded matters, Forgery and Capacity, but never any unrecorded matters.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Forgery",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Unrecorded restrictions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Unrecorded easements",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Unrecorded liens",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The opposite of alienate is:",hint:"Alienate--transfer; acquisition--receive.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"convey.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"quitclaim.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"transfer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"acquisition.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What kind of notice does recording give?",hint:"The only way to give actual notice is to notify each person individually.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Actual",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Constructive",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both (a) and (b) are correct",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Neither (a) nor (b) is correct",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Redwine passed away intestate. His property can only be sold by the administrator of the estate:",hint:"According to the laws of Probate Court proceedings, the court must approve of the purchase price and terms of sale before the sale can be completed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"to the person who bids the most at an auction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"after the court has approved the terms of sale and the price.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"with a 20% minimum down payment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under California law, title to real property can be transferred in all of the following ways, except:",hint:"Real property may be acquired or conveyed in the following ways: will, succession, accession, occupancy, and transfer of deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"by deed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"by accession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"by sufferance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"by succession.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A standard policy of title insurance does not insure against:",hint:"A title insurance policy generally consists of three sections, one of which is a list of conditions of and exclusion to coverage. One such uninsured exclusion may be “zoning and governmental restrictions.”",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"forgery in the chain of recorded title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"limitation imposed by government regulation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a transfer of title by incompetent parties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"recorded liens.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Is a separate contract, in addition to the grant deed, required for the sale of stock in a mutual water company?",hint:"Stock in a mutual water company is an appurtenance (real property). It runs with the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Yes, stock is always personal property and must be transferred with a bill of sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No, stock in a mutual water company can not be sold",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Yes, because stock in a mutual water company is chattel real",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No, water company stock runs with the land",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"According to the Subdivided Lands Law, what must the developer (seller) give a buyer before selling a lot in the subdivision?",hint:"Before a subdivider can sell each lot in the project (subdivision), he or she must give a copy of the Commissioner's final (public) report to the prospective buyer for approval.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Grant deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Preliminary public report",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Final public report",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"EIR",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a property is bought from the state at a tax sale as a result of unpaid property taxes, what kind of deed does the buyer receive?",hint:"Definition: A tax deed is the instrument used to convey legal title to property sold by a government unit for nonpayment of taxes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Grant deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Tax deed",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Assessor's deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Quitclaim deed",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A grant deed that allows someone to retain property so long as alcohol is not consumed on the property is:",hint:'A fee simple defeasible has a clause in the deed (such as "no alcohol" on property), which if violated causes the property to revert back to the grantor.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"fee simple absolute.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"estate in forfeiture.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fee simple defeasible.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"less than a freehold estate.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A transfer of possession of real property, but not ownership is called a:",hint:"A sublease transfers possession, but not ownership of real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"mortgage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sublease.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"security agreement.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"easement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who is responsible for assuring completion of paved streets, utilities, and curbs, in a new subdivision?",hint:"The developer usually has the responsibility for completing the streets, utilities and curbs in a new subdivision.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The developer",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The city",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The county",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The federal government",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The primary purpose of a master plan is to show the location of:",hint:"The master plan usually shows all of these things and more.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"commercial, industrial, and residential districts.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"public streets.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"seismic safety zones.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What is the general purpose of a building code?",hint:"The general purpose of a building code is to provide minimum construction standards.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"assure utilization of skilled labor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"assure compliance with regulatory agencies",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"provide minimum construction requirements",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"guarantee cost effectiveness",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Public services such as roads, sewers, parks, schools, and fire stations in new developments may be financed under which law?",hint:"The Mello-Roos Community Facilities Act of 1982 authorizes the formation of community facilities districts, the issuance of bonds and the levying of special taxes which will finance designated public facilities and services.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Street Improvement Act of 1911",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Mello-Roos Community Facilities Act",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Proposition 13",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Proposition 60",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The right of the state to regulate for the purpose of promoting health, safety, welfare and morality is?",hint:"Police power is the power of the state to enact laws within constitutional limits to promote the order, safety, health, morals, and general welfare of society.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Police power",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Eminent domain",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Zoning",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Impacting",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A standard policy insures against:",hint:"The standard title policy insures against a recorded deed that was not properly delivered and/or accepted. The other choices are only covered by an extended title policy.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"encroachments.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"claims of persons in possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"prescriptive easements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"recorded deed that was not properly delivered and accepted.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Subdivisions located in sparsely populated areas of California, made up of 50 parcels or more:",hint:"Definition",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"residential zones.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"time shares.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"land projects.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"tracts.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Elaine is owner of a home which she has agreed to sell to David. A preliminary title report which was prepared during escrow, shows:",hint:"A preliminary title report will show the existing loan with Elaine as trustor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"exact same information as found in David's future standard title policy.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"information about a deed of trust with Elaine as trustor.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the new trust deed with David as trustor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"title vested in David.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ann acquires title as a single female. Ann subsequently marries. Ann then sells the property, signing her married name to the grant deed. This:",hint:"Assuming she changed her name upon marriage, the different name on the deed would create a cloud on title.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is immaterial.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"creates a cloud on the title.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"is automatically cured after 90 days.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"has no impact, because this was her separate property.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Who signs a quitclaim deed?",hint:"Anyone who signs a deed can be called a grantor.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The property owner",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The occupant",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The grantor",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The item that would appear as a debit side on the buyer's closing statement is:",hint:"The purchase price is a debit on the buyers closing statement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the purchase price.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"prepaid rents.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"prepaid property taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following items are normally prorated at the close of escrow, except:",hint:"Interest on unsecured loans will not be prorated at close of escrow.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"homeowner's insurance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"property taxes and assessments.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"delinquent interest on unsecured loans.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"interest and impounds.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"During escrow, the escrow officer received two structural pest control reports. The escrow officer should:",hint:"The escrow officer must let the buyer and seller decide which termite report to use.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"contact the inspection company to ask which report is best.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"notify the buyer and sell and obtain written instructions as which report to use.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"use the report which found the most infestation and damage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"use the report which found the least infestation and damage.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are essential to create a valid contract, except:",hint:'Most contracts do not require "writing".',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"lawful object.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"writing.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"mutual consent.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"consideration.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"During the escrow process, if an unresolved dispute should arise between the seller and the buyer preventing the close of escrow, the escrow holder may legally:",hint:"An interpleader action is a legal proceeding whereby an innocent third party (stakeholder - such as an escrow agent or broker) can deposit with the court the property or money that he or she holds, and which is subject to adverse claims such as when the buyer and seller are in dispute over the purchase contract.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"arbitrate the dispute as a neutral party.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"rescind the escrow and return all documents and monies to the respective parties.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"file an interpleader action in court.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An interest in real property may be acquired by either prescription or by adverse possession. The interest resulting from prescription is:",hint:"Prescription (easement by prescription) only conveys the right to use another's land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the right to use another's land.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a possessory title.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an equitable interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a private grant.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Subdivision Map Act is concerned with:",hint:"Definition: The Subdivision Map Act is enforced by city or county authorities and is concerned with the physical aspects of a subdivision.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"financing aspects of a subdivision.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"title aspects of a subdivision.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fair housing aspects of a subdivision.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"physical aspects of a subdivision.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Many legal authorities state that a contract for the sale of land, in addition to the four essential elements of a contract, should have five additional specific items. These are a written agreement or memorandum or note, names and signatures of all parties, the designated purchase price, sufficient description, of the land, and time and manner of payment. Which of the five may be substantiated by oral evidence?",hint:"You could substantiate the description of property by oral evidence, i.e. by agreeing that the street address is sufficient description.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Designated purchase price",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Names and signatures of all parties",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Sufficient description of the land",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Time and manner of payment",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Even when fully executed and performed, this contract is unenforceable. It is a(n):",hint:"The broker must disclose the amount of his or her compensation on a net listing prior to or at the time the principal binds the broker to the agreement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"net listing where the broker did not disclose the amount of compensation to the principal.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"oral listing for the sale of a business opportunity.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"oral listing for the lease of a home for one year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"signed open listing that did not contain definite termination date.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the many requirements of an option agreement, it must specifically state:",hint:"The option must state that the offer remains open for a certain period of time. In effect, when the buyer pays consideration to the seller for the option, the buyer is purchasing an agreed amount of time in which to accept or reject the offer to purchase the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"that the offer will remain open for a specific time period.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"that the agreement is irrevocable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"that the optionor can keep the price paid for the option if the optionee fails to purchase.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the time for the optionee to purchase.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Fraud would be found if:",hint:"All of the above.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the buyer purchases property based on deceit by the seller, and the buyer loses a large sum of money.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an intentional misrepresentation by the seller induces the buyer to purchase.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"material facts are incorrectly stated causing the buyer serious financial loss.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What is the primary tool used by a planning commission?",hint:"A planning commission is an official agency usually organized on the city, county, or regional level to develop a master (General) plan which is the basis of and sets all community development decisions (land use proposals). The land use proposals outlined in a General Plan are implemented in many ways - zoning being the best known and most frequently used tool.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Eminent domain",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Adverse possession",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Zoning",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"General plan",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Rebecca bought a home that did not meet existing building codes, but was allowed to use it as a non-conforming building under what clause of the building code?",hint:"If a building or part of a building was built before the building code existed, it may remain as is, or grandfathered, until any material change takes place. At that time it must be brought up to code.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Grandfather clause",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Due on sale clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Subrogation clause",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"After-use clause",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Franchisor Adams has a net worth of $5 million with 25 franchisees operating for the last 7 years in California. Adams wants to sell 8 more franchises. In order to do so, she must register:",hint:"A franchisor, with a net worth of $5 million who has had 25 franchises operating continuously for 5 years preceding the offer or sale is exempt from registration with the California Department of Corporations.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"as a securities dealer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"with no one.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"with the Commissioner of Corporations.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"with the Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"David plans to build an improvement that is regulated by the State Housing Act and the local building codes. David must abide by:",hint:"The State Housing Law outlines the minimum construction and occupancy requirements for dwellings. In 1970, the California Legislature made the Uniform Housing Code, Uniform Building Code, Uniform Plumbing Code, Uniform Mechanical Code, and National Electric Code the applicable building codes for the entire state.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"only local regulations.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the contractor's license law.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the State Housing Law that prevails over local ordinances.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the more stringent of the laws.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A California land project refers to a:",hint:"Definition: Subdivisions located in sparsely populated areas (fewer than 1,500 registered voters within the subdivision or within two miles of its boundaries), made up of 50 parcels or more, are known as land projects.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"subdivision containing 50 or more unimproved lots located in a remote area, to be used for residential or recreational purposes.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"community apartment project.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"stock cooperative.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"planned unit development.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The law that requires all real property transactions to be closed through escrow is:",hint:"Using the escrow process to close real estate transactions is not a legal requirement (with some exceptions), but rather a well-established practice.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"California law.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"federal law.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both (a) and (b)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neither (a) nor (b)",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is correct concerning an ALTA extended coverage policy of title insurance?",hint:"An ALTA policy applies to owners or lenders not to lessees. A survey of the property is done at the time the policy is issued, but it does not protect against subsequent encroachments. Answer (b) is the only one that is correct.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It protects a lessee who occupies the property after the date shown on the title insurance policy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is limited to stated conditions of title as of the date of the issuance of the title policy",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It protects against any encroachment that occurs after the date of issuance of the title policy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It protects against any easements created during the term of the title insurance policy",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Hoover obtains permission from governmental authorities to build a structure and create a use that is currently prohibited by zoning laws. This is known as:",hint:"A variance is permission obtained from governmental zoning authorities to build a structure or conduct a use that is expressly prohibited by the current zoning laws; it is an exception from the zoning laws.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"nonconforming use.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"spot zoning or a variance.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"revitalization.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"redlining.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a buyer of the bulk of inventory of a business fails to file a note of intention to sell, the:",hint:"Any bulk sale that takes place without complying with the requirements of the bulk transfer law are considered valid between the buyer and seller, but fraudulent and void against creditors. The creditors have recourse against the debtor (the seller) because he or she sold the security for the debt without notifying the creditors.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"inventory could be attached by the seller's creditors.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"sale is still valid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sale is void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sale is illegal.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following statements concerning an option are correct except:",hint:"The question asks for the exception. The optionee does not have the legal right to use the property covered by the option until the option to purchase is exercised and the sale occurs.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"unless prohibited in the contract, the option is assignable.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the optionee has the first right to purchase the property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the optionee has the legal right to enter and use the property right after the option has been entered into.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"performance of the terms found in the lease option is sufficient consideration for the option agreement.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Buyer Smith agrees to pay $25,000 down for the purchase of seller Jones's home. Smith also agrees to assume the existing note and first trust deed of $120,000. The assumed loan on Jones' closing statement would appear as a:",hint:"The question asks about the SELLER'S closing statement. A loan assumption is a debit to a seller (deducted from sale proceeds).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"debit to Smith.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"debit to Jones.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"credit to Smith.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"credit to Jones.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A bilateral contract is one that is a(n):",hint:"A bilateral (two-sided) agreement contains a promise for a promise. For example, an exclusive authorization and right to sell listing (a bilateral agreement) contains the owner's promise to pay a commission if the property sells during the listing period. In exchange for this promise, the broker promises to use due diligence in procuring a buyer for the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"promise for performance.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"promise for an act.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"act for a promise.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"promise for a promise.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A grantee's name must appear in the grant deed as one of the deed's many essential elements. A deed would be construed as void from the beginning if the grantee is:",hint:'The term, "fictitious person" implies that no such person exists. A deed to such a person would be void. Do not confuse this term with "fictitious or assumed name," which could be a business name. A deed to a fictitious or assumed NAME would be valid.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an unincorporated association.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a fictitious person.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"not named in the deed, but adequately described or designated.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"described under an assumed name.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property was bought by Charlie and Liz. After the close of escrow, they discovered they were responsible for:",hint:"When property is sold, new taxes are assessed at 1.25% to 1.50% of the new purchase price. If the escrow closes during the time for which the seller has already paid the taxes, the new owner will receive a supplemental tax bill.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an increase in property taxes as a result of the sale, as well as the supplemental tax bill.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"no increase in taxes, but a supplemental tax bill for the following year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the former owner's back taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"paying two year's taxes in advance.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A licensee who arranges a transfer of an existing trust deed must ensure recording in how many working days?",hint:"This is per Business and Professions Code Section 10234.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10 days",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"30 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"No law applies",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"During an open escrow, when must the termite report be delivered?",hint:"A termite report needs to be delivered to escrow at least five days before the closing of escrow.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Before close of escrow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"After close of escrow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Three days after inspection is done",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"At least five days before closing of escrow",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Closing statements must contain all of the following information except:",hint:"Closing statements are not required to show clear evidence of title",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an itemized list of all adjustments, money, or things of value received or paid and which party was credited or debited for each item",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"clear evidence of title",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the total purchase price of the property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the date of closing",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An escrow agent who wishes to close a real estate transaction for a fee must hold which of the following?",hint:"An escrow agent must hold a certificate of registration in order to close a real estate transaction for a fee.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A certificate of registration",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"A real estate license",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A broker's license",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"An escrow license",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The transfer tax is paid at the rate of:",hint:"The transfer tax is paid at the rate of $0.10 per $100.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$0.10 per $100.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$0.50 per $100",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1.00 per $500.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1.00 per $1,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following will most likely not appear as a debit on the seller's closing statement?",hint:"The transfer of a loan escrow account will appear as a credit on the seller's closing statement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Removal of an existing mechanic's lien",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Proration for unpaid taxes",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Transfer of a loan escrow account",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Pay-off of the existing loan",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"On what is the intangible tax calculated?",hint:"The intangible tax is calculated on the new loan amount.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The new loan amount",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The total amount of the seller's equity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The total sales price",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The sales price less an assumption",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A house recently sold for $430,000 in cash. How much will the transfer tax cost?",hint:"The transfer tax will cost $430 because $430,000 / 100 x 0.10 = 430.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$403",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$423",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$430",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$463",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How much is Georgia's conveyance tax?",hint:"The conveyance tax in Georgia is $0.10 per $100 of the sales price.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$0.10 per $100 of the new loan amount",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$0.10 per $500 of the sales price",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$0.50 per $1,000 of the new loan amount",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$0.10 per $100 of the sales price",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Properties in Georgia are assessed for tax purposes at:",hint:"Properties in Georgia are assessed for tax purposes at 40% of market value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"25% of market value",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"40% of market value",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"45% of market value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at fair market value.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a closing takes place on October 8th, the purchaser's charge for prepaid interest on a new loan will be for:",hint:"The buyer owes 23 days of interest to cover the rest of October.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"17 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"21 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"23 days.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Deeds of conveyance must be recorded within _______ after closing.",hint:"Deeds of conveyance must be recorded within a reasonable amount of time after closing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"one business day",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"three business days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"seven business days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a reasonable amount of time",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is responsible for calculating the prorations between the buyer and seller, searching the title, and preparing the mortgage note and deed prior to closing?",hint:"The closing attorney is responsible for all of these activities.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Lender",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Salesperson",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Closing attorney",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When preparing for a closing, a broker or salesperson may do which of the following?",hint:"A broker or salesperson may legally do all of the above. He or she may not, however, conduct any title searches.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Coordinate inspections and deliver documents and escrow monies to the appropriate attorney",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Maintain a time schedule and provide net data",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Explain closing procedures to both buyer and seller and anticipate decision-making alternatives",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Who is responsible for preparing any promissory notes that are involved in a closing?",hint:"The closing attorney as a representative of the lender is responsible for preparing any promissory notes that are involved in a closing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The seller's broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The buyer or buyer's broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The closing attorney as a representative of the lender",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"The Georgia Department of Finance",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following types of title evidence will most likely be presented to a buyer at closing?",hint:"In Georgia, a title insurance policy will most likely be presented to a buyer at closing as evidence of title.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Torrens certificate of title",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Title insurance policy",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Certificate issued by a licensed title company",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Abstract of title that has been examined by an attorney",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a purchaser is buying a home for all cash, all of the following closing costs would be reduced except the:",hint:"The amount of the transfer tax would not be affected by an all-cash transaction.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"transfer tax.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"intangible tax.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"closing attorney's fees.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"discount points.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a binding purchase contract states that closing will take place on April 1, which of the following is correct?",hint:"The transaction must close on April 1 unless more time is needed for loan funding or settling a title problem, in which case either party must notify the other in writing and may extend the closing for seven days.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The transaction must close within ten days of April 1.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The transaction must close within the month of April or the contract becomes void.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The transaction must close on April 1 unless more time is needed and the party notifies the other in writing.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above is correct.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The earnest money that is left on deposit with the broker is a:",hint:"The earnest money that is left on deposit with the broker is a credit to the buyer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"debit to the buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"balancing factor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"credit to the buyer.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"credit to the seller.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How should security deposits be listed on the closing statement?",hint:"A security deposit should be listed as a credit to the buyer on the closing statement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"As a credit to the seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"As a credit to the buyer",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"As a credit to the broker",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"As a debit to the buyer",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The listing broker's commission is shown as a __________ on the closing statement.",hint:"The listing broker's commission is shown as a debit to the seller on the closing statement.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"debit to the seller",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"debit to the buyer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"credit to the seller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"credit to the buyer",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In order to be recorded in Nevada, deeds, liens on property, and other documents must include:",hint:"Deeds, liens on property, and other documents must include all of the above information in order to be eligible for recording.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"mailing address of the grantee or person requesting the recording.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the name and address of the person to whom the taxes are to be mailed (if a deed).",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the assessor's parcel number",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is true of Nevada's Electronic Transactions Act?",hint:"Nevada's Electronic Transactions Act allows the use of electronic recording of documents.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"It allows the use of electronic recording of documents.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It prohibits the use of electronic recording of documents.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It does not apply to real estate transaction documents.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"There is no Electronic Transactions Act.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Closing is referred to as many different terms in different areas of the country. Which of the following is an alternate term used in Nevada?",hint:"Closing is referred to closing escrow or close of escrow in Nevada.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Closing title",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Closing escrow",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Transfer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Settlement",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Once the contract is signed during a closing, the broker:",hint:"Once the contract is signed during a closing, the broker turns over the earnest money to the escrow agent, who deposits it in a special trust, or escrow, account.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is no longer involved and may collect his or her commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"delivers the title to the buyer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"turns over the earnest money to the escrow agent.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"must turn over all disclosure documents to the buyer.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following may be performed by a broker at closing?",hint:"A broker may arrange for title evidence, surveys, appraisals, inspections, or repairs for structural conditions, water supplies, sewage facilities, or toxic substances.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Arranging for title evidence",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Drawing up the title report",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Examining the title evidence",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is true of closings?",hint:"Salespeople may attend the closing of their transaction, a licensee may never give legal advice to their client or anyone else, and a closing of escrow may take place at a number of locations, including the office of the title company, the lending institution, one of the parties' attorneys, the broker, the county recorder, or the escrow company.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Salespeople may not attend - only brokers.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A licensee may give legal advice, but only to his or her client.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"They must take place at the office of the title company.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above is true.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When does legal title always pass from seller to buyer?",hint:"Legal title always passes from seller to buyer when the deed is delivered and accepted.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"When the deed is delivered and accepted",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"When the deed is placed in escrow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When the contracts are signed and recorded",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"When the escrow agent signs the closing statement and transfers the funds",isCorrect:!1}]}}]},{category:"Taxes",id:7,list:[{questionText:"A homeowner's exemption is:",hint:"A property owner may claim a Homeowner's Exemption in California on a residence that is both owned and occupied at 12:01 am on January 1. The exemption reduces the assessed value of the residence by $7,000 and reduces the tax bill by at least $70.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$7,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$7,500.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,500.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Daniels was preparing her federal income tax return. Provided she lives on the premises, she is allowed a deduction for all of the following except:",hint:"Maintenance expenses on an owner-occupied residence cannot be deducted.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"real estate taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interest on her home loan.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"painting of a bedroom.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"uninsured garage door valued at $200 which was stolen.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man sold real property at a profit. For which of the following classes of property would he pay the most federal income tax on the gain?",hint:"The seller of property held for sale to customers is considered to be a dealer and is taxed at ordinary rates. The seller of properties listed in choices (a), (c), and (d) would be entitled to capital gains benefits.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Investment property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Property held for sale to customers",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Property used for the production of income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Property used in his business",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The main duty of the county assessor is to determine:",hint:"The assessor appraises the property to establish the basis on which the tax is to be paid. The amount of tax is set by the county Board of Supervisors.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the amount of tax to be paid by a property owner.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the proportion of tax to be paid by a property owner.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the tax rate to be applied to the assessed value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"how taxes can be reduced.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The commission paid to a real estate licensee for the sale of a home can be deducted on the seller's federal income taxes as a(n):",hint:'The standard deduction is the 10% allowance granted to individuals who do not use the "long form" and itemize their charitable contributions, taxes, interest, etc. The commission paid for the sale of the home is deducted from the actual sale price as an expense of the sale to arrive at the gain or loss from the sale.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"standard deduction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"expense of sale.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"long term capital gain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"casualty loss.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"With certain exceptions, a property tax lien has priority over other interests in real property:",hint:"With certain exceptions, taxes are first in priority.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"according to date the lien was recorded.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"regardless of when recorded.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"based upon when the tax law was passed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"only if the property owner agrees to assume the obligation.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The due date for the second installment of real property taxes is:",hint:"Second installment is due February 1, and delinquent if not paid on or before April 10.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"December 10.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"February 1.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"March 1.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"April 10.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The second installment of property taxes becomes delinquent if not paid on or before:",hint:"Second installment is delinquent if not paid on or before April 10. It is due February 1.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"December 10.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"April 10.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"March l.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"February 1.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An individual purchased an older apartment house as an investment. Since this was his first venture in real property investments, he is uncertain as to the depreciation schedule. If the former owners had been deducting depreciation, the new owner, for income tax purposes:",hint:"As the purchaser of investment property, the new owner may establish his own economic life and schedule his depreciation on this life.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"must use the same depreciation schedule.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may use the sum-of-digits method.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"can ignore the depreciation schedule of the former owner and establish his own.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"can only depreciate the improvements based on the former owner's remaining life.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An owner of a 20-unit apartment house decides to have a $4,000 swimming pool installed for the benefit and convenience of his tenants. If he completes the installation he can handle the expense for income tax purposes by:",hint:"This expense would be considered a capital improvement and the expense must be depreciated over the life of the pool. It is not depreciated with the land, since the land is not depreciated.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"deducting the full cost as an operating expense in the year it was installed.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"adding it to his cost basis as a capital improvement.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"depreciating the improvement along with the land.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deducting it as an expense and cannot depreciate it over the life of the pool since it does not add to the life of the apartment.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Street Improvement Act of 1911 allows how long to pay for an assessment before it goes to bond?",hint:"30 days, not 1 month.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30 days",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1 month",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"60 days",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Tax consciousness should begin:",hint:"People considering the purchase of real property must examine the tax benefits and burdens of their purchase. Many times, the tax implications will seriously affect a sale and cause a buyer or seller to realize that - because of the taxes - full value of ownership may not be possible.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"before depreciation schedule is set by accountant.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"before acquisition of the property.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"after acquisition of the property and before the tax year ends.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"after acquisition of the property and after the tax year ends and before the new tax year begins.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Mr. Gurley is delinquent on his 1991-1992 real property taxes. The "sale to the state" took place on his property at the time prescribed by the law. Mr. Gurley took steps in 1995 to pay his delinquent taxes. What is the proper procedure for Mr. Gurley to redeem his property?',hint:"While the property is in a tax-defaulted status, the owner does not actually lose title and keeps possession for five years. If the taxes are not paid within that five-year redemption period a tax sale takes place, and the property may be sold at public auction to the highest bidder for cash.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Mr. Gurley should make his payment, then receive and record a comptroller's receipt, because the redemption period still applies",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Make his payment and receive a tax deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Record a full tax payment and reconveyance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Make his payment and record a tax clearance receipt",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The number of times a given item will sell in a given period of time is known as:",hint:"Definition: Turnover is the frequency with which real property in a given area is sold and resold.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"turnover.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"goods sold.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"inventory decrease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"On which date all over the State of California is all real property encumbered with a lien?",hint:"On January 1st of every year, taxes become a lien on real property in the state.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"April 15",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"April 30",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"January 1",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"March 15",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"For street improvements, lots are assessed according to:",hint:"According to county regulations, assessments for street improvements are based upon the front foot dimensions of the lot.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"front foot.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"square footage.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"market value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"performance.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Street Improvement Act gives a property owner _______ to pay the special assessment tax before it goes to bond.",hint:"He may pay all, part or none of it.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"30 days",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"45 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one month",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"60 days",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Cho purchased a brand new piece of income property for $190,000. The listed price was $220,000. Mr. Cho considered this a good deal on his part, since he only put $10,000 down and acquired a new first trust deed for the difference. The tax assessed value was indicated at $150,000. Mr. Cho's cost basis for income tax purposes would be:",hint:"Cost basis for income tax purposes (book value) is the price paid for the property, not the actual values in this case, $190,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$180,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$150,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$190,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'For the purpose of computing federal income tax, the "cost basis" may be used to determine:',hint:"The cost basis is synonymous with book value and is used to determine depreciation for income tax purposes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"depreciation.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"interest.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"economic life.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"capital assets.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following properties could not be depreciated on a federal income tax return?",hint:"You can only depreciate income or investment property, not your residence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"An apartment house",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A home rented to a welfare recipient whose rent is paid by the county",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A duplex",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A single family residence in which one resides",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The last day on which a veteran may file for his real property tax exemption is:",hint:"A property owner may claim a Homeowner's Exemption in California on a residence that is both owned and occupied at 12:01 am on January 1 and it is the property owner's responsibility to apply for the exemption and file a claim between January 1 and February 15.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"January 15.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"February 15.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"April 15.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"June 15.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An escrow may be terminated by all of the following except:",hint:"The agent is not a party to the escrow and has no right to terminate it.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"running of time limit allowed for escrow.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"full performance and closing.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"instruction by the selling real estate agent.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"mutual consent of parties.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"You would have to pay sales tax on which of the following?",hint:"Personal property only. Prescription medicines are exempt.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Personal property",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Real property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Prescription medicines",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The county tax rate is set by:",hint:"The County Board of Supervisors determines the tax rate (limited to 1% of fair market value) plus any county bond debt or other assessments.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"County Treasurer.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Board of Supervisors.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"County Tax Assessor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Planning Commission.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is not an allowable expense in computing net income for income tax purposes?",hint:"When reporting income for tax reasons you would not estimate vacancies as you do in appraising property. You must report actual vacancies.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Interest on the loan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Reserves for depreciation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Vacancy factor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Social security taxes paid for a manager",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"All of the following statements concerning real property taxes are correct except:",hint:"Some property is assessed by the State Board of Equalization (e.g., utility companies). Answers (b), (c), and (d) are all statements of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the local tax assessor appraises all real property in the county for the purpose of setting the assessed value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the lien date for real property taxes is January 1st.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"there is a separate assessment made of land and improvements, but one tax bill is issued covering both values.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the second half of real property taxes becomes delinquent if not paid on or before April 10th of the tax year.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would affect the owner's ordinary income tax liability of an owner-occupied residence?",hint:"The other answers would have no affect on the owner's ordinary income tax liability.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Depreciation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Repairs to a leaking roof",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Uninsured loss resulting from collapse of a fence caused by high winds",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Replacing a water heater",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Sales and use taxes are levied on the sale of tangible personal property by the State of California. Concerning these taxes:",hint:"The Sales and Use Tax Law protects a buyer from liability for unpaid sales tax.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"prescription drugs are exempt from sales tax.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"property exempt from sales tax is also exempt for use tax.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the amount of use tax must be separately listed on any sales document.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above are correct statements",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A person may take depreciation on all of the following for income tax purposes, with the exception of:",hint:"No depreciation on land nor owner-occupied residence.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an apartment building.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a home rented to a friend.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a vacant duplex.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"land held for future income.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which item is not allowed as a deduction on one's federal income tax return?",hint:"Taxes, interest, and uninsured loss are deductible items, but not maintenance on a residential property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Taxes on owner-occupied home",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Cost of painting bedroom",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Interest payment on second mortgage on owner-occupied home",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Loss on theft of uninsured garage door",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Prepaid rent on a 5-year lease is taxable as income:",hint:"Reported as income in the year in which it is collected.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"in the year collected.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"in the year for which it is paid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a business is sold, sales tax must be paid on which of the following items?",hint:"When a business is sold, sales tax is paid on the value of the furniture and fixtures.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The stock-in-trade which is included in the sale",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The furniture and fixtures of the business",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:'The price which is paid for "goodwill"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The state sales tax is:",hint:"There is a sales tax on personal property. An ad valorem tax is a real property tax.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an ad valorem tax.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a tax on real and personal property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a tax on prescription medicines.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a tax on tangible personal property.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following may a homeowner deduct on his federal income tax return?",hint:"The other three are not allowable deductions on a residence. Interest is deductible.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Depreciation on house",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Interest on loan",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Premium on fire insurance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Maintenance and roof repair",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Capital loss may not be taken on:",hint:"You cannot take a capital loss on residential property. You can take it on income property and land held for investment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"income producing property.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"land held for investment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"owner occupied residence.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What date does the first installment of taxes become delinquent?",hint:"First installment: Due on November 1st, delinquent on December 10th.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"November 10th",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"December 10th",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"February 1st",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"April 10th",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When do real property taxes become a lien?",hint:"January 1st, preceding the tax year.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"First Monday in March",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"First week in April",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"First day of January",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"First day of November",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If you are the owner of a business, you are required to remit your sales tax:",hint:"A retailer must collect the proper sales tax from customers and pay it to the State Board of Equalization, usually quarterly.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"monthly.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"quarterly.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"when demanded by State Board of Equalization.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"every four months.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you own an apartment house. You have a swimming pool installed on the property at a cost of $19,200. For federal income tax purposes how would this be handled?",hint:"Any improvements added by the property owner on income property would increase the cost basis of the property and would have to be adjusted accordingly for federal income tax purposes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Write it off as an expense item",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Would make an increase in your adjusted cost basis",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Is not considered at all in the federal income tax program",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Is considered a tax shelter",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If you are selling a business opportunity property, which of the following is subject to California state sales tax?",hint:"Good will and inventory stock in trade are not subject to sales tax. Fixtures, however, are subject to taxation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Fixtures",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Good will",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Inventory stock in trade",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following was never a method of calculating accelerated depreciation?",hint:"Answers (b), (c), and (d) were accelerated methods that were allowed prior years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Straight line",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Sum-of-the-digits",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"150% of the declining balance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"200% of the declining balance",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Under the Street Improvement Act of 1911, what length of time do you have to pay the assessment lien against your property before the lien goes to bond?",hint:"30 days, not 1 month.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"90 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"45 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30 days",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"15 days",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"On a seller's federal income tax return, the seller's payment of a $3,000 commission to a real estate broker was being treated as:",hint:"Statement of fact.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"capital gain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"standard deduction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"expense of sale.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"ordinary income.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The words "tax shelter" refer to:',hint:"A tax shelter is defined as a portion of the net income which is not subject to taxation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"personal tax advantages.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"income tax.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"tax deferment.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The tax that the State of California charges on the sale of a business opportunity which includes fixtures and equipment is called:",hint:"A sales tax is collected as a percentage of the retail sales of a product, by a retailer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a sales tax.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a resale tax.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an excise tax.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a state tax.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The County Tax Assessor's function as it relates to real property taxation is to:",hint:"The County Tax Assessor sets a standard so that each property owner pays his proper proportion of the taxes which are set by the Board of Supervisors.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"set the proportional assessment the property owner will pay on.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"set the tax rate.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lower the taxes if necessary.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"collect sales tax.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An owner of an industrial piece of property that conducts his own business on said property, sold the real estate to another company, and entered into a lease arrangement with the new owner. His greatest advantage was:",hint:"A state examination opinion answer. Of the answers given, we agree with their opinion.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"this would free him from the responsibility of increased taxation in the future.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"this would give him more working capital to run his business.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"more equity as a lessee.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the rentals are deductible items on his income tax return.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"County taxes must be recorded to become a lien and a tax lien takes precedence over other private recorded liens.",hint:"Since taxes need not be recorded to become a lien, the first statement is false. Since a tax lien has priority over any other private recorded lien, whether recorded before or after a tax lien, the second statement is true.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Both statements are true",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The first statement is true and the second statement is false",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The first statement is false and the second statement is true",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Both statements are false",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The real property tax rate is set by the:",hint:"The County Board of Supervisors determines the tax rate (limited to 1% of fair market value) plus any county bond debt or other assessments.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"County Board of Supervisors.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"State Tax Assessor.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Board of Equalization.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"city council.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which instrument requires a listing or inventory of buildings on real property that are to be sold, conveyed, or insured?",hint:"Neither a land contract, grant deed, nor standard coverage policy form of title insurance require a listing of the buildings or improvements. Usually a legal description is all that is required.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"A land contract",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A grant deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A.L.T.A.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A man bought a home in August 1991 for $121,000 and sold it in September 1992 for $125,000. He invested the entire sales price in a 26-unit apartment. The profit he made on the sale would be classified as:",hint:"Individuals are generally permitted to exclude from taxable income up to $250,000 ($500,000 for married couples) of gain on the sale of their principal residence. Since the owner occupied the residence for less than 2 years before selling it, his profit would be classified as a capital gain.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"boot.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"capital gains.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"deferred tax on capital gain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. and Mrs. Cool purchased a home in January 1991 for $117,000. They sold the home in August 1992 for $150,000 and moved into a furnished apartment and do not plan to own a home again. Under the Internal Revenue Code, the gain realized on the sale will:",hint:"Individuals are generally permitted to exclude from taxable income up to $250,000 ($500,000 for married couples) of gain on the sale of their principal residence. Since the owners occupied the residence for less than 2 years before selling it, their profit would be classified as a capital gain.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"be a deferred gain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be a capital gain.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"be a boot.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not be taxed at all.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The commission paid to a real estate licensee for the sale of a home can be deducted on the seller's federal income tax as:",hint:'The standard deduction is the 10% allowance granted to individuals who do not use the "long form" and itemize their charitable contributions, taxes, interest, etc. The commission paid for the sale of the home is deducted from the actual sale price as an expense of the sale to arrive at the gain or loss from the sale.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"a standard deduction.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an expense of sale.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a long term capital gain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a casualty loss.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An individual purchased an older apartment house as an investment. Since this was his first venture in real property investments, he is uncertain as to the depreciation schedule. If the former owners had been deducting depreciation, the new owner, for income tax purposes:",hint:"As the purchaser of investment property, the new owner may establish his own economic life and schedule his depreciation on this life. The sum-of-the-digits method is allowed on new property only.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"must use the same depreciation schedule.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may use the sum-of-digits method.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"can ignore the depreciation schedule of the former owner and establish his own.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"can only depreciate the improvements based on the former owner's remaining life.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property was bought by Charlie and Rose. After the close of escrow, they discovered they were responsible for:",hint:"Upon the sale of real property, the taxes will be changed to 1 to 1.5% of the new purchase price. If the escrow closes between the time the seller has paid the taxes and new taxes are assessed the buyer will receive a supplementary tax bill for the increase.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"an increase in property taxes as a result of the sale, as well as the supplemental tax bill.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"no increase in taxes, but a supplemental tax bill for the following year.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the former owner's back taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"paying two year's taxes in advance.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Concerning the second installment of property taxes, the due date and delinquent dates in California are:",hint:"The second installment of the property taxes is due February 1, and delinquent April 10.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"November 1 and December 10.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"February 1 and April 10.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"July 1 and June 30.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"January 1 and March 10.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The term "tax shelter" refers to:',hint:'The term "tax shelter" refers to a method of reducing your current income taxes.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"mortgage relief.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"real property taxes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interest income.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"income taxes.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Under federal income tax law, an individual may not deduct a loss on a sale of a home, unless:",hint:"The loss in the sale of residential income property may be deducted, subject to certain limitations.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"the loss is greater than 20%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the home is also used for business.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"it was her primary personal residence.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"bought as an investment and rented out.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"All of the following are used to determine the gain or loss on sale of real property for income tax purposes, except:",hint:"The owner's mortgage payment is not considered in the formula used to determine the gain or loss from the sale of real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"miscellaneous costs of sale.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"brokerage commission.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"purchase price.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"mortgage payment.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When commercial real estate is purchased today, the minimum period of time over which the owner can depreciate the improvements is:",hint:"Under current tax law, commercial real estate can be depreciated over a minimum of 39 years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"15 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"27 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"39 years.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Cheap, the owner of a duplex, leased one of the units for a two-year term beginning June 6, 1992, and received the rent for the last two months of the lease in advance. This prepaid rent should be:",hint:"Must be reported in the year received.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"declared in his income tax return for 1992.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"declared in his income tax return for 1994.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pro-rated over the term of the lease.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume you own an apartment house. You have a swimming pool installed on the property at a cost of $19,200. For federal income tax purposes how would this be handled?",hint:"Any improvements added by the property owner on income property would increase the cost basis of the property and would have to be adjusted accordingly for Federal Income Tax purposes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Write it off as an expense item",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It would make an increase in your adjusted cost basis",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It is not considered at all in the federal income tax program",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"It is considered a tax shelter",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is deductible each tax year for a personal residence?",hint:"Certain expenses are deductible annually to homeowners, such as interest and property taxes on first and second homes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"New driveway",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Depreciation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Property taxes",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Maintenance",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Mr. Furney is delinquent on his 1991-1992 real property taxes. The "sale to the state" took place on his property at the time prescribed by the law. Mr. Furney took steps in 1995 to pay his delinquent taxes. What is the proper procedure for Mr. Furney to redeem his property?',hint:"While the property is in a tax-defaulted status, the owner does not actually lose title and keeps possession for five years. If the taxes are not paid within that five-year redemption period a tax sale takes place, and the property may be sold at public auction to the highest bidder for cash.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:'Make his payment, then receive and record a "comptroller\'s receipt," because the redemption period still applies',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Make his payment and receive a tax deed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'Record a "full tax payment and reconveyance"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Make his payment and record a tax clearance receipt",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The Street Improvement Act gives a property owner _______ to pay the special assessment tax before it goes to bond.",hint:"He may pay all, part or none of it.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"30 days",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"45 days",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one month",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"60 days",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"With certain exceptions, property taxes that have become a lien take priority over all other interests in real property:",hint:"A mechanic's lien has priority over any other liens filed (or recorded) with the exception of government liens (unpaid property taxes or special assessments).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"if recorded first.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"regardless of when they are recorded.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"if no action has been taken on previously recorded liens.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Depreciation on real property is an allowable deduction for income tax purposes if the real property is:",hint:"The only items that are allowable for depreciation on income tax are those items that are man-made or generally speaking, improvements, on income property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"owner's personal residence.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"heavily encumbered.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"improved.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Prepaid rent on a 5 year lease is taxable as income:",hint:"Reported as income in the year in which it is collected.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"in the year collected.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"in the year for which it is paid.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In California, taxes on real property are collected on an ad valorem basis. The term ad valorem most nearly means:",hint:"Definition: Ad valorem is a Latin prefix meaning “according to value.”",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"replacement value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"according to value.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"fixed value.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"utility value.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Tax consciousness in relation to a real estate sale should be raised:",hint:"A buyer and seller should consider the tax implications prior to any contractual commitments.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"prior to the purchase.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"at close of escrow.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at time of possession.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at time of sale.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When a city taxes the gross receipts of a broker's office, it is called:",hint:"Not a sales nor property tax, but a business tax on gross receipts.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"use tax.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sales tax.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"property tax.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"business license tax.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"How many years does a taxpayer have to pay delinquent taxes before losing title to his or her property?",hint:"While the property is in a tax-defaulted status, the owner does not actually lose title and keeps possession for five years. If the taxes are not paid within that five-year period, a tax sale takes place, the property may be sold at public auction to the highest bidder for cash, and time the owner loses possession and the buyer receives a tax deed.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Two",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Three",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Four",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Five",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Concerning the second installment of property taxes, the due rate and delinquent dates in California are:",hint:"The second installment of the property taxes is due February 1, and delinquent April 10.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"November 1 and December 10.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"February 1 and April 10.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"July 1 and June 30.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"January 1 and March 10.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Another name for a tax-deferred exchange is:",hint:"The 1031 Exchange, sometimes called a “tax-free” exchange, is a method of deferring tax liability.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"installment tax exchange.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tax sale exchange.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"tax-free exchange.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"sale exchange.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following does not qualify for a tax-deferred exchange?",hint:"A personal residence would not qualify as a “like” property in an exchange with investment property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Commercial property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Personal residence",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Residential income property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Land",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following would receive the most favorable federal income taxation treatment?",hint:"“Like” property, real property used in a trade or business (an operating business), can be used to qualify as a “tax-free” exchange or a method of deferring tax liability.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Real property held for production of income",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real property held for sale to customers",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Investment property",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real property held for use in a trade or business",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"When commercial real estate is purchased today, the minimum period of time over which the owner can depreciate the improvements is:",hint:"Under current tax law, commercial real estate can be depreciated over a minimum of 39 years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"15 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"27 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30 years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"39 years.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The cost of capital improvements made to real property may be:",hint:"The cost of capital improvements may be added to the cost basis when the property is sold.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"deducted yearly.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"deducted every two years.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be added to the cost basis of the property when it is sold.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"is usually added to the selling price of the property when it is sold.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'The buyer of a business, in order to avoid "successor\'s liability," must receive a clearance from the:',hint:"It is necessary to have a Certificate of Clearance from the State Board of Equalization to be sure the sales taxes have been paid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Alcoholic Beverage Control Board.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"State Board of Equalization.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Secretary of State.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Real Estate Commissioner.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What kind of tax would be considered a progressive tax?",hint:"Income tax is considered a progressive tax because progressive taxes take a larger percentage of income from higher income people than lower income people.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Toll",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Income",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Sales",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Federal",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is the order of months on the tax calendar?",hint:"No Darn Fooling Around: November 1st due; December 10th delinquent; February 1st second due; April 10th delinquent.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"December, April, November, February",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"November, December, February, April",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"April, February, December, November",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"February, April, November, December",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In Texas, a homeowner's exemption is:",hint:"A property owner may claim a homeowner's exemption in Texas on a residence that is both owned and occupied. The exemption reduces the assessed value of the residence by $7,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$7,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$7,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,500",isCorrect:!1}]}}]},{category:"Math",id:8,list:[{questionText:"Which of the following dimensions would contain the largest area?",hint:"Two miles square = 4 square miles. (a) = 3.6 square miles; (b) = 2 square miles: (d) = 1.9 square miles.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10% of a township",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Two sections",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2 miles square",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"5,280' x 10,000'",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The NW 1/4 of the SW 1/4 of Sec. 8, T1N, R2E, SBBM:",hint:"U.S. Government Section and Township Survey (Baseline and Meridians in California and facts about Townships and Sections.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"is a 40-acre parcel.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is a 1/16 of a section.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is 1,320 feet on each side.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above are correct",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"How many square miles does a section contain?",hint:"A section is 1 mile by 1 mile, 1 mile square, and contains 1 square mile.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"6",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"36",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"180",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many acres are in one section?",hint:"There are 640 acres in a section.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"260",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"360",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"420",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"640",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The measurement of a township is:",hint:"A township is divided into 36 sections - each measuring one mile by one mile (or 36 square miles).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"l mile by l mile.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"43,560 square feet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"36 square miles.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"640 acres.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A board foot is exactly:",hint:"Any combination of 144 cubic inches.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:'2" x 6" x 12".',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'3" x 4" x 12".',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'12" x 12" x 1".',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of these",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'A board foot of lumber contains 144 cubic inches. How many board feet of lumber can be obtained from a piece 2" x 4" x 12\'?',hint:'2" x 4" x 12\' = 1,152 inches divided by 144 cubic inches = 8 board feet.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"3",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"7",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"8",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Assume that the original value of a property was $122,500, with the land valued at $24,500. If the economic life of the improvements were estimated to be 40 years using the straight line approach, what was the book value of the property after 14 years?",hint:"$122,500 - $24,500 = $98,000",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$42,875",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$63,700",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$79,625",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$98,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A 60-acre tract was purchased for $30,000 per acre and divided into 3 parcels and sold for $750,000 each. What was the percentage return on the purchase price?",hint:"60 x 30,000 = $1,800,000 (cost); $1,800,000 divided by 3 = $600,000; $750,000 - $600,000 = $150,000 divided by $600,000 = .25 (25%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"15",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"30",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If 1.86 acres are for sale at 22 1/2 cents per square foot, what is the asking price?",hint:"1.86 x 43,560 square feet = 81,021.6 square feet x 22-1/2 cents $18,229.86.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$18,229.86",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$18,267.53",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$18,983.16",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$19,096.16",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In order to be able to earn $75.00 per month from an investment that yields a 5% return, you must invest:",hint:"$75.00 per month x 12 = $900 per year.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2,500.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$9,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$18,000.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Assume a property was sold for $20,325, with buyer to assume a $12,200 loan. What amount of documentary stamps would be required on the deed?",hint:"The tax would be levied on consideration of $8,125 (20,325 - 12,200). 8000 x 1.10 = 8.80; 125 = .55; .55 + 8.80 = 9.35.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$20.90",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15.95",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$9.35",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$11.55",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The number of linear feet on each side of an acre of land that is almost square would be approximately:",hint:"Actually 208.7 feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"150 feet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"209 feet.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"320 feet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"410 feet.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man bought a second trust deed and note that had a face amount of $1,500, on which he was allowed a 20% discount. If he received payments of $131 per month, including 9% interest, for 1 year, what was his percentage of return on his investment?",hint:"1500 x 20% = 300; 1500 - 300 = 1200; 131 x 12 = 1572; 1572 - 1200 = 372; 372 / 1200 = .31\nUse the formula R= I / P, where (R)= the rate of return on the investment, (I)= income (interest + discount), and P= amount Paid (note amount minus discount). We can start with P (amount paid). [1500-(1500 X .20)] = 1500-300= 1200. P=1200.\nI= 131 X 12 (months in the year)= 1572. Since he originally only paid $1500 he made $72 which is the interest. [I= interest ($72) + discount ($300)] = 372. Using the formula R= I / P, (372/1200)=.31",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"24 1/2",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"29",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"31",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"36 1/4",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The value of the property is $193,600 at $4.40 per square foot. If the depth of the lot is 200 feet, what is the value per front foot?",hint:"$193,600 divided by $4.40 = 44,000 sq. ft. divided by 200 = 220 front",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$4.40",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$220",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$880",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Cannot be answered with the amount of information given",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man owns an apartment building with 20,000 square feet of living space and wants to carpet 60% of the area. If the carpet costs $6.00 per square yard, the total cost of carpeting was most nearly:",hint:"20,000 square feet x 60% = 12,000 square feet. 1 square yard = 9 square feet. Therefore: 12,000/9 = 1,333.33 sq. yards 1,333 x $6.00/yard = $7,999.99. Closest answer is $10,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$10,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$24,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$65,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$79,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If building costs increase by 20%, the purchasing power of the investment dollar decreases by:",hint:"$1.00 divided by $1.20 = 0.83-1/3 (83-1/3%). Purchasing power is 83-1/3% of what it was, which means it has decreased by 16-2/3%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"16-2/3%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"20%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"33-1/3%.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Bob has a loan for $16,000 with interest to be paid at the rate of $200 quarterly. What is the interest rate on the loan?",hint:"200 x 4 = 800 divided by 16,000 = 0.05 (5%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"3% but less than 4%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4% but less than 5%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5% but less than 6%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"6% but less than 7%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A person sold his home and took back a second trust deed for $3,740. He immediately sold it for $2,431. What was the rate of discount?",hint:"$3,740 - $2,431 = $1,309 (amount discounted) divided by $3,740 = .35 (35%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"28%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"35%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"55%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"65%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following measurements are equivalent to a board foot?",hint:"Any combination of 144 cubic inches (6 x 12 x 2 = 144).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:'6" x 12" x 2"',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:'6" x 12" x 1"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'12" x 12" x 2"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'12" x 12" x 12"',isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A real estate speculator purchased a property for $10,000. He paid $1,000 down and executed a non-interest bearing note for $9,000 in favor of the seller. Before the end of the first year and before he had made any principal payments, he sold the property for double what he paid for it. Each $1.00 of his investment is now worth:",hint:"The owner's equity is based upon the difference in value and the loan amount. $20,000 - $9,000 = $11,000. His $1,000 investment is now worth $11,000 or $11 for each $1 invested.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$9.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11.00.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A property is valued at $30,000 and is insured for $24,500 at a rate of 16 cents per $100. The premium for a 3-year policy is 2 1/2 times the premium for 1 year. For a 3-year policy, the monthly cost will be:",hint:"245 x 0.16 = $39.20 (per year) x 2.5 = $98 (3 years);|$98 divided by 36 = $2.72 (per month).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$3.33.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$4.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2.72.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2.64.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An individual sold his property for $35,200 and realized a 10% profit over what he paid for it. His profit was:",hint:"The selling price of $35,200 = cost + 10% or 110% of selling price;|$35,200 selling price divided by 1.10= $32,000;|$35,200-32,000 = $ 3,200 profit.|",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$3,520.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,811.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,200.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$3,872.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A person purchases a $5,000 straight note for $4,500. Interest rate on the note is 6%. What was the percentage of profit made on the investment if the note is paid off in one year?",hint:"$5,000 x 0.06 = $300; $5,000 - $4,500 = $500; $300 + $500 = $800 = divided by $4,500 = 0.178 (17.8%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"6.7%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"11.1%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"17.8%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"6%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man paid $210,000 for some income units. His tax bill showed the assessments to be as follows: Land $15,120, improvements $35,280. In arriving at a figure to be used for depreciation for income tax purposes, he used his assessment figures as a basis. Which of the following most nearly reflects the depreciable amount?",hint:"$147,000|Land $15,120|Impr. $35,280|Total $50,400|Ratio of improvement value to total:|35,280 divided by $50,400 = 70%|Total cost $210,000|% for Imp. x .70|Improvement $147,000||Land is not depreciable for tax purposes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$35,280",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$50,400",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$147,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$159,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Property is valued at $240,000 using a capitalization rate of 10%. What would the value of the same property be using a capitalization rate of 12%?",hint:"$240,000 x 0.10 = $24,000 divided by 0.12.= $200,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$210,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$200,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$240,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$220,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Inventory in a store cost $9,200 net. It was sold for 25% profit; however, 15% of the gross profit was lost due to bad credit risks over a period of one year. How much profit did the store owner make that year?",hint:"$9,200 x 0.25 = $2,300 x 0.15 = $345; $2,300 - $345 = $1,955.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,955",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$920",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$345",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many square feet of cement would be needed for a 7-foot wide continual sidewalk around the outside edge of a 60 foot by 90 foot corner lot?",hint:"Note around the outside edge. Don't forget the corner.|90 x 7 = 630;|67 x 7 = 469 + 630 = 1,099 square feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1,050 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1,099 square feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"420 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"630 square feet",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A person has a lot that he purchased for $20,000. He has been asked to build an apartment house with a projected income of $18,000 per year. His accountant estimates all expenses, including proper management, repairs, etc., to be $10,000 per year. The man wants an 8% return on his investment. Which of the following is nearest to the amount he can afford to pay for the erection of the building?",hint:"$18,000 (annual gross income) - $10,000 (expenses) = $8,000 (annual net income);|$8 000 divided by .08 = $100,000. (value of building and land);|$100,000 - $20,000 = $80,000 (for erection of the building).| (Closest answer available is (a)).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$90,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$100,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$110,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$120,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Bill pays $152,400 for a home. If it costs 12% to sell his home before he could sell it at a profit, how much would it have to appreciate?",hint:"152,400 = 88% (100%-12%)|$152,400 divided by 88% = $173,181.81|$173,181.18 - $152,400 = $20,781.81.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$20,780",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"100%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"34%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,828",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Pat purchased a house in a run-down condition and spent an amount equal to 10% of the purchase to fix it up and bring it to its present value. The house is now worth $165,000. The cost of the house is equal to the existing loan of the property. The amount of the loan is:",hint:"$165,000 = 100% purchase price + 10% fix-up money;|$165,000 divided by 110% (1.10) = $150,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$158,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$148,500.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$150,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$164,500.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Brown takes a second trust deed on Mr. Black's home. The face value of this note is $5,000. Ms. Brown sells the note to her friend at a discounted price of $3,000. Mr. Black has not made any payments on the note and lets the second trust deed go into default. Ms. Brown's friend who now holds the note should sue for:",hint:"Buying a note at a discount does not alter the face value of the note. Ms. Brown's friend could sue for the face value of the note or $5,000, as mentioned in this problem.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,500.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$5,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$8,500.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,500.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Tom buys a piece of property as an investment for $10,000. Tom's capital investment is $1,000. He pays 6% interest on a loan of $9,000, and the property appreciates 8%. After one year the property is sold. What percent of profit did he realize on his initial invested capital?",hint:"$10,000 x 8% = $800; $9,000 x 6% = $540; $800 - $540 = $260 (profit involved);| $260 divided by $1,000 (investment) = 26%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"12%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"26%",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The entire stock of a retail store was sold for $8,400 to Sam Jones. Mr. Jones then sold the stock for 25% more than he paid for it, but due to some debts he lost 15% of the selling price. The net profit on Mr. Jones' investment was:",hint:"$8,400 x 25% = $2,100 (profit);|$8,400 + $2,100 = $10,500 x 15% (loss) = $1,575 loss;|$10,500 - $1,575 = $8,925 (sales price less 15% loss);|$8,925 - $8,400 (purchase price) = $525 (net profit).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$525.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2,100.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,925.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"15%.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Smith sells a piece of land. It is free of all encumbrances. The broker will receive a 6% commission and Mr. Smith's total escrow charges are $215.30. Mr. Smith received a check at the close of escrow for $15,290. The selling price was approximately:",hint:"$15,290 (check received by Mr. Smith) + $215.30 (escrow fees) = $15,505.30 (94% of sales price); 100% sales price - 6% broker's commission = 94% to owner; $15,505.30 divided by 94% = $16,495 (approximate gross selling price).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$17,200.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$17,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,270.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,495.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'A deposit receipt states, "Buyer to assume existing first trust deed of $8,000 at 6 1/2% paid per quarter." If Mr. Pink took possession February 15th and the first interest payment was due on March 15th, how much would Mr. Pink pay on the next interest date?',hint:"$8,000 x 6-1/2% (0.065) = $520.00 interest/year; $520 divided by 12 (months) = $43.33 interest/month; $43.33 x 3 (1/4 of a year) = $130.00/quarter.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$130.00",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$520.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$43.33",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A loan was made for $14,000 at an interest rate of 6% per year for a 20-year period. The total interest that would be paid over the entire loan period if the monthly payment for this fully amortized loan is $7.17 per $1,000, would be approximately:",hint:"$7.17 per $1,000 x 14 thousands = $100.38 monthly payment;|20 years x 12 months = 240 monthly payments;|$100.38 x 240 = $24,091.20;|$24,091.20 - $14,000 (money borrowed) = $10,091.20 total interest paid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$18,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$14,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume Mr. Kelly owns his home and borrowed money to buy it with a loan payable at $114.63 per month. The balance on the loan for the last month was $16,500. $32.13 was applied on his principle on his last payment. What was the interest rate on the note in these circumstances?",hint:"$114.63 (monthly payment) - $32.13 (principal part of payment) = $82.50 (interest);|$82.50 x 12 months = $990 interest per 1 year;|$990 divided by $16,500 (loan balance) = 6%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"16.6%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"5 1/4%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"9.2%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Several years ago, Mr. Moss bought property for $10,000, paying $1,000 in cash with the seller taking back a trust deed for the balance of the purchase price. Before any payments had been made on the trust deed note, he sold the property several months later for $20,000. His invested dollar in these circumstances is worth:",hint:"$10,000 (purchase price) - $9,000 (trust deed) = $1,000 (cash paid); $20,000 (sales price) - $9,000 (trust deed) = $11,000 (cash from sale); $11,000 divided by $1,000 = $11.00.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$100.10.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11.00.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$10.10.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1.10.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The number of linear feet on each side of an acre of land that is almost square would be approximately:",hint:"Actually 208.7 feet. Take the square root of 43, 560 (square feet in an acre) to get 208.7 (use square root symbol on calculator).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"150.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"209.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"320.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"410.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A farm measures one-half mile by one-half mile. How many acres does the farm contain?",hint:"The farm is 1/4 of a section. 1/4 of 640 acres is 160 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"20 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"40 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"160 acres",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"320 acres",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many townships are in a ranch which is 36 miles square?",hint:"36 miles square means a square that is 36 miles on each side. Since a township is 6 miles on each side, there would be 6 townships on each side of the ranch. 6 x 6 = 36 townships.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"12",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"18",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"24",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"36",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Starting at the NW corner of the SE 1/4 of Section 16, thence to a point 1,320 feet directly east, thence 660 feet directly south, thence 1,320 feet directly west, thence north to the point of beginning. This description contains how many acres?",hint:"The area described is the N 1/2 of the NW 1/4 of the SE 1/4 of Section 16. This would contain 20 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"40",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"80",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Measurements of a driveway are 24' x 36'. How much would it cost to replace the driveway if a concrete slab 4\" thick cost $15.00 a cubic yard to install and the cost of labor amounted to $272.00 over and above the cost of the concrete?",hint:"24' x 36' = 864 square feet;|864 divided by 3 (4\" thick = 1/3 feet) = 288 cubic feet;|288 divided by 27 cubic feet = 10.66 cubic yards;|10.66 or 11 cubic yards x $15.00 = $165;|$165 + $272 (labor) = $437.00.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$820",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$437",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$542",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$752",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If you were to divide a one acre parcel of land into four equal sized rectangular lots, parallel to each other and each measuring 200' in depth, what is the approximate width of each lot?",hint:"43,560 square feet in one acre divided by 200 feet equals 217.8 feet total frontage divided by 4 sides equals approximately 55 feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"55'",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"63'",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"212'",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"84'",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man owns a lot with 15,400 square feet. It has a depth of 140 feet. He buys two more lots that are adjacent to his lot, both with a depth of 140 feet. Together, the two new lots contain 4,200 square feet. What is the total front footage of all the lots combined?",hint:"15,400 square feet + 4,200 square feet = 19,600 square feet;|19,600 divided by 140 = 140.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"140 feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"170 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"180 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A buyer assumed a note secured by a deed of trust. The balance of the note was $9,000 with an annual interest rate of 7 1/2% payable quarterly. The interest on the note was to be prorated upon possession of the property. If the interest on the note had been paid to March 15, and he took possession February 15, he would owe how much prorated interest?",hint:"One month's interest from February 15 to March 15.|$9,000 x 0.075 = $675/year divided by 12. = $56.25/month.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$168.75",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$56.25",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$675.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What would the transfer tax be on the sale of a lot that sold for $9,800 with a loan assumed at $9,700?",hint:"Transfer tax is paid on the difference between the selling price and any existing trust deeds that are assumed by the buyer in excess of $100. The first $100 is exempt.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"0",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"55 cents",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"One cubic yard of concrete is equal to how many cubic feet of concrete?",hint:"3' x 3' x 3' = one cubic yard = 27 cubic feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"9 cubic feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"12 cubic feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"27 cubic feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"There was fire insurance on a building valued at $9,000. The cost of the policy was $158.40 for a three-year period. The policy became effective on March 1, 1992. On November 16, 1992, the owner sold the building and canceled the policy. What was the value of the unused portion of the policy?",hint:"$158.40 divided by 36 (months in 3 years) = $4.40 per month; $4.40 per month x 8.5 months = $37.40; $158.40 - $37.40 = $121.00.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$116.60",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$121.00",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$123.10",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$125.50",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A person has an investment in a 20-unit apartment building which is adjacent to a freeway. Because of its proximity to the freeway, the owner lost $200 per month rent. If the capitalization rate were set at 12%, the loss in value to the property was:",hint:"12 x $200 = $2,400, divided by 12%= $20,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$20,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2,400.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$24,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$22,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In the E 1/2 of the NW 1/4 of the SE 1/4 of the NW 1/4 of Section 38 is how many acres?",hint:"The correct answer is 5 acres. There is no Section 38. If it did exist, it would be 5 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1-1/4 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2-1/2 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/2 acre",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'Lot "A" is 3/4 of an acre. Lot "B" is 2/3 of the size of lot "A." The owner of these lots paid $14,000 for lot "B." He subdivided two lots into as many parcels as possible, all measuring 110\' by 82.5\' each. He sold each parcel for $7,500. His total selling price gave him a 50% profit on his original investment. What was the purchase price of lot "A?"',hint:'32,670 square feet (3/4 acre) + 21,780 square feet (2/3 of lot "A") = 54,450 square feet; 82.5 x 110 = 9,075 square feet per parcel; 54,450 divided by 9,075 = 6 parcels x $7,500 = $45,000 (selling price); $45,000 divided by 1.50 = $30,000 (original price); $30,000 - $14,000 = $16,000.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$30,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$31,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"1,320 feet by 1,320 feet contains:",hint:"1,320 feet x 1,320 feet = 1,742,000 square feet divided by 43,560 square feet in an acre = 440 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10 acres.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20 acres.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"40 acres.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"80 acres.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A corner lot measuring 50' x 150' has a front yard set-back of 10' and a 15' set-back on the side street. The total number of buildable square feet is:",hint:"Draw a picture for yourself rectangularly shaped measuring 50' x 150'. Then put in your set-backs according to the problem. Measurements left for building purposes are 35' x 140'.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"4,900.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"6,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"7,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"7,500.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a property sold for $17,000, with a first trust deed assumed at $14,400, deducting commission of 6% and costs at $235, how much would the seller receive from escrow?",hint:"$17,000 - $14,400 = $2,600 - $235 = $2,365; $17,000 x 0.06 = $1,020; $2,365 - $1,020 = $1,345.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$15,980",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,345",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$15,745",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,580",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A home sold for $16,950. This included a profit of 9%. The original cost of the home was approximately:",hint:"$16,950 divided by 1.09 = $15,550. Closest answer is $15,500.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$15,500.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$15,400.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,500.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many acres are in a lot that measures 660 feet x 1,320 feet?",hint:"1,320' x 660' = 871,200 sq. ft. divided by 43,560 = 20 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"40",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An apartment was purchased for $175,000. The terms of purchase were $125,000 cash, and a purchase money deed of trust for the balance. The land was valued at $60,000. What would the adjusted cost basis of the property be after it is fully depreciated?",hint:"Only the improvements are depreciated; therefore, after the property has been fully depreciated, the adjusted cost basis would still be the original value of the land, $60,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The remaining balance on the purchase money deed of trust",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$115,000, the value of the improvements",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$60,000, the value of the land",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It would have no adjusted cost basis as it is fully depreciated",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An apartment's financial statement discloses the following: (1) gross income-$10,000; (2) vacancy factor-10%; (3) operating expenses-$4,000; (4) payments to amortize the existing 1st and 2nd deeds of trust-$250 monthly. Using a 10% capitalization rate, what is the value of the property?",hint:"$10,000 x 10% = $1,000; $9,000 - $4,000 = $5,000; Apply the standard cap rate equation: $5,000 (net operating income) divided by 10% (cap rate) = $50,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$50,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$20,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$60,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$100,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Property "A" has a monthly gross income of $300. Property "B" has a monthly gross income of $700. Using a monthly gross multiplier of 120 and calculating the difference in value between the two properties, the result would be:',hint:"$300 x 120 = $36,000;| $84,000 - $36,000 = $48,000;| $700 x 120 = $84,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$48,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$36,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$30,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$70,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is equivalent to an acre?",hint:"43,560 square feet equals one acre. All choices work out to 43,560 square feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"43,560 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"100 ft. x 435.6 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"50 ft. x 871.2 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"If a salesperson sold a parcel with 800 front feet at $100 a front foot, and he was to receive 40% of his broker's 6% commission, he would receive:",hint:"800 x $100 = $80,000 x 0.06 = $4,800 x .40 = $1,920.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$3,200.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,680.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,920.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$810.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An owner of a home listed it at a price which would leave him $18,800 after the broker had received a 6% commission. If the broker sold the property at the listed price, how much commission would he receive?",hint:"$18,800 divided by 94% = $20,000 - $18,800 = $1200 commission.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,088",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,193",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,200",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$1,064",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How much money would have to be invested at 6% interest to provide an income of $125.00 per month?",hint:"$125 x 12 = $1500 per year. $1500 divided by 6% = $25,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$9,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$25,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$20,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$50,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An apartment house has 100,000 square feet of floor space. If the owner has 60% of the floor space covered with carpeting at a cost of $6.00 per square yard, his approximate cost would be:",hint:"100,000 x 60% = 60,000 square feet:|60,000 divided by 9 = 6666 2/3 square yards;|6666 2/3 x $6 = $40,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$6,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$20,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$40,000.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A home owner sold his lot for $23,000. This selling price represented a 15% profit over what he had originally paid for it. What was the original price of the lot?",hint:"$23,000 divided by 115% = $20,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$20,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$19,550",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$27,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property was sold on these terms: selling price $25,000, $5,000 cash down payment, buyer to deposit proceeds of an $18,000 loan secured by a first trust deed and note, buyer to execute a note in favor of the seller for $2,000 secured by a second deed of trust. What amount of revenue stamps must be purchased prior to the recording of the deed?",hint:"He must pay transfer tax on the selling price of the house less any old loans assumed. There is no old loans assumed; therefore the tax is on the full selling price. $25,000 @ $1.10 per $1,000 = $27.50.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$5.50",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$27.50",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$25.30",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None required on this transaction",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Kent received a straight loan on which he paid only the interest at 4-1/2%, all due and payable in one year. His monthly interest payment was $22.50. What was the amount of the loan?",hint:"$22.50 x 12 = $270;|$270 divided by .045 = $6,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$3,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$4,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$5,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$6,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A man obtained a $750 loan at 7.2% interest. He paid $67.50 total interest. The term of the loan was:",hint:"$750 x 0.072 = $54.00; $54.00 divided by 12 = $4.50 per month; $67.50 divided by $4.50 = 15 months.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"12 months.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"15 months.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"18 months.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"24 months.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many linear feet of fencing is required to fence one standard section of land?",hint:"A standard section is a square, one mile by one mile. It would take 4 miles of fencing to enclose it. 5,280 x 4 = 21,120.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10,560",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"13,200",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20,560",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"21,120",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A buyer is purchasing a single family residence for $163,000 and assuming an existing loan of $133,000. If the documentary transfer tax is computed on the basis of $.55 for $500, the amount of the tax will be:",hint:"To determine the amount of the documentary transfer tax, you need to first find out the amount of the new money in the transaction. To do this, you subtract any existing loan that the buyer is taking over from the sales price of the property. The amount of money left is the new money and is the amount on which the tax is computed.|$163,000 (purchase price)|- $133,000 (existing loan)|$ 30,000|$30,000 divided by $500 = 60|60 x $.55 = $33 (answer).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$146.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$179.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$33.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$10.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man paid $9,300 for the stock in trade of a retail business. He sold it for 33-1/3% more than he paid for it. If he lost 15% of the gross sale price because of credit risks, the net profit on his original investment would be:",hint:"1/3 of $9,300 = $3,100 $9,300 + $3,100 = $12,400;|$12,400 x 0.15 = $1,860. $12,400 - $1,860 = $10,540; |$10,540 - $9,300 = $1,240 answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,240.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"85%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,100.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"18-1/3%.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man bought a property for $15,840. If he wants to sell it without a loss, for a price which would include a 12% commission, the value of the property would have to appreciate:",hint:"$15,840 divided by 0.88 = $18,000. $18,000 - $15,840 = $ 2,160.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"24%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,940.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"17%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,160.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A man sold a parcel of land for $14,400, which was 20% more than he paid for it. The parcel was described as the S 1/2 of the NE 1/4 of Section 6. The price he paid per acre was:",hint:"$14,400 divided by 1.20 = $12,000;|S 1/2 of NE 1/4 of Section 6 = 80 acres;|$12,000 divided by 80 = $150.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$70.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$100.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$180.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$150.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A man sold his home and escrow closed January 1, 1991. The taxes for the fiscal year of 1990-91 were unpaid. His property was assessed at $150,000, and the tax rate was 1% of assessed value. The amount of taxes with which he would be debited in escrow would be:",hint:"July 1, 1990 to January 1, 1991 = 6 months; $150,000 x 1% = $1,500 divided by 12 = $125 x 6 = $750.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$750.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$630.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$600.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man signed a note for $2,400, with 10% prepaid interest, to be paid from the loan proceeds in escrow. Which of the following amounts did he actually receive?",hint:"$2,400 x 0.10 = $240. $2,400 - $240 = $2,160.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,260",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,160",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2,400",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is the salesperson's 45% of a 6% commission on a $31,000 sale?",hint:"$31,000 x 0.06 = $1,860 x 0.45 = $837.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$923.60",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$841.80",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$837.00",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man who needed money to purchase a new car had a real estate broker arrange a fully amortized 3-year loan using his home as security. The note was for $2,400 calling for payments of $77.00 per month, including 10% interest. If the borrower received $1,980 cash proceeds from the loan after deducting all expenses, the total amount of principal that must be paid to the lender on the note is:",hint:"Since the borrower signed a note for $2,400, he will be required to pay back this amount of principal plus the interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2,400.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$3,120.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,772.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,980.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a person borrowed $5,000 on a straight note and paid $100 interest every 90 days, what would be the interest rate?",hint:"$100 x 4 = $400 interest per year divided by $5,000 = 8%;|$100 - 90 days|$100 - 90 days|$100 - 90 days|$100 - 90 days|$400 - 360 days or one year.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"8%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"5%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6.6%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume it would cost $12,500 to reproduce an improvement today. Assume the land is valued at $1,000 today. Assume the improvement is actually 12 years old. The depreciation rate is 1-1/2%. Using the above facts, what is the depreciated value today?",hint:"12 years x 1-1/2% = 18% depreciation rate;$12,500 x 18% = $2,250 depreciation;$12,500 - $2,250 = $10,250 remaining value;$10,250 + $1,000 land value = $11,250 answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$10,250",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10,750",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11,250",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"You have just bought a piece of property that contains 54,000 square feet and is 180 feet deep. There are 2 vacant lots, one on each side of your lot, that have the same depth as your lot and contain 5,400 square feet each. If you bought these lots, your total frontage would be?",hint:"54,000 square feet divided by 180 feet deep = 300' width;|5,400 square feet divided by 180 feet deep = 30' width;|30 feet x 2 lots = 60 feet + 300 feet = 360' width.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"140 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"320 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"380 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"360 feet",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The number of square feet contained in a township can be determined by multiplying:",hint:"There are 43,560 square feet in one acre. There are 640 acres in one section. There are 36 sections in one township; hence, answer (b) is correct.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"42,650 square feet x 6 sections x 640 acres.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"43,560 square feet x 36 sections x 640 acres.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"45,360 square feet x 36 sections.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"23,040 square feet x 6 sections x 640 acres.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man purchases a note worth $5,000 for $4,500. Interest rate on the note is 6%. What was his percentage of profit made on his investment if note is paid off in one year?",hint:"$5,000 x 0.06 = $300; $5,000 - $4,500 = $500; $300 + $500 = $800 = divided by $4,500 = .178 (17.8%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"6.7%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"11.1%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"17.8%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"6%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Inventory in a store cost $9,200 net. It was sold for 25% profit, but 15% of the gross profit was lost due to bad credit risks over a period of one year. How much profit did the store owner make that year?",hint:"$9,200 x .25 = $2,300 x .15 = $345; $2,300 - $345 = $1,955.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,955",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$920",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$345",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A house is to be sold in probate. The first bid submitted is $92,000. If the court asks for additional bids and you wish to raise the first bid of $92,000, your second bid must be at least:",hint:"The second bid must exceed the first bid by 10% on the first $10,000 and 5% of the remainder.| $10,000 x .10 = $1,000;| $82,000 x .05 = $4100;|$92,000 + $1,000 + $4100 = $97,100.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$95,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$97,100.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$96,200.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$92,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume a second trust deed has a face amount of $4,000, payable $65 a month plus 7.2% interest per year. What would be the amount of the interest due on the first monthly payment?",hint:"$4,000 x 0.072 equals $288 interest for one year. $288 divided by 12 equals $24 first month's interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$24",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$28.20",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$288",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$65",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A road comprising a total of 3 acres runs along the southern boundary of a section. Of the following, which is most nearly the width of the road?",hint:"The southern boundary is 1 mile long, or 5,280 feet.|43,560 x 3 = 130,680 divided by 5,280 = 24.75 feet (closest answer is 20 feet).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"20 feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"30 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"40 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"50 feet",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. and Mrs. Garcia purchased a home for $120,000 and secured a new first trust deed and note at that time. Within two months after the purchase, the Garcias recorded a homestead on the home. One year later they had an unsecured judgment lien levied against them for $5,500. Subsequently, they listed the property and sold it for $121,000 at which time the trust deed and note balance was $115,500. Under the circumstances, the holder of the judgment lien would receive which of the following amounts from escrow out of the proceeds of the sale?",hint:"The homestead will protect the Garcia's equity up to $75,000. If the property sells for $121,000 and the balance of the loan is $115,500, their equity is only $5,500, and the unsecured judgment lien holder receives nothing.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$5,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$4,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$6,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Nothing",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Atilla bought a parcel of land measuring 110 yards by 220 yards. How many acres are in this parcel?",hint:"110 yds x 220 yds = 24,200 square yards; 24,200 square yards x 9 square feet (in a square yard) = 217,800 square feet; 217,800 square feet divided by 43,560 square feet per acre = 5 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2.5",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"10",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a property with a $2,400 gross monthly income sold at an annual GRM (gross rent multiplier) of 10.72, what did the property sell for?",hint:"$2,400 x 12 = $28,800 gross annual income;|$28,800 x 10.72 GRM = $308,736.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$250,650",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$280,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$295,640",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$308,736",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Rudolfo held a $1,968 straight note bearing 8.5% interest for 3 years, 10 months and 20 days. Approximately, how much interest did he earn?",hint:"Use a banker's year: 30 months and 360 day year;|3 years, 10 months and 20 days = 1,400 days;|$1,968 x 8.5% = $167.28 interest per year = $.464666 per day;|1,400 x $.464666 = $650.53.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$668",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$650",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$550",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$503",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An investor purchased a home for $144,000, with a $40,000 down payment and financing the balance with $104,000 straight note. The investor then sold the property for double the purchase price. If the investor had made no principal or interest payments on the loan, each dollar invested would now be worth:",hint:"(1) $144,000 x 2 = $288,000 new selling price;|(2) $288,000 - $104,000 loan = $184,000 profit;|(3) $184,000 (profit) divided by $40,000 (invested) = $4.60.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2.20.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$4.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$4.60.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$6.60.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A person bought a parcel of land measuring 110 yards by 220 yards. How many acres are in this parcel?",hint:"(1) 110 yards x 220 yards = 24,200 square yards; (2) 24,200 square yards divided by 4,840 square yards (in an acre) = 5 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2.5 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5 acres",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"10 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20 acres",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A house sells for $150,000. The buyer assumed an existing loan against the property for $130,000. The documentary transfer tax is:",hint:"$150,000 - $130,000 = $20,000 consideration; $20,000 divided by $500 = 40 taxable units; 40 x $.55 = $22.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$11.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$22.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$33.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$44.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When there is an existing assessment lien against a property and the buyer assumes that lien, the cost basis of the property is then the original cost, plus the amount of the lien. If Juan and Rosa bought a home for $240,000, and assumed an existing assessment lien in the amount of $2,000, what is their cost basis?",hint:"The cost basis of a property is the purchase price plus any liens and capital improvements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$240,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$238,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$240,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$242,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Bert purchased a property for 20% less than the listed price and later, he sold the property for the original listed price. What percentage profit did he make?",hint:"If a property were listed at $100,000 and it was purchased at 20% discount (purchased for $80,000) and then sold for the list price ($100,000), this would be a profit of $20,000. Based on an investment of $80,000, there would be a profit of 25%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"20",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"35",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"45",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"John owns a single family home which rents for $800 per month. A home across the street rents for $890 per month and recently sold for $78,000. If John applied the same gross rent multiplier to his home as was used on the home across the street, what would be the value of John's home?",hint:"(1) $78,00 (selling price) divided by $890 (rent) = 87.640|GRM (gross rent multiplier);|(2) $800 (rent) x 87.640 (GRM) = $70,112. D is the best answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$50,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$67,800",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$69,565",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$70,112",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Billy divided an acre of land into four lots. He then sold the lots for $10,000 each. If his cost basis on each lot was $2,000, what was his total gain on the sale of the lots?",hint:"$10,000 - $2,000 = $8,000 gain per lot; $8,000 x 4 lots = $32,000 gain.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$8,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$32,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$40,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Angie owns a single family home which rents for $600 per month. A home across the street rents for $690 per month and recently sold for $78,000. If Angie applied the same gross rent multiplier to her home as was used on the home across the street, what would be the value of Angie's home?",hint:"$78,000 (selling price) divided by $690 (rent) = 113.04 GRM (gross rent multiplier);$600 (rent) x 113.04 (GRM) = $67,826.09.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$50,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$67,800",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$69,565",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$70,909",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many parcels of land, each measuring 50' by 100', could be created from an acre of land?",hint:"50 feet x 100 feet = 5,000 square feet;|43,560 square feet (acre) divided by 5,000 square feet =8.71 parcels.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"7",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"8",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Placido has set an asking price of $78,200 for his 9 acres of land. His friend, Luciano, wants to buy a portion of this land measuring 100' by 145.2'. Assuming Luciano pays Placido's asking price on a square foot basis, how much will Luciano pay?",hint:"9 x 43,560 = 392,040 square feet;|$78,200 divided by 392,040 square feet = $.20 per square foot asking price;|100' x 145.2' = 14,520 square feet;|$.20 x 14,520 square feet = $2,904.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Less than 3% of $78,200",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"More than $2,000, but less than $2,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"More than $2,500, but less than $3,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"More than 5% of $78,200",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Craig purchased a home for $82,500. He got a first trust deed from a bank for 80% of the purchase price and put up a cash deposit of $1,800. In a separate transaction, he sold a $9,600 trust deed for a 30% discount and applied the proceeds to the purchase price. If the seller will carry a second trust deed for the balance of the purchase price, what will be the amount of the second trust deed carried by the owner?",hint:"$82,500 x 80% = $66,000 first trust deed;|$82,500 - $66,000 first trust deed = $16,500 balance of the purchase price;|$9,600 trust deed x 70% (100% - 30% discount) = $6,720 buyer received from sale of $9,600 trust deed;|$6,720 + $1,800 cash deposit = $8,520 cash down payment; |$16,500 - $8,520 = $7,980.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$7,980",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$8,330",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$6,421",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$5,222",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What would be the total property value of a four unit apartment building if each unit rented for $206.25 per month, vacancies were 5% of gross rents, annual operating expenses were $4,140, and the net income represented an 8% capitalization rate?",hint:"(1) $206.25 x 4 x 12 = $9,900 annual scheduled gross income.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$65,812.50",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$68,400",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$71,484",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$72,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A buyer has agreed to buy a home for $210,000. She has deposited $6,000 into escrow. A lender has agreed to loan 80% of the appraised value, which is $200,000, and the settlement costs to be charged the buyer amount to 3% of the purchase price. How much additional money must the buyer deposit into escrow prior to closing?",hint:"$200,000 x 80% = $160,000 loan amount; $210,000 x 3% = $6,300 closing costs; $210,000 - $160,000 = $50,000; $50,000 + $6,300 = $56,300; $56,300 - $6,000 (initial deposit in escrow) = $50,300 needed to be deposited into escrow to close the transaction.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$25,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$40,300",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$50,300",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"There is insufficient information to arrive at an answer.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A 60-acre tract was purchased for $300 per acre and divided into 3 parcels and sold for $7,500 each. What was the percentage return on the purchase price?",hint:"60 x 300 = $18,000 (cost).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"15%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"30%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If 1.86 acres are for sale at 22 1/2 cents per square foot, what is the asking price?",hint:"1.86 x 43,560 sq. ft. = 81,021.6 sq. ft. x 22-1/2 cents = $18,229.86.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$18,229.86",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$18,267.53",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$18,983.16",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$19,096.16",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following dimensions would contain the largest area?",hint:"Two miles square = 4 square miles.\n(a) = 3.6 sq. mi.\n(b) = 2 sq. mi.\n(d) = 1.9 sq. mi.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10% of a township",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two sections",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2 miles square",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"5,280' x 10,000'",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many acres are in the following described area? The NW 1/4 of the NE 1/4 of section 5?",hint:"A section contains 640 acres. A 1/4 section contains 160 acres. 1/4 of 1/4 section contains 40 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"40",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A parcel of land 1/4 mile by 1/4 mile is equivalent to:",hint:"This would be a 1/4 of a 1/4 of a section, which would be 1/16 of a section.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1/16 of a section.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1/8 of a section.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/4 of a section.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Alfred bought a piece of property for 20% less than the listed price. He later sold it for the listed price. His gain was:",hint:"Listing price is $100,000. At 20% less, would be 80,000. Later selling at $100,000 would be a gain of $20,000 divided by $80,000 = 0.25 (25%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A person sold his home and took back a second trust deed for $3,740. He immediately sold it for $2,431. What was the rate of discount?",hint:"$3,740 - $2,431 = $1,309 (amount discounted) divided by $3,740 = .35 (35%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"28%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"35%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"55%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"65%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man purchases a $5,000 straight note for $4,500. Interest rate on the note is 6%. What was his percentage of profit made on his investment if the note is paid off in one year?",hint:"$5,000 x 0.06 = $300. $5,000 - $4,500 = $500. $300 + $500 = $800. $800 divided by $4,500 = 0.178 (17.8%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"6.7%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"11.1%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"17.8%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"6%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Inventory in a store cost $9,200 net. It was sold for 25% profit. However, 15% of the gross profit was lost due to bad credit risks over a period of one year. How much profit did the store owner make that year?",hint:"$9,200 x 0.25 = $2,300 x 0.15 = $345. $2,300 - $345 = $1,955.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,955",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$920",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$345",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A house is to be sold in probate. The bid submitted to court for confirmation is $200,000. The first minimum overbid would be:",hint:"The first minimum overbid must exceed the bid submitted for confirmation by 10% on the first $10,000 and 5% of the remainder. $10,000 x 0.10 = $1,000. $190,000 x 0.05 = $9,500. $200,000 + $1,000 + $9,500 = $210,500.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$200,001.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$210,500.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$225,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$230,500.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many acres are in the S 1/2 of the SE 1/4 of Section 5 and the N 1/2 of the NW 1/4 of Section 13 and the N 1/2 of the NE 1/4 of Section 32?",hint:"1/2 of 1/4 of anything is 1/8 (1/2 x 1/4). There are 640 acres in a section. 1/8 x 640 = 80. 80 + 80 + 80 = 240 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"80",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"160",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"240",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"320",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many square feet of cement would be needed for a 7-foot wide continual sidewalk around the outside edge of a 60 foot by 90 foot corner lot?",hint:"Note around the outside edge. Don't forget the corner. 90 x 7 = 630. 67 x 7 = 469 + 630 = 1,099 sq. ft.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1,050 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1,099 square feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"420 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"630 square feet",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Jones purchased a home for $72,000 with a $20,000 cash down payment and a $52,000 loan. This loan was interest free and required no payments of principal for five years. One year later, he sold the home for double its purchase price. Each dollar of his original cash investment now equals:",hint:"$72,000 x 2 = $144,000. $144,000 - $52,000 = $92,000 (equity). $92,000 / $20,000 (original investment) = $4.60.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$4.60.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$7.30.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$9.20.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"John Doe buys a piece of property as an investment for $10,000. John's capital investment is $1,000. He pays 6% interest on a loan of $9,000, and the property appreciates 8%. After one year the property is sold. What percent of profit did he realize on his initial invested capital?",hint:"$10,000 x 8% = $800; $9,000 x 6% = $540; $800 - $540 = $260 (profit involved); $260 divided by $1,000 (investment) = 26%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"12%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"22%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"26%",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Smith sells his home. It is free of all encumbrances. The broker will receive a 6% commission and Mr. Smith's total escrow charges are $215.30. Mr. Smith received a check at the close of escrow for $15,290. The selling price was approximately:",hint:"$15,290 (check received by Mr. Smith) + $215.30 (escrow fees) = 15,505.30 (94% of sales price); 100% sales price - 6% broker's commission = 94% to owner; 15,505.30 divided by 94% = $16,495 (approximate gross selling price).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$17,200.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$17,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,270.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,495.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'A deposit receipt states, "Buyer to assume existing first trust deed of $8,000 at 6-1/2% paid per quarter." If Mr. Pinkham took possession February 15th and the first interest payment was due on March 15th, how much would Mr. Pinkham pay on the next interest date?',hint:"$8,000 x 6-1/2% (0.065) = $520.00 interest/year; $520 divided by 12 (months) = $43.33 interest/month; $43.33 x 3 (1/4 of a year) = $130.00/quarter.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$130.00",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$520.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$43.33",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Bingham pays $15,240 for a lot. It costs 12% to sell his lot. Before he could sell it at a profit how much would it have to appreciate?",hint:"100% (sales price) - 12% = 88% or $15,240 purchase price;$15,240 divided by 88% = $17,318.18;$17,318.18 - $15,240 = $2,078.18.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2,078",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"100%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"34%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,828",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Prendergast purchased a house in a run-down condition and spent an amount equal to 10% of the purchase to fix it up and bring it to its present value. The house is now worth $16,500. The cost of the house is equal to the existing loan of the property. The amount of the loan is:",hint:"$16,500 = 100% purchase price + 10% fix-up money. $16,500 divided by 110% (1.10) = $15,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$15,800.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$14,850.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$16,450.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume Mr. Kelly owns his home but he borrowed money to buy it with a loan payable at $114.63 per month. The balance on the loan for the last month was $16,500. $32.13 was applied on his principle on his last payment. What was the interest rate on the note in these circumstances?",hint:"$114.63 (monthly payment) - $32.13 (principal part of payment) =| 82.50 (interest);|$82.50 x 12 months = $990 interest per 1 year;|$990 divided by $16,500 (loan balance) = 6%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"16.6%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"5 1/4%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"9.2%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Several years ago, Mr. Mossman bought property for $10,000, paying $1,000 in cash with the seller taking back a trust deed for the balance of the purchase price. Before any payments had been made on the trust deed note, he sold the property several months later for $20,000. His invested dollar in these circumstances is worth:",hint:"$10,000 (purchase price) - $9,000 (trust deed) = $1,000 (cash aid);|$20,000 (sales price) - $9,000 (trust deed) = $11,000 (cash from sale);|$11,000 divided by $1,000 = $11.00.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$100.10.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11.00.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$10.10.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1.10.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following dimensions is equivalent to an acre?",hint:"Answers (a), (b), and (c) are all equivalent to an acre.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"43,560 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"180' x 242'",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/640 of a section",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The reciprocal of 8% is:",hint:"To find the reciprocal of a number, you first convert it into a fraction (8% = 8/100). You then reverse the numerator and the denominator of the fraction (100/8). 100 divided by 8 = 12.5.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"125.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1.25.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"12.5.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"125.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is larger than a section?",hint:"A section has 27,878,400 sq. ft;|5,000 ft. x 6,000 ft. = 30,000,000 sq. ft.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"27,000,000 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/36 of a township",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"16 times 40 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"A parcel 5,000 feet by 6,000 feet",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The total number of square feet contained in township 1 North in range 14 East is:",hint:"640 acres (in 1 section) x 36 sections (in 1 township) = 23,040 acres;|23,040 x 43,560 square ft./acre = number of square feet in 1 township.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"24,030",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"23,040",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"23,040 acres x 43,650 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"43,560 square feet x 23,040 acres",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Sing purchased a brand new piece of income property for $190,000. The listed price was $220,000. Mr. Sing considered this a good deal on his part, since he only put $10,000 down and acquired a new first trust deed for the difference. The tax assessed value was indicated at $150,000. Mr. Sing's cost basis for income tax purposes would be:",hint:"Cost basis for income tax purposes (book value) is the price paid for the property, not the actual values. In this case, $190,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$180,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$150,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$190,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Harry sold two parcels of land for $9,430, which was 15% more than their cost four years ago. While Harry owned the parcels, he paid taxes each year at a rate of $8.00 per $100 on an assessed value of 25% of the purchase price. Assuming an annual loss of 5% imputed interest on Harry's original investment as an expense, how much did Harry lose on the transaction?",hint:"(1) $9,430 divided by 115% = $8,200 original cost;|(2) $8,200 x 25% = $2,050 assessed value;|(3) $2,050 x .08 = $164 annual property taxes;|(4) $164 x 4 = $656 taxes;|(5) $8,200 x 5% x 4 = $1,640 loss of interest;|(6) $8,200 + $656 + $1,640 = $10,496 total cost;|(7) $10,496 - $9,430 = $1,066 loss.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$650",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$885",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,066",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above, because Harry made money on the transaction",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many acres are in the E 1/2 of the NW 1/4 of the SE 1/4 of the NW 1/4 of Section 38?",hint:"The correct answer is 5 acres. There is no Section 38. If it did exist, it would be 5 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1-1/4 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2-1/2 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/2 acre",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:'Lot "A" is 3/4 of an acre. Lot "B" is 2/3 of the size of lot "A". The owner of these lots paid $14,000 for lot "B." He subdivided these two lots into as many parcels as possible, all measuring 110\' by 82.5\' each. He sold each parcel for $7,500. His total selling price gave him a 50% profit on his original investment. What was the purchase price of lot "A?"',hint:'32,670 sq. ft. (3/4 acre) + 21,780 sq. ft. (2/3 of lot "A") = 450 sq. ft; 82.5 x 110 = 9,075 sq. ft. per parcel; 54,450 divided by 9,075 = 6 parcels x $7,500 = $45,000 (selling price); $45,000 divided by 1.50 = $30,000 (original price); $30,000 - $14,000 = $16,000.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$30,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$31,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property sold for $16,950. This included a profit of 9%. The original cost of the property was approximately:",hint:"$16,950 divided by 1.09 = $15,550. Closest answer is $15,500.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$15,500.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$15,400.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,500.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many acres are in a lot that measures 660' x 1,320'?",hint:"1,320' x 660' = 871,200 sq. ft. divided by 43,560 = 20 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"40",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A 20-unit apartment building is valued at $600,000 based on a 10% capitalization rate. If the rent for each unit increased $10 per month, what would the value of the same building be based on a capitalization rate of 12%?",hint:"$600,000 x .10 = $60,000; 20 units x $10 = $200 per month x 12 = $2,400 per year; $60,000 + $2,400 = $62,400; $62,400 / .12 = $520,000",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$520,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$530,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$540,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$500,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A $5,000 loan is sold to an investor for $4,500. It is a straight note, due and payable at the end of one year. It bears a 6% interest rate. What percentage return on the principal dollar invested will be made by the investor?",hint:"$5,000 x 6% = $300 interest paid on the loan.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"6.6%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"11%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"17.8%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"25%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"It would cost $12,500 to reproduce an improvement today. The land is valued at $1,000. The improvement is 12 years old. The depreciation rate is 1-1/2%. Using the above facts, what is the depreciated value today?",hint:"12 years x 1-1/2% = 18% depreciation rate; $12,500 x 18% = $2,250 depreciation; $12,500 - $2,250 = $10,250 remaining value; $10,250 + $1,000 land value = $11,250 answer.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$10,250",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10,750",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11,250",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Buyer is considering purchasing an apartment building. He is given the following information by the agent: listing price, $948,000; gross income $143,000; expenses, $57,200; net income, $85,800. He wants an overall return of at least 8%. His agent should advise him in which of the following ways?",hint:"$85,800 divided by $948,000 = 9.05%. If he buys for the listed price he would have a return of 9.05%. Since he will settle for a 8% return, he should buy the property because the cap rate is approximately 1% greater than he is asking for.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Buy the property, since the capitalization rate is approximately 1% greater than required",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Buy the property, since the capitalization rate is approximately 7% greater than required",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Do not buy the property, since the capitalization rate is approximately 5% less than required",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Do not buy the property, since the capitalization rate is approximately 1% less than required",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A rectangular parcel of land has an area of 540 square yards. It has a 45-foot frontage. How deep is the lot?",hint:"540 square yards x 9 (sqare feet in a square yard) = 4,860 sqare feet. 4,860 square feet divided by 45 feet = 108 feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"60 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"108 feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1,080 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"200 yards",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A real estate broker arranges a hard money loan secured by a second trust deed for $7,000 to be repaid in 5 years. Her maximum commission would be:",hint:"Article 7 applies to first trust deeds less than $30,000 and second trust deeds less than $20,000. Commission on a second trust deed for a term of 3 years or more is 15%",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"15%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"5%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The SW 1/4 of the NE 1/4 and the NW 1/4 of the NW 1/4 of Sec. 25 contains:",hint:"1/4 of a 1/4 section is 40 acres. 40 acres and 40 acres equals 80 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10 acres.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20 acres.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"40 acres.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"80 acres.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"If a salesman sold a parcel with 800 front feet at $100 a front foot, and he was to receive 40% of his broker's 6% commission, he would receive:",hint:"800 x $100 = $80,000 x 0.06 = $4,800 x 0.40 = $1,920.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$3,200.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,680.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,920.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$810.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An owner of a home listed it at a price which would leave him $18,800 after the broker had received a 6% commission. If the broker sold the property at the listed price, how much commission would he receive?",hint:"$18,800 divided by 94% = $20,000 - $18,800 = $1200 commission.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,088",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,193",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,200",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$1,064",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A home owner sold his house for $23,000. This selling price represented a 15% profit over what he had originally paid for the house. What was the original price of the home?",hint:"$23,000 divided by 115% = $20,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$20,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$19,550",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$27,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. and Mrs. Carr listed their property with broker Smith. Some years ago they homesteaded the property and subsequently, a creditor secured a $15,000 judgment against the property, which has not been satisfied in any way. There is a purchase money trust deed with a $165,000 balance against the property. The broker sells the property for $200,000 cash. How much would be applied to the $15,000 judgment?",hint:"$75,000 (exemption) + $165,000 (trust deed) = $240,000 - ($40,000 more than sale price). No balance available.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$6,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$14,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Nothing",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Brown listed his home with broker Green for $150,000 with a commission rate of 6%. Broker Green brought an offer at 15% less than the listed price, Mr. Brown said he would accept the offer if the broker reduced his commission by 16 2/3%. If they all agreed to these terms, what amount of commission would broker Green receive?",hint:"1. $150,000 x 15% (.15) = $127,500. 2. 16-2/3% (.1667) x 6% (.06) = 1% (.01); 6%-1% = 5% 3. $127,500 x 5% (.05) = $6,375 commission.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$5,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,250",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$7,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$6,375",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The rule of thumb for lenders is 1 point of each 1/8 of 1% interest that they are not allowed to charge. If FHA increased the maximum interest rate from 6% to 6-3/4%, this would reflect a reduction of:",hint:"If the interest rate were increased 3/4%, that would mean 6 points the lender would not need to collect. 3/4 of 8 equals 6.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"8 points.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6 points.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"4 points.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2 points.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man paid $9,300 for the stock in trade of a retail business. He sold it for 33-1/3% more than he paid for it. If he lost 15% of the gross sale price because of credit risks, the net profit on his original investment would be:",hint:"1/3 of $9,300 = $3,100 $9,300 + $3,100 = $12,400.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,240.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"85%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,100.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"18-1/3%.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What is the salesman's 45% of a 6% commission on a $31,000 sale?",hint:"$31,000 x 0.06 = $1,860 x 0.45 = $837.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$923.60",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$841.80",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$837.00",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A homeowner paid 4 points for a bank loan. The bank sold the loan to an insurance company at a 3 1/2 point discount and received a check for $14,475. The original amount of the loan was:",hint:"100 - 0.035 = 0.965, $14,475 divided by 0.965 = $15,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$15,054.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,648.72.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,563.63.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,000.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A house is to be sold in probate. The first bid submitted is $92,000. If the court asks for additional bids and you wish to raise the first bid of $92,000, your second bid must be at least:",hint:"The second bid must exceed the first bid by 10% on the first $10,000 and 5% of the remainder.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$95,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$97,100.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$96,200.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$92,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Two vacant lots sold for a total of $17,940. Five years ago, the owner purchased them for $15,600. During the period of ownership, the following expenses were incurred: 6% annual interest on original cost, $50 annual weed burning for both lots, $10 annual miscellaneous expenses for both lots, and $225 annual real property taxes on each lot. How much did the owner gain or lose on the sale?",hint:"The annual expenses are $1,446 [$936 interest ($15,600 x 6%), $50 weeds, $10 misc., $450 property taxes ($225 per lot)]. Expenses for 5 years are $7,230 ($1,446 x 5). The cost of the lots is $22,830 ($15,600 + $7,230). Subtract the cost of the lots from the selling price to calculate the gain or loss on sale. $17,940 (sales price) - $22,830 (total cost) = $4,890 loss.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"He had a $4,890 loss.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"He had a $2,240 loss.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"He had a $4,890 gain.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"He had a $2,240 gain.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Attila bought a parcel of land measuring 110 yards by 220 yards. How many acres are in this parcel?",hint:"Estates or fees describe the degree, quantity, nature and extent of interest or ownership one has in real property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2.5 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5 acres",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"10 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20 acres",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Bert purchased a property for 20% less than the listed price and later he sold the property for the original listed price. What percentage profit did he make?",hint:"If a property were listed at $100,000 and it was purchased at 20%",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"20",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"35",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"45",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An apartment building cost $450,000. It brings in a net income of $3,000 per month. The owner is making what percentage of return on the investment?",hint:"$3,000 per month x 12 months $36,000 per year (always convert monthly rent to annual rent in the income approach). Net income $36,000 + $450,000 cost (or value) = 8% return on the investment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"7%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"8%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"11%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"13%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"When there is an existing assessment lien against a property and the buyer assumes that lien, the cost basis of the property is then the original cost plus the amount of the lien. If Juan and Rosa bought a home for $240,000 and assumed an existing assessment lien in the amount of $2,000, what is their cost basis?",hint:"The cost basis of a property is the amount the property cost to purchase plus any liens or capital improvements.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$240,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$238,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$240,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$242,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Waylon purchased a home for $82,500. He got a first trust deed from a bank for 80% of the purchase price and put up a cash deposit of $1,800. In a separate transaction he sold a $9,600 trust deed for a 30% discount and applied the proceeds to the purchase price. If the seller will carry a second trust deed for the balance of the purchase price, what will be the amount of the second trust deed carried by the owner?",hint:"$82,500 x 80% = $66,000 first trust deed; $82,500 - $66,000 first trust deed = $16,500 balance of the purchase price; $9,600 trust deed x 70% (100% - 30% discount) = $6,720 buyer received from sale of $9,600 trust deed; $6,720 + $1,800 cash deposit = $8,520 cash down payment; $16,500 - $8,520 = $7,980.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$7,980",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$8,330",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$6,421",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$5,222",isCorrect:!1}]}}]},{category:"Math Appraisal",id:9,list:[{questionText:"An acre is:",hint:"All are equivalent to an acre.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"43,560 square feet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"220' x 198'.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/640 of a section.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Dividing a one acre parcel of land into four equal sized rectangular lots parallel to each other and each measuring 240' in depth would give an approximate width of each lot equal to:",hint:"43,560 square feet in one acre divided by 240 feet equals 181.5 feet total frontage divided by 4 sides equals approximately 45 feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"45'.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"726'.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"182'.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"84'.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Jim owns a lot with 14,500 square feet. The lot has a depth of 160 feet. He buys two more lots adjacent lots both with a depth of 160 feet. Together, the two new lots contain 6,000 square feet. What is the total front footage of all the lots combined?",hint:"14,500 sq. ft + 6,000 sq. ft. = 20,500 sq. ft. 20,500 divided by 160 = 128.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"128 feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"133 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"91 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property is valued at $195,600 at $5.00 per square foot. If the depth of the lot is 150 feet, what is the value per front foot?",hint:"$195,600 divided by $5.00 = 39,120 sq. ft. divided by 150 = 260.8 front feet. $195,600 divided by 260.8 = $750 per front foot.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$5.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$260",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$750",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Cannot be answered with the amount of information given.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Starting at the SW corner of the SE 1/4 of Section 16, thence to a point 1,210 feet directly east, thence 900 feet directly north, thence 1,210 feet directly west, thence south to the point of beginning. This description contains:",hint:"The area described is a rectangle 1,210 feet by 900 feet. The total area equals 1,089,000 sq. ft. divided by 43,560 (an acre) = 25 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"20 acres.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25 acres.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"40 acres.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"80 acres.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Property Z is comparable to a house being appraised. Property Z sold for $220,000, but has an oversized lot valued at an extra $25,000. The indicated value for the subject property using this comparable is:",hint:"The difference between the two properties is the oversized lot valued at $25,000. $220,000 - $25,000 = $195,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$195,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$245,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$207,500.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not determinable from the information given.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a comparable has landscape lighting valued at $3,000, and the subject property does not, the sales price of the comparable is adjusted by:",hint:"Subtract the feature from the comparable to equal the sale price of the subject property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"+$3,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"-$3,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"-$1,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"can't compute on the basis of the information given.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If the subject property has built in appliances valued at $1,500 and a comparable property does not, the sales price of the comparable is adjusted by:",hint:"Add $1,500 to make the price of the comparable equivalent to the price of the subject property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"+$1,500.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"-$1,500.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"-$875.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"can't compute on the basis of the information given",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A single-family residence has an estimated value by the sales comparison approach of $142,000. Its value by the cost approach is $139,500 and by the income capitalization approach, $125,000. Which value will probably be your final estimate of value?",hint:"The sales comparison approach is the best for use in this instance.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$142,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$139,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"125,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$135,500",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many square yards of linoleum would be needed to cover a floor that's 1,700 square feet? Round your answer up to the next full square yard.",hint:"There are 9 square feet per square yard. Therefore, divide 1,700 square feet by 9 which equals 188.8 or 189.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"134 square yards.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"189 square yards.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"534 square yards.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of these.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many square feet are there in a building, rectangular in shape that is 29 feet wide and 69 feet long?",hint:"The area of a rectangle is length x width. 69 feet x 29 feet = 2,001 square feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2,001 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2,368 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2,001 square feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A triangular-shaped lot has a road frontage (base) of 80 feet and a depth of 120 feet. What is the area of the lot?",hint:"The area of a truing is base x height divided by 2. 80 x 120 = 9,600 divided by 2 = 4,800.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"277 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4,800 square feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"9,600 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"George is planning to build a warehouse 50 feet wide by 200 feet long. The walls will be 10 feet high and the building will have a flat roof. How many cubic feet of space will George have when the warehouse is completed?",hint:"Length x width x height = cubic feet. 200 feet x 50 feet x 10 feet = 100,000 cubic feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"4,200 cubic feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"8,400 cubic feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"100,000 cubic feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"306,000 cubic feet",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A club house construction cost $513,000. The building is 70 feet long, 50 feet wide and 12 feet high. What was the cost of this building per cubic foot?",hint:"The total cubic footage is 70 x 50 x 12 which equals 42,000. $513,000 divided by 42,000 cubic feet = $12.21 per cubic foot.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$6.91",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16.44",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$72",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of these",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Ed owns 80 acres of land that is 1/2 mile long by 1/4 mile wide. Ed asks Bill to clear 4 strips of land, each 50 feet wide for access to roads. One strip will run the length of the land and 3 strips will run the width of the land. If Bill charges $100 per acre of cleared land, he will receive approximately:",hint:"50 x 2640 = 132,000 sq. ft. 50 x 1320 = 66,000 x 3 = 198,000 sq. ft. 132,000 + 198,000 = 330,000 sq. ft. But there are 3 intersections 50 ft. by 50 ft. where the strips crossed that have been counted twice, so we need to subtract them. 50 x 50 x 3 = 7,500 sq. ft. 330,000 - 7,500 = 322,500 sq. ft. 322,500 divided by 43,560 = 7.40 acres (approximately). 7.40 x $100 = $740 received by Bill for clearing the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$222.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$388.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$740.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$888.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following formulas is used to calculate the cubic footage of an attic with a gable roof?",hint:'A gable roof is an "A-shaped" roof with two sloping sides rising to a point. Memorize this formula to find the cubic footage: Width x length divided by 2 x Height = cubic feet.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"Width x length x height = cubic feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Width x length divided by 5 x height x 2 = cubic feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Width x length divided by 4 x height = cubic feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Width x length divided by 2 x height = cubic feet",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which contains the largest area?",hint:"10% of 36 square miles (a township) = 3.6 square miles.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5280 feet by 5280 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one mile by one mile",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10% of a township",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"two sections",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The largest area is:",hint:"Two sections square would be two sections by two sections, which would equal four sections (one mile square per section) = 4 square miles.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"5280 feet by 5280 feet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one mile by one mile.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10% of a township.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two sections square.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The inside of a building measured 25 feet by 35 feet and has 1 foot thick walls. How many square feet of ground does the building cover?",hint:"1 foot thick walls on both sides of a building would increase the overall width by 2 feet (2 x 1 foot) and the depth by 2 feet (2 x 1 foot). This gives measurements of 27 feet by 37 feet (27 x 37 = 999) or 999 square feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"999 square feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"875 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"945 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"925 square feet",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If 2.50 acres are for sale at 27-1/2 cents per square foot, what is the asking price?",hint:"2.50 x 43,560 sq. ft. = 108,900 sq. ft. x 27-1/2 cents = $29,947.50.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$29,947.50",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$11,979.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$18,983.16",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$19,096.16",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following contains the largest area?",hint:"Two miles square = 4 square miles. 20% of a township = 7.2 square miles. Two sections = 2 square miles. 5,280 x 10,000 = 1.9 square miles.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"20% of a township",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"two sections",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2 miles square",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5,280 x 10,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The number of linear feet on each side of 2 acres of land that is almost square would be approximately?",hint:"43,560 x 2 = 87,120. The square root of 87,120 = 295.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"209",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"295",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"320",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"410",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"John paid $6.50 per square foot to purchase a rectangular parcel of land containing 40,000 square feet that was 400 feet deep. What was the cost per front foot?",hint:"40,000 square feet divided by 400 foot deep = 100 front footage. 40,000 square feet x $6.50 per square foot = $260,000 purchase price. $260,000 purchase price divided by 100 front footage = $2,600 per front foot.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$222",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$650",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,600",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$1,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A corner lot has dimensions of 100 feet by 100 feet. The owner decided to put a 6-foot wide sidewalk along the street frontage on two sides of his lot. The sidewalk was outside of his property line. If the walk costs 60 cents per square foot, how much did the sidewalk cost?",hint:"100 x 6 = 600 square feet. 106 x 6 = 636 square feet. 636 + 600 = 1,236 square feet. 1,236 square feet x $.60 per square foot = $741.60.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$697.60",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$710.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$741.60",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$750.60",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mary bought a piece of land which was 3/4 of an acre. It was 110 feet deep and she paid $1,750 for the land. She owned the adjoining land which was 2/3 the size of the land she purchased and had the same depth. Both parcels were rectangular. She then decided to divide the land into lots which were 82 feet wide. The lots were sold for $600 each. The total money she received represented a 25% profit over the cost of the two original parcels. What was the price of the 2/3 acre piece of land?",hint:"43,560 x .75 = 32.670 sq. ft. = area of the piece of land purchased. 32,670 x .66667 = 21,780 sq. ft. = area of piece of land owned previously. 32,670 + 21,780 = 54,450 sq. ft. = total area of the two pieces of land. 54,450 divided by 110 ft. = 495 (width of the two lots at the street). 495 divided by 82 = 6 lots. $600 x 6 = $3,600. $3,600 divided by 125% = $2,880 original cost of the land. $2,880 - $1,750 = $1,130.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,130",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2,880",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,600",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An investor paid $18,900 for a lot that had an area of 22,500 sq. ft. and was 160 ft. deep. The lot was sold and a 35% profit was made after paying a 10% brokers commission. At what price per front foot did the lot sell?",hint:"$18,900 x (100%+35% profit) = $25,515.60 net after paying the commission. $25,515.60 divided by 90%(total percentage after discount) = $28,350 selling price. 22,500(area) divided by 160 ft.(length) = 140.63(width). $28,350(sales price) divided by 140.63 ft. (width of lot at the street) = $201.59 per front foot.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$155",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$202",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$177",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$181",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"John Brown purchased a 1/2 acre vacant lot which was 100 feet deep. He paid $0.50 per square foot and now wants to sell the lot and make a 25% profit after paying $250 in costs plus a 10% commission. At what price per front foot must the lot sell?",hint:"43,560 sq. ft. divided by 2 = 21,780 sq. ft. x $0.50 per sq. ft. = $10,890 (cost of lot). $10,890 x 125% = $13,612.50 + $250 (costs) = $13,862.50. $13,862.50 divided by 90% = $15,402.78 divided by 217.8 ft. = $70.72 per front foot.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$50",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$71",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$109",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$154",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A road runs across the entire northern boundary of a section of land. The road contains two acres of land. The approximate width of the road would be:",hint:"This is a rectangular figure which is 5280 feet in length and contains 2 acres. Change the 2 acres into square feet. 43,560 square feet (1 acre) x 2 acres = 87,120 square feet contained in the rectangle. Divide the area of the rectangle, 87,120 by the length of the road, 5,280 to arrive at the width of the road 16.5 feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"17 feet.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"20 feet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30 feet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"40 feet.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many acres are in the following described area: the NW 1/2 of the NE 1/2 of section 5?",hint:"A section 640 acres. A 1/2 sections contains 320 acres. 1/2 of 1/2 section contains 160 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"110",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"120",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"140",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"160",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"1/4 mile by 1/4 mile is equivalent to:",hint:"1/4 of a mile (1,320) by 1/4 of a mile (1,320) = 1,742,400 divided by 43,560 = 40 acres which is 1/16 of a section.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1/16 of a section.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1/8 of a section.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/4 of a section.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following, which is equivalent to a board foot?",hint:"Any combination of 144 cubic inches = a board foot.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:'6" x 12" x 2"',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:'6" x 12" x 1"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'12" x 12" x 2"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'12" x 12" x 12"',isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The S 1/2 of the SE 1/4 of Section 4, the N 1/2 of the NW 1/4 of Section 8, and the N 1/2 of the NE 1/4 of Section 15 contain how many acres?",hint:"The S 1/2 (640 acres to a section divided by 2 = 320) of the SE 1/4 (320 divided by 4 = 80) contains 80 acres. The N 1/2 of the NW 1/4 and the N 1/2 of the NE 1/4 both contain 80 acres. 80 x 3 = 240 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"80",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"320",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"720",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"240",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"How many square feet of cement would be needed for a 7-foot wide continual sidewalk around the outside edge of a 60 foot by 90 foot corner lot?",hint:"Note around the outside edge. Don't forget the corner. 90 x 7 = 630. 67 x 7 = 469 + 630 = 1,099 sq. ft.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1,050 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1,099 square feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"420 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"630 square feet",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Fred owns an apartment building with 40,000 square feet of living space and wants to carpet 75% of the area. If the carpet costs $7.50 per square yard, the total cost of carpeting was most nearly:",hint:"40,000 square feet x 75% = 30,000 square feet. 1 square yard = 9 square feet. Therefore, 30,000 divided by 9 = 3,333.33 sq. yards. 3,333.33 x $7.50 per yard = $24,999.98. Closest answer is $25,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$10,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$25,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$4,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$33,300.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A driveway measures 25' x 35'. How much would it cost to replace the driveway if a concrete slab 4\" thick cost $15.00 a cubic yard and the cost of labor is $300.00 over and above the cost of the concrete?",hint:"25' x 35' x (1/3)' = 291.667 cu. ft. (4\" thick = 1/3 foot) or 292 cubic feet. 292 divided by 27 cubic feet = 10.81 cubic yards. (3' x 3' x 3' = 27 cu. ft. or 1 cu. yd.)10.81 or 11 cubic yards x $15.00 = $165. $165 + $300 (labor) = $465.00.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$820",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$465",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$381",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$786",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Of the following which is larger than a section?",hint:"A section has 27,878,400 sq. ft. 5,000 ft. x 6,000 ft. = 30,000,000 sq. ft.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1/36 of a township",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"27,000,000 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a parcel 5,000 feet by 6,000 feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"16 times 40 acres",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Township 1 North in range 14 East is how many square feet?",hint:"640 acres (in 1 section) x 36 sections (in 1 township) = 23,040 acres. 23,040 x 43,560 sq. ft. per acre = number of square feet in 1 township.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"24,040",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"23,030",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"43,560 square feet x 23,040 acres",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"23,040 acres x 43,650 square feet",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"One cubic yard is equal to how many cubic feet?",hint:"3' x 3' x 3' = 1 cubic yard = 27 cubic feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"9 cubic feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"27 cubic feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"12 cubic feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A board foot is exactly:",hint:"Any combination of 144 cubic inches.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:'2" x 8" x 9".',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'2" x 72".',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'16" x 9".',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of these",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lot measures 75' x 130' and has a front yard set-back of 10' and a 15' set-back on the side street. The total number of buildable square feet is:",hint:"Subtract the set-backs from the measurement. 75' - 10' = 65'. 130 - 15' = 115'. 65' x 115' = 7,475 buildable sq. feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"7,475 square feet.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"9,750 square feet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"7,000 square feet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"7,500 square feet.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many acres are in a lot that measures 750' x 1,320'?",hint:"1,320' x 750' = 990,000 sq. ft. divided by 43,560 = 23 acres (approximately).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"15",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"23",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"20",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"40",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The SW 1/2 of the NE 1/2 and the NW 1/2 of the NW 1/2 of Section 25 contains:",hint:"1/2 of a 1/2 section is 160 acres. 160 acres and 160 acres equals 320 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"320 acres.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"640 acres.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"160 acres.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"80 acres.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is an acre?",hint:"43,560 square feet equals one acre. All choices work out to 43,560 sq. ft.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"43,560 square feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"100 ft. x 435.6 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"33 ft. x 1,320 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"If a salesman is to receive 25% of his brokers 6% commission, how much would he receive on a parcel with 900 front feet that sold for $150 a front foot?",hint:"900 x $150 = $135,000 x 6% = $8,100 x 25% = 2,025.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$8,100",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,025",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$1,920",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$810",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A building has 150,000 square feet of floor space. If the owner wants 80% of the floor space covered with carpeting at a cost of $4.00 per square yard, his approximate cost would be:",hint:"150,000 x 80% = 120,000 sq. ft. 120,000 divided by 9 = 13,333.33 sq. yards x $4 = $53,333.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$13,330.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$48,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$66,667.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$53,333.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"How many linear feet of fencing is required to fence one standard section of land?",hint:"A standard section is a square, one mile by one mile. It would take 4 miles of fencing to enclose it. 5,280 x 4 = 21,120.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10,560",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"13,200",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20,560",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"21,120",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following is larger than a section?",hint:"Section = 640 x 43,560 = 27,878,400 sq. ft. 5,000 x 6,000 = 30,000,000 sq. ft.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"1/36 of a township",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"27,000,000 sq. ft.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5,280 ft. x 5,280 ft.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5,000 x 6,000 ft.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Bill sold a parcel of land for $15,600, which was 25% more than he paid for it. The parcel was described as the S 1/2 of the NE 1/4 of Section 9. The price he paid per acre was:",hint:"$15,600 divided by 125% = $12,480 (price paid). S 1/2 of NE 1/4 of Section 9 = 80 acres. $12,480 divided by 80 = $156 per acre.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$70.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$100.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$180.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$156.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A piece of property contains 44,000 square feet and is 180 feet deep. There are 2 vacant lots on each side of the property that have the same depth and contain 6,000 square feet each. What is the frontage of the combined lots?",hint:"6,000 sq. ft. x 2 = 12,000 sq. ft. of the 2 adjacent lots. 12,000 + 44,000 = 56,000 (total sq. feet). 56,000 divided by 180 ft. = 311 frontage (approximately).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"311 ft.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"320 ft.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"244 ft.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"277 ft.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'How many board feet of lumber can be obtained from a piece 8" x 12" x 12"?',hint:'8" x 12" x 12" = 1,152 cubic inches divided by 144 cubic inches = 8 board feet.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"3",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"7",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"8",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"How many acres are in the S 1/4 of the SE 1/4 of Section 10 and the N 1/2 of the NW 1/2 of Section 3 and the N 1/2 of the NE 1/4 of Section 16?",hint:"40 + 160 + 80 = 280 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"280",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"160",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"240",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"320",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A road comprising a total of 5 acres runs along the northern boundary of a section. Which is most nearly the width of the road?",hint:"The northern boundary is 1 mile long, or 5,280 feet. 43,560 x 5 = 217,800 divided by 5,280 = 41.25 feet. Closest answer is 40 ft.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"20 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"40 feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"50 feet",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Fred owns an apartment building with 40,000 square feet of floor space and wants to carpet 50% of the area. If the carpet costs $10.00 per square yard, the total cost of carpeting was most nearly:",hint:"40,000 square feet x 50% = 20,000 square feet. 1 square yard = 9 square feet. Therefore 20,000 divided by 9 = 2,222 sq. yards. 2,222 x $10.00 per yard = $22,220. Closest answer is $22,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$22,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$24,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$65,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$79,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If an acre of land is divided into 4 lots of equal size and the depth of each lot is 250', the front foot measurement of each lot is closest to which of the following figures:",hint:"1 acre = 43,560 sq. ft. divided by 250' = 174.24 divided by 4 = 43.56'.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"40.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"100.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"63.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"174.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A rectangular lot is 45 feet wide at the street and contains 620 square yards. How deep is the lot?",hint:"There are 9 sq. ft. in a sq. yd.; 620 sq. yd. x 9 = 5,580 sq. ft.; 5,580 sq. ft. divided by 45 ft. = 124 ft. deep.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"80 ft.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"124 ft.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"115 ft.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"120 ft.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A parcel of land 330 feet wide and 330 feet deep contains approximately how many acres?",hint:"330 ft. x 330 ft. 108,900 sq. ft. An acre contains 43,560 square feet. 108,900 sq. ft. divided by 43,560 sq. ft. = 2.5 = 2-1/2 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"2.75 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2-1/3 acres",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2-1/2 acres",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"2-2/3 acres",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A parcel of land contains exactly one acre. If the parcel is divided into 4 equally sized lots, rectangular in shape and is 240 feet deep, approximately how wide is each of the 4 lots?",hint:'An acre = 43,560 sq. ft. 43,560 divided by 240 ft = 181.5 feet (width of combined lots). 181.5 feet divided by 4 lots = 45.375 feet wide. "D" is the best answer.',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"181.5 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"55 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"60 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"45 feet",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Debbie paid $6.40 per square foot to purchase a rectangular lot contain 40,000 square feet. The lot was 400 feet deep. What was the cost per front foot?",hint:"40,000 square feet divided by 400 foot depth = 100 foot frontage. 40,000 square feet x $6.40 per square foot = $256,000 purchase price. $256,000 purchase price divided by 100 front footage = $2,560 per front foot.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$220",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$640",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,560",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$1,010",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A house fronts on two roads running at right angles to each other. The house touches one road for 2,660 feet and on the second road for 1,980 feet. Another property line is parallel to the shorter of the two roads and runs for 2,660 feet. The final boundary is a straight line connecting the open ends. How many acres does the property contain?",hint:"This property is in the shape of a trapezoid. To find the area of a trapezoid, add base 1 and base 2, then divide the total by 2 and multiply by the height. The shorter road (1,980 feet) and the property line that runs parallel to it (2,660 feet) are the bases. 1,980 feet (base 1) + 2,660 feet (base 2) = 4,640 feet. 4,640 feet divided by 2 = 2,320 feet. 2,320 feet x 2,660 feet (height) = 6,171,200 sq. ft. 6,171,200 divided by 43,560 square feet/acre = 142 acres (approximately).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"121",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"142",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"180",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"270",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A parcel of land, rectangular in shape, has an area of 560 square yards. It has a 45-foot frontage. How deep is the lot?",hint:"560 x 9 = 5,040. 5,040 divided by 45 = 112.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"60 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"112 feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"2,800 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"200 yards",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A rectangular-shaped building that is 45 feet wide and 65 feet long has a perimeter of:",hint:"Perimeter = 2 x length(65) + 2 x width(45) = 130 + 90 = 220 feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"220 feet.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"220 square feet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2,925 feet.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2,925 square feet.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The cost to pave a driveway that is 450 feet by 16 feet, at $7.25 per square yard is:",hint:"450 ft. x 16 ft. = 7,200 sq. ft. 7,200 divided by 9 = 800 sq. yards. 800 x $7.25 = $5,800.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$5,445.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,335.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$52,200.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$5,800.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A house comparable to the subject property sold recently for $160,000 and is very similar to the subject, except that the comparable has an extra bathroom, valued at $5,000. What is the adjusted value of the comparable?",hint:"$160,000 - $5,000 = $155,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$155,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$165,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$160,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of these",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A rectangular parcel of land has an area of 770 square yards. It has a 55-foot frontage. How deep is the lot?",hint:"770 x 9 (sq. ft. in a sq. yd.) = 6,930 sq. ft. 6,930 sq. ft. divided by 55 = 126 feet.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"126 feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"114 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4,705 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6,930 yards",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Steve paid $5.50 per square foot to purchase a rectangular parcel of land containing 30,000 square feet. The land was 150 feet deep, what was the cost per front foot?",hint:"30,000 square feet divided by 150 foot depth = 200 foot frontage. 30,000 square feet x $5.50 per square foot = $165,000 purchase price. $165,000 purchase price divided by 200 front footage = $825 per front foot.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$222",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,100",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$825",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$1,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How many acres are in the following described area: the W 1/2 of the N 1/2 of section 5?",hint:"A section contains 640 acres. A 1/2 section contains 320 acres. 1/2 of 1/2 section contains 160 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"110",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"120",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"140",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"160",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"How many acres are in the NW 1/4 of the SE 1/4 of Section 10 and the SE 1/4 of Section 3 and the N 1/2 of the NE 1/4 of Section 16?",hint:"40 + 160 + 80 = 280 acres.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"280",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"160",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"240",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"320",isCorrect:!1}]}}]},{category:"Math Escrow",id:10,list:[{questionText:"A property sold for $19,000 with a first trust deed assumed at $15,500. Deducting commission of 8% and costs at $260, how much would the seller receive from escrow?",hint:"$19,000 - $15,500 = $3,500 - $260 = $3,240. $19,000 x .08 = $1,520. $3,240 - $1,520 = $1,720.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$3,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,720",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$17,220",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$13,720",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Jim made an agreement to sell his house on December 1, 1990. Escrow closed January 1, 1991 and the taxes for the fiscal year of 1990-91 were unpaid. His property was assessed at $175,000, and the tax rate was 2% of assessed value. The amount of taxes with which he would be debited in escrow would be:",hint:"July 1, 1990 to January 1, 1991 = 6 months. $175,000 x 2% = $3,500 divided by 12 = $291.67 x 6 = $1,750.02. NOTE - The date of the agreement is not important for determining taxes to be debited in escrow.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,750.02.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$1,458.35.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,500.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of these.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Sue agreed to buy a home for $310,000 and she deposited $15,000 into escrow. A bank has agreed to loan her 80% of the appraised value which is $295,000. The settlement costs are to be charged to the buyer and amount to 5% of the purchase price. How much additional money must the buyer deposit?",hint:"$295,000 x 80% = $236,000 loan amount. $310,000 - $236,000 = $74,000 total down payment. $310,000 x 5% = $15,500 settlement costs. $74,000 + $15,500 = $89,500 total of down payment and settlement costs. $89,500 - $15,000 (already in escrow) = $74,500.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$74,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$89,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$74,500",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"There is insufficient information to arrive at an answer",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mary sold her house to Bob and escrow closed on November 10. The property taxes for the year ($3,500) have been paid. Using 30-day months and a 360-day year in the calculations, approximately how much does Bob owe to Mary for property taxes?",hint:"Property taxes are paid through June 30th. Therefore, the buyer will owe the seller for 20 days in November and for December through June (7 months). 7 x 30 = 210 + 20 = 230 days total. 3,500 divided by 360 = 9.72 per day x 230 = 2,235.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,326",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,235",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$1,333",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,250",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The seller of a home has paid the annual property taxes of $2,360; escrow will close on May 1. If the buyer and seller agree to prorate the property taxes as of the sale date, the buyer's portion of the taxes would be most nearly:",hint:"The seller has paid through June 30. The buyer will have the property for two months during this period. Divide the annual tax of $2,360 by 12 to find the monthly cost of $196.67. Multiply $196.67 x 2 months = $393.34 buyer pays.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$393.34.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$196.67.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,360.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,966.70.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Brown sells a piece of land. It is free of all encumbrances. The broker will receive a 6% commission and Mr. Brown's total escrow charges are $345. Mr. Brown received a check at the close of escrow for $16,300. The selling price was approximately:",hint:"$16,300 (check received by Mr. Brown) + $345 (escrow fees) = $16,645 (94% of sales price). $16,645 divided by 94% = $17,707 (approximate gross selling price).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$17,200.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$17,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,270.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$17,707.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In order to earn $65.00 per month from an investment that yields a 5% return, you must invest:",hint:"$65.00 per month x 12 = $780 per year. $780 divided by .05 = $15,600. Remember to work the problem using the annual income and the annual interest rate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2,500.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$9,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,600.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A buyer assumed a note secured by a deed of trust. The balance of the note was $11,000 with an annual interest rate of 9-1/2% payable quarterly. The interest on the note was to be prorated upon possession of the property. If the interest on the note had been paid to March 15, and he took possession February 15, he would owe how much prorated interest?",hint:"One month's interest from February 15 to March 15. $11,000 x .095 = $1,045 divided by 12 = $87.08 per month.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$168.75",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$56.25",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$87.08",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}}]},{category:"Math Finance",id:11,list:[{questionText:"Converted to a decimal, 2/3% becomes:",hint:"2 divided by 3 = .666 or .67.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:".67.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:".83.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1.333.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:".75.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"John wants a loan to finance the purchase of a house. The bank requires an 80% LTV. The purchase price of the house is $122,500. What is the maximum loan amount Brown could get?",hint:"$122,500 x .80 = $98,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$110,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$95,777",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$99,875",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$98,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Ed spends 24% of his gross monthly income on his house payment of $732. What is his gross monthly income?",hint:"$732 divided by 24% = $3,050.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$3,200",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,050",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2,750",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How much money must be loaned to receive $15,000 if the money is loaned for five years at 12% interest?",hint:"$15,000 (total interest) divided by 5 = $3,000 (interest per year). $3,000 divided by 12% = 25,000 loan amount.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$109,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$25,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$15,750",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How long will it take $6,000 to earn $2,400 at 8% interest?",hint:"$6,000 x 8% = $480 per year. $2,400 divided by $480 = 5 years.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"6 years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5 and a half years",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5 years",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Bill sold his office building for $185,000. This was 15% more than what he paid for it. His original cost was approximately:",hint:"To find 115%of the purchase price, divide $185,000 by 1.15 to produce an answer of $160,869.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$212,750.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$157,250.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$160,869.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"there is insufficient information to arrive at an answer",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Which of the following loans will require a balloon payment?",hint:"$320 x 12 x 10 = $38,400 total payments. $38,400 - $19,827.60 interest = $18,572.40 has been paid on principal reduction. $22,500 - $18,572.50 = $3,927.50 balloon payment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$22,500 with interest at 14.25% per year payable at $320 a month for 10 years; the total interest is $19,827.60",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$40,000 with interest at 10% per year payable at $429.85 a month for 15 years; the total interest is $37,373",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$100,000 with interest at 9.5% per year payable at $840.86 a month for 30 years; the total interest is $202,709",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Jill sold a house and carried back a promissory note for $13,340, secured by a 2nd trust deed. She then sold the note at close of escrow to an investor for $6,670. What was the amount of the discount?",hint:"$13,340 - $6,670 = $6,670 discount. $6,670 divided by $13,340 = 50% discount.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"30%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"32%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"50%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"40%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume a property was sold for $23,500 with buyer to assume a $13,500 loan. What amount of documentary stamps would be required on the deed?",hint:"The tax would be levied on consideration of $10,000 (selling price of $23,500, less assumed loan of $13,500). $10,000 at $1.10 per $1,000 = $11.00.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$20.90",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15.95",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$9.35",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11.00",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Broker Bob listed a home for sale for $200,000. He presented the seller with an offer which was 15% less than the listed price. The seller said he would accept the offer if the Broker Bob agreed to reduce her 6% commission by 16-2/3%. If Broker Bob agreed, how much commission would he receive?",hint:"$200,000 x 15% = $30,000. $200,000 - $30,000 = $170,000 (amount of the offer). 16-2/3% = 1/6 (memorize this). 6% reduced by 1/6 = 5% commission. $170,000 x 5% = $8,500 commission to Broker Bob.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$8,500",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$10,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$9,180",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10,800",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Jane purchased a house for $100,000 with a down payment of 25% of the purchase price. The balance was financed on a 30-year amortized loan with interest at 8% per annum. The lender requires monthly impounds for property taxes of $1,000 per year and casualty insurance costing $788 for a three year policy. Assuming that the first monthly payment on the principal is $217, the total amount the buyer will have to pay the first month will be approximately:",hint:"$100,000 x 25% = $25,000 cash down payment. $100,000 - $25,000 = $75,000 loan amount. $75,000 x 8% = $6,000 annual interest. $6,000 divided by 12 = $500 monthly interest. $788 divided by 36 = $21.89 monthly insurance. $1,000 divided by 12 = $83.33 monthly taxes. $500 + $21.89 + $83.33 + $217 principal = $822.22 total first month payment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$989.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,063.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$822.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$827",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Jim purchased a property for 20% less than the listed price. Later he sold the property for the original listed price. What percentage profit did he make?",hint:"If a property were listed at $150,000 and it was purchased at 20% discount, the purchase price was $120,000. The property is then sold for the list price, $150,000. $150,000 (selling price) - $120,000 (purchase price) = $30,000 (profit) divided by $120,000 = .25 or 25%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"25%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"20%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"35%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"45%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Property "A" has a monthly gross income of $500. Property "B" has a monthly gross income of $900. Using a monthly gross multiplier of 120 and calculating the difference in value between the two properties, the result would be:',hint:"$500 x 120 = $60,000. $900 x 120 = $108,000. $108,000 - $60,000 = $48,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$48,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$36,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$30,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$70,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An owner of a home listed it at a price which would leave him $16,800 after the broker received a 6% commission. If the broker sold the property at the listed price, how much commission would he receive?",hint:"$16,800 divided by 94% = $17,872 - $16,800 = $1,072 commission.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,088.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,193.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,072.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$1,064.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"There was fire insurance on a building valued at $12,000. The cost of the policy was $166.40 for a three-year period. The policy became effective on March 1, 1992. On November 16, 1992, the owner sold the building and canceled the policy. What was the value of the unused portion of the policy?",hint:"$166.40 divided by 36 = $4.62 x 8.5 = $39.27. $166.40 - $39.27 = $127.13.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$116.60",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$127.13",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$123.10",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$125.50",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Bob took a listing providing for a 6% commission on the sales price of $210,000. Sue made an offer at the listed price, but did not complete the transaction. The seller declared a forfeiture of the 5% deposit. A provision in the deposit receipt provides that the broker will receive half of the buyer's deposit in the event of the buyer's default. Under these circumstances, the broker is entitled to:",hint:"$210,000 x 5% = $10,500 divided by 2 = $5,250.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$10,500.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$12,600.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$6,300.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$5,250.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Jim purchased a home for $85,000, with a $25,000 down payment and financed the balance with a $60,000 straight note. He then sold the property for double the purchase price, paying no principal or interest payments on the loan during his ownership. Each dollar invested is now worth?",hint:"$85,000 x 2 = $170,000 new selling price. $170,000 - $60,000 loan = $110,000 profit. $110,000 (profit) divided by $25,000 (invested) = $4.40.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2.20",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$4.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$4.60",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$4.40",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Ted paid $85,000 for a house, putting up a 15% cash down payment and borrowing the balance at 8.5% interest. The loan is payable over 30 years with monthly payments of $560, including principal and interest. If Ted makes the payments as scheduled, the percentage that the original cost of the house increased because of the use of credit is?",hint:"$560 x 360 months = $201,600 (loan payments). $85,000 x 15% = $12,750 (down payment). $201,600 + $12,750 = $214,350 (total cost). $214,350 divided by $85,000 x 100 = 252.2%. 252.2% - 100% (original cost) = 152.2% increase.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"75%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"120%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"162%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"152.2%",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A lender loans borrower Smith a sum of $1,800 and takes back a note and deed of trust. The note was set up to be fully amortized over a 1-year period, interest at 8% per year, payable at $162 per month. When the note was drawn, it was immediately sold to an investor for a 15% discount. If the loan were fully paid off at the end of the year, what percent return would the investor make on this investment?",hint:"12 monthly payments x $162 per month (includes principal and interest) = $1,944 total amount received. $1,800 x 15% (discount) = $270. $1,800 - $270 = $1,530 (cost to investor). $1,944 (amount received) - $1,530 (cost to investor) = $414 profit made. $414 divided by $1,530 x 100 = 27% return.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"9%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"24%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"23%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"27%",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Bob owns a home, which is free and clear. He recently purchased a new home. The contract to purchase the new home however, has a contingency that Bob's current home be sold within 60 days and that Bob net $19,500 from the sale after all expenses have been deducted. Bob employs broker Jones to assist him in the sale of the property. The broker is to receive a 6% commission and there will be an escrow fee of $300. How much must the home in Irvine sell for in order to net Bob $19,500?",hint:"$19,500 cash (net to owner after expenses) + 300 cash (to cover escrow fee) = $19,800 total cash needed except for the cash needed to pay the 6% commission. Therefore $19,800 represents 94% of what the selling price should be. $19,800 divided by 94% = $21,063.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$19,916",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$19,928",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$20,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$21,063",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An income property has a value of $400,000 and returns a net of 8% to its owner. What would the value of this property be to a new purchaser who wished to receive an 10% return on his money?",hint:"The trick is getting the NET INCOME. The net income is determined by recognizing that the property nets its present owner 8% of $400,000 which is $32,000 (400,000 x 8% = $32,000). Now knowing the net income is $32,000 and the investor wants and 10% return on a property with a $32,000 net, you divide the $32,000 (net income) by 10% (the cap rate) to get $320,000 (the appraised value).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$200,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$266,667",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$320,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$160,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Jim bought a second trust deed and note that had a face amount of $1,800 on which he was allowed a 20% discount. If he received payments of $120 per month, including 8% interest, for 1 year, what was his percentage of return on his investment?",hint:"$1,800 x 20% = $360. $1,800 - $360 = $1,440. $120 x 12 = $1,440 - $1,440 = 0. No return on this investment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"No return was received on the investment",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"29%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"31%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"36-1/4%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Steve bought a piece of property for 25% less than the listed price. He later sold it for the listed price. His gain was:",hint:"If the listing price is $100,000, 25% less would be $75,000. Later selling at $100,000 would be a gain of $25,000 divided by $75,000 = .33 (33%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"33%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"20%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"John has a loan for $18,000 with interest to be paid at the rate of $225 quarterly. What is the interest rate on the loan?",hint:"225 x 4 = 900 divided by 18,000 = .05 (5%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"3% but less than 4%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4% but less than 5%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"5% but less than 6%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"6% but less than 7%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mary sold her house and took back a second trust deed for $5,400. She immediately sold it for $4,050. What was the rate of discount?",hint:"$5,400 - $4,050 = $1,350 (amount discounted) divided by $5,400 = .25 (25%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"28%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"35%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"65%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A real estate investor purchased a property for $15,000. He paid $5,000 down and executed a non-interest bearing note for $10,000 in favor of the seller. Before the end of the first year and before he had made any principal payments, he sold the property for double what he paid for it. Each $1.00 of his investment is now worth?",hint:"The owner's equity is based upon the difference in value and loan amount. $30,000 - $10,000 = $20,000. $20,000 / $5,000 = $4. His $5,000 investment is now worth $20,000 or $4 for each $1 invested.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$4.00",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$9.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11.00",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property is valued at $35,000 and is insured for $30,000 at a rate of 15 cents per $100. The premium for a 3-year policy is 2-1/2 times the premium for 1 year. For a 3-year policy, the monthly cost will be:",hint:"$30,000 divided by 100 = 300 x .15 = $45.00 (per year) x 2.5 = $112.50 (3 years). $112.50 divided by 36 = $3.13 per month.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$3.33.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3.13.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2.72.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2.64.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Sue sold her property for $27,500 and realized a 7% profit over what she paid for it. Her profit was:",hint:"The selling price of $27,500 = cost + 7% or 107% of selling price. $27,500 divided by 107% = $25,700 purchase price. $27,500 - $25,700 = $1,800 profit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$3,520.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,811.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,800.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$3,872.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man purchases a $8,000 straight note for $6,500. Interest rate on the note is 5%. What was his percentage of profit made on his investment if the note is paid off in one year?",hint:"$8,000 x .05 = $400. $8,000 - $6,500 = $1,500. $400 + $1,500 = $1,900 divided by $6,500 = .292 (29.2%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"29.2%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"11.1%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"17.8%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Inventory in a store costs $8,500 net. It was sold for 20% profit. However, 10% of the gross profit was lost due to bad credit risks over a period of one year. How much profit did the store owner make that year?",hint:"$8,500 x .20 = $1,700 x .10 = $170. $1,700 - $170 = $1,530.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,955",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,530",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$345",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Fred pays $16,240 for a home. If it costs 10% to sell his home before he could sell it at a profit, how much would it have to appreciate?",hint:"100% (sales price) - 10% = 90% or $16,240 purchase price. $16,240 divided by 90% = $18,044.44. $18,044.44 - $16,240 = $1,804.44.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2,078.18",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"100%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"34%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,804.44",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Ms. Williams purchased a house in a run-down condition and spent an amount equal to 10% of the purchase to fix it up and bring it to its present value. The house in now worth $18,700. The cost of the house is equal to the existing loan of the property. The amount of the loan is:",hint:"$18,700 = 100% purchase price + 10% fix-up money. $18,700 divided by 110% = $17,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$15,800.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$17,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$15,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,450.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"What would the transfer tax be on the sale of a lot that sold for $10,500 with a loan assumed at $10,400?",hint:"Transfer tax is paid on the difference between the selling price and any existing trust deeds that are assumed by the buyer in excess of $100. The first $100 is exempt.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"0",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"55 cents",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A lot sold for $18,950. This included a profit of 7%. The original cost of the home was approximately?",hint:"$18,950 divided by 1.07 = $17,710.28. Closest answer is $17,700.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$15,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,400",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$17,700",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Cindy purchased a lot for $40,000. She has been asked to build an apartment house with a projected income of $20,000 per year. Her accountant estimates all expenses, including proper management, repairs, etc., to be $12,000 per year. Cindy wants a 10% return on her investment. Which of the following is nearest to the amount she can afford to pay for the erection of the building?",hint:'$20,000 (annual gross income) - $12,000 (expenses) = $8,000 (annual net income) divided by .10 = $80,000 (value of building and land). $80,000 - $40,000 = $40,000 for erection of the building. Closest answer available is "A."',answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$50,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$100,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$110,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$120,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"John buys a piece of property as an investment for $15,000. John's capital investment is $5,000. He pays 5% interest on a loan of $10,000, and the property appreciates 8%. After one year the property is sold. What percent of profit did he realize on his initial invested capital?",hint:"$15,000 x 8% = $1,200. $10,000 x 5% = $500. $1,200 - $500 = $700 (profit). $700 divided by $5,000 (investment) = 14%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"12%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"14%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The entire stock of a retail store was sold for $9,400 to Bill Smith. Mr. Smith then sold the stock for 20% more than he paid for it, but due to some debts he lost 10% of the selling price. The net profit on Mr. Smith's' investment was:",hint:"$9,400 x 20% = $1,880 (profit). $9,400 + $1,880 = $11,280 x 10% (loss) = $1,128 loss. $11,280 - $1,128 = $10,152 (sales price less 10% loss). $10,152 - $9,400 (purchase price) = $752 (net profit).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$752.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2,100.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,925.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"15%.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'A deposit receipt states, "Buyer to assume existing first trust deed of $9,600 at 5-1/2% paid per quarter." If Mr. Taylor took possession February 15th and the first interest payment was due on March 15th, how much would Mr. Taylor pay on the next interest date?',hint:"$9,600 x 5-1/2% = $528.00 interest per year. $528 divided by 12 (months) = $44 interest per month. $44 x 3 (1/4 of a year) = $132.00 per quarter.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$132.00",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$520.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$43.33",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A loan was made for $15,000 at an interest rate of 5% per year for a 20-year period. The total interest that would be paid over the entire loan period if the monthly payment for this fully amortized loan is $6.50 per $1,000, would be approximately:",hint:"$6.50 per $1,000 x 15 (thousand) = $97.50 monthly payment. 20 years x 12 months = 240 monthly payments. $97.50 x 240 = $23,400.00. $23,400.00 - $15,000 (money borrowed) = $8,400.00 total interest paid.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$18,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$16,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,400.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$14,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume Mr. Willis owns his home but he borrowed money to buy it with a loan payable at $112.44 per month. The balance on the loan for the last month was $16,000. $32.44 was applied on his principle on his last payment. What was the interest rate on the note in these circumstances?",hint:"$112.44 (monthly payment) - $32.44 (principal part of payment) = $80.00 (interest). $80.00 x 12 months = $960 interest per 1 year. $960 divided by $16,000 (loan balance) = 6%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"16.6%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"5-1/4%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"9.2%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Several years ago, Mr. Matthews bought property for $12,000, paying $2,000 in cash with the seller taking back a trust deed for the balance of the purchase price. Before any payments had been made on the trust deed note, he sold the property several months later for $24,000. His invested dollar in these circumstances is worth:",hint:"$12,000 (purchase price) - $2,000 (cash paid) = $10,000 (trust deed). $24,000 (sales price) - $10,000 (trust deed) = $14,000 (cash from sale). $14,000 divided by $2,000 = $7.00.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$7.00.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$11.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10.10.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1.10.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A buyer assumed a note secured by a deed of trust. The balance of the note was $11,000 with an annual interest rate of 6-1/2% payable quarterly. The interest on the note was to be prorated upon possession of the property. If the interest on the note had been paid to March 15, and he took possession February 15, he would owe how much prorated interest?",hint:"One month's interest from February 15 to March 15. $11,000 x .065 = $715 per year divided by 12 = $59.58 per month.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$168.75",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$59.58",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$675.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"How much money would have to be invested at 8% interest to provide an income of $140.00 per month?",hint:"$140 x 12 = $1,680 per year. $1,680 divided by 8% = $21,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$9,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$25,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$20,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$21,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Jay sold his lot for $25,000. This selling price represented a 25% profit over what he had originally paid for it. What was the original price of the lot?",hint:"$25,000 divided by 125% = $20,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$20,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$19,550",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$27,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property was sold on these terms: Selling price $35,000, $10,000 cash down payment, buyer to deposit proceeds of an $158,000 loan secured by a first trust deed and note, buyer to execute a note in favor of the seller for $10,000 secured by a second deed of trust. What amount of revenue stamps must be purchased prior to the recording of the deed?",hint:"He must pay transfer tax on the selling price of the house less any old loans assumed. There is no old loans assumed, therefore the tax is on the full selling price. $35,000 divided by $1,000 x $1.10 = $38.50.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$38.50",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$27.50",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$25.30",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None required on this transaction",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Stevens received a straight loan on which he paid only the interest at 6%, all due and payable in one year. His monthly interest payment was $23.00. What was the amount of the loan?",hint:"$23.00 x 12 = $276 divided by .06 = $4,600.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$3,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$4,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$5,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$4,600",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A buyer is purchasing a single family residence for $175,000 and assuming an existing loan of $125,000. If the documentary transfer tax is computed on the basis of $.55 for $500, the amount of the tax will be:",hint:"To determine the amount of the documentary transfer tax, you need to first find out the amount of the new money in the transaction. To do this you subtract any existing loan that the buyer is taking over from the sales price of the property. The amount of money left over is the new money and is the amount on which the tax is computed. $175,000 - $125,000 = $50,000 divided by $500 = 100 x $.55 = $55.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$55.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$179.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$33.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Johnson listed his home with Broker Smith for $165,000 with a commission rate of 6%. Broker Smith brought an offer at 10% less than the listed price. Mr. Johnson said he would accept the offer if the broker reduced his commission by 16-2/3%. If they all agreed to these terms, what amount of commission would Broker Smith receive?",hint:"16-2/3% is 1/6. 1/6 of 6% is 1% (so total commission is 5%). $165,000 x 90% (100% - 10%) = $148,500 selling price. $148,500 x 5% = $7,425.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$5,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,250",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$7,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$7,425",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A man paid $9,500 for the stock in trade of a retail business. He sold it for 25% more than he paid for it. If he lost 15% of the gross sale price because of credit risks, the net profit on his original investment would be:",hint:"$9,500 x 25% = $2,375. $9,500 + $2,375 = $11,875 x .15 = $1,781.25. $11,875 - $1,781.25 = $10,093.75 - $9,500 = $593.75.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$593.75.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"85%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,375.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"18-1/3%.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ken purchased a property for $16,380. If he wants to sell it without a loss for a price which would include a 9% commission, the value of the property would have to appreciate:",hint:"$16,380 divided by .91 = $18,000. $18,000 - $16,380 = $1,620.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"24%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,940.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"17%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,620.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What is the salesman's 40% of a 6% commission on a $32,000 sale?",hint:"$32,000 x .06 = $1,920 x .40 = $768.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$768.60",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$841.80",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$837.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man needed money to purchase a new car and had a real estate broker arrange a fully amortized 3-year loan using his home as security. The note was for $2,500 calling for payments of $80.00 per month, including 10% interest. If the borrower received $1,900 cash proceeds from the loan after deducting all expenses, the total amount of principal that must be paid to the lender on the note is:",hint:"Since the borrower signed a note for $2,500, he will be required to pay back this amount of principal plus the interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2,500.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$3,120.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,772.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,980.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A homeowner paid 4 points for a bank loan. The bank sold the loan to an insurance company at 5-1/2 point discount and received a check for $15,000. The original amount of the loan was:",hint:"100% - 5.5% = 94.5%. $15,000 divided by 94.5% = $15,873.02.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$15,054.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,648.72.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,563.63.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,873.02.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"To buy a car, Bob executed a second trust deed and note on his home for $2,600, payable at $66.00 per month, including interest at 8%. When he sold his home, he paid off the entire loan balance of $1,989.50. What was the total face amount of the principal on the loan?",hint:"The face amount of the loan is the amount of the original amount on the note.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2,600",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2,772",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,989.50",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If a person borrowed $10,000 on a straight note and paid $50 interest every 90 days, what would be the interest rate?",hint:"$50 x 4 = $200 interest per year divided by $10,000 = 2%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"10%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"8%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"6.6%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Steve purchased a note worth $6,000 for $5,500. Interest rate on the note is 5%. What was his percentage of profit made on his investment if the note is paid off in one year?",hint:"$6,000 x .05 = $300. $6,000 - $5,500 = $500. $300 + $500 = $800 divided by $5,500 = .145 (14.5%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"6.7%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"14.5%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"17.8%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Inventory in a store costs $8,500 net. It was sold for 25% profit. However, 15% of the gross profit was lost due to bad credit risks over a period of one year. How much profit did the store owner make that year?",hint:"$8,500 x .25 = $2,125 x .15 = $318.75. $2,125 - $318.75 = $1,806.25.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,955",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$920",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$345",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Assume a second trust deed has a face amount of $6,000, payable at $75 a month plus 8.2% interest per year. What would be the amount of the interest due on the first monthly payment?",hint:"$6,000 x .082 equals $492 interest for one year. $492 divided by 12 = $41 first month's interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$24",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$28.20",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$41",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$65",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An individual sold his property for $40,000 and realized a 10% profit over what he paid for it. His profit was:",hint:"The selling price of $40,000 = cost + 10% or 110% of selling price. $40,000 divided by 110% = $36,363 (cost). $40,000 - $36,363 = $3,637 profit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$3,520.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,811.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,637.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$3,872.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Jerry spends 25% of her gross monthly income on her apartment rent of $600. What is her gross monthly income?",hint:"$600 divided by 25% = $2,400.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,400",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,420",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Frank just sold his house for 6% more than he paid for it. The selling price was $140,450. What was the original purchase price?",hint:"$140,450 divided by 106% = $132,500.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$120,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$124,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$130,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$132,500",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"How much interest would a $6,000 loan earn in five years at 10% simple interest?",hint:"$6,000 x 10% = $600 per year x 5 years = $3,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$3,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Tom obtains an interest-only purchase money loan for $60,000. The interest rate is 9.5% and the term is 30 years. How much interest will Tom have paid at the end of the 30-year term?",hint:"$60,000 x 9.5% = $5,700 interest per year. $5,700 x 30 years = $171,000 total interest.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$171,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$17,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,700",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,710,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property is sold for $125,000. If the lender charges a 2% loan fee for an 80% loan, what is the amount of the fee?",hint:"$125,000 x 80% = $100,000 amount of loan. 100,000 x 2% loan fee = 2,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,350",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$1,080",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man has an investment in a 30-unit rental property which was adjacent to a freeway. Because of its proximity to the freeway, the owner lost $250 per month in rent. If the capitalization rate were set at 15%, the loss in value to the property was:",hint:"$250 x 12 = $3,000 divided by .15 = $20,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2,400.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$20,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$24,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A man purchased income property for $240,000, which was returning 8% per annum on the gross investment. He paid $20,000 down, the balance on a long term straight loan on which he paid interest annually at 6%. Disregarding other expenses, the return on his equity was:",hint:"Divide his net return by his equity. $240,000 x .08 = $19,200 gross. $240,000 - $20,000 = $220,000 x .06 = $13,200 expense. $19,200 - $13,200 = $6,000 net divided by $20,000 = .3 (30%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"8%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"48%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"36%.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Jane purchased a home for $150,000. She received a loan from the bank for 75% of the purchase price, payable at $1,600 per month including 10% interest. She then sold the home for $165,000 before she even made the first payment on the loan. What was her equity at the time of the sale?",hint:"$150,000 x 75% = $112,500 loan amount. $165,000 - $112,500 loan = $52,500 equity.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$12,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$14,750",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$52,500",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$125,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Jay is the beneficiary on a trust deed. The annual interest rate is 8%. If in 5 years he has received $4,500 in interest, what is the principal amount of the loan?",hint:"$4,500 divided by 5 years = $900 interest per year. $900 divided by 8% = $11,250 principal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$5,460",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11,050",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11,250",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$65,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ted borrowed $40,000 from a bank to purchase a lot. He paid 4 points to get the loan. The loan contained a 4% prepayment penalty. His monthly payment was $160.00, including interest at 8% per year. Five years later, John sold this real estate and paid-off the loan. If the loan had an average loan balance of $38,500 during the five years Ted owned the property, what was the bank's gross profit on this loan?",hint:"$40,000 x 4% = $1,600 points. $40,000 x 4% = $1,600 prepayment penalty. $38,500 x 8% = $3,080 interest per year. $3,080 x 5 years = $15,400. $1,600 + $1,600 + $15,400 = $18,600 gross profit by bank.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$18,600.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$7,248.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,600.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$9,999.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ned, a salesperson working for Broker George, received a 45% share of a 8% commission. His share came to $9,000. What was the selling price of the property?",hint:"$9,000 commission divided by 45% share = $20,000 total commission. $20,000 divided by 8% = $250,000 selling price.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$100,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$150,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$250,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$300,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mike sold his home and carried back a $35,500 second trust deed. He immediately sold the loan at a discount to an investor and received $30,000. What was the rate of discount?",hint:"$30,000 divided by $35,500 = .845 (84.5%). 100% - 84.5% = 15.5% discount.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"25%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"15.5%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A lender charged the borrower 2 points for making a loan. The lender then sold the loan immediately to an investor at a discount of 4-1/2 percent and received $35,800. What was the original loan amount?",hint:"$35,800 divided by 95.5% = $37,486.91. Note the 2 points have nothing to do with answering this question.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$35,750",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$37,487",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$36,350",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$37,987",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker John and Broker Jay agreed to divide a 4 1/2% commission equally on the sale of a home, which sold for $180,000. Sue, the listing salesperson, works for Broker John on a 50-50 commission split. Sue would receive approximately how much commission as a result of the sale?",hint:"$180,000 x 4 1/2% = $8,100 total commission. $8,100 divided by 2 = $4,050 commission to Broker John's office. $4,050 divided by 2 = $2,025 commission to Sue.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,828",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,828",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,025",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$7,312",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Steve sold his home which had no loans against it. He received a settlement check from escrow for the amount of $96,400 after paying escrow fees of $1,365.00 plus a 6% real estate broker's commission. What was the selling price?",hint:"$96,400 + $1,365.80 = $97,765.00 net amount after paying commission. $97,765.00 divided by 94% = $104,005.32 selling price.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$104,005",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$96,857",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$97,995",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$98,970",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Lynn sold a home for $27,000. She made a 15% profit. What did the home cost?",hint:"$27,000 divided by 115% = $23,478.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$18,333",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$20,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$20,833.33",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$23,478",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Johnson bought a house for $64,500. He later sold the house and broke even, after paying 8% of the selling price in commission, and escrow fees. How much had the lot increased in value?",hint:"$64,500 divided by 92% = $70,109 selling price. $70,109 - $64,500 = $5,609 increase in value in order to break even.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"12%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$6,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$8,640",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$5,609",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The regular monthly payment on a loan, including principal and interest, was $560. All of the payment went toward interest, except for $45. The principal balance on the loan during that month was $55,500. What was the interest rate?",hint:"$560 - $45 principal payment = $515 interest payment. $515 x 12 months = $6,180 annual interest. $6,180 divided by $55,500 loan balance = .1114 = 11.14% interest rate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"8%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"9-1/2%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"11.14%",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Ben sold two parcels of land for $9,775 which was 15% higher than their cost four years ago. While Ben owned the parcels, he paid taxes each year at a rate of $7.00 per $100 on an assessed value of 30% of the purchase price. Assuming an annual loss of 4% imputed interest on Ben's original investment as an expense, how much did Ben lose on the transaction?",hint:"$9,775 divided by 115% (1.15) = $8,500 original cost. $8,500 x 30% (.30) = $2,550 assessed value. $2,550 divided by 100 = 25.5. 25.5 x $7.00 = $178.50 annual property taxes. $178.50 x 4 = $714 taxes. $8,500 + $714 + $1,360 ($8,500 x 4% x 4 years) = $10,574 total cost. $10,574 - $9,775 = $799 loss.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$650",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$885",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$799",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Frank purchased a home for $80,000. He financed the purchase with a 90% conventional fixed-rate loan. The loan fee charged by the lender was 2%. The private mortgage insurance company charged a .50% first-year premium and a .75% renewal premium. What was the loan fee? The first-year premium? The monthly renewal premium?",hint:"Loan fee = $80,000 x 90% x 2% = $1,440. First year premium = $80,000 x 90% x .5% = $360. Monthly renewal = $80,000 x 90% x .75% divided by 12 = $45.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,782.75; $586.10; $17.90",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,580; $505.60; $18.43",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,975; $632; $23.04",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,440; $360; $45",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Dick purchased a home for $118,600 and arranges to finance the purchase with a 90% loan. The terms of the loan are 10.75% annual interest, a 2% loan fee, and a three point discount. What is the amount of the loan fee and the discount?",hint:"$118,606 x 90% = $106,740 (amount of loan) x 2% (loan fee) = $2,135. $106,740 x 3% (discount) = $3,202.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,913; $4,660",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,335; $4,194",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,135; $3,202",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$1,201; $4,660",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property sold for $110,000. Buyer Tom financed 90%. Approximately how much will the monthly PMI increase his payment if the renewal rate is .30%?",hint:"$110,000 x 90% = $99,000 (amount of loan) x .30% = $297 yearly renewal rate. 297 divided by 12 = 24.75 monthly increase.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$20.10",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15.41",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10.50",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$24.75",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"The Bakers bought a vacation home with a $90,000 first mortgage. Current conventional rates are 10.5%, 30-year term. The seller agreed to pay three points, which will amount to:",hint:"$90,000 x 3% = $2,700.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2,100.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,400.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,800.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,700.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Dave financed a $120,000 home with an 80% first mortgage from his local credit union, a 10% second mortgage from the seller and a 10% down payment. The seller offered terms of 9.5% INTEREST ONLY on the second mortgage. What are Johnson's monthly payments on the second mortgage?",hint:"$120,000 x 10% = $12,000 (2nd mortgage amount). 12,000 x 9.5% = $1,140 divided by 12 = $95.00.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$146.92",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$132.12",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$95.00",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$186.37",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property is sold for $125,000, subject to the seller's existing loan with a balance of $75,000. The amount of the documentary transfer tax due on the sale is:",hint:"Documentary transfer tax is paid at a rate of $1.10 per 1,000 of new money. Therefore, 125,000 - 75,000 = 50,000 amount subjected to documentary transfer tax. 50,000 divided by 1,000 x $1.10 = $55.00.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$55.00.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$49.50.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$132.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$82.50.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A $5,000 investment at 10% interest compounded annually earns how much in three years?",hint:"$5,000 x 10% = $500 (interest for 1st year). $5,000 + $500 = $5,500 x 10% = $550 (interest for the 2nd year). $5,500 + $550 = $6,050 x 10% = $605 (interest for the 3rd year). $500 + $550 + $605 = $1,655 interest earned in 3 years. Remember, compound interest is interest on the principal and prior interest earned.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,200",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,655",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$1,400",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,525",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"John bought a house four years ago for $80,000. He just sold it for $86,900. What was the percent of profit?",hint:"$86,900 - $80,000 = $6,900 (profit) divided by $80,000 = .086 (8.6%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"8.6%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"10%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"15%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ned just sold his house for 9% less than he paid for it. The selling price was $105,900. What was the original purchase price?",hint:"$105,900 represents 91% of the original price. $105,900 divided by 91% = $116,373.63(original purchase price).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$111,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$116,374",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$112,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$110,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. White sold an apartment building for $139,000. This was 20% more than what he paid for it. His original cost was approximately:",hint:"Divide $139,000 by 120% to produce an answer of $115,833.33.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$114,200.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$115,833.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$144,176.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"there is insufficient information to arrive at an answer",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'An offer said, "Seller to take back a second mortgage securing the note for $12,400, payable at $200.00 or more per month, including interest at 9% per annum from May 15, 1989." If the first payment date on the second mortgage is June 15, 1989, how much of the regular payment will go to principal reduction?',hint:"$12,400 loan amount x 9% annual interest rate = $1,116 annual interest. $1,116 annual interest divided by 12 months = $93 first month's interest. $200 monthly payment - $93 first month's interest = $107 first month's principal.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$80.00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$173.50",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$184.50",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$107",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"What percentage profit would an investor make if he purchased two lots for $16,000 each and then divided into three lots and sold them for $14,000 each?",hint:"$16,000 x 2 = $32,000 cost of lots. $14,000 x 3 = $42,000 selling price. $42,000 - $32,000 = $10,000 profit. $10,000 divided by $32,000 = 31.25% profit.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"31%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"21%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"15%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A $7,000 loan is sold to an investor for $6,500. It is a straight note, due and payable at the end of one year. It bears a 9% interest rate. What percentage return on the principal dollar invested will be made by the investor?",hint:"$7,000 x 9% = $630 interest paid on the loan. $7,000 - $6,500 = $500 made by investor as a result of the discount. $630 + $500 = $1,130 total profit made by investor. $1,130 divided by $6,500 = 17.38%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"17.38%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"11%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"17.8%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The principal balance on a loan is currently $58,500. The scheduled monthly payment on the loan, including principal and interest, is $550. All of the payment goes toward interest, except for $46. What is the interest rate?",hint:"$550 - $46 principal payment = $504 interest payment. $504 x 12 months = $6,048 annual interest. $6,048 divided by $58,500 loan balance = .1034 (10.34%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"9%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"9.5%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10.34%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"12.75%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Johnson purchased a home for $79,000 with a $19,000 cash down payment and a $60,000 loan. This loan was interest free and required no payments of principal for five years. One year later he sold the home for double its purchase price. Each dollar of his original cash investment now equals:",hint:"$79,000 x 2 = $158,000. $158,000 - $60,000 = $98,000. $98,000 divided by $19,000 = $5.16.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$4.60.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$7.30.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$5.16.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"In order to earn $250 per month, the amount an investor would have to invest at 6% is:",hint:"$250 income x 12 months = $3,000 annual income. $3,000 annual income divided by 6% rate of return = $50,000 total required investment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$15,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$50,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$22,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$30,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A buyer purchased a home for $125,000 putting up a good down payment of 20% of the purchase price, and financing the balance on a 25-year amortized loan with interest at 8.25% per annum. The bank requires monthly impounds for property taxes of $750 per year and casualty insurance costing $945 for a three year policy. Assuming that the first monthly payment on the principal is $155, the total amount the buyer will have to pay the first month will be approximately:",hint:"$125,000 x 20% = $25,000 cash down payment. $125,000 - $25,000 = $100,000 loan amount. $100,000 x 8.25% = $8,250 annual interest. $8.250 divided by 12 = $687.50 monthly interest. $945 divided by 36 = $26.25 monthly insurance. $750 divided by 12 = $62.50 monthly taxes. $687.50 + $26.25 + $62.50 + $155 principal = $931.25 total first month payment.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$931.25.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$357.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$751.00.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$827.00.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An individual borrowed $9,000 on a straight note and an interest of 7%. If the total interest paid on the note totaled $840.00, the term of the loan was:",hint:"To determine this, you multiply $9,000 times 7%, which equals $630.00 interest per year. Next $630.00 divided by 12 equals $52.50 per month. And finally $840.00 total interest divided by $52.50 equals 16 months.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"14 months.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"16 months.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"18 months.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20 months.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Broker Bob leased a commercial property for 30 years at a rent of $26,000 per year. His commission was 9% of the first year rent, 7% of the rent for years 2 through 5, 4% of the rent for years 6 through 10, and 2% of the rent for years 11 through 30. Assuming all the commission is paid to him as per this schedule, what is the total commission he will receive?",hint:"$26,000 x 9% = $2,340 (first year commission). $26,000 x 7% = $1,820 (per year 2, 3, 4, 5). $1,820 x 4 = $7,280 (total commission for years 2-5). $26,000 x 4% = $1,040 (per year 6, 7, 8, 9, 10). $1,040 x 5 = $5,200 (total commission for years 6-10). $26,000 x 2% = $520 (per year 11-30). $520 x 20 years = $10,400 (total commission for years 11-30). $2,340 + $7,280 + $5,200 + $10,400 = $25,220 total commission.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$5,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$25,220",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$10,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$20,500",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A 120-room building has 14 1-bedroom units renting monthly at $150.00. 12 2-bedroom units at $200.00, and 8 3-bedroom units at $250.00. The gross annual rental would be?",hint:"$150 x 14 = $2,100. 200 x 12 = $2,400. 250 x 8 = $2,000. $2,100 + $2,400 + $2,000 = $6,500 x 12 = $78,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$78,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$58,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$66,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"None of these",isCorrect:!1}]}}]},{category:"Math Economic",id:12,list:[{questionText:"A parcel of land was purchased in 1985 and subdivided into four separate lots. Five years later, each lot sold for $200,000. The adjusted basis for each lot was $10,000. What was the capital gain on these transactions?",hint:"$10,000 x 4 lots = $40,000 adjusted basis. $200,000 x 4 lots = $800,000 total selling price. $800,000 - $40,000 = $760,000 capital gain.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$40,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$760,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$400,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$800,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"In order to be able to earn $90.00 per month from an investment that yields a 6% return, you must invest?",hint:"$90.00 per month x 12 = $1,080 per year. $1,080 divided by .06 = $18,000. Remember to work the problem using the annual income and the annual interest rate.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$2,500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$9,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$15,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$18,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A buyer wants a 8% return on his investment and he is interested in a retail center that produces a net operating income of $75,000 per year, what would the investor be willing to pay for the center?",hint:"Divide the net income, $75,000 by the capitalization rate, 8% to get $937,500.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$937,500",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$630,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$900,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11,250,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"To receive a 12% return on an investment of $750,000, what would be the required net operating income?",hint:"Net income = purchase price x capitalization rate. $750,000 x 12% = $90,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$6,250,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$625,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$90,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$900,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A building that has an effective gross income of $65,000 and total operating expenses of $6,500 has a net income ratio of:",hint:"$65,000 (gross income) - $6,500 (operating expenses) = $58,500 (net income) divided by $65,000 = .90.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:".16.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:".10.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:".90.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:".19.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If an income property is valued at $250,000 using a 6% capitalization rate, how much would an investor pay for the property if he demanded a 10% capitalization rate?",hint:"$250,000 x 6% = $15,000 annual net income. $15,000 divided by 10% = $150,000. Remember, as capitalization rate goes up, the value goes down.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$225,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$150,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$300,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$500,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The estimated remaining economic life of a building is 25 years. What is the annual recapture rate using the straight-line method?",hint:"100% (total depreciation) divided by 25 years = 4% depreciation per year.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"25%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"40%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"400%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Susan had two lots which she sold for $10,000. The sale gave her a 20% profit over their cost four years ago. While she owned the lots, she paid property taxes each year at a rate of $8.00 per $100 of an assessed value of 25% of their purchase price. She suffered an annual loss of 6% imputed interest on her original investment as an expense. How much did she gain or lose in this transaction?",hint:"$10,000 / 1.2 (120%) = $8,333 original cost. $8,333 x 0.25 (25%) = $2,083 assessed value. $2,083 x 0.08 (8%) = $167 annual property tax. $167 x 4 = $667 property taxes for 4 years. $8,333 x 0.06 (6%) = $500 imputed interest. $500 x 4 = $2,000 imputed interest for 4 years. $2,000 + $667 = $2,667 total expenses. $2,667 + $8,333 = $11,000 total cost. $11,000 - $10,000 = $1,000 loss.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$420 loss",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,000 loss",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$533 gain",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,000 gain",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property had improvements totaling $200,000; annual net income before recapture of depreciation of $40,000; and economic life of improvements equal to 40 years. Applying the land residual technique using straight line depreciation and an interest rate of 10% results in:",hint:"$200,000 divided by 40 years = $5,000 annual depreciation. $40,000 - $5,000 = $35,000 net income depreciation recapture. $35,000 divided by 10% = $350,000 value of land and improvements. $350,000 - $200,000 = $150,000 land value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$50,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$75,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$150,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$125,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The original value of a property was $130,000, with the land valued at $20,000. If the economic life of the improvements were estimated to be 30 years using the straight line approach, what was the book value of the property after 15 years?",hint:"$130,000 - $20,000 = $110,000. $110,000 divided by 30 years = $3,666.67. $3,666.67 x 15 years = $55,000 depreciation. $130,000 - $55,000 = $75,000 book value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$85,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$55,575",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$65,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$75,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A 40-acre tract was purchased for $500 per acre and divided into 4 parcels. The parcels sold for $6,000 each. What was the percentage return on the purchase price?",hint:"40 x 500 = $20,000 (cost). $6,000 x 4 = $24,000 - $20,000 = $4,000 (profit). $4,000 divided by $20,000 = .20 (20%).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"15%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"25%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"30%",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Two appraisers, one using a capitalization rate of 10% and the other one 8%, both agree that the net income of a building was $11,200. The higher capitalization rate made the price of the building:",hint:"$11,200 divided by 10% = $112,000. $11,200 divided by 8% = $140,000. $140,000 - $112,000 = $28,000 or 20% lower.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"higher by 25%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lower by 20%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$896 lower.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lower by 25%.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Investor Bob bought a piece of income property for $185,000. The listed price was $240,000. He put $10,000 down and acquired a new first trust deed for the difference. The tax assessed value was indicated at $160,000. Investor Bob's cost basis for income tax purposes would be:",hint:"Cost basis for income tax purposes (book value) is the price paid for the property.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$160,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$240,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$185,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"John purchased an income property for $575,000. The land is valued at $200,000. If straight line depreciation is used over a 30 year period, the annual depreciation would be:",hint:"$575,000 - $200,000 = $375,000 (value of improvements). $375,000 divided by 30 years = $12,500 annual depreciation.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$19,166.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$18,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$12,500.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Bill paid $240,000 for some income units. The land was valued at $16,500, and improvements at $35,640. Using the previous figures for depreciation for income tax purposes, which of the following most nearly reflects the depreciable amount?",hint:"$16,500 (land) + $35,640 (improvements) = $52,140. $35,640 divided by $52,140 = .684 (68.4%). $240,000 (total cost) x .684 = $164,160 improvements. Land is not depreciable for tax purposes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$35,640",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$52,140",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$164,160",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$240,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:'Lot "X" is an acre. Lot "Z" is 2/3 of the size of lot "X." Lot Z was purchased for $16,000. The two lots were divided into as many parcels as possible, all measuring 110\' by 82.5\' each. Each parcel was sold for $6,500. The total selling price was 25% profit on the original investment. What was the purchase price of lot "X?"',hint:"1 acre = 43,560 sq. ft. 2/3 of an acre = 29,040 sq. ft. 43,560 + 29,040 = 72,600 sq. ft. 82.5 x 110 = 9,075 sq. ft. per parcel. 72,600 divided by 9,075 = 8 parcels x 6,500 = $52,000 (selling price). $52,000 divided by 125% = 41,600 (original price). $41,600 - $16,000 = $25,600.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$36,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$25,600",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$41,600",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$52,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ted purchased a building for $250,000. The terms of purchase were $175,000 cash, and a purchase money deed of trust for the balance. If the land is valued at $50,000 what is the adjusted cost basis of the property after it is fully depreciated?",hint:"Only the improvements are depreciated. Therefore, after the property has been fully depreciated the adjusted cost basis would still be the original value of the land, $50,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"The remaining balance on the purchase money deed of trust.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$200,000, the value of the improvements.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$50,000, the value of the land.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"It would have no adjusted cost basis as it is fully depreciated.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assume it would cost $16,500 to reproduce an improvement today. The land is valued at $2,000 today. Assuming the improvement is actually 12 years old and the depreciation rate is 2-1/2%, what is the depreciated value today?",hint:"12 years x 2-1/2% = 30% depreciation rate. $16,500 x 30% = $4,950 depreciation. $16,500 - $4,950 = $11,550 remaining value. $11,550 + $2,000 land value = $13,550.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$10,250",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10,750",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$11,550",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$13,550",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Sam paid $310,000 for an income property. His tax bill showed the assessments to be as follows: Land $20,120, improvements $37,200. In arriving at a figure to be used for depreciation for income tax purposes, he used his assessment figures as a basis. Which of the following most nearly reflects the depreciable amount:",hint:"$20,120 (land) + $37,200 (improvement) = $57,320. $37,200 divided by $57,320 = 65% improvement. $310,000 x 65% = $201,500. Land is not depreciable for tax purposes.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$37,200.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$57,320.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$201,500.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$310,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"If building costs increase by 15%, the purchasing power of the investment dollar decreases by:",hint:"$1.00 divided by $1.15 = .87 (87%). Purchasing power is 87% of what it was, which means it has decreased by 13%.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"13%.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"20%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"25%.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"33-1/3%.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Ken, an investor, wants to build a rental property which will have a gross income of $3,200 per month and annual expenses of $6,500. The investors require a 10% capitalization rate on the investment. If the improvements cost $200,000, how much can the investors pay for the land?",hint:"$3,200 x 12 = $38,400 gross annual income. $38,400 - $6,500 (expenses) = $31,900 annual net income. $31,900 divided by 10% (cap rate) = $319,000 total property value (land and improvements). $319,000 - $200,000 = $119,000 available to pay for the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$31,900",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$50,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$119,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$319,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property is valued at $260,000 using a capitalization rate of 10%. What would the value of the same property be using a capitalization rate of 8%?",hint:"$260,000 x .10 = $26,000 divided by .08 = $325,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$210,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$325,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$240,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$220,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Stewart has an investment in a 20-unit apartment building which is adjacent to a freeway. Because of its proximity to the freeway, the owner lost $150 per month rent. If the capitalization rate were set at 8%, the loss in value to the property was:",hint:"12 x $150 = $1,800 divided by 8% = $22,500.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$22,500.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2,400.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$24,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$22,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A 20-unit apartment building is valued at $800,000 based on a 10% capitalization rate. If the rent for each unit increased $20 per month, what would the value of the same building be based on a capitalization rate of 16%?",hint:"$800,000 x .10 = $80,000. 20 units x $20 = $400 per month. $400 x 12 = $4,800 per year. $80,000 + $4,800 = $84,800. $84,800 divided by .16 = $530,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$520,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$530,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$540,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$500,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An apartment's financial statement disclosed the following: Gross income = $20,000; vacancy factor = 9%; operating expenses = $5,000; payments to amortize the existing 1st and 2nd deeds of trust = $300 monthly. Using a 12% capitalization rate, what is the value of the property?",hint:"$20,000 (gross income) - $1,800 (vacancy factor) = $18,200 (effective gross income). $18,200 - $5,000 (operating expenses) = $13,200 (net income). $13,200 divided by .12 (cap. rate) = $110,000. Note: You cannot subtract principal or interest payments on trust deeds. This is not an operating expense.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$110,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$20,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$60,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$100,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"A property is valued at $200,000 using a capitalization rate of 8%. What would the value of the same property be using a capitalization rate of 10%?",hint:"$200,000 x .08 = $16,000 divided by .10 = $160,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$210,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$200,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$160,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$220,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Assuming that the real property taxes on an income property increased $700 per year and all other expenses and income remained the same. The value of the property would decrease by which of the following amounts if you used a capitalization rate of 10%?",hint:"$700 divided by .10 = $7,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$7",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$70",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$700",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$7,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Mr. Jones, an owner of a packaging firm, purchased a new machine in 1991 and paid $5,500. It was estimated at the time of the purchase to have a total economic life of 10 years and a salvage value of $550. Using the straight line method of depreciation, the book value at the end of 7 years would be:",hint:"Salvage value must be deducted before computing depreciation. $5,500 - $550 = $4,950 divided by 10 = $495 per year x 7 years = $3,465. $5,500 - $3,465 = $2,035 (book value).",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,920.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,729.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$2,035.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$2,368.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"The net income of an apartment building went down $200 per month when a freeway was built nearby. If investors demand a 10% capitalization rate for this area, how much has the building lost in value?",hint:"$200 x 12 = $2,400. $2,400 divided by 10% = $24,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$3,333",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$20,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$36,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$24,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"Ted, an intelligent real estate investor wants to purchase a 60-unit apartment building that has an annual net income of $180,000. How much would he be willing to pay for the building if he uses a 12% capitalization rate?",hint:"$180,000 divided by 12% = $1,500,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$1,400,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,650,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,985,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$1,500,000",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"A small income property generates a monthly gross income of $600. Over the last five years it has been vacant for three months. The annual expenses are $2,000. If an appraiser applied a 10% capitalization rate to this property, what would be the value?",hint:"$600 x 12 = $7,200 annual gross income. 12 months x 5 years = 60 months. 3 months vacant divided by 60 months = .05 (5%) vacancy factor. $7,200 x 5% = $360 annual vacancy loss. $7,200 - $360 = $6,840 adjusted gross income. $6,840 - $2,000 annual expenses = $4,840 annual net income. $4,840 divided by 10% = $48,400.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$58,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$65,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$48,400",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$90,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Bob bought a parcel of raw land in 1985 and subdivided it into four separate lots. Five years later, he sold each lot for $50,000. The adjusted basis for each lot was $25,000. Bob's long-term capital gain on these transactions is:",hint:"$25,000 x 4 lots = $100,000 adjusted basis. $50,000 x 4 lots = $200,000 total selling price. $200,000 - $100,000 = $100,000 capital gains.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$100,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$320,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$400,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$500,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Mrs. Adams owned an income property with an adjusted cost basis of $160,000 and a fair market value of $240,000. She exchanged the property for another income property which had a fair market value of $230,000. Both properties had no loans against them and no adjustment was made for the differences in value. For federal income tax purposes, the new property will have a basis for Mrs. Johnson of:",hint:"In a tax deferred exchange, the cost basis of the property being traded becomes the cost basis for the property being acquired if no adjustment is made for differences in value; in this case, $160,000.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$100,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$160,000.",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$200,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$210,000.",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Brad bought a parcel of land in 1989 and subdivided it into four separate lots. Five years later, he sold each lot for $75,000. The adjusted basis for each lot was $25,000. Brad's capital gain on these transactions is:",hint:"$25,000 x 4 lots = $100,000 adjusted basis. $75,000 x 4 lots = $300,000 total selling price. $300,000 - $100,000 = $200,000 capital gain.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$80,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$320,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$400,000.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$200,000.",isCorrect:!0}]}},{questionText:"An apartment building is valued at $275,000 using a 7% capitalization rate. How much would an investor pay for the property if she demanded a 9% capitalization rate?",hint:"$275,000 x 7% = $19,250 annual net income. $19,250 divided by 9% = $213,889.89. Remember, as capitalization rate goes up, the value goes down.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$250,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$225,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$213,889",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$300,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"Investors want to build an apartment house which will have a gross income of $3,000 per month and annual expenses of $7,000. The investors require a 8% capitalization rate on the investment. If the improvements cost $175,000, how much can the investors pay for the land?",hint:"$3,000 x 12 = $36,000 gross annual income. $36,000 - $7,000 (expenses) = $29,000 annual net income. $29,000 divided by 8% (cap rate) = $362,500 total property value (land and improvements). $362,500 - $175,000 (cost of improvements) = $187,500 available to pay for the land.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$24,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$187,500",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"$150,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$200,000",isCorrect:!1}]}},{questionText:"An income property has a net income of $40,000. How much value would be lost if the current capitalization rate in the area changed from 5% to 8%?",hint:"Divide the net income of $40,000 by 5%. It will give you a value of $800,000. You divide the same net income of $40,000 by 8%. It gives you a value of $500,000. The net difference is a $300,000 decrease in value.",answers:{answer:[{answerText:"$100,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$10,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"$300,000",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]}}]}];
const examCategories=[{category:"Brokerage",id:1,amount:5},{category:"Practice",id:2,amount:18},{category:"Ownership",id:3,amount:35},{category:"Appraisal",id:4,amount:24},{category:"Finance",id:5,amount:31},{category:"Transfer",id:6,amount:30},{category:"Taxes",id:7,amount:7}];function getRandom(e,t){var a=new Array(t),r=e.length,o=new Array(r);if(t>r)throw new RangeError("getRandom: more items taken than available");for(;t--;){var n=Math.floor(Math.random()*r);a[t]=e[n in o?o[n]:n],o[n]=--r in o?o[r]:r}return a}function shuffle(e){let t,a=e.length;for(;0!=a;)t=Math.floor(Math.random()*a),a--,[e[a],e[t]]=[e[t],e[a]];return e}function createExam(){let e=[];for(let t=0;t<examCategories.length;t++){const a=questions.find((e=>e.id===examCategories[t].id)).list;e=e.concat(getRandom(shuffle(a),examCategories[t].amount))}return shuffle(e)}function createQuizExams(){let e=[];let t=1;return questions.forEach(((a,r)=>{for(var o=0;o<a.list.length;o+=100){let r={category:a.category+" "+t,id:t,list:a.list.slice(o,o+100)};e.push(r),t++}})),e}
"use strict";const HashRouter=ReactRouterDOM.HashRouter,NavLink=ReactRouterDOM.NavLink,Route=ReactRouterDOM.Route,Routes=ReactRouterDOM.Routes,useState=React.useState,useEffect=React.useEffect,useRef=React.useRef,greenButton="px-5 m-2 text-green-100 transition-colors duration-150 bg-green-700 rounded-lg focus:shadow-outline hover:bg-green-800",redButton="px-5 m-2 text-red-100 transition-colors duration-150 bg-red-700 rounded-lg focus:shadow-outline hover:bg-red-800",whiteButton="px-5 text-indigo-700 transition-colors duration-150 border border-indigo-500 rounded-lg focus:shadow-outline hover:bg-indigo-500 hover:text-white";function Timer(e){const{checkTimer:t,time:a}=e,{hours:l=0,minutes:c=0,seconds:n=0}=a,[[r,s,o],i]=React.useState([l,c,n]),m=()=>i([parseInt(l),parseInt(c),parseInt(n)]);return React.useEffect((()=>{const e=setInterval((()=>{0===r&&0===s&&0===o?m():i(0===s&&0===o?[r-1,59,59]:0===o?[r,s-1,59]:[r,s,o-1])}),1e3);return()=>clearInterval(e)})),t(l,s,o),React.createElement("div",{className:"inline-block"},React.createElement("p",null,`${r.toString().padStart(2,"0")}:${s.toString().padStart(2,"0")}:${o.toString().padStart(2,"0")}`))}function Glossary(){const[e,t]=useState(dictionary),[a,l]=useState(""),c=e=>{t(dictionary.filter((t=>t.term.toLocaleLowerCase().includes(e))))};return React.createElement("div",{className:"w-full container mx-auto"},React.createElement("div",{className:"flex justify-center flex-col"},React.createElement("h1",{className:"w-full text-center mb-6 text-4xl"},"Glossary"),React.createElement("div",{className:"my-6 w-full"},React.createElement("input",{className:"w-full border-2 border-gray-300 bg-white h-10 px-5 rounded-lg transition ease-in-out text-baseline focus:text-gray-700 focus:bg-white focus:border-blue-600 focus:outline-none",type:"text",placeholder:"Search",onChange:e=>{const t=e.target.value;l(t),c(a)}}))),React.createElement("div",{className:"bg-white shadow overflow-hidden sm:rounded-lg"},React.createElement("div",{className:"px-4 py-5 sm:px-6"},React.createElement("h3",{className:"text-lg leading-6 font-medium text-gray-900"},"Instructions: Just type for your desired term and the list will auto-populate as you type.")),React.createElement("div",{className:"border-t border-gray-200"},React.createElement("dl",null,e.map(((e,t)=>React.createElement("div",{key:t,className:"bg-gray-50 px-4 py-5 sm:grid sm:grid-cols-3 sm:gap-4 sm:px-6"},React.createElement("dt",{className:"text-lg font-medium text-gray-500"},e.term),React.createElement("dd",{className:"mt-1 text-lg text-gray-900 sm:mt-0 sm:col-span-2"},e.definition))))))))}function Exam(){const[e,t]=useState(0),[a,l]=useState(!1),[c,n]=useState(0),[r,s]=useState(!1),[o,i]=useState(0),[m,u]=useState(!1),[d,x]=useState([]);useEffect((()=>{x(createExam())}),[]);const g=({isCorrect:e},t)=>r?t===o&&e?greenButton:t!==o||e?e?greenButton:whiteButton:redButton:whiteButton,R=(e,t)=>Math.round(e/t.length*100);return d.length&&React.createElement(React.Fragment,null,React.createElement("div",{className:"w-full flex flex-col justify-center items-center"},a?React.createElement("div",{className:"text-3xl text-center"},React.createElement("p",null,"You scored ",c," out of ",d.length,".  That is ",R(c,d),"%."),React.createElement("p",null,R(c,d)>=70?"You Passed!":"You Failed! Try Again.")):React.createElement("div",{className:"max-w-lg bg-white shadow-md rounded-lg overflow-hidden mx-auto"},React.createElement("div",{className:"py-4 px-8 mt-3"},React.createElement("div",{className:"flex flex-col mb-4"},React.createElement("div",{className:"text-gray-700 font-semibold text-2xl tracking-wide mb-2"},React.createElement("p",null,"Time left: ",React.createElement(Timer,{checkTimer:(e,t,a)=>{0===e&&0===t&&0===a&&l(!0)},time:{hours:3,minutes:0,seconds:0}})),React.createElement("span",null,"Question ",e+1),"/",d.length),React.createElement("div",{className:"text-gray-500 text-2xl"},d[e].questionText),React.createElement("div",{className:"py-4"},m?React.createElement("div",{className:"text-xl"},"Hint: ",d[e].hint):React.createElement("button",{className:"w-full h-10 px-5 text-blue-100 transition-colors duration-150 bg-blue-600 rounded-lg focus:shadow-outline hover:bg-blue-700",onClick:e=>{e.preventDefault(),u(!0)}},"Show Hint"))),React.createElement("div",{className:"bg-gray-100 rounded-lg"},React.createElement("div",{className:"py-4 px-4"},React.createElement("div",{className:"flex flex-col gap-y-5"},d[e].answers.answer.map(((e,t)=>React.createElement("button",{key:t,disabled:r,className:`mb-1 py-4 text-xl ${g(e,t)}`,onClick:()=>(({isCorrect:e},t)=>{e&&n(c+1),i(t),s(!0)})(e,t)},e.answerText)))))),React.createElement("div",{className:"py-4"},React.createElement("button",{className:"w-full block tracking-widest uppercase text-center shadow bg-indigo-600 hover:bg-indigo-700 focus:shadow-outline focus:outline-none text-white text-xs py-3 px-10 rounded",onClick:()=>(()=>{const a=e+1;a<d.length?(t(a),s(!1),u(!1)):l(!0)})()},r?"Next Question":"Skip"))))))}function Quiz(){const[e,t]=useState(0),[a,l]=useState(!1),[c,n]=useState(0),[r,s]=useState(!1),[o,i]=useState(0),[m,u]=useState(!1),[d,x]=useState([]),[g,R]=useState([]);useEffect((()=>{R(createQuizExams())}),[]);const E=({isCorrect:e},t)=>r?t===o&&e?greenButton:t!==o||e?e?greenButton:whiteButton:redButton:whiteButton;return React.createElement(React.Fragment,null,React.createElement("div",{className:"w-full flex flex-col justify-center items-center"},React.createElement("div",{class:"flex flex-col justify-center"},React.createElement("div",{class:"flex flex-wrap justify-center py-3"},React.createElement("div",{className:"text-xl text-center"},React.createElement("p",null,"You will probably not be tested on the Math in the Exam but you can take the quiz if you like."))),React.createElement("div",{class:"flex flex-wrap justify-center space-x-2"},g.length?g.map(((e,a)=>React.createElement("span",{key:e.id,onClick:a=>{return l=e.id,x(g.find((e=>e.id===l)).list),t(0),n(0),void s(!1);var l},class:"px-4 py-2 my-2 rounded-full text-gray-500 bg-gray-200 font-semibold text-sm flex align-center w-max cursor-pointer active:bg-gray-300 transition duration-300 ease"},e.category))):null)),d.length?React.createElement("div",{className:"max-w-lg bg-white shadow-md rounded-lg overflow-hidden mx-auto"},React.createElement("div",{className:"text-xl text-center"},React.createElement("p",null,(()=>{const t=r?e+1:e,a=Math.round(c/t*100);return`You scored ${c} out of ${t}.  That is ${isNaN(a)?0:a}%.`})())),React.createElement("div",{className:"py-4 px-8 mt-3"},React.createElement("div",{className:"flex flex-col mb-4"},React.createElement("div",{className:"text-gray-700 font-semibold text-2xl tracking-wide mb-2"},React.createElement("span",null,"Question ",e+1),"/",d.length),React.createElement("div",{className:"text-gray-500 text-2xl"},d[e].questionText),React.createElement("div",{className:"py-4"},m?React.createElement("div",{className:"text-xl"},"Hint: ",d[e].hint):React.createElement("button",{className:"w-full h-10 px-5 text-blue-100 transition-colors duration-150 bg-blue-600 rounded-lg focus:shadow-outline hover:bg-blue-700",onClick:()=>{u(!0)}},"Show Hint"))),React.createElement("div",{className:"bg-gray-100 rounded-lg"},React.createElement("div",{className:"py-4 px-4"},React.createElement("div",{className:"flex flex-col gap-y-5"},d[e].answers.answer.map(((e,t)=>React.createElement("button",{key:t,disabled:r,className:`mb-1 py-4 text-xl ${E(e,t)}`,onClick:()=>(({isCorrect:e},t)=>{e&&n(c+1),i(t),s(!0)})(e,t)},e.answerText)))))),React.createElement("div",{className:"py-4"},React.createElement("button",{className:"w-full block tracking-widest uppercase text-center shadow bg-indigo-600 hover:bg-indigo-700 focus:shadow-outline focus:outline-none text-white text-xs py-3 px-10 rounded",onClick:()=>(()=>{const a=e+1;a<d.length?(t(a),s(!1),u(!1)):l(!0)})()},r?"Next Question":"Skip")))):null))}function Home(){return React.createElement("div",{className:"text-3xl text-center"},React.createElement("p",null,"This application was designed to help you prepare for the California Real Estate Agent Exam.  THIS IS NOT THE REAL EXAM.  Do not refresh your browser while you are taking your Exam in this app or else you will have to start over."))}class Main extends React.Component{render(){return React.createElement(HashRouter,null,React.createElement("main",{className:"container mx-auto w-screen pt-4 min-h-screen"},React.createElement("nav",{class:"flex items-center flex-col flex-wrap bg-teal-500 p-6"},React.createElement("div",{class:"flex items-center flex-shrink-0 text-white mr-6"},React.createElement("img",{class:"fill-current h-8 w-8 mr-2",width:"54",height:"54",src:"data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAEAAAABACAYAAACqaXHeAAAABmJLR0QA/wD/AP+gvaeTAAAET0lEQVR4nO2bQWgVRxjHf08kIngQIVFfwMRDSw8FzcFLq1BQkdB4EAK2FXqpBxUverANpVXQGrVQjL14jQdvHj20YqCUlh5iEdJeKoiCCpZGYm2oiZrnYb5hZze7+2Z2Z3ez5v1h2Pe+mfnm+/93Zna+fQksczSqDqBgvAUMA/3ANHAd+MXnAOuBW0Cr5PIEuAEMJsTVAE4CL2L6XgPW+CL/ZwXko+VUDPkxqVsArgJHgQso4bQI3smXiXXAcWAOeAw0xW6Sfw7sjfR7G5iR+veyDm6Sn6IaATQ+ANbKZ5N8C3gJHIjpc0Hqz2QZMEq+m2oF0Ije+SsEInwSaXtI6i67DhJHHqoXIEpeb4zniBdBi3PCZZAk8lCtAEnkuwkvTy3CEPAKmAc22w6SRn6H2B/kIJEVNuSngFECEZ7L5y/THO8hvD5snvNnPRBygS35HrGPE8R6kZQD4FcEz8+NYksj/gBFvssLLTu4kh8kuPOp5HdJo3nUM3a12Kve5EwURh7gR2l4LGLPK0APcDhHf41CyQP8LY27I3ZbAfYBPwGzUiaAj43gjlj4SELh5CGZqI0A35G8T0SDc0Up5CG7AMNGcCdQm+c7BGfuFmomJPmNKxoN4BLp5P/AA3kzIFu7xq+ET1Y9RnBP5XozxW+SAKWSNwOytesg56W+SZj8FGomtIB/HWPxQd55884iwArCAhwhvCab8v2ZSyDAZwTnkSGxud75UgQA+E3qP5fvh43gRqRuIsVvnP9Jwz4ObKA9+THC0740AfZL/RxKhKaUEbG1WPxiwvQb9b9Fvs+glo6eQS7kbeJODMjWbsJ8EREt37oEYfj6HnifsAj6eN6OvG3cVh1sHe1HPRHmUPvCz6jDkQtWAf/IeHvEZoowjtoT2pF3ibttB2dHOaCXUwu4C/SJ3RRhgfbkYQkJ4JIL/CBj6be3d4HdKLLmwcok7y3uvI7y5gKbUG9r/gcGCEQwy+/AQex2+1IF8JELfC1tZ1Ei6L7TqEPR1gLi9uIoby6gccewvUIth49QG2MRcXtzlDcX0LgJ/IWaCZtKiNuLo6JyARfkEmBlzsGjj6Fh4F3UiW2n4b8Wv0JnVdJXLhAtRcftzZGvXKC2AoDfXMAVS0IA8JMLZMGSEaAq5Ip7hfdwaoaOAFUHUDWiWdWbiNRD2LKfAXFH4VocWy1gNaOX/Qx4EwTIdU4xBfhPrs24hjVDr1zbpuGmAJNy/dR7OMWiweJ9S3OYxAF7CbK6L6jnTOglnIV+6OrgG9qnqXUpp13JawyhXmDo3+PqVJ6h3i0633mfGJBgbmfoe1v6DniNKAVFPAb75XovQ1/dpz+1lUd0BCjAp/5B836GvrpPX2orj+jMgAJ81koAH+gCzgOP8P9Ye4j6x4cy/xjbGfo/M4os50pjkwEPUUFuK8D3doKZUAh87gFF7Ce1eDlTxhIYLY1NBnShRNBLYdltgh3UGa8BW5tyu+S4YLkAAAAASUVORK5CYII="}),React.createElement("span",{class:"font-semibold text-xl tracking-tight"},"California Real Estate Exam Prep")),React.createElement("div",{class:"w-full block text-center flex-grow lg:flex lg:items-center lg:w-auto"},React.createElement("ul",{class:"text-sm lg:flex-grow"},React.createElement("li",{class:"block mt-4 px-3 lg:inline-block lg:mt-0 text-teal-200 hover:text-white"},React.createElement(NavLink,{to:"/"},"Home")),React.createElement("li",{class:"block mt-4 px-3 lg:inline-block lg:mt-0 text-teal-200 hover:text-white"},React.createElement(NavLink,{to:"/glossary"},"Glossary")),React.createElement("li",{class:"block mt-4 px-3 lg:inline-block lg:mt-0 text-teal-200 hover:text-white"},React.createElement(NavLink,{to:"/quiz"},"Quiz")),React.createElement("li",{class:"block mt-4 px-3 lg:inline-block lg:mt-0 text-teal-200 hover:text-white"},React.createElement(NavLink,{to:"/exam"},"Exam"))))),React.createElement("div",{className:"content"},React.createElement(Routes,null,React.createElement(Route,{exact:!0,path:"/",element:React.createElement(Home,null)}),React.createElement(Route,{path:"/glossary",element:React.createElement(Glossary,null)}),React.createElement(Route,{path:"/quiz",element:React.createElement(Quiz,null)}),React.createElement(Route,{path:"/exam",element:React.createElement(Exam,null)})))))}}ReactDOM.render(React.createElement(Main,null),document.querySelector("#root"));